<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="above[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">above</hw> <sound><wav>above001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈbʌv</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or to a higher place <vi>They stood under the tree and looked at the branches <it>above</it>. [=<it>overhead</it>]</vi> <vi>The stars shone <it>above</it>. [=in the sky]</vi> <vi>The stairs lead <it>above</it> [=<it>upstairs</it>] to the bedrooms.</vi> <vi>up <it>above</it> and down below</vi> <snote>The opposite of every sense of <it>above</it> is <it>below</it>.</snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or to a higher rank or number <vi>Students in the grade <it>above</it> [=in the next grade] study algebra.</vi> <vi>Groups of six and <it>above</it> [=of six or more] need reservations.</vi> <vi>a game that is suitable for children at/of age 10 and <it>above</it> [=<it>older</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:above zero <vi>Temperatures range from 5 below to 5 <it>above</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:higher, further up, or earlier on the same page or on a preceding page :at a previous point in the same document <vi>Write to us at the address shown <it>above</it>. [=at the above address]</vi> <vi>Except as noted <it>above</it>, all the information can be verified.</vi> <vi>the person named <it>above</it> = the <it>above</it>-named person</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>from above</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:from a higher place or position <vi>It looks like a cross when viewed <it>from above</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:from someone with greater power or authority <vi>waiting for orders <it>from above</it></vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="above[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">above</hw> <altpr>əˈbʌv</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or to a higher place than (something) :<sx>over</sx> <vi>He raised his arms <it>above</it> his head.</vi> <vi>They hung a mirror <it>above</it> the mantel.</vi> <vi>We rented an apartment <it>above</it> a restaurant.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>below</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:greater in number, quantity, or size than (something) :more than (something) <vi>Temperatures were <it>above</it> average all week.</vi> <vi>men <it>above</it> 50 years old</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>below</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to a greater degree or extent than (something) <vi>She values her private time <it>above</it> her fame.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in a higher or more important position than (something) <vi>He puts his child's needs <it>above</it> his own.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>below</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:having more importance or power than (someone) :having a higher rank than (someone) <vi>A captain is <it>above</it> a lieutenant. [=a captain outranks a lieutenant]</vi> <vi>Who is <it>above</it> him in that department?</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>below</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:too important for (something) :not able to be affected by (something) <vi>She thinks that she's <it>above</it> criticism/suspicion. [=that she cannot be criticized/suspected]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>above the law</tag> at <dxt>law</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:too good for (some type of behavior, work, etc.) <vi>I thought you were <it>above</it> lying to people. [=I thought such dishonest behavior was beneath you]</vi> <vi>He was not <it>above</it> cheating when it served his purposes. [=he would cheat when it served his purposes]</vi> <vi>Does she think she's <it>above</it> that kind of work? [=does she think that kind of work is beneath her?]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:more loudly and clearly than (another sound) <vi>I heard the whistle <it>above</it> [=<it>over</it>] the roar of the crowd.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <def><dt>:as the most important thing :<sx>especially</sx> <vi><it>Above all</it>, we must consider what is best for the children.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>above and beyond</dre> <def><dt>:far beyond what is required by (something, such as a duty) <vi>He went <it>above and beyond</it> the call of duty. [=he did more than his duty required him to do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get above yourself</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to think you are more important than you really are <vi>We are pleased by his success, but we worry that he might be <it>getting above himself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over and above</dre> <dx>see <dxt>over</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="above[3]"> <hw hindex="3">above</hw> <altpr>əˈbʌv</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:mentioned at an earlier point in the same document :written above <vi>You can contact me at the <it>above</it> address. [=at the address shown above]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>the above</dre> <def><dt>:something that is mentioned at an earlier point in the same document <vi>If any of <it>the above</it> is incorrect, please me know.</vi> <vi>Contact any of <it>the above</it> [=any of the people mentioned above] for more information.</vi> <vi>The correct answer is “<phrase>none of the above</phrase>.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the entire number, quantity, or amount <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] that I have is yours.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] will be explained soon.</vi> <vi>She told us <it>all</it> about what happened.</vi> <vi>Her other books were good, but this one is the best of <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> are welcome! [=everyone is welcome]</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> enjoyed the movie. = <it>All</it> of us enjoyed the movie.</vi> <vi>Many people were invited and <it>all</it> came.</vi> <vi>His stories may be entertaining, but I don't think <it>all</it> (of them) are true.</vi> <vi>Thanks to <it>all</it> who helped out.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> of this money will be yours when I die.</vi> <vi>Not <it>all</it> of our students go on to college.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>was all (that) I could do</phrase> to keep from laughing! [=I had a hard time trying not to laugh]</vi> <vi>“Is there anything else to be done?” “No, <phrase>that's all</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He gave equal attention to <phrase>one and all</phrase>. [=to everyone]</vi> <vi><phrase>Come one, come all</phrase>. [=everyone is invited to come]</vi> <usageref>altogether</usageref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the only thing <vi>That's <it>all</it> I can do to help.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> I know is that the game was canceled. I don't know why.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>after</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>All aboard!</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aboard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all in all</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a general way :when everything is thought of or considered <vi><it>All in all</it> [=<it>in general, generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi> <vi>We did lose some money, but we got most of it back. So <it>all in all</it> things might have been a lot worse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>The cost of the repairs came to about $300 <it>all told</it>. [=<it>in all</it>] [=the total cost of the repairs was about $300]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>and all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:and everything else <vi>What with the noise outside, the fire <it>and all</it>, we got hardly any sleep.</vi> <vi>He endured everything, insults <it>and all</it>, without getting angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a response <vi>“It's really hot out!” “It is <it>and all</it>!” [=it certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>He will go anywhere <it>at all</it> to get a job.</vi> <vi>Did you find out anything <it>at all</it>?</vi></un> <un>used especially in negative statements <vi>“Did she say anything?” “No, nothing <it>at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't mind cooking <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>at all</it> what you think it is. It's something else entirely.</vi> <vi>I wasn't tired <it>at all</it>. = I wasn't <it>at all</it> tired. [=I wasn't even slightly tired]</vi> <vi>This chair is not <it>at all</it> comfortable.</vi> <vi>I didn't like it <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>That is not <it>at all</it> likely.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>not at all</phrase> is sometimes used as a polite response when someone thanks you. <vi>“Thank you for all your trouble.” “<it>Not at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>“That was very kind of you.” “<it>Not at all</it>. It was the least I could do.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your all</dre> <def><dt>:to do or give as much as you can to achieve something, to support a cause, etc. <vi>He <it>gave his all</it> for the cause. = He <it>gave his all</it> to help the cause.</vi> <vi>You'll never succeed in this business unless you <it>give (it) your all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>There were about a thousand people at the concert <it>in all</it>. [=<it>all told</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>once and for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <def><dt>:after considering or doing everything <un>used for a final general statement or judgment <vi>It won't be easy, but <it>when all is said and done</it>, we'll be glad we did it.</vi> <vi>The candidates claim to have different views but, <it>when all is said and done</it>, they're very much alike.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="beyond[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">beyond</hw> <altpr>bɪˈɑ:nd</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:on or to the farther part or side of (something) :at a greater distance than (something) <vi>From the house we can see the valley and the mountains <it>beyond</it> it.</vi> <vi>The parking area is just <it>beyond</it> those trees.</vi> <vi>Our land extends <it>beyond</it> the fence to those trees.</vi> <vi>planets <it>beyond</it> our solar system</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:outside the limits or range of (something) :more than (something) <vi>The job is <it>beyond</it> his ability. [=the job is too hard for him; he is not capable of doing the job well]</vi> <vi>Such a project is <it>beyond</it> the city's budget. [=the project is too expensive]</vi> <vi>The results were <it>beyond</it> our expectations. [=were better than we expected]</vi> <vi>His influence does not extend <it>beyond</it> this department.</vi> <vi>She became rich <phrase>beyond her wildest dreams</phrase>. [=became very rich]</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>live beyond your means</phrase>, you spend more money than you earn. <vi>We need to stop <it>living beyond our means</it> and start saving some money.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something cannot be changed, understood, etc. <vi>The situation is <phrase>beyond help</phrase>. [=the situation cannot be made better; nothing can help the situation]</vi> <vi>The city has changed <phrase>beyond (all) recognition</phrase>. [=it has changed so much that it looks completely different]</vi> <vi>The circumstances are <phrase>beyond our control</phrase>. [=we cannot control the circumstances]</vi> <vi>The stories she tells are <phrase>beyond belief</phrase>. [=are not believable]</vi> <vi>His irresponsible actions are <phrase>beyond comprehension/understanding</phrase>. [=cannot be understood]</vi></un> <snote>If something is <phrase>beyond you</phrase>, you do not understand it. <vi>“Why is he going?” “It's <it>beyond me</it>.”</vi> <vi>How she was able to afford the trip is <it>beyond me</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:for a period of time that continues after (a particular date, age, etc.) <vi>The program is unlikely to continue <it>beyond</it> next year. [=it will probably end after next year]</vi> <vi>She plans to continue working <it>beyond</it> the usual retirement age.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:in addition to <vi>There were no other problems with the house <it>beyond</it> [=<it>besides</it>] the leaky roof.</vi> <vi>I knew nothing about him <it>beyond</it> [=<it>except</it>] what he told me.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above and beyond</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cut[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">cut</hw> <altpr>ˈkʌt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cuts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:an opening or hole made with a sharp tool (such as a knife) <vi>Make a few small <it>cuts</it> in the crust to let the air escape.</vi> <vi>a two-inch <it>cut</it> in the cloth</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a wound on a person's body that is made by something sharp <vi>She had a small <it>cut</it> [=<it>gash</it>] above her left eye.</vi> <vi>He came home covered in <it>cuts</it> and bruises.</vi> <vi>a deep/superficial <it>cut</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an act of making something smaller in amount :<sx>reduction</sx> <vi>Further <it>cuts</it> in spending are needed.</vi> <vi>He had to accept a <it>cut</it> in pay. = He had to accept a <phrase>pay cut</phrase>.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>tax cut</phrase></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the act of removing something from a book, movie, etc. <vi>You'll have to make a few <it>cuts</it> in your manuscript if you want us to publish it.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a version of a movie at a particular stage of being edited <vi>Fortunately, that scene didn't make the film's final <it>cut</it>. [=that scene did not appear in the final version of the film]</vi> <vi>I saw a <phrase>rough cut</phrase> [=a version that is not yet finished] of the movie.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>director's cut</phrase> [=a special version of a movie that is created by the director and that usually includes scenes that are not included in other versions]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a song on a record, tape, or CD <vi>We listened to the same <it>cut</it> [=<it>track</it>] over and over.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the shape and style of a piece of clothing <vi>the <it>cut</it> of his pants</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:the act or result of cutting someone's hair :<sx>haircut</sx> <vi>I had a shampoo and a <it>cut</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>buzz cut</dxt> <dxt>crew cut</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:a piece of meat that is cut from a particular part of an animal's body <vi>a thick/tender/expensive <it>cut</it> of meat</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:a part of something that is divided and shared among people <un>usually singular <vi>We each got a <it>cut</it> [=<it>share</it>] of the profits.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>a cut of the action</tag> at <dxt>action</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:the act of reducing the size of a group (such as a group of competitors) by removing the ones that are not good enough or that have not done well enough <un>usually used with <it>make</it> or <it>miss</it> <vi>He has to birdie the last hole in order to <phrase>make the cut</phrase>. [=in order to have a score that is low enough to be among the players allowed to continue playing]</vi> <vi>If he doesn't birdie this hole, he'll <phrase>miss the cut</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Only the best players are good enough to <it>make the cut</it> when the team is being chosen.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a cut above</dre> <def><dt>:better than other people or things <vi>All of his books are good, but this one is <it>a cut above</it> (the rest).</vi> <vi>She's <it>a cut above</it> the other competitors and should win easily.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut and thrust</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:the lively and exciting quality of an activity in which people compete or argue with each other <vi>He has always enjoyed the <it>cut and thrust</it> of politics.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="fray[1]"> <hw hindex="1">fray</hw> <sound><wav>fray0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfreɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>frays</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a fight, struggle, or disagreement that involves many people <vi>He threw himself into the <it>fray</it>.</vi> <vi>He joined/entered the political <it>fray</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above the fray</dre> <def><dt>:not directly involved in an angry or difficult struggle or disagreement <vi>His political aides handled the controversy while he remained <it>above the fray</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="get"> <hw highlight="yes">get</hw> <sound><wav>get00001.wav</wav><wav>get00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɛt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gets</if></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <il>or US</il> <if>got*ten</if> <sound><wav>get00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:tn̩</pr></in> <in><if>get*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to obtain (something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to receive or be given (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> a new bicycle for his birthday.</vi> <vi>I never did <it>get</it> an answer to my question.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> a letter from my lawyer.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a phone call from her sister.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>get</it> my message?</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] a ride to town with you? [=will you give me a ride to town?]</vi> <vi>You need to <it>get</it> your mother's permission to go.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to obtain (something) through effort, chance, etc. <vi>She hasn't been able to <it>get</it> a job.</vi> <vi>It's nearly impossible to <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a reservation at that restaurant.</vi> <vi>If you want to be successful you need to <it>get</it> a good education.</vi> <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> the waiter's attention.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a look at the thief. [=she managed to look at the thief]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to obtain the use or services of (something) <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> a taxi.</vi> <vi>It's hard to <it>get</it> good help these days.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to earn or gain (something) <vi>How much does he <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a week?</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> $50 when I sold my old bicycle. = I <it>got</it> $50 for my old bicycle.</vi> <vi>He's <it>gotten</it> a bad reputation (for himself). = He's <it>gotten</it> himself a bad reputation.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> an “A” on my history exam!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>She <it>got</it> first prize in the essay contest.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to buy or pay for (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> (himself) a new car at a great price.</vi> <vi>“Did you <it>get</it> that dress at the mall?” “Yes, and I <it>got</it> it for only $20.”</vi> <vi>Do you <it>get</it> [=subscribe to] the local newspaper?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the next round of drinks.</vi> <vi>He offered to <it>get</it> the check, but I insisted on <it>getting</it> it myself.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> a beautiful necklace for his wife. = He <it>got</it> his wife a beautiful necklace.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go somewhere and come back with (something or someone) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> a pencil from the desk.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> anything for you? = Can I <it>get</it> you anything?</vi> <vi>Someone has to (go) <it>get</it> the boss from the airport and bring her back here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to send or take (something or someone) <it>to</it> a person or place <vi>I have to <it>get</it> an important message <it>to</it> her at once!</vi> <vi>We have to <it>get</it> him <it>to</it> the hospital immediately.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to move or go <vi>He quickly <it>got</it> himself and his luggage through customs.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> the car out of the garage.</vi> <vi>I could barely <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] the luggage into the car's trunk.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> this ring on/off my finger.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <vi>He <it>got</it> on the horse and rode away.</vi> <vi>We <it>got</it> on/off the bus.</vi> <vi>They quickly <it>got</it> [=<it>passed</it>] through customs.</vi> <vi>She never <it>got</it> out of the house last weekend.</vi> <vi>He lost weight to be able to <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] into his jeans again.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> between them to keep them from fighting.</vi> <vi>Ouch! <it>Get</it> off my foot!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>When did you <it>get</it> here/there?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> home last night.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have (a feeling, an idea, etc.) <vi>I <it>got</it> a funny feeling when I saw her again.</vi> <vi>He somehow <it>got</it> the idea that I was lying to him.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> the impression that he wasn't interested.</vi> <vi>One thing led to another, and—well, <phrase>you get the picture/idea</phrase>. [=you can easily guess the rest]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become affected by (a disease) <vi>I <it>got</it> a bad cold when I was on vacation.</vi> <vi>Clean the wound carefully so you don't <it>get</it> an infection.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suffer (an injury) <vi>He <it>got</it> a broken nose in a fight.</vi> <vi>Where/how did you <it>get</it> that bruise on your leg?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or experience (something) <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> a lot of rain recently.</vi> <vi>I finally <it>got</it> a good night's sleep last night. [=I finally slept well last night]</vi> <vi>The inn doesn't <it>get</it> many visitors these days.</vi> <vi>“Do people often ask if you're Irish?” “Yes, I <it>get</it> that a lot.” [=people ask me that often]</vi> <vi><phrase>You get</phrase> [=there are] so many crazy drivers these days.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a particular reaction) <vi>That joke always <it>gets</it> a laugh.</vi> <vi>Her comments <it>got</it> an angry reaction.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make progress in some activity <vi>He hasn't <it>gotten</it> far with the essay. [=he hasn't made much progress with the essay]</vi> <vi>You won't <it>get</it> anywhere with flattery. [=you won't succeed by using flattery]</vi> <vi>At last we're <phrase>getting somewhere</phrase> (with our work)!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get ahead <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to make progress <vi>All that effort didn't really <it>get</it> us very far.</vi> <vi>Flattery will <phrase>get you nowhere</phrase>. = Flattery <phrase>won't get you anywhere</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a specified position or condition <vi>He <it>got</it> his feet wet when he stepped in a puddle.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> his nose broken in a fight. [=his nose was broken in a fight]</vi> <vi>I told you not to <it>get</it> yourself dirty.</vi> <vi>You nearly <it>got</it> us both killed!</vi> <vi>I need to <it>get</it> [=<it>have</it>] my hair cut.</vi> <vi>She finally <it>got</it> her office organized.</vi> <vi>He promised to <it>get</it> the work done quickly. [=to do the work quickly]</vi> <vi>When you're making a measurement be careful to <phrase>get it right</phrase>. [=to do it correctly]</vi> <vi>Let me <phrase>get this straight</phrase> [=let me be sure that I understand this correctly]: are you saying that you won't help us?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do something <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> the children <it>to behave</it>.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>get</it> you <it>to understand</it> that this isn't a good idea?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>to work</it> again.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>working</it> again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start <it>doing</it> something <vi>We <it>got talking</it> about old times.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>1a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or be given the chance <it>to do</it> something :to be able <it>to do</it> something <vi>She never <it>got to go</it> to college.</vi> <vi>Why do I never <it>get to drive</it> the car?</vi> <vi>She hopes she'll finally <it>get to spend</it> more time working on her garden this year.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to deal with (something that needs attention): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to answer (a telephone) <vi>Would somebody please <it>get</it> the phone?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to open (a door) <vi>If you'll <it>get</it> the door for me, I'll carry that box inside.</vi> <vi>There's someone at the door. Would you please <phrase>get it</phrase>? [=open the door and deal with the person who knocked]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to understand (something or someone) <vi>I just don't <it>get</it> the point of what you're saying.</vi> <vi>He didn't <it>get</it> the joke.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>get</it> what you mean.</vi> <vi>Oh, now I <phrase>get it</phrase>. [=<it>understand</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I just don't <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>Don't <phrase>get me wrong</phrase>. [=don't misunderstand what I am saying]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>get your drift</phrase>. [=I understand what you are saying]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I didn't quite <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] his name.</vi></dt> <sn>17 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:<sx>become <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>My hands <it>got</it> dirty when I was working in the garden.</vi> <vi>I <it>get</it> very nervous when I have to speak in public.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> sick last week but I'm feeling better now.</vi> <vi>I just can't <it>get</it> used to this cold weather.</vi> <vi>She sent her sick friend a “<it>Get</it> Well Soon” card.</vi> <vi>I should go; it's <it>getting</it> late.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) Your daughter's <it>getting</it> quite a big girl now!</vi> <vi>We need to finish by 5 o'clock, so we'd better <phrase>get busy</phrase>. [=begin to work]</vi> <vi>You've never heard of the Internet? Come on, now. <phrase>Get with it</phrase>. [=become up-to-date in your knowledge]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>how stupid/lucky (etc.) can you get</phrase> to mean that someone or something is unusually stupid, lucky, etc. <vi>He tried to rob a policeman. <it>How stupid can you get</it>? [=he was very stupid to try to rob a policeman]</vi> <vi>Just look at that dress! <it>How tacky can you get</it>? [=that dress is very tacky]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change in a specified way as time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Your daughter is <it>getting to be</it> [=is becoming] quite a big girl now!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Once you <it>get to know</it> him, you will like him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>be</it> with the past participle of some verbs to form passive constructions <vi>They <it>got</it> [=<it>were</it>] married last month.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>was</it>] paid for his work.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> arrested for fraud.</vi> <vi>I nearly <it>got</it> killed.</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a meal) <vi>We <it>got</it> dinner at an Italian restaurant last night.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare (a meal) <vi>On weekends, my wife sleeps late while I <it>get</it> breakfast.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (punishment) <vi>He <it>got</it> five years in prison for his crime.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you don't stop misbehaving you're going to <phrase>get it</phrase> when your father gets home! [=your father is going to punish you]</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to grip and hold (something or someone) <vi>The dog <it>got</it> the thief by the leg.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>] me around/by the neck and wouldn't let go.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find and catch (someone) <vi>The Royal Canadian Mounted Police always <it>get</it> their man! [=they always capture the man they are trying to capture]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone) <vi>The bullet <it>got</it> him in the leg.</vi></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or cause trouble for (someone) <vi>He's convinced that his ex-wife is out to <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you if it's the last thing I do!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the death of (someone) <vi>He had heart problems for many years, but it was pneumonia that <it>got</it> him in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>It really <it>gets</it> me that such a foolish man has so much influence.</vi> <vi>What <it>gets</it> me is all these delays!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) sad <vi>The end of that movie always <it>gets</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2b (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be fooled or unable to think of an answer <vi>Well, you <it>got</it> [=<it>fooled, tricked</it>] me that time. That was very clever.</vi> <vi>That's a good question. <phrase>You've got me (there)</phrase>. [=I don't know the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a phone call and hear or speak to (a person or answering machine) <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get</it> [=<it>reach</it>] you (on the phone) all day!</vi> <vi>When I tried to call him I <it>got</it> his answering machine. [=the phone was answered by his answering machine]</vi></dt> <sn>28</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (a radio or TV station or channel) <vi>We don't <it>get</it> this channel at home.</vi></dt> <sn>29</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce or provide (a level of performance) <vi>Our new car <it>gets</it> [=<it>delivers</it>] excellent gas mileage.</vi></dt> <sn>30</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to notice (someone or something) <vi>Did you <it>get</it> the way he looked at you?</vi> <un>often used to direct someone's attention to a person or thing that is seen as foolish, surprising, etc. <vi>Just <it>get</it> him in his new pants!</vi> <vi>She showed up at the party in—<phrase>get this</phrase>—a $3,000 designer dress!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>get about</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get above yourself</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my point has finally <it>gotten across</it> to you. [=I hope you finally understand what I am trying to say]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my point <it>across</it> to you.</vi> <vi>a politician who is trying hard to <it>get</it> his message <it>across</it> (to the voters)</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>get after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to tell (someone) repeatedly to do something <vi>His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him about doing his homework. = His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him to do his homework.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to become more successful <vi>a book about how to <it>get ahead</it> in the business world</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be or remain friendly <vi>We <it>get along</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi> <vi>My brother and my uncle don't really <it>get along</it> (with each other).</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How are you <it>getting along</it> with your work? [=how's your work coming along?]</vi> <vi>He never showed up, but we managed to <it>get along</it> [=<it>get by</it>] without him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>I really must be <it>getting along</it>. [=<it>going, leaving</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become old <vi>Her parents are <phrase>getting along in years</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to go, walk, or travel to different places <vi>She <it>gets around</it> a lot because of her job.</vi> <vi>He's having trouble <it>getting around</it> because of his sore knee.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get round</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to become known by many people <vi>People will be shocked when the news about her arrest <it>gets around</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got around</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to avoid being stopped by (something) :to avoid having to deal with (something) <vi>I'm sure we can find a way to <it>get around</it> these problems.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no getting around</phrase> the fact that the current system isn't working. [=there is no way to deny that the current system isn't working]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around to (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or deal with (something that you have not yet done or dealt with) <vi>Don't you think it's about time you <it>got around to</it> tidying your room?</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call her, but I just haven't <it>gotten around to</it> it. [=I haven't called her]</vi> <vi>Sooner or later we'll have to <it>get around to</it> the subject of taxation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach (something or someone) <vi>The valve is hard to <it>get at</it> unless you have a special tool.</vi> <vi>An angry mob tried to <it>get at</it> him but the police protected him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find out (information that is hidden or hard to know) <vi>How can we ever <it>get at</it> the truth?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or suggest (something) in an indirect way <un>usually used as <phrase>getting at</phrase> <vi>Just what are you <it>getting at</it>? [=what are you suggesting?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>He says his teachers are always <it>getting at</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>getting on</it>] him unfairly.</vi> <vi>He's always being <it>got at</it> by his teachers.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You have a lot of work to do so you'd better <it>get at it</it>. [=<it>get to it</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go away from a place <vi>I'll be busy at work all day and I can't <it>get away</it> until tonight.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company is having problems because they've <phrase>gotten away from</phrase> the things they do best. [=they have stopped doing the things they do best]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go away from your home for a vacation <vi>I'm taking some time off because I really need to <it>get away</it> for a few days.</vi> <vi>We went on a cruise to <phrase>get away from it all</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to avoid being caught :to escape <vi>The robbers <it>got away</it> (from the police) in a fast car.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The robbers <it>got away with</it> a lot of stolen jewelry.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can't <it>get away</it> from the facts. = <phrase>There's no getting away from</phrase> the facts. [=you can't avoid or deny the facts; the facts are known and cannot be ignored]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>getaway</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be criticized or punished for (something) <vi>She's incredibly rude. I don't know how she <it>gets away with</it> it.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>There's a chance of rain, but I think I can probably <it>get away with</it> leaving my umbrella at home. [=I probably will not need my umbrella]</vi> <vi>It would be nice to have more food for the party, but I think we can <it>get away with</it> what we have. [=I think what we have is enough and will not cause problems for us]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given only slight or mild punishment for a crime or for doing something wrong <vi>The policeman stopped her for speeding but let her <it>get away with</it> just a warning.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get away with murder</tag> at <dxt>murder</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place after going away <vi>When did you <it>get back</it> from your vacation?</vi> <vi>We <it>got back</it> to the office in the early afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to return to an activity, condition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Things are finally <it>getting back to</it> normal.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>get back to</it> the topic we were discussing yesterday.</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>get back to work</phrase>. [=to start working again]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or obtain (something you have lost) again :to recover (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> his old job <it>back</it> after a long struggle.</vi> <vi>Someone stole his wallet but he <it>got</it> it <it>back</it> from the police.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back at (someone)</pva> <pvl>or Brit</pvl> <pva>get your own back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do something bad or unpleasant to someone who has treated you badly or unfairly <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you <it>back</it> for what you did to me!</vi> <vi>After he lost his job, he vowed that he would find a way to <it>get back at</it> his old boss.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get back to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk to or write to (someone) at a later time in order to give more information, answer a question, etc. <vi>He <it>got back to</it> me (by e-mail) in a few days with a new offer.</vi> <vi>“How much will it cost?” “I'm not sure. I'll have to <it>get back to</it> you on that.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to call (someone) back on the telephone <vi>“There's someone on the phone for you, sir.” “Tell them I can't take their call now but I'll <it>get back to</it> them as soon as I can.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back to (the) basics</dre> <dx>see <dxt>basic</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fail to do something as quickly as required or expected <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> further (and further) <it>behind</it> (schedule).</vi> <vi>We <it>got behind</it> with our car payments.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get behind (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to support (someone or something) <vi>The proposal may succeed if a few more people <it>get behind</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do enough or to do well enough to avoid failure <vi>He's doing very well in his history classes, but he's barely <it>getting by</it> in math.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be able to live or to do what is needed by using what you have even though you do not have much <vi>We don't have a lot of money, but we <it>get by</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>How can you <it>get by on</it> such a small salary?</vi></un> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>We <it>got by with</it> a minimum of clothing when we went camping.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get cracking</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>The weather was really <it>getting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Talking about politics always <it>gets</it> me <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to swallow (something) :to eat or drink (something) <vi>You'll feel better once you <it>get</it> this medicine <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to write (something) down <vi>If you have a good idea, you should <it>get</it> it <it>down</it> (in writing) so that you won't forget it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to play music or dance with skill and enthusiasm <vi>She likes to <it>get down</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) :to begin to give your attention or effort to (something) <vi>It's time to stop delaying and <it>get down to</it> work.</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>get down to business</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk about or describe (something) in a very simple and accurate way <vi><phrase>When you get right down to it</phrase>, this movie is just not very good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get even</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get going</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave <vi>We ought to <it>get going</it> if we don't want to be late.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You should <it>get going</it> on that assignment.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to start talking <vi>Once he <it>gets going</it> about the war you can't shut him up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to start talking <vi>Don't <it>get</it> him <it>going</it> about the war or you'll never shut him up!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>The burglar <it>got in</it> through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The train <it>got in</it> late.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to arrive home <vi>Her husband was out late last night. He didn't <it>get in</it> until almost midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become involved in an activity <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got in</it> at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be chosen or elected for office <vi>The mayor <it>got in</it> by a very slim margin.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>It's a very good school. I hope your daughter <it>gets in</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (someone) come to your home, business, etc., to do work <vi>We had to <it>get</it> a doctor/plumber <it>in</it> to deal with the emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do or say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get</it> a few good punches <it>in</it> before they stopped the fight.</vi> <vi>May I <phrase>get a word in</phrase> here? [=may I say something here?]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get a word in edgewise</tag> at <dxt>edgewise</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send or deliver (something) to the proper person or place <vi>Did you <it>get</it> your assignment <it>in</it> on time?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to do (something) in the amount of time that is available <vi>I was able to <it>get in</it> a few hours of reading last night.</vi> <vi>I hope we can <it>get in</it> a visit to the art museum the next time we're in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to harvest (a crop) and put it in a safe or dry place <vi>It's time to <it>get</it> the crop/harvest <it>in</it>.</vi> <vi>We'd better <it>get</it> the hay <it>in</it> before it rains.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>It sounds like an interesting project and I'd like to <it>get in on</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become friends with (someone) <vi>She <it>got in with</it> [=<it>fell in with</it>] a bad crowd and got into trouble.</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>get in good with</phrase> the boss. [=he got the boss to like him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (a place)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>The burglar <it>got into</it> the house through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The train <it>got into</it> New York late last night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become involved in (an activity) <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got into</it> it at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to be interested in and to enjoy (something) <vi>It's only recently that I've really <it>gotten into</it> music.</vi> <vi>I tried reading the book, but I just couldn't <it>get into</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>I hope your daughter <it>gets into</it> the school.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>into</it> the school.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become involved or to cause (someone) to become involved in (something bad, such as trouble or a fight) <vi>He <it>got into</it> a lot of trouble when he was a teenager.</vi> <vi>They <it>got into</it> an argument.</vi> <vi>His friends <it>got</it> him <it>into</it> trouble.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll tell you what happened, but I don't want to <it>get into</it> [=<it>go into</it>] all the reasons for why it happened.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>got into (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect the behavior of (someone) <un>used to say that someone is behaving in an unusual way and you don't know why <vi>I don't know what has <it>gotten into</it> him lately.</vi> <vi>She never used to be so rude to people. <phrase>What got into her?</phrase> [=why is she behaving this way?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get lost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get lucky</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lucky</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get moving</dre> <dx>see <dxt>move</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave at the start of a journey <vi>We <it>got off</it> early on our camping trip.</vi> <un>often used figuratively in the phrase <phrase>get off to a good/bad (etc.) start</phrase> <vi>He and I <it>got off to a bad start</it>, but now we get along well.</vi> <vi>The project <it>got off to a slow start</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>get off on the right/wrong foot</tag> at <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be punished for a crime :to be judged not guilty of a crime <vi>He's been arrested several times, but he always <it>gets off</it>.</vi> :to help (someone) to be judged not guilty <vi>His lawyer <it>got</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given or to help (someone) to be given only a slight punishment for a crime <vi>She <it>got off</it> lightly.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He <it>got off with</it> a light sentence.</vi> <vi>His lawyer tried to <it>get</it> him <it>off with</it> a light sentence.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>It was a bad accident. You're lucky that you <it>got off with</it> just a broken leg—you could have been killed!</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being on or against someone or something <vi><it>Get off</it>—you're hurting me!</vi> <vi>I took the subway and <it>got off</it> at the downtown station.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>5a</dxn> <dxn>b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop talking about (something) or to cause (someone) to stop talking about (something) <vi>We somehow <it>got off</it> (the subject of) work and started talking about our personal lives.</vi> <vi>I tried to change the subject, but I couldn't <it>get</it> her <it>off</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off work</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to finish working and leave the place where you work <vi>I <it>get off</it> early on Fridays.</vi> <vi>I <it>got off work</it> early last Thursday so I could see the parade.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write and send (a letter, an e-mail message, etc.) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the letter <it>off</it> (to them) tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to shoot (something) from a gun <vi>The policeman <it>got off</it> [=<it>fired</it>] several shots before the criminal escaped.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He managed to <it>get off</it> a few good jokes in his speech.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to fall asleep or to help (someone, such as a baby) to fall asleep <vi>I had just <it>got off</it> [=<it>dropped off</it>] when the doorbell rang. = I had just <phrase>got off to sleep</phrase> when the doorbell rang.</vi> <vi>I just <it>got</it> the baby <it>off to sleep</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have an orgasm or to cause (someone) to have an orgasm</dt> <sn>9</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal + sometimes disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy or be excited by (something) especially in a sexual way <vi>He's one of those guys who seem to <it>get off on</it> making other people feel guilty.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone) :to begin a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She found out he'd <it>gotten off with</it> another woman.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>tell someone where to get off</phrase> is to criticize or disagree with someone in a very direct and angry way. <vi>I was sick of listening to his constant complaints, so I <it>told him where to get off</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>don't know where someone gets off</phrase> (doing something), you are angry because someone has done something that is not right. <vi>I <it>don't know where he gets off</it> telling me what to do. = <phrase>Where does he get off</phrase> telling me what to do? [=he has no right to tell me what to do]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you. I'll let you <it>get on with</it> your work.</vi> <vi>You need to stop feeling sorry for yourself and just <phrase>get on with your life</phrase>. [=return to doing the things you do in your normal life]</vi> <vi>This introduction is taking forever. I wish they'd just <phrase>get on with it</phrase>. [=stop delaying and get to the interesting or important part]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be or remain friendly :to get along <vi>They've never really <it>got on</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>We <it>get on</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How is your daughter <it>getting on</it> in/at school?</vi> <vi>We can <it>get on</it> [=<it>get along, get by, manage</it>] just fine without them.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to achieve greater success :to get ahead <vi>an ambitious young woman trying to <it>get on</it> in business</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“These files need to be organized.” “I'll <it>get on</it> it right away.”</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>His boss has been <it>getting on</it> him about the quality of his work.</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>getting on his case</phrase> about cleaning his room. [=she's always telling him to clean it]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it on</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <dt>:to have sex</dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on in years</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to grow old <vi>My grandmother is <it>getting on</it> [=<it>aging</it>] a bit, but she's still very active.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become late <vi>It's <it>getting on</it>, and we really ought to go.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to move toward becoming (a specified age, time, etc.) <vi>He's <it>getting on for</it> 70. [=he's approaching 70; he is nearly 70]</vi> <vi>It was <it>getting on for</it> noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get onto</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>get on to</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“We need someone to send out the invitations.” “I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get on</it>] it right away.”</vi> :to start to talk about something <vi>How did we <it>get onto</it> this topic?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to speak to or write to (someone) about a particular problem, job, etc. <vi>I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get in touch with</it>] the doctor/plumber straightaway and see if he'll come round.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave or escape from a place, a vehicle, etc. <vi>He was trapped in the burning building/car, but he was somehow able to <it>get out</it> (of it) alive.</vi> <un>used as an angry way to tell someone to leave <vi><it>Get out</it>! I never want to see you again!</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to leave or escape <vi>The firemen managed to <it>get</it> him <it>out</it> (of the burning building) alive.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) from storage so that it can be used <vi>It's raining. I'd better <it>get out</it> the umbrella.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to places outside your home for social occasions, events, etc. <vi>You spend too much time at home. You need to <it>get out</it> more.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>Their secret <it>got out</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got out</it> that she was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get out</it> a few words before he collapsed.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to show that you are surprised by something or do not believe it <vi>“They gave the job to Jane.” “<it>Get out</it>!” = “<phrase>Get out of here</phrase>!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get out of (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone or something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to avoid doing (something) or to help (someone) to avoid doing (something) <vi>I didn't want to go to the lecture, but I couldn't <it>get out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>He tried to <it>get out of</it> doing his homework.</vi> <vi>My sister said she could <it>get</it> me <it>out of</it> going to the party if I really didn't want to go</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having (a habit) or to cause (someone) to stop having (a habit) <vi>I used to exercise every day, but I <it>got out of</it> the habit.</vi> <vi>All the extra work I've been doing has <it>gotten</it> me <it>out of</it> the habit of exercising.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop being in or involved in (something) or to cause (someone or something) to stop being in or involved in (something) <vi>The company has decided to <it>get</it> (itself) <it>out of</it> the computer business.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> her money <it>out of</it> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something) from (something or someone) <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> the gun <it>out of</it> the suspect's hand.</vi> <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> a confession <it>out of</it> the suspect.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to gain (something) from (something) <vi>What do you hope to <it>get out of</it> this experience?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop being controlled or bothered by (something, such as a problem or feeling) <vi>You need to <it>get over</it> [=<it>overcome</it>] your fear of being lied to.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy about (something) <vi>She's disappointed about their decision, but she'll <it>get over</it> it eventually.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that you are very surprised or impressed by something <vi>I just can't <it>get over</it> how much weight you've lost!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become healthy again after (an illness) <vi>He had a bad cold, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> it completely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy after ending a relationship with (someone) <vi>He broke up with his girlfriend a couple of months ago, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get (something) over with</va></svr> <dt>:to cause or experience the end of (something) :to finish (something) <vi>I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over</it>! = I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over with</it>! = I just want to <phrase>get</phrase> this ordeal <phrase>over and done with</phrase>! [=I want this ordeal to end]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get over (something)</va></svr> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my message <it>over</it> [=<it>across</it>] to them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get real</dre> <dx>see <dxt>real</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rid of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roll</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>best</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the better of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get there</dre> <def><dt>:to reach a goal :to do what you are trying to do <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we'll <it>get there</it> eventually. [=we'll make a profit eventually]</vi> :to come closer to reaching a goal <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we're <it>getting there</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to finish a job or activity <vi>When you <it>get through</it> (with that job), I've got something else for you to do.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or finish (something, such as an amount of work) <vi>We <it>got through</it> [=<it>covered</it>] all of the material that we wanted to cover.</vi> <vi>There's still a lot of paperwork to be <it>gotten through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to complete or to help (someone) to complete (a test, an exam, etc.) successfully <vi>She studied hard and <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] her exams.</vi> <vi>The extra hours of study are what <it>got</it> her <it>through</it> her exams.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pass through or beyond something that blocks you or slows you down <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting through</it> to the flood victims.</vi> :to cause (something) to pass through or beyond something <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get</it> our truck <it>through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting</it> supplies <it>through</it> to the flood victims.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something that is difficult, dangerous, etc.) <vi>It was a very difficult time in our marriage, but we <it>got through</it> it.</vi> <vi>I don't know how those early settlers managed to <it>get through</it> [=<it>survive</it>] the winter.</vi> :to help (someone) to live through (something) <vi>It was pure determination that <it>got</it> them <it>through</it> that crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] all the money he inherited in just a few years.</vi> <vi>They <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my message has finally <it>gotten through to</it> you. [=I hope you finally understand my message]</vi> <vi>I think my message finally <it>got through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through to (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express something clearly so that it is understood by (someone) <vi>I've talked to him many times, but I just can't seem to <it>get through to</it> him.</vi> <vi>I hope I've finally <it>gotten</it> my message <it>through to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a successful telephone call to someone <vi>I tried to call home but I couldn't <it>get through</it>.</vi> <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get through to</it> you (on the phone) all day!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or approved by an official group <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] and eventually became a law.</vi> <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] Congress and eventually became a law.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>She sometimes <it>gets to worrying</it> over her health.</vi> <vi>We <it>got to talking</it> about old times.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to deal with (something) <vi>The letter is on my desk, but I haven't <it>gotten to</it> it yet.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get to</it> the accounts as soon as I can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>All these delays are starting to <it>get to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel sad <vi>The movie's sad ending really <it>got to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to change or influence the behavior of (someone) wrongly or illegally by making threats, paying money, etc. <vi>The witness changed his story. Someone must have <it>gotten to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to or reach (somewhere) <vi>We <it>got to</it> the station/airport just in time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to meet and spend time together <vi>I'd like to <it>get together</it> with you soon.</vi> <vi>He often <it>gets together</it> with his friends after work.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to have a sexual or romantic relationship <vi>He and his wife first <it>got together</it> in college.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to meet or to have a relationship <vi>Their shared interest in photography is what <it>got</it> them <it>together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept something <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The two sides have been unable to <it>get together on</it> a new contract.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get together (things or people)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (things or people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to collect (things) or gather (people) into one place or group <vi>He <it>got together</it> [=<it>assembled</it>] a great art collection.</vi> <vi>The government <it>got together</it> a group of experts to study the problem.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>get together</it> [=<it>obtain</it>] the money we need to buy a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get your act together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get yourself together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get it together</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get your life together</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to live in a good and sensible way :to stop being confused, foolish, etc. <vi>His life got much better when he stopped drinking and <it>got his act together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to function in a skillful or effective way <vi>The company finally <it>got its act together</it> and started making a profit this year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to sleep</dre> <def><dt>:to start sleeping :to fall asleep <vi>She finally <it>got to sleep</it> after midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to work</dre> <def><dt>:to start working <vi>We need to stop delaying and <it>get to work</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to rise or to cause (someone) to rise after lying or sleeping in a bed <vi>I <it>got up</it> [=got out of bed] early this morning.</vi> <vi>I woke up early but I didn't <it>get up</it> till later.</vi> <vi>The alarm clock <it>got</it> me <it>up</it> earlier than usual.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stand up <vi>He <it>got up</it> to greet her when she entered the room.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as courage) in yourself by trying or making an effort <vi>He couldn't <it>get up</it> the courage to ask her out on a date.</vi> <vi>She was so tired she could hardly <it>get up</it> the energy to make dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare or organize (something that involves a group of people) <vi>They're trying to <it>get up</it> a petition to have the movie theater reopened.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to get an erection</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up on the wrong side of the bed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get what's coming to you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get wind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your goat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have got</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="ground[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ground</hw> <sound><wav>ground01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>grounds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the ground</bnote> <dt>:the surface of the earth <vi>An apple fell to <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>Mechanical problems kept the plane on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They were lying/sitting on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>close to <it>the ground</it> = low to <it>the ground</it></vi> <vi>The flight was watched by many observers on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They sent in <phrase>ground forces/troops</phrase>. [=soldiers who fight on the ground instead of in the air or at sea]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>ground war</phrase> [=a war fought by soldiers on the ground]</vi> <vi><phrase>ground transportation</phrase> [=transportation that is over the ground instead of on water or in the air]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the soil that is on or under the surface of the earth <vi>planting seeds in the <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>She drove a spike into the <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>damp/frozen <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>solid/firm/dry <it>ground</it></vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of land <vi>They built their house on bare/level/flat <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>We realized that we were on hallowed/sacred <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They built their house on high <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area of land or sea that is used for a particular purpose <vi>a camping <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>fishing/hunting <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>Each fall the birds return to their wintering <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a football <it>ground</it> [=(<it>US</it>) a soccer field]</vi> <vi>an ancient <phrase>burial ground</phrase> [=a place where people were buried in ancient times]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>spawning ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the land around a building <vi>the capitol <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>He was trespassing on school <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>We toured the <it>grounds</it> of the estate.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the bottom of the ocean, a lake, etc. <vi>The boat struck <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of knowledge or interest <vi>We have a lot of <it>ground</it> to go over before the test.</vi> <vi>We covered much more <it>ground</it> [=we went over more information] than we expected to at the meeting.</vi> <vi>The book covers <phrase>familiar ground</phrase>. [=subjects that have often been discussed before]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a place or situation in which someone or something is developed or tested <vi>The laboratory has become a <phrase>testing ground</phrase> for ideas about the origins of the universe.</vi> <vi>The tournament has come to be regarded as a <phrase>proving ground</phrase> for young players.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a set of beliefs, opinions, or attitudes <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The two sides are trying to find some <phrase>common ground</phrase> [=an area in which they can agree with each other] on these issues.</vi> <vi>When a politician talks about raising taxes, he's <phrase>on dangerous ground</phrase>. [=he is doing or saying something that may cause anger or criticism]</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>The two sides continue to look for a <phrase>middle ground</phrase> [=a middle position] between two extremes.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>high ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason for doing or thinking something <un>usually plural <vi>The company has been accused of discriminating on the <it>grounds</it> of race.</vi> <vi>We have no <it>grounds</it> for believing that the crisis will end soon.</vi> <vi>Her husband's infidelity was <it>grounds</it> for divorce.</vi> <vi>Many critics have objected to the proposal <phrase>on the grounds that</phrase> [=because] it would be too costly.</vi> <vi>The law was rejected <it>on the grounds that</it> it was not constitutional. = The law was rejected on constitutional <it>grounds</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:very small pieces of crushed coffee beans <vi>coffee <it>grounds</it></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a wire or metal object that makes an electrical connection with the earth <un>usually singular <vi>This metal bracket provides the <it>ground</it>.</vi></un> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>earth</cat></ca></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the area behind or around a design <vi>The wallpaper has red tulips on a white <it>ground</it>. [=<it>background</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above ground</dre> <def><dt>:on top of the earth's surface <vi>The bird's nest is located high <it>above ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>below ground</dre> <def><dt>:under the earth's surface <vi>The seeds should be planted a few inches <it>below ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to dig into the ground at the start of building something <vi>Workers <it>broke ground</it> on the new stadium last week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>break new ground</va></svr> <dt>:to make new discoveries <vi>Critics say that the study does not <it>break</it> (any) <it>new ground</it> in the search for a cure for cancer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn to the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>down to the ground</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:completely or perfectly <vi>The job <phrase>suits her down to the ground</phrase>. [=suits her perfectly]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from the ground up</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:completely or thoroughly <vi>The car has been redesigned <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:from a point at which nothing has been done :from the very beginning <vi>They built the resort <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>gain ground</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make up ground</va></vr> <def><dt>:to move faster so that you come closer to someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was trailing in the race, but she was beginning to <it>gain ground</it> (on the leaders).</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Alternative forms of energy are quickly <it>gaining ground</it>. [=becoming more popular or successful]</vi> <vi>The company has been <it>gaining ground on</it> [=<it>catching up with</it>] its competitors.</vi> <vi>The campaign is trying to <it>make up ground</it> by advertising heavily in key states.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get off the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin to operate or proceed in a successful way <vi><it>The project</it> never really <it>got off the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off the ground</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to operate or proceed in successful way <vi>We're still trying to <it>get</it> this project <it>off the ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move backward when you are being attacked :<sx>retreat</sx> <vi>The troops were forced to <it>give ground</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The controversy has continued, and both sides are still refusing to <it>give ground</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep your feet on the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the ground running</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold/stand your ground</dre> <def><dt>:to not change your position when you are being attacked :to not retreat <vi>The troops managed to <it>hold their ground</it> despite a fierce enemy attack.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company has managed to <it>hold its ground</it> in the marketplace.</vi> <vi>The president has continued to <it>stand his ground</it> despite criticism.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to the point of being very tired or exhausted <vi>She's been working/running/driving herself <it>into the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to the point of complete failure or ruin <vi>He ran that company <it>into the ground</it>. [=he destroyed that company]</vi> <vi>She drove that old car <it>into the ground</it>. [=she drove it until it would not run anymore]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move slower so that you are farther away from someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was beginning to <it>lose ground</it> (to the leaders) in the race.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The political party <it>lost ground</it> [=became less popular or successful; did not do well] in the election.</vi> <vi>The company is <it>losing ground to</it> [=falling behind; not doing as well as] its competitors.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="head[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">head</hw> <sound><wav>head0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>heads</if> <il>or in sense 7</il> <if>head</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body containing the brain, eyes, ears, nose, and mouth <vi>She patted the dog on the <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>He nodded his <it>head</it> in agreement.</vi> <vi>The ceiling's low—watch your <it>head</it>!</vi> <vi><it>head</it> injuries</vi> <vi>They were covered <phrase>from head to foot/toe</phrase> in mud. [=they were completely covered in mud]</vi> <vi>He has a <phrase>full head of hair</phrase>. [=he has a full amount of hair on his head]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>talking head</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person's mental ability :mind or intellect <vi>You shouldn't let your heart rule your <it>head</it>. [=you should be guided by reason and not by your emotions]</vi> <vi>She did some quick calculations <phrase>in her head</phrase>. [=without writing anything; mentally]</vi> <vi>I keep hearing that song <it>in my head</it>. = That song keeps running through my <it>head</it>. = I can't get that song <phrase>out of my head</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It never even <phrase>entered my head</phrase> to run for office. [=I never thought of running for office]</vi> <vi>The problem is <phrase>all in his head</phrase>. [=the problem is not real; he's just imagining it]</vi> <vi>Don't go <phrase>putting ideas in/into his head</phrase>. [=don't cause him to have ideas or suspicions that he would not have himself]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>put that idea out of your head</phrase>. [=you should stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>She always says the first thing that <phrase>comes/pops into her head</phrase>. [=the first thing that she thinks of]</vi> <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <phrase>use our heads</phrase>. [=think carefully]</vi> <vi>That guy should <phrase>have his head examined</phrase>. = That guy is <phrase>not right in the head</phrase>. [=that guy is crazy]</vi> <vi>You need a <phrase>cool/calm head</phrase> [=an ability to remain calm] to deal with someone like him.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>clear head</phrase> [=an ability to think clearly]</vi> <snote>If you have <phrase>a good head on your shoulders</phrase>, you are intelligent and have good judgment. <vi>You don't have to worry about her—she's got <it>a good head on her shoulders</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>When you <phrase>get/take it into your head</phrase> to do something, you suddenly decide to do it in a way that seems foolish or surprising. <vi>He's <it>taken it into his head</it> to try skydiving.</vi> <vi>I somehow <it>got it into my head</it> to run for public office.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get it into your head</phrase> that something is true, you begin to believe something even though there is no good reason for believing it. <vi>She's somehow <it>gotten it into her head</it> that I don't like her. [=she believes that I don't like her although I do like her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who has a specified mental or emotional quality <vi>A fight was avoided when <phrase>cooler heads prevailed</phrase>. [=when calmer or less angry people were able to convince others not to fight]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hothead</dxt> <dxt>sorehead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a distance equal to the length of a head <vi>The horse won the race by a <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a <it>head</it> taller than you.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the front side of a coin :the side of a coin that shows a picture of a person's head <vi>the <it>head</it> of a penny</vi> <un>usually used in the plural to refer to one of the two choices you can make when a coin is thrown in the air to decide something <vi>I call <it>heads</it>.</vi> <vi>Is it <it>heads</it> or tails? [=did the coin land with heads or tails facing up?]</vi> <vi>It landed <it>heads</it> up.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>tail <dxn>3</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>head</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:individual animals <vi>100 <it>head</it> of cattle</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an end of something that is like a head in shape or position <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She placed the pillows at the <it>head of</it> the bed.</vi> <vi>We arrived early so that we'd be at the <it>head</it> [=<it>front</it>] <it>of</it> the line.</vi> <vi>The chairman sat at the <it>head of</it> the table.</vi> <vi>the <it>head</it> [=<it>top</it>] <it>of</it> a nail/pin/screw</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an object that hits or touches something else <vi>a grinding <it>head</it></vi> <vi>the hammer's <it>head</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a spear</vi> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a golf club</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>arrowhead</dxt> <dxt>spearhead</dxt> <dxt>warhead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the position of being a leader <vi>She's <phrase>at the head of</phrase> her class. [=she is the best student in her class]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who leads or directs a group or organization <vi>Have you met the new department <it>head</it>?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She is the <it>head of</it> our sales division.</vi> <vi><it>heads of</it> families/households</vi> <vi><phrase>heads of state</phrase> [=leaders of countries]</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the restaurant's <it>head</it> cook</vi> <vi>the team's <it>head</it> coach</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>head teacher</sx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a tight mass of leaves or flowers on a plant <vi>The flower <it>heads</it> on the plant are very large.</vi> <vi>a <it>head</it> of cabbage/lettuce</vi> <vi>a <it>head of</it> garlic</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where a stream or river begins <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>head</it> of the Nile</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:pressure caused by the water or steam in a machine <snote>When an engine has a <phrase>full head of steam</phrase>, it has built up a full amount of power. This phrase is often used figuratively to describe something that is moving forward in a fast and powerful way. <vi>The project started slowly, but now we have a <it>full head of steam</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the bubbles that form on the top of some liquids (such as beer) <un>usually singular <vi>the foamy <it>head</it> on a beer</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the point at which a situation becomes very serious or when action is required <vi>Things <phrase>came to a head</phrase> when the workers threatened to go on strike.</vi> <vi>These new revelations <phrase>brought</phrase> the scandal <phrase>to a head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small, inflamed area on the skin with a spot in the middle <dx>see also <dxt>blackhead</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a big/swelled head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an overly high opinion of yourself <vi>All those compliments have given him a <it>big head</it>. [=have made him very conceited]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>a head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a price on someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>price</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bang heads together</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>butt heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>butt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get it through someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to learn and remember something <vi>She's finally <it>gotten it through their heads</it> that she doesn't eat meat.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get it through your head</dre> <def><dt>:to accept or understand (something) <vi>He can't seem to <it>get it through his head</it> that I'm not interested in working with him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your head round</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to understand (something) <vi>She couldn't <it>get her head round</it> why he had to leave.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to discuss something with a person who is higher in rank than someone else <vi>He <it>went over his supervisor's head</it> to complain about the policy to the company's president. [=he complained about the policy to the company's president rather than his supervisor]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of an alcoholic drink</ssl> <dt>:to make you feel drunk <vi>I just had one glass of wine, but it <phrase>went straight to my head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make you believe that you are better than other people <vi>He has never let his fame <it>go to his head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a head for</dre> <def><dt>:to have an ability to understand or deal with (something) <vi>She's always <it>had a</it> (good) <it>head for</it> business.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) He <phrase>has a head for heights</phrase>. [=he is not afraid of heights; being up high does not bother him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/get your head (screwed) on right/straight</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to think or act in a smart and sensible way <vi>She's young, but it's clear that she <it>has her head screwed on right</it>.</vi> <vi>You think that's a good idea? You need to <it>get your head screwed on straight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head and shoulders above</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone or something is much better than others <vi>They <phrase>are/stand head and shoulders above</phrase> the competition.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head in the sand</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>bury/have/hide (etc.) your head in the sand</phrase>, you ignore something unpleasant that you should be dealing with. <vi>He can't just <it>bury his head in the sand</it> every time there's a problem.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head over heels</dre> <def><dt>:very deeply in love <vi>We were <it>head over heels</it> (in love).</vi> <vi>He <phrase>fell head over heels for</phrase> some girl he met at school.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>went head over heels for</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heads roll</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that <phrase>heads will roll</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>heads are going to roll</phrase>, you mean that people will be severely punished or will lose their jobs because of something that has happened. <vi>When the boss finds out about the mistake, <it>heads will roll</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the nail on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold up your head</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold your head (up) high</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be proud :to not feel ashamed <vi>Even though they lost the game, they can still <it>hold up their heads</it> because they tried their best.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head</dre> <def><dt>:to remain calm <vi>She has shown that she can <it>keep her head</it> in a crisis.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head above water</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid financial failure while having money problems <vi>We have so much debt that we're barely able to <it>keep our heads above water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head down</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in a quiet way that does not attract attention <vi>a politician who is <it>keeping his head down</it> and trying to avoid controversy</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock some sense into someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock (something) on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your head</dre> <def><dt>:to become very upset or angry <vi>He <it>lost his head</it> and said some things he regrets.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not make head or/nor tail of</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>not make heads or/nor tails (out) of</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be unable to understand (something) <vi>I <it>couldn't make heads or tails of</it> her reaction.</vi> <vi>His handwriting was so bad that we <it>couldn't make heads or tails out of</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the top of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>off your head</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:crazy or foolish <vi>He's not just eccentric—he's completely <it>off his head</it>!</vi> <vi>He's gone <it>off his head</it> over some girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with the upper and lower parts of your body reversed in position <vi>Can you <phrase>stand on your head</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or into great disorder <vi>News of the discovery <phrase>turned</phrase> the scientific world <phrase>on its head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you will be blamed for something <vi>If we miss our deadline, it will be <it>on your head</it>. [=it will be your fault]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to act or think in a reasonable and controlled way because of drunkenness or strong emotion <vi>He was (drunk) <it>out of his head</it>. [=he was extremely drunk]</vi> <vi>Her parents were <it>out of their heads</it> with worry [=were extremely worried and upset] when she didn't come home on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over your head</dre> <def><dt>:beyond your understanding or ability <vi>The technical details were <it>over my head</it>. [=too complicated for me to understand]</vi> <vi>That joke went right <it>over my head</it>. [=I did not get that joke]</vi> <vi>We realized after we started the business that we were (in) <it>over our heads</it>. [=we were trying to do something that was too difficult]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>per head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>per head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick/raise your head above the parapet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>parapet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your heads together</dre> <def><dt>:to think of a solution to a problem with another person <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <it>put our heads together</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rear/raise its ugly head</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something bad <it>rears/raises its ugly head</it>, it suddenly becomes obvious or causes trouble. <vi>Inflation threatened to <it>rear its ugly head</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be confused about something and unable to understand the reason for it <vi>His odd behavior left us all <it>scratching our heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) your head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) very loudly or for a long time <vi>She was <it>screaming her head off</it>.</vi> <vi>You can <it>shout your head off</it> at him, but he still won't listen.</vi> <vi>If they saw me dressed like this, they'd <it>laugh their heads off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>shake your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two heads are better than one</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is easier for two people who help each other to solve a problem than it is for one person to solve a problem alone</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn heads</dre> <def><dt>:to attract attention or notice <vi>The car's sleek design is bound to <it>turn heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
