<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="display[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dis*play</hw> <sound><wav>displa05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>dɪˈspleɪ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>dis*plays</if></in> <in><if>dis*played</if></in> <in><if>dis*play*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to put (something) where people can see it <vi>Students <it>displayed</it> their projects at the science fair.</vi> <vi>The results are <it>displayed</it> [=<it>shown</it>] on the computer screen.</vi> <vi>Toys were <it>displayed</it> in the store window.</vi> <vi>Her awards are prominently/proudly <it>displayed</it> on the mantel.</vi> <vi>The museum <it>displays</it> relics found during the excavation of the site.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The tree <it>displays</it> pretty pink flowers in the spring.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to show that you have (an emotion, quality, skill, etc.) <vi>He <it>displayed</it> no emotion when I told him the news.</vi> <vi>I was impressed by the care she <it>displayed</it> in making the flower arrangements.</vi> <vi>The children <it>displayed</it> [=<it>exhibited</it>] no interest in learning how to play the piano.</vi> <vi>The rookie player <it>displayed</it> great skill.</vi> <vi>The company has <it>displayed</it> exceptional dedication to this community.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="display[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">display</hw> <altpr>dɪˈspleɪ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>displays</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an arrangement of objects intended to decorate, advertise, entertain, or inform people about something <vi>Each table had a beautiful <it>display</it> of flowers. = Each table had a beautiful flower <it>display</it>.</vi> <vi>the bookstore's <it>display</it> of dictionaries = the bookstore's dictionary <it>display</it></vi> <vi>The library's current <it>display</it> features locally made crafts.</vi> <vi>There is a <it>display</it> [=<it>exhibit, exhibition</it>] of his early paintings at the museum.</vi> <vi>Her trophies are in a <it>display</it> case/cabinet.</vi> <vi>a store's <phrase>window display</phrase> [=a display of products shown in a store's window]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an event at which something is done or shown to impress or entertain people <vi>The celebration ended with a spectacular fireworks <it>display</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an action, performance, etc., which shows very clearly that you have some ability, feeling, quality, etc. <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>display of</it> anger</vi> <vi>In a remarkable <it>display of</it> generosity, the students gave the money they had raised for the class trip to their sick classmate.</vi> <vi>the soccer player's impressive <it>display of</it> footwork</vi> <vi>shocking <it>displays of</it> wealth in a country of extreme poverty</vi> <vi>He disapproved of their public <it>displays of</it> affection. [=hugging, kissing, etc., in public]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:an electronic device (such as a computer monitor) that shows information <vi>The computer comes with a high-resolution color <it>display</it>.</vi> <vi>The <it>display</it> showed an error message.</vi> <vi>a calculator's <it>display</it> screen</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>biology</ssl> <dt>:a way of behaving that a bird or animal uses to show another bird or animal that it wants to mate, fight, etc. <vi>courtship/threat <it>displays</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>on display</dre> <def><dt>:put somewhere for people to see :in a display <vi>Autographed baseballs are <it>on display</it> at the show.</vi> <vi>Only a few of the artifacts will be <phrase>put on display</phrase>. = Only a few of the artifacts will <phrase>go on display</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="caller display"> <hw>caller display</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>caller id</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="liquid crystal display"> <hw>liquid crystal display</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -plays</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>lcd</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="self-"> <hw>self-</hw> <pr>ˌsɛlf</pr> <fl>combining form</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-pitying</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-destructive</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-sacrifice</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:by, to, with, for, or toward yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-made</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-evident</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-propelled</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-addressed</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-respect</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
