<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="absence"> <hw highlight="yes">ab*sence</hw> <sound><wav>absenc01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæbsəns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ab*senc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a state or condition in which something expected, wanted, or looked for is not present or does not exist :a state or condition in which something is absent <vi>There was an <it>absence</it> [=<it>lack</it>] of enthusiasm in the crowd. [=the crowd was not enthusiastic]</vi> <vi>The products showed a remarkable <it>absence</it> of defects.</vi> <vi><phrase>In the absence of</phrase> reform [=without reform], progress was slow.</vi> <vi><phrase>With the (continued) absence of</phrase> rain [=because of the lack of rain], crops have begun to dry up.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a failure to be present at a usual or expected place <vi>He had many <it>absences</it> from work.</vi> <vi>I expected to see her and was surprised by her <it>absence</it>.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>conspicuous by his absence</phrase>. [=it was very noticeable that he was not present]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a period of time when someone is not present at a place, job, etc. <vi>She returned to the company after a long/prolonged <it>absence</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>leave of absence</dxt></dx> <snote>The saying <phrase>absence makes the heart grow fonder</phrase> means that you tend to like someone better when that person goes away for a time. <vi>She'll be away for a month, but you know what they say—<it>absence makes the heart grow fonder</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>in someone's absence</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:while someone is away <vi>The study was completed <it>in her absence</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in the place of someone who is not present <vi>He was asked to speak <it>in his brother's absence</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="leave of absence"> <hw>leave of absence</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>leaves of absence</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:permission to be away from a job for a period of time <vi>He was granted/given <it>leave of absence</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a period of time when someone has special permission to be away from a job :<sx>leave</sx> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He took two unpaid <it>leaves of absence</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She has been <phrase>on leave of absence</phrase> for almost two years.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="heart"> <hw highlight="yes">heart</hw> <sound><wav>heart001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>hearts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the organ in your chest that pumps blood through your veins and arteries <vi>I could feel my <it>heart</it> pounding/racing.</vi> <vi>He has a bad/weak <it>heart</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>He suffers from a <it>heart</it> condition.</vi> <vi><it>heart</it> failure/disease/surgery</vi> <vi>a <it>heart</it> murmur</vi> <vi>Aerobic exercise increases your <phrase>heart rate</phrase>. [=<it>pulse</it>]</vi></un> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>coronary heart disease</dxt> <dxt>open-heart</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the front part of your chest <vi>He put his hand on his <it>heart</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>literary</it>) She clutched the child to her <it>heart</it>. [=<it>breast, bosom</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the heart thought of as the place where emotions are felt <vi>You shouldn't let your <it>heart</it> rule your head. [=you should be guided by reason and not by your emotions]</vi> <vi>When she heard the news, her <it>heart</it> filled with joy/sorrow.</vi> <vi>You're a man <phrase>after my own heart</phrase>. [=we have similar likes and dislikes]</vi> <vi>He offered to help us <phrase>out of the goodness of his heart</phrase>. [=because he is a good person and not because he wanted to get anything for himself]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>wears his heart on his sleeve</phrase>. [=he shows his emotions very openly]</vi> <vi>She's not too smart, but at least her <phrase>heart is in the right place</phrase>. [=she is a kind person who is trying to do good things]</vi> <vi>I just <phrase>didn't have the heart</phrase> to tell her that I didn't like her singing. [=I couldn't tell her because I knew that she would be hurt by what I said]</vi> <vi>The idea <phrase>struck fear into their hearts</phrase>. [=made them very afraid]</vi> <vi>I decided to <phrase>follow my heart</phrase> [=to do what I truly wanted to do] and take up acting.</vi> <vi><phrase>My heart goes out to</phrase> [=I feel very sorry for] the families of the victims.</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>heart's desire</phrase> [=greatest wish] was to become a movie star.</vi> <vi>She just couldn't <phrase>find it in her heart to</phrase> forgive them.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>felt in my heart</phrase> that our relationship was never meant to be.</vi> <vi>I think she knows <phrase>in her heart</phrase> that they're right. = I think she knows it <phrase>in her heart of hearts</phrase>. [=she knows it even though she does not want to admit it]</vi> <vi>They said they'd try to fix the problem, but I could see that <phrase>their hearts (just) weren't in it</phrase>. [=they did not really feel much interest or enthusiasm about doing it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a kind or generous feeling for other people <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a ruler without <it>heart</it></vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a ruler without a <it>heart</it></vi> <vi>He has a kind <it>heart</it>. [=he treats people kindly]</vi> <vi>He has a cold/hard <it>heart</it>. [=he treats people in a harsh or unfriendly way]</vi> <vi>She has <phrase>a big heart</phrase>. = She is <phrase>all heart</phrase>. = She has <phrase>a heart of gold</phrase>. [=she is a very kind person]</vi> <vi>She has <phrase>a heart of stone</phrase>. [=she does not care at all about the feelings of other people]</vi> <vi><phrase>Have a heart</phrase>! Can't you see he needs help?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>change of heart</dxt> <dxt>heart-to-heart</dxt> <dxt>lonely hearts</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:feelings of love or affection <vi>It's best not to interfere in <phrase>matters/affairs of the heart</phrase>. [=romantic matters/affairs]</vi> <vi>He was determined to <phrase>win/steal/capture her heart</phrase>. [=to win her love]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:emotional strength that allows you to continue in a difficult situation <vi>The team has shown a lot of <it>heart</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <bnote>the heart</bnote> <dt>:the central or most important part of something <vi>deep in <it>the heart</it> of the forest</vi> <vi>Their offices are in <it>the heart</it> of the city.</vi> <vi>Let's get right to <it>the heart of</it> the matter.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the central part of some vegetables <vi>artichoke <it>hearts</it></vi> <vi><it>cabbage</it> hearts</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a shape that looks like a simple drawing of a heart and that is used as a symbol of love and affection <vi>The child decorated the card with <it>hearts</it> and flowers.</vi></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a playing card that is marked with a red heart <vi>one <it>heart</it>, two diamonds, and two clubs</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>playing card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>hearts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the suit in a deck of playing cards that consists of cards marked by hearts <vi>the king of <it>hearts</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>club</dxt> <dxt>diamond</dxt> <dxt>spade</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>absence makes the heart grow fonder</dre> <dx>see <dxt>absence</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at heart</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at the most basic level <vi>I'm really a romantic <it>at heart</it>.</vi> <vi>She's 81 years old, but she's still <phrase>young at heart</phrase>. [=she behaves and thinks like a much younger person]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:as a main concern <vi>We <phrase>have your best interests at heart</phrase>. [=we want to do what is best for you]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break someone's heart</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to feel great sorrow or sadness <vi>He <it>broke her heart</it> when he left her for another woman.</vi> <vi>Her boyfriend left her with a <it>broken heart</it>.</vi> <vi>It <it>breaks my heart</it> to think of how those children have suffered.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by heart</dre> <def><dt>:from memory <vi>She knows the entire poem <it>by heart</it>. [=she has learned the poem and can recite it from memory]</vi> <vi>He learned the speech <it>by heart</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close/dear/near to your heart</dre> <def><dt>:very personally and emotionally important to you <vi>This topic is one that's very <it>close to my heart</it>. [=I care very much about this subject]</vi> <vi>The school is very <phrase>near and dear to her heart</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross my heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cry your heart out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do your heart good</dre> <def><dt>:to make you feel very happy <vi>It <it>does his heart good</it> to know that his daughters have become friends.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat your heart out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>faint of heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>faint</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from the bottom of your heart</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>from the/your heart</va></vr> <def><dt>:in a very sincere way <vi>He thanked us <it>from the bottom of his heart</it>.</vi> <vi>When I said you were my best friend, I meant it <it>from the bottom of my heart</it>.</vi> <vi>His speech at the memorial service was <phrase>straight from the heart</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>harden your heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>harden</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have your heart set on (something)</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>set your heart on (something)</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>When you <it>have your heart set on something</it> or when you <it>set your heart on something</it>, you want it very much. <vi>She <it>has her heart set on</it> a new bicycle.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heart in your mouth</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If <phrase>your heart is in your mouth</phrase>, you are very excited or nervous about something. <vi>He waited for her arrival with <it>his heart in his mouth</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heart is knocking</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>heart skips a beat</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>When you say that your <phrase>heart skipped a beat</phrase> or that something <phrase>made your heart skip a beat</phrase>, it means that you suddenly became very surprised, excited, or nervous about something. <vi>When I learned I was on live television, my <it>heart skipped a beat</it>.</vi> <vi>The news was enough to <it>make his heart skip a beat</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heavy heart</dre> <def><dt>:a feeling of sadness <vi>It is with a <it>heavy heart</it> that I bring you this bad news.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know your own heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>light heart</dre> <def><dt>:a feeling of happiness <vi>He left for home with a <it>light heart</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose heart</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to feel that you cannot do something that you have been trying to do :to become discouraged <vi>They never <it>lost heart</it>, even in the face of adversity.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose your heart</dre> <def><dt>:to fall in love with someone <vi>He met a beautiful woman and <it>lost his heart</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>lost her heart to</it> a dashing young artist.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your heart</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to talk in a very open and honest way about your feelings <vi>He <it>opened his heart</it> (to her) and told her how he really felt.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to begin to be generous and kind <vi>We should all <it>open our hearts</it> and do something to help those poor children.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pour your heart out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pour</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sick at heart</dre> <def><dt>:very sad and upset <vi>The idea of children suffering from hunger made him <it>sick at heart</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sing/dance/play (etc.) your heart out</dre> <def><dt>:to sing/dance/play (etc.) with great energy or effort <vi>The band <it>played their hearts out</it> in hopes of winning the prize.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take heart</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to feel better and more hopeful :to stop feeling sad or discouraged <vi><it>Take heart</it>; things will get better soon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) to heart</dre> <def><dt>:to be deeply affected or hurt by something <vi>He <it>took their criticism</it> (very much) <it>to heart</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to your heart's content</dre> <def><dt>:until you feel satisfied :as long or as much as you want <vi>They let him eat and drink <it>to his heart's content</it>.</vi> <vi>Let's go somewhere where we can talk <it>to our hearts' content</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>warm the cockles of your heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cockle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with all your heart</dre> <def><dt>:in a very sincere and deeply felt way <vi>I love him <it>with all my heart</it>.</vi> <vi>She tried <it>with all her heart</it> to please them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your heart bleeds for</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>your heart bleeds for</it> someone, you feel great sadness or pity for that person.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your heart leaps</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your heart leaps</it>, you become very happy or joyful about something. <vi><it>Our hearts leapt</it> when we heard that she had won.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your heart melts</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your heart melts</it>, you begin to feel love, affection, or sympathy for someone or something. <vi>When he saw the puppies, <it>his heart melted</it>.</vi> <vi>It would have <it>melted your heart</it> to see her lying in that hospital bed.</vi> <vi>A warm smile <it>melts the heart</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your heart sinks</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your heart sinks</it>, you become sad or disappointed about something. <vi><it>My heart sank</it> when I saw the sad expression on her face.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
