<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="accept"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*cept</hw> <sound><wav>accept01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ɪkˈsɛpt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ac*cepts</if></in> <in><if>ac*cept*ed</if></in> <in><if>ac*cept*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to receive or take (something offered) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>accept</it> a gift</vi> <vi><it>accept</it> a proposal</vi> <vi><it>accept</it> a bribe</vi> <vi><it>accept</it> an assignment/invitation/offer</vi> <vi>They offered him the job, and he <it>accepted</it> it.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>They offered him the job, and he <it>accepted</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (something) as payment <vi>The store doesn't <it>accept</it> credit cards.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be able or designed to take or hold (something) <vi>a surface that will not <it>accept</it> ink</vi> <vi>a computer program ready to <it>accept</it> commands</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to agree to (something) :to agree to receive or allow (something) <vi><it>accept</it> a telephone call</vi> <vi>They <it>accepted</it> some applications and rejected others.</vi> <vi>She's still trying to get her manuscript <it>accepted</it> for publication.</vi> <vi>I <it>accept</it> your apology.</vi> <vi>They refused to <it>accept</it> his resignation.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to think of (something) as true, proper, or normal <vi>a word that has come to be <it>accepted</it> as standard</vi> <vi>This treatment is now <it>accepted</it> by many doctors.</vi> <vi>He refused to <it>accept</it> the decision.</vi> <vi>I <it>accepted</it> his advice and joined the health club.</vi> <vi>They <it>accepted</it> [=<it>believed</it>] her explanation.</vi> <vi>The theory is widely <it>accepted</it> as correct. = It is widely <it>accepted</it> that the theory is correct.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop denying or resisting (something true or necessary) <vi>She found it difficult to <it>accept</it> change.</vi> <vi>The truth is sometimes hard to <it>accept</it>.</vi> <vi>He behaved badly, and now he has to <it>accept</it> the consequences.</vi> <vi>He has to <phrase>accept the fact that</phrase> his baseball career is over. [=he has to admit that his baseball career is over]</vi> <vi>He was unwilling to <phrase>accept</phrase> [=<it>believe</it>] <phrase>that</phrase> he could no longer play as he once had.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to admit that you have or deserve (something, such as blame or responsibility) <vi><it>accept</it> blame</vi> <vi>I <it>accept</it> responsibility for the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to be willing to have or experience (something) <vi>To be a successful investor you have to <it>accept</it> some risk.</vi> <vi>She <it>accepted</it> [=<it>took on, faced</it>] the challenge of starting her own business.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to allow (someone) to join a club, to attend a school, etc. <vi>The club <it>accepted</it> her as a member but rejected her sister.</vi> <vi>She was <it>accepted</it> at/by Georgetown University.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to regard (someone) as belonging to a group <vi>She felt that her in-laws had never really <it>accepted</it> her (as a member of the family).</vi> <vi>She doesn't yet feel <it>accepted</it> (by her in-laws).</vi> <vi>The new family was quickly <it>accepted</it> into the community.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>accepted</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>accepted</it> practice</vi> <vi>an <it>accepted</it> definition</vi> <vi>a widely <it>accepted</it> truth</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>ac*cept*er</ure> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>ac*cep*tor</va> <sound><wav>accept13.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ɪkˈsɛptɚ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*cepters</if> <il>or</il> <if>ac*ceptors</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="faith"> <hw highlight="yes">faith</hw> <sound><wav>faith001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfeɪθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>faiths</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:strong belief or trust in someone or something <vi>His supporters have accepted his claims with blind/unquestioning <it>faith</it>.</vi> <vi>Our <it>faith</it> in the government has been badly shaken by the recent scandals.</vi> <vi>His parents have always <phrase>had faith in</phrase> him. = His parents have never <phrase>lost faith in</phrase> him. [=his parents have always believed that he is a person who deserves to be trusted and who will succeed]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>have no faith</phrase> in politicians. = I <phrase>put/have little faith in</phrase> politicians. [=I do not trust politicians]</vi> <vi>Lending him the money to start his own business was an <phrase>act of faith</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It requires a giant <phrase>leap of faith</phrase> for us to believe that she is telling the truth.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad faith</dxt> <dxt>good faith</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:belief in the existence of God :strong religious feelings or beliefs <vi>religious <it>faith</it></vi> <vi>Nothing is more important to her than her <it>faith</it> in God.</vi> <vi>She says that her <it>faith</it> has given her the courage to deal with this tragedy.</vi> <vi>He says he has <phrase>found faith</phrase>. [=he has begun to believe in God or has developed strong religious beliefs]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a system of religious beliefs :<sx>religion</sx> <vi>people of all <it>faiths</it></vi> <vi>the Christian/Jewish/Muslim <it>faith</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>accept/take (something) on faith</dre> <def><dt>:to accept (something) as true without proof or evidence that it is true <vi>I'm not willing to <it>take her statements on faith</it>.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>accept it on faith</it> that he knows the truth.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an article of faith</dre> <def><dt>:something that is believed without being questioned or doubted <vi>For many it is an <it>article of faith</it> that the economy will begin to improve soon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break faith with</dre> <def><dt>:to stop supporting or being loyal to (someone) :to betray (someone) <vi>He has accused the government of <it>breaking faith with</it> its supporters.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep faith with</dre> <def><dt>:to continue supporting or being loyal to (someone) <vi>He has <it>kept faith with</it> his old political allies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep the faith</dre> <def><dt>:to continue to believe in, trust, or support someone or something when it is difficult to do so <vi>The team has been playing poorly, but its devoted fans have <it>kept the faith</it>. [=they have continued to support the team]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
