<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="acquire"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*quire</hw> <sound><wav>acquir02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈkwajɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ac*quires</if></in> <in><if>ac*quired</if></in> <in><if>ac*quir*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to get (something) :to come to own (something) <vi>They're planning to <it>acquire</it> [=<it>buy</it>] a new home in the country.</vi> <vi>He <it>acquired</it> [=<it>got, inherited</it>] a small fortune after the death of her parents.</vi> <vi>The two ships were <it>acquired</it> by the navy after the war.</vi> <vi>The team <it>acquired</it> three new players this year.</vi> :to come to have (something) <vi>She dreamed of <it>acquiring</it> [=<it>gaining, getting</it>] control of the company.</vi> <vi>When I saw her next she had somehow managed to <it>acquire</it> a few cuts and bruises. [=she had a few cuts and bruises]</vi> <vi>The old word has <it>acquired</it> a new meaning.</vi> <vi>This apparently minor event has <it>acquired</it> increasing significance in recent weeks.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to gain (a new skill, ability, etc.) usually by your own effort <vi>She quickly <it>acquired</it> [=<it>gained</it>] fluency in French.</vi> <vi>He is studying the way that language is <it>acquired</it> by children.</vi> <vi><it>acquire</it> knowledge</vi> <vi>He has <phrase>acquired a reputation</phrase> as a careful/careless worker. [=people regard him as a careful/careless worker]</vi> <snote>When people <phrase>acquire a taste for</phrase> something, they like something that they did not like before. <vi>Although he usually avoided unusual foods, he eventually began to <it>acquire a taste for</it> raw fish.</vi></snote> <snote>An <phrase>acquired taste</phrase> is something or someone that is not easily or immediately liked. <vi>Brussels sprouts are an <it>acquired taste</it> for many people.</vi> <vi>I admit that she is something of an <it>acquired taste</it>, but I think her art is wonderful.</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
