<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="act[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">act</hw> <sound><wav>act00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈækt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>acts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is done <vi>His first official <it>act</it> [=<it>action</it>] as President was to sign the bill.</vi> <vi>We were grateful for her many <it>acts</it> of kindness.</vi> <vi>an <it>act</it> of bravery = a brave <it>act</it></vi> <vi>criminal/illegal/unlawful/wrongful <it>acts</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sex act</dxt></dx> <snote>An <phrase>act of God</phrase> is a natural event (such as a storm or earthquake) that cannot be controlled by people. <vi>The company cannot be held responsible in cases of bad weather or other <it>acts of God</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a law made by a group of legislators <vi>The program was created by (an) <it>act</it> of Congress/Parliament.</vi> <vi>legislative <it>acts</it></vi> <vi>the Civil Rights <it>Act</it> of 1964</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the main divisions of a play or opera <vi>Please read <it>act</it> II, scene 1 of Shakespeare's <it>Romeo and Juliet</it>.</vi> <vi>In the first/opening <it>act</it>, two characters are talking in a restaurant.</vi> <vi>a play in three <it>acts</it> = a three-<it>act</it> play</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:one of the performances in a show <vi>a circus/magic <it>act</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a show that a person or group performs often <vi>He has a great stand-up/comedy <it>act</it>. [=<it>routine</it>]</vi> <vi>She took her <it>act</it> on the road. [=she traveled and performed her act in different places]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a person or group that performs in shows <vi>a two-person comedy <it>act</it> from New York City</vi> <vi>The band was one of this summer's most successful live <it>acts</it>.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>balancing act</phrase> or <phrase>juggling act</phrase> is an attempt to do several different things or deal with several different situations at the same time. <vi>It's a difficult <it>balancing act</it>, but many students hold full-time jobs while attending school.</vi> <vi>Working and raising children can be a real <it>juggling act</it> for parents.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>class act</dxt> <tag>a hard/tough act to follow</tag> at <dxt>follow</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a way of behaving that is not honest or sincere <vi>He said he was sorry, but I realize now that it was all just an <it>act</it>.</vi> <vi>He wasn't really sorry. He was just <phrase>putting on an act</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>clean up your act</dre> <dx>see <tag>clean up</tag> at <dxt>clean</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get into the act</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>get in on the act</va></vr> <def><dt>:to start to participate in an activity <vi>We started selling them last year, and now other stores are <it>getting into the act</it>. [=now other stores are also selling them]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your act together</dre> <dx>see <tag>get together</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the act (of doing something)</dre> <def><dt>:while doing something <vi>When they arrived, I was just <it>in the act</it> of starting to make dinner.</vi> <vi>He tried to rob a bank and was <phrase>caught in the act</phrase>. = He was <it>caught in the act</it> of robbing a bank.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="act[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">act</hw> <altpr>ˈækt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>acts</if></in> <in><if>act*ed</if></in> <in><if>act*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something :to take action <vi>Think before you <it>act</it>.</vi> <vi>He knew he had to <it>act</it> quickly/fast.</vi> <vi>The government was slow to <it>act</it>.</vi> <vi>The firefighters <it>acted</it> with great courage. = They <it>acted</it> courageously.</vi> <vi>She <it>acted</it> on behalf of her father, who was not at the meeting.</vi> <vi>I believe that the killer <it>acted</it> alone.</vi> <vi>She had <it>acted</it> in self-defense when she killed her attacker.</vi> <vi>We were <it>acting</it> in the best interests of our children.</vi> <vi>If he refuses to cooperate, he'll be <it>acting</it> against his own (best) interests. [=he'll be acting in a way that is harmful to himself]</vi> <vi>We must <it>act</it> soon to end this crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to behave in a particular way <vi>She learned at an early age how to <it>act</it> properly in social situations.</vi> <vi>People are always telling me how I should <it>act</it> and what I should say.</vi> <vi>I noticed that the dog was <it>acting</it> funny/differently/strangely this morning.</vi> <vi><it>acting</it> more naturally/aggressively/responsibly</vi> <vi>She's been <it>acting</it> kind of crazy lately.</vi> <vi>Please learn the new rules and <phrase>act accordingly</phrase>. [=follow the new rules]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>act the part</phrase> is to behave the way that people in a particular role usually behave. <vi>Now that he's rich he certainly <it>acts the part</it>. [=behaves like a rich person]</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>act your age</phrase> is to behave the way that people your age should behave and not to behave like a younger person. <vi>John, <it>act your age</it>. You're not a kid anymore.</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>act like</phrase> a particular kind of person or thing is to behave the way that person or thing behaves. <vi>You two are <it>acting like</it> children.</vi> <vi>It's time you start <it>acting like</it> a man.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry about yesterday. I <it>acted like</it> a fool/jerk.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>act <dxn>3c (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to behave in a way that is not sincere or honest <vi>Stop <it>acting</it>. We know you're guilty.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to pretend to be something <vi>Stop <it>acting</it> innocent.</vi> <vi>She was terribly nervous, but she <it>acted</it> confident.</vi> <vi>I know you're bored, but can you at least try to <it>act</it> interested.</vi> <vi>He did his best to <it>act</it> excited.</vi> <vi>There she goes, offering advice and <it>acting</it> the expert. [=pretending to be an expert]</vi> <vi>If anybody asks you where I am, <phrase>act dumb</phrase>. [=pretend that you do not know]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to pretend that something is true <un>usually used in the phrases <phrase>act as if</phrase>, <phrase>act as though</phrase>, and (<it>chiefly US</it>) <phrase>act like</phrase> <vi>She <it>acted as if</it> nothing had happened.</vi> <vi>We <it>acted as though</it> we knew what was going on.</vi> <vi>I tried to <it>act like</it> it didn't bother me, but it did.</vi> <vi>Even if you don't like your gift, you should <it>act like</it> you do.</vi> <vi>I didn't <it>act like</it> it, but I really was happy.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>act like</tag> at <dxt>act <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to perform the words and actions of a character in a play, movie, etc. :to perform as an actor <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>It had always been his dream to <it>act</it>.</vi> <vi>She can sing, dance, and <it>act</it>.</vi> <vi>As a child, she began <it>acting</it> in television commercials.</vi> <vi>Both actors have agreed to <it>act</it> in the movie.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He'll be <it>acting</it> the part of Romeo in tonight's play.</vi> <vi>The role of Romeo was wonderfully <it>acted</it> by Mr. Jacob Smith.</vi> <vi>a beautifully <it>acted</it> movie [=a movie in which the acting is excellent]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do the work of a particular kind of person or thing :to perform a certain function or role <un>+ <it>as</it> <vi>A young man <it>acted</it> [=<it>served</it>] <it>as</it> our guide through the city.</vi> <vi>She'll be <it>acting as</it> her own attorney during the court trial.</vi> <vi>She agreed to <it>act as</it> his secretary.</vi> <vi>The trees <it>act as</it> a source of shade and protection from the wind.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make something happen :to have a particular effect <vi>The chemical <it>acts</it> [=<it>works</it>] by destroying the cells in the brain.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>These medicines <it>act on</it> [=<it>affect</it>] the heart.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>act on/upon <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>act on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>act on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something, such as a feeling or suggestion) as a reason or basis for doing something <vi>They never <it>acted on</it> the information they had.</vi> <vi>We were too late to <it>act upon</it> his suggestion.</vi> <vi>It's okay to feel angry or jealous, but you mustn't <it>act on</it> those feelings.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>act <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>act out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to behave badly especially because you are feeling painful emotions (such as fear or anger) <vi>What can parents do when their kids start <it>acting out</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>act out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>act (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to show that you are feeling (a painful emotion) by acting in ways that are not good or acceptable <vi>children <it>acting out</it> their emotions in inappropriate ways</vi> <vi>He tries not to <it>act out</it> his anger/frustrations.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>act out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>act (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to perform (a play, a character in a movie, etc.) <vi>plays <it>acted out</it> on stage</vi> <vi>She skillfully <it>acted out</it> the role of a young queen.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do and say the things that happen in (a movie, past event, etc.) <vi>At their last party, they <it>acted out</it> [=<it>reenacted</it>] scenes from old movies.</vi> <vi>The children were <it>acting out</it> what they saw on television.</vi> <vi>adults <it>acting out</it> their childhood dreams/fantasies [=doing the things they wanted to do when they were children]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>act the fool</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fool</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>act up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to behave badly :to act in a way that is not polite or acceptable <vi>The kids are <it>acting up</it> [=<it>misbehaving</it>] again.</vi> <vi>The book gives advice to parents whose children <it>act up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to not work properly <vi>The camera started <it>acting up</it> [=<it>malfunctioning</it>] after I dropped it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a disease</ssl> <dt>:to become worse and to start causing pain or physical problems <vi>His asthma <it>acts up</it> when it's cold outside.</vi> <vi>Whenever it rains, my arthritis starts <it>acting up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="ACT"> <hw>ACT</hw> <fl>abbreviation</fl> <def><dt>American College Test <snote>The <it>ACT</it> is a test that some U.S. students take as a part of applying to colleges.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="class act"> <hw>class act</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ acts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:someone who is admirable and usually very fair or polite <vi>She's a real <it>class act</it> on and off the soccer field.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sex act"> <hw>sex act</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ acts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an action performed with another person for sexual pleasure <vi>paid to perform a <it>sex act</it></vi> <vi>a pair of actors simulating <phrase>the sex act</phrase> [=<it>sexual intercourse</it>]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="vanishing act"> <hw>vanishing act</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an occurrence in which someone or something suddenly goes away or disappears <vi>He <phrase>pulled a vanishing act</phrase> [=he disappeared] when the check for the meal arrived.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="follow"> <hw highlight="yes">fol*low</hw> <sound><wav>follow01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɑ:loʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>fol*lows</if></in> <in><if>fol*lowed</if></in> <in><if>fol*low*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to go or come after or behind (someone or something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>followed</it> us into the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>followed</it> the children home.</vi> <vi>The exit is right this way. Just <it>follow</it> me.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The children went home and the dog <it>followed</it> behind.</vi> <vi>If one sheep goes through the gate, the rest will <it>follow</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go after or behind (someone) secretly and watch to find out what happens <vi>He hired a private detective to <it>follow</it> his wife everywhere. [=to secretly find out where she went and what she did]</vi> <vi><it>follow</it> a suspect</vi> <vi>I think that someone is <it>following</it> us. = I think we're being <it>followed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to come after (something) in time or place or as part of a series <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Spring <it>follows</it> winter. = Winter <it>is followed</it> by spring.</vi> <vi>The number 15 <it>follows</it> 14.</vi> <vi>Her accident was <it>followed</it> by a long period of recovery.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>First came the student speeches, and the presentation of awards <it>followed</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>formal)</it> The war ended. <phrase>There followed</phrase> [=<it>then came</it>; then there was] a long period of rebuilding.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or do something after (something else) <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>I <it>followed</it> my dinner <it>with</it> a liqueur. [=I had a liqueur after dinner]</vi> <vi>The actor <it>followed</it> his success as Othello <it>with</it> a triumph as Macbeth.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to happen after and as a result of (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Rioting <it>followed</it> the unjust verdict.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you work hard, success will/must surely <it>follow</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be true or seem to be true because of something <vi>From the evidence given, several conclusions <it>follow</it>. = Several conclusions <it>follow</it> from the evidence given. [=we can make several conclusions based on the evidence given]</vi> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>From the evidence given, it <it>follows that</it> the accused is guilty.</vi> <vi>Just because he's done some bad things, does/must it <it>follow that</it> he's a bad person? [=does it mean that he is a bad person?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be guided by (something) <vi>You should <it>follow</it> [=<it>obey</it>] your conscience.</vi> <vi><it>follow</it> your instincts</vi> <vi><it>follow</it> my advice</vi> <vi>She must learn to <it>follow</it> instructions.</vi> <vi>We must <it>follow</it> the evidence wherever it leads.</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>follow her example</phrase>. = You should <it>follow</it> the example she set. [=you should do what she did]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do the same thing as (someone) <vi>She <it>followed</it> her father (by going) into medicine. = She <it>followed</it> her father by becoming a doctor.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move forward on (a road, a path, etc.) <vi><it>Follow</it> that path, and you will come to a log cabin.</vi> <vi>You should <it>follow</it> the main highway until you see signs for the stadium.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His friends all went to college, but he chose to <it>follow</it> a different path. [=to do something different]</vi> <vi>Do recessions <it>follow</it> a predictable cycle/pattern?</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>of a road, path, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to be on or next to (something) for a distance <vi>The path <it>follows</it> the river pretty closely.</vi> <vi>The road <it>follows</it> the curve of the hill.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep your eyes or attention on (something) <vi><it>Follow</it> the bouncing ball.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give close attention to what happens in (something) <vi>He <it>followed</it> her career with interest.</vi> <vi><it>follow</it> football</vi> <vi>The book <it>follows</it> his political career from its humble beginnings to his election as president.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be a fan of (a team) :<sx>support</sx> <vi>He <it>follows</it> Manchester United.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to understand the sense or logic of (something or someone) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I found it hard to <it>follow</it> the twists and turns of the movie's complicated plot.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry—I don't <it>follow</it> your argument/reasoning. = I'm sorry—I don't <it>follow</it> you. [=I don't understand you]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'm sorry—I don't <it>follow</it>. [=I don't understand]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a hard/tough act to follow</dre> <def><dt>:someone or something that has been so successful that it is very difficult for the person or thing coming next to be as good <vi>Yesterday's thrilling victory will be <it>a tough act to follow</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as follows</dre> <def><dt><un>used to introduce a list, a statement, instructions, etc. <vi>The names of the finalists are <it>as follows</it>: Mary, James, and George.</vi> <vi>Proceed <it>as follows</it>: go straight ahead to Martin Street and then turn left.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>follow around</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>follow about</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>follow (someone) around/about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go wherever (someone) goes <vi>The little boy <it>followed</it> his mother <it>around</it> all day.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>follow in someone's footsteps</dre> <dx>see <dxt>footstep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>follow someone's lead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>follow suit</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>in card games</ssl> <dt>:to play a card of the same suit (such as hearts or spades) as the card that was played just before <vi>Jane played a spade, and Roger <it>followed suit</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do the same thing that someone else has just done <vi>His brother went to medical school, and he <it>followed suit</it>.</vi> <vi>After one airline lowers their fares, the other airlines usually <it>follow suit</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>follow the path/line of least resistance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>resistance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>follow through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>follow through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>follow (something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to complete an activity or process that has been started <vi>He always starts the school year off studying and working hard, but he doesn't <it>follow through</it>. [=he doesn't continue to study and work hard]</vi> <vi>He doesn't <it>follow</it> his good intentions <it>through</it>. [=although he makes plans to do things, he doesn't actually do them]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> or <it>with</it> <vi>He doesn't <it>follow through on</it> his good intentions.</vi> <vi>We feared they would <it>follow through on/with</it> their threat. [=we feared that they would do what they threatened to do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to keep your arms, legs, etc., moving after you hit or kick a ball :to complete a stroke or swing <vi>You should <it>follow through</it> on your backhand.</vi> <vi>Don't forget to <it>follow through</it> when you putt.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>follow-through</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>follow up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>follow up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>follow (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>follow up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to follow (something) with something similar, related, or additional <un>+ <it>with</it> or <it>by</it> <vi>He <it>followed up</it> his early findings <it>with</it> another study.</vi> <vi>After you submit your job application, you should <it>follow</it> it <it>up by</it> making a phone call.</vi> <vi>Her first book was a big success, and she <it>followed up with</it> another best seller.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>follow up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>follow (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>follow up</pva></phrasev> <sin><il>or chiefly US</il> <if>follow up on (something)</if></sin> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to try to get more information about (something) <vi>The police <it>followed up (on)</it> the leads.</vi> <vi>The references in the book were too vague to <it>follow up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do something in response to (something) :to take appropriate action about (something) <vi>Police <it>followed up</it> the complaints with several arrests.</vi> <vi>He complained several times, but the police never <it>followed up</it>.</vi> <vi>He says that the police failed to <it>follow up on</it> his complaints.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>follow-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>follow your nose</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go in a straight or obvious course <vi>Just <it>follow your nose</it> until you get there; you can't miss it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to proceed without a definite plan :to do what seems right or best without careful planning <vi>You don't need my advice—just <it>follow your nose</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go toward the place where a smell is coming from <vi>I <it>followed my nose</it> to the kitchen, where dinner was cooking.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="fool[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fool</hw> <sound><wav>fool0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfu:l</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>fools</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a person who lacks good sense or judgment :a stupid or silly person <vi>those <it>fools</it> who ride motorcycles without wearing helmets</vi> <vi>Only a <it>fool</it> would ask such a silly question.</vi> <vi>You'd be a <it>fool</it> to believe what he tells you.</vi> <vi>You're making yourself look like a <it>fool</it>.</vi> <vi><phrase>A fool and his money are soon parted</phrase>. [=a foolish person spends money too quickly on unimportant things]</vi> <vi><phrase>Any fool</phrase> can see [=anyone can see] that he's lying.</vi> <vi>I never thought you'd be <phrase>fool enough</phrase> to believe him. = I never thought you'd be enough of a <it>fool</it> to believe him.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Only that <phrase>fool of a</phrase> brother [=that foolish brother] of yours would ask such a silly question!</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Some (damn/damned) <it>fool of a</it> driver kept trying to pass me!</vi> <vi><phrase>Fools rush in</phrase> (<phrase>where angels fear to tread</phrase>). [=it is foolish to take action if you do not know much about what you are doing]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) (<phrase>The</phrase>) <phrase>more fool you</phrase> if you believe him. = (<it>The</it>) <it>more fool you</it> for believing him. [=you would be a fool to believe him]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) <it>More fool him</it> for trusting her.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no fool like an old fool</phrase>. [=a foolish old person is especially foolish because an old person should have learned from experience not to make the kind of mistakes a young person makes]</vi> <snote>A smart or clever person can be described as <phrase>no fool</phrase> or as <phrase>nobody's fool</phrase>. <vi>He may not look very smart, but he's <it>no fool</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't try to trick her—she's <it>nobody's fool</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a person who enjoys something very much <vi>He's a dancing <it>fool</it>. [=he loves to dance]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>a fool for</phrase> candy. [=he loves to eat candy]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:a dessert made with cooked fruit and cream or a thick sauce <vi>a strawberry <it>fool</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:<sx>jester</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>act/play the fool</dre> <def><dt>:to behave in a silly or foolish way <vi>If you keep <it>playing the fool</it> by asking silly questions, people won't take you seriously.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a fool of yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to behave in a very foolish or silly way <vi>He got drunk at the party and <it>made a fool of himself</it>.</vi> <vi>He's <it>making a fool of himself</it> over that woman.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a fool (out) of</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (someone) to look stupid or foolish <vi>She <it>made a fool of me</it> by insulting me in front of my friends.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>april fools' day</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="get"> <hw highlight="yes">get</hw> <sound><wav>get00001.wav</wav><wav>get00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɛt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gets</if></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <il>or US</il> <if>got*ten</if> <sound><wav>get00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:tn̩</pr></in> <in><if>get*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to obtain (something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to receive or be given (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> a new bicycle for his birthday.</vi> <vi>I never did <it>get</it> an answer to my question.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> a letter from my lawyer.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a phone call from her sister.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>get</it> my message?</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] a ride to town with you? [=will you give me a ride to town?]</vi> <vi>You need to <it>get</it> your mother's permission to go.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to obtain (something) through effort, chance, etc. <vi>She hasn't been able to <it>get</it> a job.</vi> <vi>It's nearly impossible to <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a reservation at that restaurant.</vi> <vi>If you want to be successful you need to <it>get</it> a good education.</vi> <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> the waiter's attention.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a look at the thief. [=she managed to look at the thief]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to obtain the use or services of (something) <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> a taxi.</vi> <vi>It's hard to <it>get</it> good help these days.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to earn or gain (something) <vi>How much does he <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a week?</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> $50 when I sold my old bicycle. = I <it>got</it> $50 for my old bicycle.</vi> <vi>He's <it>gotten</it> a bad reputation (for himself). = He's <it>gotten</it> himself a bad reputation.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> an “A” on my history exam!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>She <it>got</it> first prize in the essay contest.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to buy or pay for (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> (himself) a new car at a great price.</vi> <vi>“Did you <it>get</it> that dress at the mall?” “Yes, and I <it>got</it> it for only $20.”</vi> <vi>Do you <it>get</it> [=subscribe to] the local newspaper?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the next round of drinks.</vi> <vi>He offered to <it>get</it> the check, but I insisted on <it>getting</it> it myself.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> a beautiful necklace for his wife. = He <it>got</it> his wife a beautiful necklace.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go somewhere and come back with (something or someone) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> a pencil from the desk.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> anything for you? = Can I <it>get</it> you anything?</vi> <vi>Someone has to (go) <it>get</it> the boss from the airport and bring her back here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to send or take (something or someone) <it>to</it> a person or place <vi>I have to <it>get</it> an important message <it>to</it> her at once!</vi> <vi>We have to <it>get</it> him <it>to</it> the hospital immediately.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to move or go <vi>He quickly <it>got</it> himself and his luggage through customs.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> the car out of the garage.</vi> <vi>I could barely <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] the luggage into the car's trunk.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> this ring on/off my finger.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <vi>He <it>got</it> on the horse and rode away.</vi> <vi>We <it>got</it> on/off the bus.</vi> <vi>They quickly <it>got</it> [=<it>passed</it>] through customs.</vi> <vi>She never <it>got</it> out of the house last weekend.</vi> <vi>He lost weight to be able to <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] into his jeans again.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> between them to keep them from fighting.</vi> <vi>Ouch! <it>Get</it> off my foot!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>When did you <it>get</it> here/there?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> home last night.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have (a feeling, an idea, etc.) <vi>I <it>got</it> a funny feeling when I saw her again.</vi> <vi>He somehow <it>got</it> the idea that I was lying to him.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> the impression that he wasn't interested.</vi> <vi>One thing led to another, and—well, <phrase>you get the picture/idea</phrase>. [=you can easily guess the rest]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become affected by (a disease) <vi>I <it>got</it> a bad cold when I was on vacation.</vi> <vi>Clean the wound carefully so you don't <it>get</it> an infection.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suffer (an injury) <vi>He <it>got</it> a broken nose in a fight.</vi> <vi>Where/how did you <it>get</it> that bruise on your leg?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or experience (something) <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> a lot of rain recently.</vi> <vi>I finally <it>got</it> a good night's sleep last night. [=I finally slept well last night]</vi> <vi>The inn doesn't <it>get</it> many visitors these days.</vi> <vi>“Do people often ask if you're Irish?” “Yes, I <it>get</it> that a lot.” [=people ask me that often]</vi> <vi><phrase>You get</phrase> [=there are] so many crazy drivers these days.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a particular reaction) <vi>That joke always <it>gets</it> a laugh.</vi> <vi>Her comments <it>got</it> an angry reaction.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make progress in some activity <vi>He hasn't <it>gotten</it> far with the essay. [=he hasn't made much progress with the essay]</vi> <vi>You won't <it>get</it> anywhere with flattery. [=you won't succeed by using flattery]</vi> <vi>At last we're <phrase>getting somewhere</phrase> (with our work)!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get ahead <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to make progress <vi>All that effort didn't really <it>get</it> us very far.</vi> <vi>Flattery will <phrase>get you nowhere</phrase>. = Flattery <phrase>won't get you anywhere</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a specified position or condition <vi>He <it>got</it> his feet wet when he stepped in a puddle.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> his nose broken in a fight. [=his nose was broken in a fight]</vi> <vi>I told you not to <it>get</it> yourself dirty.</vi> <vi>You nearly <it>got</it> us both killed!</vi> <vi>I need to <it>get</it> [=<it>have</it>] my hair cut.</vi> <vi>She finally <it>got</it> her office organized.</vi> <vi>He promised to <it>get</it> the work done quickly. [=to do the work quickly]</vi> <vi>When you're making a measurement be careful to <phrase>get it right</phrase>. [=to do it correctly]</vi> <vi>Let me <phrase>get this straight</phrase> [=let me be sure that I understand this correctly]: are you saying that you won't help us?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do something <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> the children <it>to behave</it>.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>get</it> you <it>to understand</it> that this isn't a good idea?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>to work</it> again.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>working</it> again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start <it>doing</it> something <vi>We <it>got talking</it> about old times.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>1a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or be given the chance <it>to do</it> something :to be able <it>to do</it> something <vi>She never <it>got to go</it> to college.</vi> <vi>Why do I never <it>get to drive</it> the car?</vi> <vi>She hopes she'll finally <it>get to spend</it> more time working on her garden this year.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to deal with (something that needs attention): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to answer (a telephone) <vi>Would somebody please <it>get</it> the phone?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to open (a door) <vi>If you'll <it>get</it> the door for me, I'll carry that box inside.</vi> <vi>There's someone at the door. Would you please <phrase>get it</phrase>? [=open the door and deal with the person who knocked]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to understand (something or someone) <vi>I just don't <it>get</it> the point of what you're saying.</vi> <vi>He didn't <it>get</it> the joke.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>get</it> what you mean.</vi> <vi>Oh, now I <phrase>get it</phrase>. [=<it>understand</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I just don't <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>Don't <phrase>get me wrong</phrase>. [=don't misunderstand what I am saying]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>get your drift</phrase>. [=I understand what you are saying]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I didn't quite <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] his name.</vi></dt> <sn>17 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:<sx>become <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>My hands <it>got</it> dirty when I was working in the garden.</vi> <vi>I <it>get</it> very nervous when I have to speak in public.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> sick last week but I'm feeling better now.</vi> <vi>I just can't <it>get</it> used to this cold weather.</vi> <vi>She sent her sick friend a “<it>Get</it> Well Soon” card.</vi> <vi>I should go; it's <it>getting</it> late.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) Your daughter's <it>getting</it> quite a big girl now!</vi> <vi>We need to finish by 5 o'clock, so we'd better <phrase>get busy</phrase>. [=begin to work]</vi> <vi>You've never heard of the Internet? Come on, now. <phrase>Get with it</phrase>. [=become up-to-date in your knowledge]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>how stupid/lucky (etc.) can you get</phrase> to mean that someone or something is unusually stupid, lucky, etc. <vi>He tried to rob a policeman. <it>How stupid can you get</it>? [=he was very stupid to try to rob a policeman]</vi> <vi>Just look at that dress! <it>How tacky can you get</it>? [=that dress is very tacky]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change in a specified way as time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Your daughter is <it>getting to be</it> [=is becoming] quite a big girl now!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Once you <it>get to know</it> him, you will like him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>be</it> with the past participle of some verbs to form passive constructions <vi>They <it>got</it> [=<it>were</it>] married last month.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>was</it>] paid for his work.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> arrested for fraud.</vi> <vi>I nearly <it>got</it> killed.</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a meal) <vi>We <it>got</it> dinner at an Italian restaurant last night.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare (a meal) <vi>On weekends, my wife sleeps late while I <it>get</it> breakfast.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (punishment) <vi>He <it>got</it> five years in prison for his crime.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you don't stop misbehaving you're going to <phrase>get it</phrase> when your father gets home! [=your father is going to punish you]</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to grip and hold (something or someone) <vi>The dog <it>got</it> the thief by the leg.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>] me around/by the neck and wouldn't let go.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find and catch (someone) <vi>The Royal Canadian Mounted Police always <it>get</it> their man! [=they always capture the man they are trying to capture]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone) <vi>The bullet <it>got</it> him in the leg.</vi></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or cause trouble for (someone) <vi>He's convinced that his ex-wife is out to <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you if it's the last thing I do!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the death of (someone) <vi>He had heart problems for many years, but it was pneumonia that <it>got</it> him in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>It really <it>gets</it> me that such a foolish man has so much influence.</vi> <vi>What <it>gets</it> me is all these delays!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) sad <vi>The end of that movie always <it>gets</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2b (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be fooled or unable to think of an answer <vi>Well, you <it>got</it> [=<it>fooled, tricked</it>] me that time. That was very clever.</vi> <vi>That's a good question. <phrase>You've got me (there)</phrase>. [=I don't know the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a phone call and hear or speak to (a person or answering machine) <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get</it> [=<it>reach</it>] you (on the phone) all day!</vi> <vi>When I tried to call him I <it>got</it> his answering machine. [=the phone was answered by his answering machine]</vi></dt> <sn>28</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (a radio or TV station or channel) <vi>We don't <it>get</it> this channel at home.</vi></dt> <sn>29</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce or provide (a level of performance) <vi>Our new car <it>gets</it> [=<it>delivers</it>] excellent gas mileage.</vi></dt> <sn>30</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to notice (someone or something) <vi>Did you <it>get</it> the way he looked at you?</vi> <un>often used to direct someone's attention to a person or thing that is seen as foolish, surprising, etc. <vi>Just <it>get</it> him in his new pants!</vi> <vi>She showed up at the party in—<phrase>get this</phrase>—a $3,000 designer dress!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>get about</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get above yourself</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my point has finally <it>gotten across</it> to you. [=I hope you finally understand what I am trying to say]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my point <it>across</it> to you.</vi> <vi>a politician who is trying hard to <it>get</it> his message <it>across</it> (to the voters)</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>get after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to tell (someone) repeatedly to do something <vi>His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him about doing his homework. = His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him to do his homework.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to become more successful <vi>a book about how to <it>get ahead</it> in the business world</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be or remain friendly <vi>We <it>get along</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi> <vi>My brother and my uncle don't really <it>get along</it> (with each other).</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How are you <it>getting along</it> with your work? [=how's your work coming along?]</vi> <vi>He never showed up, but we managed to <it>get along</it> [=<it>get by</it>] without him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>I really must be <it>getting along</it>. [=<it>going, leaving</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become old <vi>Her parents are <phrase>getting along in years</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to go, walk, or travel to different places <vi>She <it>gets around</it> a lot because of her job.</vi> <vi>He's having trouble <it>getting around</it> because of his sore knee.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get round</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to become known by many people <vi>People will be shocked when the news about her arrest <it>gets around</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got around</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to avoid being stopped by (something) :to avoid having to deal with (something) <vi>I'm sure we can find a way to <it>get around</it> these problems.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no getting around</phrase> the fact that the current system isn't working. [=there is no way to deny that the current system isn't working]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around to (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or deal with (something that you have not yet done or dealt with) <vi>Don't you think it's about time you <it>got around to</it> tidying your room?</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call her, but I just haven't <it>gotten around to</it> it. [=I haven't called her]</vi> <vi>Sooner or later we'll have to <it>get around to</it> the subject of taxation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach (something or someone) <vi>The valve is hard to <it>get at</it> unless you have a special tool.</vi> <vi>An angry mob tried to <it>get at</it> him but the police protected him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find out (information that is hidden or hard to know) <vi>How can we ever <it>get at</it> the truth?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or suggest (something) in an indirect way <un>usually used as <phrase>getting at</phrase> <vi>Just what are you <it>getting at</it>? [=what are you suggesting?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>He says his teachers are always <it>getting at</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>getting on</it>] him unfairly.</vi> <vi>He's always being <it>got at</it> by his teachers.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You have a lot of work to do so you'd better <it>get at it</it>. [=<it>get to it</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go away from a place <vi>I'll be busy at work all day and I can't <it>get away</it> until tonight.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company is having problems because they've <phrase>gotten away from</phrase> the things they do best. [=they have stopped doing the things they do best]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go away from your home for a vacation <vi>I'm taking some time off because I really need to <it>get away</it> for a few days.</vi> <vi>We went on a cruise to <phrase>get away from it all</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to avoid being caught :to escape <vi>The robbers <it>got away</it> (from the police) in a fast car.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The robbers <it>got away with</it> a lot of stolen jewelry.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can't <it>get away</it> from the facts. = <phrase>There's no getting away from</phrase> the facts. [=you can't avoid or deny the facts; the facts are known and cannot be ignored]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>getaway</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be criticized or punished for (something) <vi>She's incredibly rude. I don't know how she <it>gets away with</it> it.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>There's a chance of rain, but I think I can probably <it>get away with</it> leaving my umbrella at home. [=I probably will not need my umbrella]</vi> <vi>It would be nice to have more food for the party, but I think we can <it>get away with</it> what we have. [=I think what we have is enough and will not cause problems for us]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given only slight or mild punishment for a crime or for doing something wrong <vi>The policeman stopped her for speeding but let her <it>get away with</it> just a warning.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get away with murder</tag> at <dxt>murder</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place after going away <vi>When did you <it>get back</it> from your vacation?</vi> <vi>We <it>got back</it> to the office in the early afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to return to an activity, condition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Things are finally <it>getting back to</it> normal.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>get back to</it> the topic we were discussing yesterday.</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>get back to work</phrase>. [=to start working again]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or obtain (something you have lost) again :to recover (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> his old job <it>back</it> after a long struggle.</vi> <vi>Someone stole his wallet but he <it>got</it> it <it>back</it> from the police.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back at (someone)</pva> <pvl>or Brit</pvl> <pva>get your own back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do something bad or unpleasant to someone who has treated you badly or unfairly <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you <it>back</it> for what you did to me!</vi> <vi>After he lost his job, he vowed that he would find a way to <it>get back at</it> his old boss.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get back to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk to or write to (someone) at a later time in order to give more information, answer a question, etc. <vi>He <it>got back to</it> me (by e-mail) in a few days with a new offer.</vi> <vi>“How much will it cost?” “I'm not sure. I'll have to <it>get back to</it> you on that.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to call (someone) back on the telephone <vi>“There's someone on the phone for you, sir.” “Tell them I can't take their call now but I'll <it>get back to</it> them as soon as I can.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back to (the) basics</dre> <dx>see <dxt>basic</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fail to do something as quickly as required or expected <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> further (and further) <it>behind</it> (schedule).</vi> <vi>We <it>got behind</it> with our car payments.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get behind (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to support (someone or something) <vi>The proposal may succeed if a few more people <it>get behind</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do enough or to do well enough to avoid failure <vi>He's doing very well in his history classes, but he's barely <it>getting by</it> in math.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be able to live or to do what is needed by using what you have even though you do not have much <vi>We don't have a lot of money, but we <it>get by</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>How can you <it>get by on</it> such a small salary?</vi></un> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>We <it>got by with</it> a minimum of clothing when we went camping.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get cracking</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>The weather was really <it>getting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Talking about politics always <it>gets</it> me <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to swallow (something) :to eat or drink (something) <vi>You'll feel better once you <it>get</it> this medicine <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to write (something) down <vi>If you have a good idea, you should <it>get</it> it <it>down</it> (in writing) so that you won't forget it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to play music or dance with skill and enthusiasm <vi>She likes to <it>get down</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) :to begin to give your attention or effort to (something) <vi>It's time to stop delaying and <it>get down to</it> work.</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>get down to business</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk about or describe (something) in a very simple and accurate way <vi><phrase>When you get right down to it</phrase>, this movie is just not very good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get even</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get going</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave <vi>We ought to <it>get going</it> if we don't want to be late.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You should <it>get going</it> on that assignment.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to start talking <vi>Once he <it>gets going</it> about the war you can't shut him up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to start talking <vi>Don't <it>get</it> him <it>going</it> about the war or you'll never shut him up!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>The burglar <it>got in</it> through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The train <it>got in</it> late.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to arrive home <vi>Her husband was out late last night. He didn't <it>get in</it> until almost midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become involved in an activity <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got in</it> at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be chosen or elected for office <vi>The mayor <it>got in</it> by a very slim margin.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>It's a very good school. I hope your daughter <it>gets in</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (someone) come to your home, business, etc., to do work <vi>We had to <it>get</it> a doctor/plumber <it>in</it> to deal with the emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do or say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get</it> a few good punches <it>in</it> before they stopped the fight.</vi> <vi>May I <phrase>get a word in</phrase> here? [=may I say something here?]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get a word in edgewise</tag> at <dxt>edgewise</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send or deliver (something) to the proper person or place <vi>Did you <it>get</it> your assignment <it>in</it> on time?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to do (something) in the amount of time that is available <vi>I was able to <it>get in</it> a few hours of reading last night.</vi> <vi>I hope we can <it>get in</it> a visit to the art museum the next time we're in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to harvest (a crop) and put it in a safe or dry place <vi>It's time to <it>get</it> the crop/harvest <it>in</it>.</vi> <vi>We'd better <it>get</it> the hay <it>in</it> before it rains.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>It sounds like an interesting project and I'd like to <it>get in on</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become friends with (someone) <vi>She <it>got in with</it> [=<it>fell in with</it>] a bad crowd and got into trouble.</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>get in good with</phrase> the boss. [=he got the boss to like him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (a place)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>The burglar <it>got into</it> the house through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The train <it>got into</it> New York late last night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become involved in (an activity) <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got into</it> it at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to be interested in and to enjoy (something) <vi>It's only recently that I've really <it>gotten into</it> music.</vi> <vi>I tried reading the book, but I just couldn't <it>get into</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>I hope your daughter <it>gets into</it> the school.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>into</it> the school.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become involved or to cause (someone) to become involved in (something bad, such as trouble or a fight) <vi>He <it>got into</it> a lot of trouble when he was a teenager.</vi> <vi>They <it>got into</it> an argument.</vi> <vi>His friends <it>got</it> him <it>into</it> trouble.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll tell you what happened, but I don't want to <it>get into</it> [=<it>go into</it>] all the reasons for why it happened.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>got into (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect the behavior of (someone) <un>used to say that someone is behaving in an unusual way and you don't know why <vi>I don't know what has <it>gotten into</it> him lately.</vi> <vi>She never used to be so rude to people. <phrase>What got into her?</phrase> [=why is she behaving this way?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get lost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get lucky</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lucky</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get moving</dre> <dx>see <dxt>move</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave at the start of a journey <vi>We <it>got off</it> early on our camping trip.</vi> <un>often used figuratively in the phrase <phrase>get off to a good/bad (etc.) start</phrase> <vi>He and I <it>got off to a bad start</it>, but now we get along well.</vi> <vi>The project <it>got off to a slow start</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>get off on the right/wrong foot</tag> at <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be punished for a crime :to be judged not guilty of a crime <vi>He's been arrested several times, but he always <it>gets off</it>.</vi> :to help (someone) to be judged not guilty <vi>His lawyer <it>got</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given or to help (someone) to be given only a slight punishment for a crime <vi>She <it>got off</it> lightly.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He <it>got off with</it> a light sentence.</vi> <vi>His lawyer tried to <it>get</it> him <it>off with</it> a light sentence.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>It was a bad accident. You're lucky that you <it>got off with</it> just a broken leg—you could have been killed!</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being on or against someone or something <vi><it>Get off</it>—you're hurting me!</vi> <vi>I took the subway and <it>got off</it> at the downtown station.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>5a</dxn> <dxn>b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop talking about (something) or to cause (someone) to stop talking about (something) <vi>We somehow <it>got off</it> (the subject of) work and started talking about our personal lives.</vi> <vi>I tried to change the subject, but I couldn't <it>get</it> her <it>off</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off work</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to finish working and leave the place where you work <vi>I <it>get off</it> early on Fridays.</vi> <vi>I <it>got off work</it> early last Thursday so I could see the parade.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write and send (a letter, an e-mail message, etc.) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the letter <it>off</it> (to them) tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to shoot (something) from a gun <vi>The policeman <it>got off</it> [=<it>fired</it>] several shots before the criminal escaped.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He managed to <it>get off</it> a few good jokes in his speech.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to fall asleep or to help (someone, such as a baby) to fall asleep <vi>I had just <it>got off</it> [=<it>dropped off</it>] when the doorbell rang. = I had just <phrase>got off to sleep</phrase> when the doorbell rang.</vi> <vi>I just <it>got</it> the baby <it>off to sleep</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have an orgasm or to cause (someone) to have an orgasm</dt> <sn>9</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal + sometimes disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy or be excited by (something) especially in a sexual way <vi>He's one of those guys who seem to <it>get off on</it> making other people feel guilty.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone) :to begin a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She found out he'd <it>gotten off with</it> another woman.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>tell someone where to get off</phrase> is to criticize or disagree with someone in a very direct and angry way. <vi>I was sick of listening to his constant complaints, so I <it>told him where to get off</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>don't know where someone gets off</phrase> (doing something), you are angry because someone has done something that is not right. <vi>I <it>don't know where he gets off</it> telling me what to do. = <phrase>Where does he get off</phrase> telling me what to do? [=he has no right to tell me what to do]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you. I'll let you <it>get on with</it> your work.</vi> <vi>You need to stop feeling sorry for yourself and just <phrase>get on with your life</phrase>. [=return to doing the things you do in your normal life]</vi> <vi>This introduction is taking forever. I wish they'd just <phrase>get on with it</phrase>. [=stop delaying and get to the interesting or important part]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be or remain friendly :to get along <vi>They've never really <it>got on</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>We <it>get on</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How is your daughter <it>getting on</it> in/at school?</vi> <vi>We can <it>get on</it> [=<it>get along, get by, manage</it>] just fine without them.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to achieve greater success :to get ahead <vi>an ambitious young woman trying to <it>get on</it> in business</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“These files need to be organized.” “I'll <it>get on</it> it right away.”</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>His boss has been <it>getting on</it> him about the quality of his work.</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>getting on his case</phrase> about cleaning his room. [=she's always telling him to clean it]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it on</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <dt>:to have sex</dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on in years</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to grow old <vi>My grandmother is <it>getting on</it> [=<it>aging</it>] a bit, but she's still very active.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become late <vi>It's <it>getting on</it>, and we really ought to go.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to move toward becoming (a specified age, time, etc.) <vi>He's <it>getting on for</it> 70. [=he's approaching 70; he is nearly 70]</vi> <vi>It was <it>getting on for</it> noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get onto</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>get on to</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“We need someone to send out the invitations.” “I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get on</it>] it right away.”</vi> :to start to talk about something <vi>How did we <it>get onto</it> this topic?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to speak to or write to (someone) about a particular problem, job, etc. <vi>I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get in touch with</it>] the doctor/plumber straightaway and see if he'll come round.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave or escape from a place, a vehicle, etc. <vi>He was trapped in the burning building/car, but he was somehow able to <it>get out</it> (of it) alive.</vi> <un>used as an angry way to tell someone to leave <vi><it>Get out</it>! I never want to see you again!</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to leave or escape <vi>The firemen managed to <it>get</it> him <it>out</it> (of the burning building) alive.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) from storage so that it can be used <vi>It's raining. I'd better <it>get out</it> the umbrella.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to places outside your home for social occasions, events, etc. <vi>You spend too much time at home. You need to <it>get out</it> more.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>Their secret <it>got out</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got out</it> that she was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get out</it> a few words before he collapsed.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to show that you are surprised by something or do not believe it <vi>“They gave the job to Jane.” “<it>Get out</it>!” = “<phrase>Get out of here</phrase>!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get out of (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone or something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to avoid doing (something) or to help (someone) to avoid doing (something) <vi>I didn't want to go to the lecture, but I couldn't <it>get out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>He tried to <it>get out of</it> doing his homework.</vi> <vi>My sister said she could <it>get</it> me <it>out of</it> going to the party if I really didn't want to go</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having (a habit) or to cause (someone) to stop having (a habit) <vi>I used to exercise every day, but I <it>got out of</it> the habit.</vi> <vi>All the extra work I've been doing has <it>gotten</it> me <it>out of</it> the habit of exercising.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop being in or involved in (something) or to cause (someone or something) to stop being in or involved in (something) <vi>The company has decided to <it>get</it> (itself) <it>out of</it> the computer business.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> her money <it>out of</it> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something) from (something or someone) <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> the gun <it>out of</it> the suspect's hand.</vi> <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> a confession <it>out of</it> the suspect.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to gain (something) from (something) <vi>What do you hope to <it>get out of</it> this experience?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop being controlled or bothered by (something, such as a problem or feeling) <vi>You need to <it>get over</it> [=<it>overcome</it>] your fear of being lied to.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy about (something) <vi>She's disappointed about their decision, but she'll <it>get over</it> it eventually.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that you are very surprised or impressed by something <vi>I just can't <it>get over</it> how much weight you've lost!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become healthy again after (an illness) <vi>He had a bad cold, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> it completely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy after ending a relationship with (someone) <vi>He broke up with his girlfriend a couple of months ago, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get (something) over with</va></svr> <dt>:to cause or experience the end of (something) :to finish (something) <vi>I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over</it>! = I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over with</it>! = I just want to <phrase>get</phrase> this ordeal <phrase>over and done with</phrase>! [=I want this ordeal to end]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get over (something)</va></svr> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my message <it>over</it> [=<it>across</it>] to them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get real</dre> <dx>see <dxt>real</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rid of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roll</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>best</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the better of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get there</dre> <def><dt>:to reach a goal :to do what you are trying to do <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we'll <it>get there</it> eventually. [=we'll make a profit eventually]</vi> :to come closer to reaching a goal <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we're <it>getting there</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to finish a job or activity <vi>When you <it>get through</it> (with that job), I've got something else for you to do.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or finish (something, such as an amount of work) <vi>We <it>got through</it> [=<it>covered</it>] all of the material that we wanted to cover.</vi> <vi>There's still a lot of paperwork to be <it>gotten through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to complete or to help (someone) to complete (a test, an exam, etc.) successfully <vi>She studied hard and <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] her exams.</vi> <vi>The extra hours of study are what <it>got</it> her <it>through</it> her exams.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pass through or beyond something that blocks you or slows you down <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting through</it> to the flood victims.</vi> :to cause (something) to pass through or beyond something <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get</it> our truck <it>through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting</it> supplies <it>through</it> to the flood victims.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something that is difficult, dangerous, etc.) <vi>It was a very difficult time in our marriage, but we <it>got through</it> it.</vi> <vi>I don't know how those early settlers managed to <it>get through</it> [=<it>survive</it>] the winter.</vi> :to help (someone) to live through (something) <vi>It was pure determination that <it>got</it> them <it>through</it> that crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] all the money he inherited in just a few years.</vi> <vi>They <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my message has finally <it>gotten through to</it> you. [=I hope you finally understand my message]</vi> <vi>I think my message finally <it>got through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through to (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express something clearly so that it is understood by (someone) <vi>I've talked to him many times, but I just can't seem to <it>get through to</it> him.</vi> <vi>I hope I've finally <it>gotten</it> my message <it>through to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a successful telephone call to someone <vi>I tried to call home but I couldn't <it>get through</it>.</vi> <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get through to</it> you (on the phone) all day!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or approved by an official group <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] and eventually became a law.</vi> <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] Congress and eventually became a law.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>She sometimes <it>gets to worrying</it> over her health.</vi> <vi>We <it>got to talking</it> about old times.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to deal with (something) <vi>The letter is on my desk, but I haven't <it>gotten to</it> it yet.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get to</it> the accounts as soon as I can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>All these delays are starting to <it>get to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel sad <vi>The movie's sad ending really <it>got to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to change or influence the behavior of (someone) wrongly or illegally by making threats, paying money, etc. <vi>The witness changed his story. Someone must have <it>gotten to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to or reach (somewhere) <vi>We <it>got to</it> the station/airport just in time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to meet and spend time together <vi>I'd like to <it>get together</it> with you soon.</vi> <vi>He often <it>gets together</it> with his friends after work.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to have a sexual or romantic relationship <vi>He and his wife first <it>got together</it> in college.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to meet or to have a relationship <vi>Their shared interest in photography is what <it>got</it> them <it>together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept something <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The two sides have been unable to <it>get together on</it> a new contract.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get together (things or people)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (things or people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to collect (things) or gather (people) into one place or group <vi>He <it>got together</it> [=<it>assembled</it>] a great art collection.</vi> <vi>The government <it>got together</it> a group of experts to study the problem.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>get together</it> [=<it>obtain</it>] the money we need to buy a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get your act together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get yourself together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get it together</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get your life together</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to live in a good and sensible way :to stop being confused, foolish, etc. <vi>His life got much better when he stopped drinking and <it>got his act together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to function in a skillful or effective way <vi>The company finally <it>got its act together</it> and started making a profit this year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to sleep</dre> <def><dt>:to start sleeping :to fall asleep <vi>She finally <it>got to sleep</it> after midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to work</dre> <def><dt>:to start working <vi>We need to stop delaying and <it>get to work</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to rise or to cause (someone) to rise after lying or sleeping in a bed <vi>I <it>got up</it> [=got out of bed] early this morning.</vi> <vi>I woke up early but I didn't <it>get up</it> till later.</vi> <vi>The alarm clock <it>got</it> me <it>up</it> earlier than usual.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stand up <vi>He <it>got up</it> to greet her when she entered the room.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as courage) in yourself by trying or making an effort <vi>He couldn't <it>get up</it> the courage to ask her out on a date.</vi> <vi>She was so tired she could hardly <it>get up</it> the energy to make dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare or organize (something that involves a group of people) <vi>They're trying to <it>get up</it> a petition to have the movie theater reopened.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to get an erection</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up on the wrong side of the bed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get what's coming to you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get wind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your goat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have got</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="god"> <hw highlight="yes">god</hw> <sound><wav>god00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:d</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>God</bnote> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the perfect and all-powerful spirit or being that is worshipped especially by Christians, Jews, and Muslims as the one who created and rules the universe <vi>Does she believe in <it>God</it>?</vi> <vi>(May) <it>God</it> bless us all.</vi> <vi>(May) <it>God</it> rest her soul. [=I pray that God will give her soul peace now that she has died]</vi> <vi>I pray to <it>God</it> that no one was seriously injured in the accident.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>man of god</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote><it>God</it> is used informally by itself and in phrases to make a statement or question more forceful or to express surprise, anger, etc. These uses are common but are considered offensive by some people. <vi><it>God</it>, it's hot out today.</vi> <vi><phrase>Good God</phrase>, that's a lot of food!</vi> <vi><phrase>God Almighty</phrase>, is it that late already?</vi> <vi><phrase>My God</phrase>, what were you thinking?!</vi> <vi><phrase>Oh my God</phrase>! I can't believe it!</vi> <vi><phrase>By God</phrase>, I refuse to give up!</vi> <vi><phrase>For God's sake</phrase>, what do you want from me?</vi> <vi>Who <phrase>in God's name</phrase> [=<it>on earth, in heaven's name</it>] could that be?</vi> <vi>Where <it>in God's name</it> have you been?</vi> <vi>I <phrase>swear to God</phrase>, if you're not ready in five minutes, I'm leaving without you.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>wish to God</phrase> you would stop complaining.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a spirit or being that has great power, strength, knowledge, etc., and that can affect nature and the lives of people :one of various spirits or beings worshipped in some religions <vi>the <it>gods</it> and goddesses of ancient Egypt</vi> <vi>a Hindu <it>god</it></vi> <vi>a myth about the <it>god</it> of war</vi> <vi>an offering for the <it>gods</it></vi> <un>often used informally to suggest that what happens to someone is controlled by gods or by luck <vi>The <it>gods</it> smiled/frowned on us. = The <it>gods</it> were/weren't on our side [=we had good/bad luck; things went well/badly for us]</vi> <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) The golf <it>gods</it> seem to like you today. [=you are playing golf very well today]</vi> <vi>Her sudden arrival was <phrase>a gift from the gods</phrase>. [=a very lucky and helpful thing]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person and especially a man who is greatly loved or admired <vi>a professor who was regarded as a kind of <it>god</it></vi> <vi>a guitar <it>god</it> like Jimi Hendrix</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person who is very important or powerful in a particular field <un>usually plural <vi>a talented writer who never found favor with the <it>gods</it> of the literary world</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is regarded as one of the most important things in someone's life <vi>He made a <it>god</it> of money. [=he worshipped money; he regarded money as more important than it really is]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>the gods</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the highest and cheapest seats in a theater <vi>The people in <it>the gods</it> can be the hardest to please.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>act of God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>act</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for the love of God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God bless you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bless</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God forbid</dre> <dx>see <dxt>forbid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God help someone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>help</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God knows</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God's gift</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gift</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God willing</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say what you hope and expect to do or happen if no problems occur <vi>We'll be able to move into our new house next week, <it>God willing</it>.</vi> <vi><it>God willing</it>, I'll finish my degree this year.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the lap of the gods</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>play God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>play</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put the fear of God into</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>so help me God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>help</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>thank God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(there) but for the grace of God (go I)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>god*like</ure> <sound><wav>godlik01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈga:dˌlaɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
