<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="add"> <hw highlight="yes">add</hw> <sound><wav>add00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>adds</if></in> <in><if>add*ed</if></in> <in><if>add*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to put (something) with another thing or group of things <vi>She's planning to <it>add</it> some new flowers to the garden.</vi> <vi>The company is <it>adding</it> over 200 jobs this year.</vi> <vi>This winter, he <it>added</it> skiing to his list of favorite sports.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to mix or combine (an ingredient) with other ingredients <vi><it>Add</it> (in) a little more salt and pepper.</vi> <vi>I <it>added</it> (in) just a dash/pinch of flour.</vi> <vi><it>Add</it> one cup of sugar to the mixture.</vi> <vi>Next, <it>add</it> the remaining butter to the pan.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to include (something) with something else <vi>It took us four hours to get there, if you <it>add</it> (in) the time we stopped to eat.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause something to have (a usually good quality or characteristic) <vi>In this dish, fresh herbs <it>add</it> lots of color and flavor.</vi> <vi>As an employee, she will <it>add</it> [=<it>bring</it>] great value to your company.</vi> <vi>We can help you <it>add</it> excitement to your vacation.</vi> <vi>The historical details <it>add</it> depth/richness/weight to his story.</vi> <vi>She <it>adds</it> a certain amount of experience and authority to the project.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to put (two or more numbers or amounts) together to find a total or sum <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>When you <it>add</it> three and/to seven, you get ten.</vi> <vi><it>Add</it> these three numbers together.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>schoolchildren learning how to <it>add</it> [=to perform addition] and subtract</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>subtract</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or write (something more or extra) <vi>That's all I have to say. Do you have anything (else/more) to <it>add</it>? = Is there anything (else/more) you would like to <it>add</it>?</vi> <vi>“They all went to the bar,” he said. “But I didn't go with them,” he quickly <it>added</it>.</vi> <vi>He was quick to <it>add</it> that he didn't go with them. = He <phrase>hastened to add</phrase> that he didn't go with them.</vi> <vi>It was a long project and, <phrase>I might add</phrase>, an expensive one.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>add insult to injury</dre> <dx>see <dxt>insult</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>add on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>add (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>add on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to put (something) with another thing or group of things <vi>We're going to <it>add on</it> a new garage.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We're <it>adding</it> a new garage <it>on to</it> our house.</vi> <vi>They're <it>adding</it> $200 <it>on to</it> what we already have to pay.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <it>add on to</it> is also written as <it>add onto</it>. <vi>We're <it>adding</it> a new garage <it>onto</it> our house.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>add to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>add to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (something) larger, better, or greater <vi>He bought another rare coin to <it>add to</it> his collection.</vi> <vi>Her research has greatly <it>added to</it> our knowledge of the subject.</vi> <vi>She's been able to <it>add to</it> her savings [=to save more money] this year.</vi> <vi>This movie will <it>add to</it> his fame. [=it will make him more famous]</vi> <vi>The loud music <it>added to</it> the confusion. [=it made the confusion greater]</vi> <vi>We hope this <it>adds to</it> your enjoyment of the play.</vi> <vi>The funny characters really <it>add to</it> the story. [=they make the story better]</vi> <snote>Phrases like <phrase>add to this/that</phrase> and <phrase>added to this/that</phrase> are often used informally to introduce a statement about something that makes a thing or situation better, worse, more important, etc. <vi>We were given little time to finish. <it>Add to this</it> the fact that nobody helped us, and you can understand why we were angry.</vi> <vi>We were short of money. <it>Added to that</it>, we were lost!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>add up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to be added together and equal the expected or correct total <un>usually used in negative constructions <vi>The numbers just don't <it>add up</it>. [=they don't equal the expected total]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make sense :to seem to be logical or true <vi>They must be lying; their story just doesn't <it>add up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to slowly increase and become a large number or amount <vi>A cup of coffee may only cost a dollar, but those dollars <it>add up</it> quickly.</vi> <vi>I'm saving a little money each month. Eventually it'll <it>add up</it>.</vi> <vi>The hours that I spend traveling to work really <it>add up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>add (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>add up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to put together or count (the number or amount of something) to find the total <vi>Start by <it>adding up</it> how much money you have, and then <it>add up</it> your costs.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>add up</it> all of the money we saved.</vi> <vi>When you <it>add</it> it all <it>up</it>, he's spent over half of his life in jail.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>add up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a number) as a total <vi>The amount of money she spends on coffee <it>adds up to</it> $2.75 a day.</vi> <vi>That <it>adds up to</it> more than a thousand dollars a year.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (a specified result) <vi>These plans should <it>add up to</it> a very exciting vacation.</vi> <vi>With these three bands playing together, it all <it>adds up to</it> one of the year's best rock concerts.</vi> <vi>All of the team's hard work didn't <it>add up to</it> a win.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>added</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>The historical details provide <it>added</it> [=<it>additional</it>] depth/richness/weight to his story.</vi> <vi><it>added</it> value</vi> <vi>an <it>added</it> attraction/advantage</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="ADD"> <hw>ADD</hw> <fl>abbreviation</fl> <def><dt>attention deficit disorder</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="add-on"> <hw>add–on</hw> <pr>ˈædˌɑ:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>add–ons</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an extra part or device that can be added to something else to improve it <vi>He has all the latest <it>add-ons</it> for his computer.</vi> <vi>I knew the base price for the car, but with the <it>add-ons</it> I wanted, the final price was quite a bit higher.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>add-on</it> components</vi> <vi><it>add-on</it> equipment</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hasten"> <hw>has*ten</hw> <sound><wav>hasten01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈheɪsn̩</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>has*tens</if></in> <in><if>has*tened</if></in> <in><if>has*ten*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen more quickly <vi>A factory was built, <it>hastening</it> [=<it>accelerating</it>] the town's growth.</vi> <vi>His death was <it>hastened</it> by alcohol abuse.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to move or act quickly <vi>When she heard the baby crying, she <it>hastened</it> [=<it>hurried</it>] up the stairs.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>hasten to add/say/explain (etc.)</dre> <def><dt>:to immediately say something in order to prevent confusion or misunderstanding <vi>The company announced that the initial tests look promising, but they <it>hastened to add</it> that there is still much more testing to be done.</vi> <vi>Let me <it>hasten to point out</it> that these changes will not affect our existing clients.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="injury"> <hw highlight="yes">in*ju*ry</hw> <sound><wav>injury01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪnʤəri</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>in*ju*ries</if></in> <def><dt>:harm or damage :an act or event that causes someone or something to no longer be fully healthy or in good condition <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Hikers need to take sensible precautions to prevent <it>injury</it>.</vi> <vi>She's concerned about the risk of <it>injury</it> to her reputation.</vi> <vi>The team has been weakened by illness and <it>injury</it>.</vi> <vi>Careless use of these tools can cause serious bodily <it>injury</it>.</vi> <vi>She survived the accident without <it>injury</it>.</vi> <vi>an athlete who is <phrase>injury-prone</phrase> [=an athlete who is frequently injured]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She fell and suffered an <it>injury</it> to her arm.</vi> <vi>His athletic career has been slowed by <it>injuries</it>.</vi> <vi>minor/serious/severe <it>injuries</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>add insult to injury</dre> <dx>see <dxt>insult</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do yourself an injury</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to hurt yourself :to become injured because of your own actions <vi>If you keep on lifting those heavy weights, you'll <it>do yourself an injury</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="insult[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">in*sult</hw> <sound><wav>insult03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪnˌsʌlt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>in*sults</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a rude or offensive act or statement :something that insults someone <vi>The fans hurled/shouted <it>insults</it> at the referee as he walked off the field after the game.</vi> <vi>Their decision to cancel the project was an <it>insult</it> to all my hard work.</vi> <vi>They got into a fight over a minor <it>insult</it>.</vi> <vi>We could hear them angrily trading/exchanging <it>insults</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>The assignment was an <it>insult</it> to our intelligence. [=the assignment was too simple]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>add insult to injury</dre> <def><dt>:to do or say something that makes a bad situation even worse for someone <vi>Most people were forced to work longer hours each week, and to <it>add insult to injury</it>, the company decided not to give pay raises.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
