<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="admission"> <hw highlight="yes">ad*mis*sion</hw> <sound><wav>admiss03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ədˈmɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*mis*sions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of admitting or allowing something <vi>the <it>admission</it> of evidence in a court of law</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a statement or action by which someone admits a weakness, fault, etc. <vi>His statement was interpreted as an <it>admission</it> of failure/weakness.</vi> <vi>an <it>admission</it> of error/defeat</vi> <vi>her <it>admission</it> of guilt = her <it>admission</it> that she was guilty</vi> <vi><phrase>By his own admission</phrase>, he is a terrible cook. [=he admits that he is a terrible cook]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the right or permission to enter a place <vi>He tried to get into the theater but was refused <it>admission</it>. [=he was not allowed to enter]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the right or permission to join a club, group, etc. <vi>They opposed the <it>admission</it> of women into/to the club.</vi> <vi>She was unable to gain <it>admission</it> into/to the club. = She was denied <it>admission</it> into/to the club.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the act or process of accepting a patient in a hospital for treatment <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He died several hours after <it>admission</it> to the hospital. [=after being admitted to the hospital]</vi> <vi>Her injuries were serious enough to require hospital <it>admission</it>.</vi> <vi>The patient was unconscious on (his) <it>admission</it> to the hospital. [=when he was admitted to the hospital]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a large number of hospital <it>admissions</it></vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:the act or process of accepting someone as a student at a school <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The school's standards of <it>admission</it> are high.</vi> <vi>He submitted an application for <it>admission</it> to the school.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>college/university <it>admissions</it></vi> <vi>The school has a policy of <phrase>open admissions</phrase>. [=a policy of accepting all students who want to go to the school]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>an <it>admission(s)</it> exam</vi> <vi>an <phrase>admissions officer</phrase> [=an official at a school who is in charge of admitting students]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:the cost of entering a theater, sports stadium, museum, etc. <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi><it>Admission</it> (to the museum) is free on Tuesdays.</vi> <vi>A movie will be shown in the auditorium tomorrow night. <it>Admission</it>: $5 for adults, $2 for children.</vi> <vi>The museum offers reduced <it>admission</it> for young children.</vi> <vi>Her performance by itself was <phrase>worth the price of admission</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Reduced <it>admissions</it> are available for young children.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>an <it>admission</it> fee/charge</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="general admission"> <hw>general admission</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a situation in which a customer pays a fee to get into an event (such as a concert or baseball game) but is not assigned to a specific seat <vi>Reserved seating is $20; <it>general admission</it> is $10.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="open admission"> <hw>open admission</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>open enrollment</sx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
