<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="afraid"> <hw highlight="yes">afraid</hw> <sound><wav>afraid01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈfreɪd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>more afraid; most afraid</sgram> <dt>:feeling fear: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:worried that something will cause pain or injury <vi>Don't be <it>afraid</it> [=<it>frightened, scared</it>]—the dog won't hurt you.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>I don't like tall buildings because I'm <it>afraid of</it> heights. [=of being high up in the air]</vi> <vi>He's <it>afraid of</it> snakes.</vi> <vi>All the kids at school were <it>afraid of</it> him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:nervous about doing something <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She's <it>afraid of</it> failing/failure.</vi> <vi>He wasn't <it>afraid of</it> saying what he thought.</vi> <vi>Don't be <it>afraid of</it> [=don't worry about] what everyone else thinks.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>He wasn't <it>afraid to say</it> what he thought.</vi> <vi>I wanted to visit her, but I was <it>afraid to ask</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't be <it>afraid to take</it> risks.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:nervous or worried that something might happen <vi>She's <it>afraid</it> (that) she might fail.</vi> <vi>We were all <it>afraid</it> (that) she wouldn't live.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>afraid</it> (that) everyone will laugh at me.</vi> <vi>I was <it>afraid</it> (that) you would say “no.”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in the phrase <phrase>I'm afraid</phrase> as a polite way of showing that you are sorry about a disappointing, negative, or critical statement <vi>I'm sorry, but <it>I'm afraid</it> (that) I won't be able to come to your party.</vi> <vi>She tries hard, but <it>I'm afraid</it> that her work just isn't very good.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>afraid</it> that I still don't understand the problem.</vi> <vi>This is only the beginning of the battle, <it>I'm afraid</it>.</vi> <vi>Most of us worked very hard, but she, <phrase>I'm afraid to say</phrase> [=<it>I'm sorry to say</it>; <it>I regret to say</it>], did no work at all.</vi> <vi>“Is it raining?” “<phrase>I'm afraid so</phrase>.” = “<it>I'm afraid</it> it is.” [=yes, it is]</vi> <vi>“Can you come to our party?” “<phrase>I'm afraid not</phrase>.” = “<it>I'm afraid</it> I can't.” [=no, I can't come]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>not</it> to say that someone is willing to do something</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She's <it>not afraid of</it> hard work. = She's <it>not afraid of</it> working hard. [=she's willing to work hard; she works hard]</vi> <vi>You <it>can't be afraid of</it> getting dirty in this job. [=you have to be willing to get dirty in this job]</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She's <it>not afraid to work</it> hard.</vi> <vi>He's <it>not afraid to admit</it> his mistakes.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>afraid for</dre> <def><dt>:feeling fear or worry about (something or someone) <vi>I'm <it>afraid for</it> the children.</vi> <vi>They were <it>afraid for</it> their lives. [=they feared for their lives; they were afraid that they might die]</vi> <vi>He's <it>afraid for</it> his job. [=he's worried that he might lose his job]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
