<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="again"> <hw highlight="yes">again</hw> <sound><wav>again001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈgɛn</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:for another time :one more time <vi>Please, come see us <it>again</it>.</vi> <vi>Spring is beginning <it>again</it>.</vi> <vi>It was nice to see my friends <it>again</it>.</vi> <vi>She wants to prove that she can do it <it>again</it>.</vi> <vi>Things are back to normal <it>again</it>.</vi> <vi>I will never be so foolish <it>again</it>. = <phrase>Never again</phrase> will I be so foolish.</vi> <vi>When we heard the news, we all said, “Oh no! <phrase>Not again</phrase>!”</vi> <vi>She demonstrated <phrase>yet again</phrase> her remarkable artistic talents.</vi> <vi>It'll just be the same thing <phrase>all over again</phrase>.</vi> <vi>I told him <phrase>over and over again</phrase> to be careful. = I told him <phrase>again and again</phrase> to be careful. [=I told him many times to be careful]</vi> <vi>She returned to the bookstore <it>again and again</it>. [=repeatedly, many times]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to a previous position or place <vi>We flew from Boston to Chicago and back <it>again</it>. [=back to Boston]</vi> <vi>When he stood up, he got so dizzy that he had to sit down <it>again</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a thought or possibility that differs from a preceding one <vi>He might go, and <it>again</it> he might not.</vi></un> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>then again</phrase> <vi>He might go, and <it>then again</it>, he might not.</vi> <vi><it>Then again</it>, perhaps they were right.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that repeats and stresses something previously said <vi><it>Again</it>, this is a serious problem.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to ask someone to repeat something because you did not hear or understand it clearly <vi>What was your name <it>again</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like (<it>chiefly US</it>) <phrase>half again as much</phrase> and (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <phrase>half as much again</phrase> to compare two amounts <vi>My ticket costs <it>half again as much</it> as your ticket. [=(for example) my ticket costs $15 and your ticket costs $10]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>(every) now and again</dre> <dx>see <dxt>every</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>now and again</dre> <dx>see <dxt>now</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>once again</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>time and again</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="born-again"> <hw>born–again</hw> <sound><wav>borna01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌboɚnəˈgɛn</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a new or stronger belief in the Christian religion <vi>The <it>born-again</it> actor often talks about his faith during interviews.</vi> <vi>She's <it>born-again</it> now.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>born-again Christian</phrase></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:newly interested in and enthusiastic about something and eager to make other people think the way you do <vi>a <it>born-again</it> fitness buff</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="on-again, off-again"> <hw>on–again, off–again</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:happening or existing at some times and not at other times <vi><it>on-again, off-again</it> fads</vi> <vi>She has been his <it>on-again, off-again</it> girlfriend for the past several years. [=she has been his girlfriend at certain times and not been his girlfriend at other times during the past several years]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="anon"> <hw>anon</hw> <sound><wav>anon0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈnɑ:n</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>literary + humorous</sl> <dt>:in a short time :<sx>soon</sx> <vi>I will answer his letter <it>anon</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>ever and anon</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ever</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="come[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">come</hw> <sound><wav>come0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>comes</if></in> <in><if>came</if> <sound><wav>come0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeɪm</pr></in> <in><if>come</if></in> <in><if>com*ing</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move toward someone or something <vi>Please <it>come</it> here for a minute. I want to show you something.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>come</it> near me.</vi> <vi>She <it>came</it> quietly into the room.</vi> <vi>He <it>came</it> home late again last night.</vi> <vi>The dog began to growl as we <it>came</it> closer.</vi> <vi>Here he <it>comes</it>. [=he is approaching us]</vi> <vi>The captain of the ship invited us to <it>come</it> aboard.</vi> <vi>The dog <phrase>came running</phrase> when she called it. [=the dog ran to her when she called it]</vi> <vi>If you need me I'll <it>come running</it>. [=I'll come to you very quickly]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place <vi>People <it>come</it> from all over the country to see him.</vi> <vi>Some people <it>came</it> by car while others <it>came</it> by plane.</vi> <vi>Why don't you <it>come</it> and/to stay with us for a while?</vi> <vi>My parents are <it>coming</it> for a visit. = My parents are <it>coming</it> to visit.</vi> <vi>I hope you'll <it>come</it> (to/and) visit us soon.</vi> <vi>About a hundred people are <it>coming</it> to the wedding.</vi> <vi>People <it>come</it> many miles to visit the shrine.</vi> <vi>They <it>came</it> very far [=they traveled a long way] to see you.</vi> <vi>My brother is <phrase>coming down</phrase> [=traveling south] to visit me this week, and I'll be going up to visit him next month.</vi> <vi>She lives uptown and rarely <it>comes down</it> to this part of the city.</vi> <vi>My parents are <phrase>coming up</phrase> [=traveling north] to visit me this weekend.</vi> <vi>She lives downtown and rarely <it>comes up</it> to this part of the city.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We've <it>come</it> so far [=we've made so much progress]; we can't stop now.</vi> <vi>It's remarkable to think of how far she's <it>come</it> since she started her career.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>come a long way <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of mail</ssl> <dt>:to be delivered to a place <vi>Did/has the mail <it>come</it> yet?</vi> <vi>The mail <it>comes</it> every day at four o'clock.</vi> <vi>A letter <it>came</it> for you.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to have or form an opinion, attitude, etc., after time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I didn't like him at first, but I eventually <it>came to regard</it> him as a friend.</vi> <vi>He has <it>come to be</it> considered one of the leading candidates for the job.</vi> <vi>They <it>came to believe</it> that no one would help them.</vi> <vi>She <it>came to be known</it> [=she became known] as the world's greatest dancer.</vi> <vi>The food wasn't as good as I've <it>come to expect</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I don't know how he <it>came to acquire</it> the property. [=I don't know how he acquired the property]</vi> <vi>How did you <it>come to have</it> such an idea? [=what caused you to have such an idea?]</vi> <vi>How did she <it>come to be</it> there? [=why was she there?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to reach a specified level, part, etc. <vi>Her dress <it>came</it> (down) to her ankles.</vi> <vi>The water <it>came</it> almost up to the window.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to reach a specified state or condition <vi>My shoe <it>came</it> untied.</vi> <vi>The screw <it>came</it> loose.</vi> <vi>Things will <it>come</it> [=<it>become</it>] clear if we are patient.</vi> <vi>The party suddenly <phrase>came alive</phrase>. [=the party suddenly became lively]</vi> <vi>The rent is <phrase>coming due</phrase> next week. [=the rent will be due next week]</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:to happen or occur <vi>These changes couldn't have <it>come</it> at a better time.</vi> <vi>I promise that no harm will <it>come</it> to you. [=I promise that you will not be harmed]</vi> <vi>Her success <it>came</it> at a high price. [=she paid a high price for her success]</vi> <vi>It's important for children to learn about the people and things that <it>came</it> before us.</vi> <vi>Success didn't <phrase>come easy</phrase> for her. [=she did not achieve success easily]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive or happen after time has passed <vi>The days will be longer when spring <it>comes</it>. = <it>Come</it> spring the days will be longer.</vi> <vi>She'll be back in school <it>come</it> September. = She'll be back in school when September <it>comes</it>.</vi> <vi>This war will end eventually, and when that day <it>comes</it>, we will all be profoundly thankful.</vi> <vi>The time has <it>come</it> to stop hesitating and make a decision.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <ssl>of a product that is being sold</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be available <vi>This model <it>comes</it> in several sizes. [=this model can be bought in several sizes]</vi> <vi>a product that <it>comes</it> in a variety of colors and shapes</vi> <vi>when the product first <phrase>came on the market</phrase> [=when the product was first being sold]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have something as a feature, quality, ability, etc. <vi>The car <it>comes</it> (equipped/complete) with air-conditioning.</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <dt>:to have a specified position or place in a series <vi>I don't know which <it>came</it> first.</vi> <vi>The letter D <it>comes</it> after C and before E.</vi> <vi>He cares about his job, but his family <phrase>comes first</phrase>. [=his family is more important than his job]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to end a race or competition in a specified position <vi>Joan won the race and her sister <it>came</it> [=<it>finished, came in</it>] second.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a mild way to urge someone to do something or to become less upset, angry, etc. <vi><it>Come</it>, it's not that bad. I'm sure you'll feel better soon.</vi> <vi><phrase>Come now</phrase>, there's no reason to be so upset.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a mild way to show that you do not approve of or agree with what someone has said <vi><phrase>Come, come</phrase>. You know as well as I do that he never said that.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <dt>:to experience an orgasm</dt></def> <dro><dre>as…as they come</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe someone or something as very good, bad, etc. <vi>Their daughter is <it>as clever as they come</it>. [=their daughter is very clever]</vi> <vi>The movie was <it>as boring as they come</it>. [=the movie was extremely boring]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>Their meeting <it>came about</it> by accident/chance.</vi> <vi>I don't know how it <it>came about</it> that she overheard our conversation.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to turn to a different direction <vi>The captain gave the order to <it>come about</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come a cropper</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cropper</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to seem to have a particular quality or character :to make a particular impression <vi>How did he <it>come across</it>? [=what kind of impression did he make?]</vi> <un>usually + <it>as</it> <vi>He <it>comes across as</it> (being) a good speaker. [=he seems to be a good speaker; people think that he is a good speaker when they hear him talk]</vi> <vi>He <it>came across as</it> a nice guy. [=he seemed to be a nice guy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be expressed to someone <vi>She says she was trying to be helpful, but that's not what <it>came across</it> when I talked to her. [=I did not get the feeling that she was trying to be helpful when I talked to her]</vi> <vi>Her enthusiasm really <it>came across</it> [=<it>came through</it>] when she talked about her job. [=we could see that she was really enthusiastic when she talked about her job]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>come across (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to meet or find (something or someone) by chance <vi>Researchers have <it>come across</it> important new evidence.</vi> <vi>As I was walking through the town, I <it>came across</it> a group of street performers.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to pay money that someone wants or demands <vi>They threatened to hurt him if he doesn't <it>come across</it> (with the money).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come adrift</dre> <dx>see <dxt>adrift</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to chase (someone) :to try to find or capture (someone you want to hurt or punish) <vi>They're worried that the government might be <it>coming after</it> them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come again</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to ask someone to repeat something that was not heard or understood clearly <vi>“Her name is Hermione.” “<it>Come again</it>? I didn't quite hear you.” “I said her name is Hermione.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go somewhere with someone <vi>They asked me to <it>come along</it> (with them) on the trip. [=they asked me to go with them on the trip]</vi> <vi>I'm going to the museum tomorrow. Would you like to <it>come along</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress :to get better or to proceed in a desired way <vi>The project started slowly, but now the work is <it>coming along</it>.</vi> :to proceed in a specified way <vi>The work is <it>coming along</it> well.</vi> <vi>The investigation is <it>coming along</it> slowly, and there's still a lot more work to be done.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to happen or appear as someone or something that might be used, chosen, etc. <vi>She says she won't just marry the first man that <it>comes along</it>.</vi> <vi>An opportunity like this doesn't <it>come along</it> [=<it>occur</it>] too often.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come a long way</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a much higher level of success :to become very successful <vi>He's <it>come a long way</it> from his days as a young reporter. Now he's one of the country's most respected journalists.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make a great amount of progress <vi>Medicine has <it>come a long way</it> in recent years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about time that has passed <vi>More than a hundred years have <it>come and gone</it> since the day of that famous battle.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about people who appear and then leave as time passes <vi>She's seen a lot of employees <it>come and go</it> during her time in the company.</vi> <vi>Politicians <it>come and go</it>. They all seem pretty much the same to me.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come apart</dre> <def><dt>:to break into parts or pieces <vi>an old house that is <phrase>coming apart at the seams</phrase> [=an old house that is in very bad condition]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>a coalition that is <it>coming apart</it></vi> <vi>Their marriage is <it>coming apart at the seams</it>. [=their marriage is failing]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>come round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to accept and support something (such as an idea) after opposing it :to stop opposing or disagreeing with something or someone <vi>She still says she won't support us, but she'll <it>come around</it> eventually. [=she'll support us eventually]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She'll <it>come around to</it> our side eventually.</vi> <vi>People are starting to <it>come around to</it> the idea.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become conscious <vi>He took a bad fall and knocked himself out. When he <it>came around</it> [=<it>woke up</it>, <it>came to</it>], he didn't remember what had happened.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go to visit someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come around</it> [=<it>come over</it>] (to my house) after work today?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to occur in the usual way as time passes <vi>I always feel a little sad when the end of the school year <it>comes around</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>what goes around comes around</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to turn to a different direction <vi>The sailboat <it>came around</it> [=<it>came about</it>] and began to head east.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come as</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe the effect that something has when people first learn about it <vi>Their decision <it>came as</it> a surprise (to me). [=their decision was a surprise to me]</vi> <vi>It should <it>come as</it> no surprise that many people oppose the plan.</vi> <vi>It <it>came as</it> a shock to me [=I was shocked] to see how old he looks now.</vi> <vi>The news of her recovery <it>came as</it> a great relief to all of us.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move toward (someone) in a threatening or aggressive way <vi>They kept <it>coming at</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be directed at or toward (someone) <vi>The questions kept <it>coming at</it> him so quickly that he didn't know how to respond to them.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to deal with or think about (something) <vi>We need to <it>come at</it> [=<it>approach</it>] these problems from a different angle.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come away from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come away from (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move away from (an area, place, etc.) <vi>The guard told him to <it>come away from</it> the door.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Most readers <it>come away from</it> the book feeling reassured. [=most readers feel reassured when they finish the book]</vi> <vi>It was a difficult experience, but she <it>came away from</it> it a stronger and more confident person.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I hope you'll <it>come back</it> and see us again soon.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a decision that may <phrase>come back to haunt us</phrase> [=a decision that may cause problems for us in the future]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a former good condition :to become strong, successful, or effective again after a time of weakness, failure, etc. <vi>It can be difficult for an athlete to <it>come back</it> [=<it>recover</it>] from an injury like this.</vi> <vi>a species that was nearly extinct but that has been <it>coming back</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become popular or fashionable again <vi>Short skirts were out of fashion for many years, but now they're <it>coming back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be successful in a game, sport, etc., after being behind <vi>The team was trailing after the first half, but they <it>came back</it> and won in the second half.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to return to someone's memory <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>I had forgotten a lot of what I learned about music, but it's all <it>coming back to</it> me now. [=I am beginning to remember it now]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to make a reply or response <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>When questioned about his involvement, he <it>came back with</it> an angry denial.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>comeback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come between</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come between (people or groups)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause disagreement between (people or groups) <vi>We shouldn't let these problems <it>come between</it> us.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a visit to someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come by</it> [=<it>come over</it>] for a while after dinner?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come by (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or acquire (something) <vi>I asked him how he <it>came by</it> the money, but he wouldn't tell me.</vi> <vi>A good job is <phrase>hard to come by</phrase>. [=it's hard to get a good job]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come cheap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cheap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come clean</dre> <dx>see <dxt>clean</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come close</dre> <dx>see <dxt>close</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move or fall downward <vi>The crowd erupted in applause as the curtain <it>came down</it>.</vi> <vi>One of the tree's branches <it>came down</it> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of rain, snow, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to fall from the sky <vi>She stood at the window, watching the rain <it>come down</it>.</vi> <vi>The rain was <it>coming down</it> in sheets. [=it was raining very heavily]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to a lower level <vi>Stock prices have continued to <it>come down</it> [=<it>fall</it>] this week. = Stocks have continued to <it>come down</it> in price this week.</vi> <vi>It's sad to see how he has <phrase>come down in the world</phrase>. [=how he has fallen to a lower position or status after being wealthy, successful, etc.]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>comedown</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to decide or say in an official or public way that you support or oppose someone or something <vi>The committee <phrase>came down in favor of</phrase> the proposal. = The committee <phrase>came down on the side of</phrase> the proposal. [=the committee approved the proposal]</vi> <vi>Some of his former supporters have <phrase>come down against</phrase> him.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>An announcement or decision that <phrase>comes down</phrase> is an announcement or decision from someone who has power or authority. <vi>Word <it>came down</it> that the strike was over.</vi> <vi>The decision <it>came down</it> in his favor.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>Something that <phrase>comes down from</phrase> the past is something that has existed for a very long time. <vi>This is a story that has <it>come down</it> from ancient times.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop feeling the effect of an illegal drug :to stop being high on a drug <vi>an addict who is <it>coming down</it> from heroin</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to criticize or punish (someone) <vi>The governor has promised to <phrase>come down hard on</phrase> corrupt officials. [=to severely punish corrupt officials]</vi> <vi>Her boss <it>came down on</it> her pretty hard when she didn't finish the report on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come down on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a strong effort to stop or oppose (something) <vi>The governor has promised to <it>come down hard on</it> corruption.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (something) as the most important part <vi>People talk about various reasons for the company's failure, but it all <it>comes down to</it> one thing: a lack of leadership.</vi> <vi>The election is going to <it>come down to</it> which candidate seems most trustworthy to the voters. [=the candidate who seems most trustworthy will win the election]</vi> <vi>It's nice to be rich, but <phrase>when you come (right) down to it</phrase>, it's more important to be healthy and happy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>She <it>came down with</it> [=<it>contracted</it>] measles.</vi> <vi>I think I may be <it>coming down with</it> [=<it>getting, catching</it>] a cold.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to say openly or publicly that you are the person who should get something or who can do something <vi>No one has yet <it>come forward</it> to claim the reward.</vi> <vi>Several people <it>came forward</it> to offer their assistance.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a specified origin or source) <vi>Wine <it>comes from</it> grapes. [=wine is made from grapes]</vi> <vi>English words <it>come from</it> a wide variety of sources.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a person's family <vi>She <it>comes from</it> a wealthy family. [=her family is wealthy]</vi> <vi>He <it>comes from</it> a long line of entertainers. [=the people in his family have been entertainers for many years]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be the result of (something) <vi>I'm not surprised that you don't feel well. That's what <it>comes from</it> not eating the right kinds of food.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be from (a place): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a person</ssl> <dt>:to have been born or raised in (a place) <vi>She <it>comes</it> (originally) <it>from</it> a small southern town.</vi> :to live in (a place) <vi>The people who attend the convention <it>come from</it> countries all around the world.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>(<it>informal</it>) I understand where you're <it>coming from</it>. [=I understand why you feel or think the way you do; I understand your point of view]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a thing</ssl> <dt>:to be produced in (a place) <vi>Where did this wine <it>come from</it>? [=where is this wine from?]</vi> <vi>There was a bad smell <it>coming from</it> the basement.</vi> <vi>A sob <it>came from</it> her throat. [=she sobbed]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be said or told by (someone) <vi>This information <it>comes from</it> a person I trust.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Those comments are pretty surprising, <phrase>coming from you</phrase>. [=it is surprising that you would make those comments]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come full circle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>full circle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come hell or high water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come home to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>home</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>Welcome. Please <it>come in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The store will have some exciting new products <it>coming in</it> next week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be received <vi>The election results should start <it>coming in</it> soon. [=we should start receiving/getting the election results soon]</vi> <vi>The broadcast was <it>coming in</it> loud and clear. [=we could hear the broadcast very clearly]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to end a race or competition in a specified position <vi>Joan won the race and her sister <it>came in</it> [=<it>finished</it>] second.</vi> <vi>He <it>came in</it> first/last.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to have a particular role or function <vi>We're going to need someone to help with the cooking, and <phrase>that's where you come in</phrase>. [=your job will be to help us with the cooking]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>Something that <phrase>comes in handy</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>comes in useful/helpful</phrase> turns out to be useful when it is needed. <vi>A pocketknife can <it>come in handy</it>.</vi> <vi>A little extra money would <it>come in useful</it> right now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in/into bloom</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>come into flower</va></vr> <def><sl>of a plant</sl> <dt>:to begin to produce flowers :to start to bloom <vi>in early spring, when the forsythias are <it>coming into bloom</it></vi> <vi>The lilacs have begun to <it>come into flower</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or be given (something unpleasant, such as criticism) :to be subjected to (something) <vi>The government's policies are <it>coming in for</it> increasing criticism. [=more people are beginning to criticize the government's policies]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in from the cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come in on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>He says he'd like to <it>come in</it> (with us) <it>on</it> the deal.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>Everyone watched her as she <it>came into</it> the room.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to get (something) as a possession <vi>He <it>came into</it> a fortune when he inherited his father's estate.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be involved in (something) <vi>Deciding who to hire should be a business decision. You shouldn't allow personal feelings to <it>come into</it> it. [=you shouldn't allow personal feelings to affect your decision]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come into effect</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come into your own</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to have the kind of success that you are capable of having :to become very skillful, successful, etc. <vi>She has really started to <it>come into her own</it> recently.</vi> <vi>The company was struggling for many months, but now it really seems to be <it>coming into its own</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in/into view/sight</dre> <def><dt>:to appear :to begin to be seen <vi>Another ship suddenly <it>came into view</it>.</vi> <vi>As we turned the corner, the distant mountains <it>came in sight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come naturally</dre> <dx>see <dxt>naturally</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be the result of (something) <vi>the excitement that <it>comes of</it> meeting people who share your interests</vi> <vi>They had discussions about possible new products, but <phrase>nothing came of it</phrase>. [=no new products resulted from their discussions]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come of age</dre> <dx>see <dxt>age</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>come off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop being attached to something <vi>When I tried to pick up the suitcase, the handle <it>came off</it>. = The handle <it>came off</it> the suitcase.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to produce a desired result :to succeed <vi>His plans to start his own business never <it>came off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>The meeting <it>came off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to do or perform well or badly <vi>She <it>came off</it> well in the contest.</vi> <vi>He <it>came off</it> badly/poorly in the debate.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to seem to have a specified quality or character <un>usually + <it>as</it> <vi>He's really just shy, but he <it>comes off as</it> a little arrogant. [=he seems a little arrogant]</vi> <vi>He <it>came off as</it> a stuffy old man.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>come off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to have recently completed or recovered from (something) <vi>a company that is <it>coming off</it> a very successful year</vi> <vi>an athlete who is <it>coming off</it> a serious injury</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have recently stopped using (an illegal drug) <vi>an addict who is <it>coming off</it> heroin</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>where do you come off?</phrase> to express anger or annoyance at what someone has said or done <vi><it>Where do you come off</it> talking to me like that? [=you have no right to talk to me like that; how dare you talk to me like that?]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>don't know where he comes off</phrase> making those kinds of accusations. [=he has no right to make those kinds of accusations]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come off it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop talking or acting in a foolish way <un>usually used as an interjection <vi>“I could be a pro golfer if I really tried.” “Oh, <it>come off it</it>! You're not even close to being that good!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to happen or progress as time passes <vi>Darkness <it>came on</it> rapidly/gradually [=it rapidly/gradually became dark] as the sun went down.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to happen <vi>Rain <it>came on</it> toward noon. [=it began to rain when it was almost noon]</vi> <vi>I feel a headache <it>coming on</it>.</vi> <vi>It looks like it might be <phrase>coming on to rain</phrase>. [=it looks like it might start to rain soon]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <ssl>of an electrical machine, light, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>came on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a TV or radio program</ssl> <dt>:to start <vi>That program you like is <it>coming on</it> in a few minutes.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to ask or urge someone to do something <vi>“I don't feel like going out tonight.” “Oh, <it>come on</it>! It'll do you good to get out of the house for a while.”</vi> <vi>“I don't think I can go any further.” “<it>Come on</it>! You can do it if you keep trying!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to tell someone to hurry or to go faster <vi><it>Come on</it>, let's go.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to express surprise, disbelief, etc. <vi>“I think she could win the election.” “<it>Come on</it>! She doesn't have a chance!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to have or seem to have a certain quality or nature <vi>He <it>comes on</it> [=<it>comes across</it>] as a conservative.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on strong</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be very forceful or too forceful in talking to someone or dealing with someone <vi>She didn't like him because she felt that he <it>came on</it> too <it>strong</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become stronger or more successful in a continuing contest, race, etc. <vi>The team was playing poorly in the early part of the season, but it has been <it>coming on strong</it> lately.</vi> <vi>a political candidate who has been <it>coming on strong</it> in the polls as the day of election draws closer</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to show sexual interest in (someone) :to try to start a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She complained that her boss has been <it>coming on to</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to start to talk about or deal with (something) <vi>We'll <it>come on to</it> [=<it>come to, get to</it>] that question later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become available :to begin to be produced or sold <vi>A new magazine is <it>coming out</it> next week.</vi> <vi>The book/movie <it>comes out</it> next month.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become obvious :to be clearly shown <vi>His pride <it>came out</it> in his refusal to accept help. [=his refusal to accept help showed his pride]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>The truth finally <it>came out</it>. [=people finally learned the truth]</vi> <vi>It <it>came out</it> that he had known about these problems all along, but he hadn't said anything.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to say something openly <vi>Why don't you just <it>come out</it> and say what you really think?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to say publicly that you support or oppose someone or something <vi>She <phrase>came out in favor of</phrase> the proposal.</vi> <vi>Some of his former supporters have <phrase>come out against</phrase> him.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to say openly that you are a homosexual <vi>Many gay entertainers have been reluctant to <it>come out</it>.</vi> <vi>Last year she <it>came out</it> (as a lesbian) to her parents. [=she told her parents that she is a lesbian]</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:to appear after being hidden <vi>The rain stopped and the sun/moon/stars <it>came out</it> as the clouds cleared away.</vi> :to appear in the open <vi>animals that only <it>come out</it> at night</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a flower</ssl> <dt>:to open :to blossom <vi>in the spring, when the flowers are beginning to <it>come out</it> (in bloom)</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:to end or finish in a specified way <vi>How did the game <it>come out</it>? [=<it>turn out</it>] [=who won the game?]</vi> <vi>Everything <it>came out</it> [=<it>ended up, turned out</it>] all right.</vi> <vi>She expects to <it>come out</it> ahead in the end.</vi> <vi>He's confident that he'll <it>come out</it> a winner.</vi> <vi>He's confident that he'll <phrase>come out on top</phrase> [=that he'll win] when all the votes have been counted.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a photograph</ssl> <dt>:to produce a good picture <vi>Those pictures I took at the game yesterday didn't <it>come out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the quality that something has when it is finished <vi>The picture <it>came out</it> blurry.</vi> <vi>The brownies <it>came out</it> a little too dry.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be said, expressed, or understood in a particular way <vi>That's not what I meant to say. It didn't <it>come out</it> right.</vi> <vi>He was trying to make a joke, but it <it>came out</it> wrong.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to result from (something) <vi>It's hard to see how anything good can <it>come out of</it> this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go through the experience of (something) <vi>I was lucky to <it>come out of</it> [=<it>come through</it>] the accident alive.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>come out of nowhere</phrase> is to be very surprising and unexpected or to become successful, popular, etc., in a very sudden and surprising way. <vi>That question <it>came out of nowhere</it>.</vi> <vi>a company that has <it>come out of nowhere</it> to become one of the leaders in the industry</vi></snote> <dx>see also <tag>come out of left field</tag> at <dxt>left field</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come out with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say or express (something, such as an idea) <vi>She <it>came out with</it> a new proposal.</vi> <vi>He's always saying ridiculous things. You never know what he'll <it>come out with</it> next.</vi> <vi>Why don't you just <it>come out with</it> it and say what you really think?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to publish or produce (something that will be sold to the public) <vi>a publisher that is <it>coming out with</it> a new series of children's books</vi> <vi>a car company that is <it>coming out with</it> several new models next year</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a social visit to someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come over</it> [=<it>come around</it>] (to my place) after work?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change from one side to the other in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>I've been trying to persuade her to <it>come over to</it> our side, but I haven't convinced her yet.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>become</sx> <vi>He suddenly <it>came over</it> all bashful. [=he suddenly became very bashful]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>come over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect (someone) in a sudden and strong way <vi>A sudden feeling of dread <it>came over</it> me. [=I felt a sudden feeling of dread]</vi> <vi>He's behaving so strangely. I don't know what's <it>come over</it> him lately. [=I don't know what has caused him to behave so strangely]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to succeed in doing something :to do what is needed or expected <vi>an athlete who is known for <it>coming through</it> in the clutch</vi> <vi>“I managed to get the tickets.” “Great! I knew you'd <it>come through</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to be received and understood <vi>The message <it>came through</it> loud and clear.</vi> <vi>The signal wasn't <it>coming through</it>. [=we weren't receiving the signal]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be expressed to someone <vi>Her enthusiasm really <it>came through</it> [=<it>came across</it>] when she talked about her job. [=we could see that she was really enthusiastic when she talked about her job]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be given or made official in a formal and final way <vi>We're still waiting for approval of our loan application to <it>come through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>come through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something) <vi>It was a very difficult illness, but he <it>came through</it> it in pretty good shape.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become conscious <vi>He took a bad fall and knocked himself out. When he <it>came to</it> [=<it>woke up</it>, <it>came around</it>], he didn't remember what had happened.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to reach (a place) while traveling <vi>We <it>came to</it> a fork in the road.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reach (a particular point or step in a process) <vi>Deciding to buy a new car was easy. Now we <it>come to</it> the hard part: finding the money.</vi> <vi>I can't believe that it has <it>come to</it> this.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to approach or reach (a specified condition) <vi>The water <it>came</it> slowly <it>to</it> a boil. [=the water slowly began to boil]</vi> <vi>The project suddenly <phrase>came to a stop/halt</phrase>. [=the project suddenly stopped]</vi> <vi>The work has finally <phrase>come to an end</phrase>. [=has finally ended]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>come to a bad end</tag> at <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to result in (something) <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>His ambitious plans never <it>came to</it> much.</vi> <vi>She talked about learning to fly, but it all <phrase>came to nothing</phrase> in the end. [=she never did learn to fly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to make or reach (something, such as a decision or an agreement) after thinking or talking <vi>The two sides finally <it>came to</it> an agreement/understanding after many hours of discussion.</vi> <vi>I've been thinking about what to do next, and I've <it>come to</it> a decision. [=I've made a decision]</vi> <vi>I've <phrase>come to the conclusion</phrase> [=I've decided] that we need to try a different method.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>People say that they <phrase>don't know what the world is coming to</phrase> or they ask <phrase>What is the world coming to?</phrase> when they are shocked or disgusted by something that has happened in the world. <vi>I <it>don't know what the world is coming to</it> when so many poor children have to go to bed hungry every night.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>when it comes to</phrase> is used to identify the specific topic that is being talked about. <vi><it>When it comes to</it> playing chess, he's the best I know.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>if it comes to that</phrase> means “if that is necessary.” <vi>I'm willing to pay more money <it>if it comes to that</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (an amount)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to produce (an amount) when added together <vi>The bill <it>came to</it> [=<it>amounted to</it>] 10 dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be thought of by (someone) :to occur to (someone) <vi>The answer suddenly <it>came to</it> me. [=I suddenly thought of the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>coming to</phrase> you is something that is owed to you. <vi>I have another dollar <it>coming to</it> me. [=I am owed another dollar]</vi> <vi>He wants all the credit that's <it>coming to</it> him. [=he wants all the credit that he deserves]</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get what's coming to you</phrase>, you get the punishment that you deserve. <vi>He's a dirty cheat, and I'm going to see that he <it>gets what coming to him</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>have it coming (to you)</phrase> you deserve to get something bad, such as punishment. <vi>I'm not sorry to hear that he lost his job. He <it>had it coming</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to blows</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to join or meet <vi>the place where two rivers <it>come together</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to form a group <vi>People from many different areas have <it>come together</it> to try to find a solution.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin to work or proceed in the desired way <vi>The project started slowly, but everything is finally starting to <it>come together</it> now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to grief</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grief</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to grips with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>life</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to light</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to pass</dre> <def><sl>formal + literary</sl> <dt>:to happen <vi>Many of the things he predicted have <it>come to pass</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to terms</dre> <dx>see <dxt>term</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to think of it</dre> <def><dt><un>used in speech to say that you have just remembered or thought of something <vi>The meeting is next Tuesday, which, <it>come to think of it</it>, is also the date of my doctor's appointment.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to your senses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come true</dre> <dx>see <dxt>true</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come under (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be subjected to (something) <vi>The troops were resting when they suddenly <it>came under</it> attack. [=when they were suddenly attacked]</vi> <vi>His policies have been <it>coming under</it> attack/criticism/fire from conservatives. [=conservatives have been attacking/criticizing his policies]</vi> <vi>Many people feel that their civil rights are <it>coming under</it> threat. [=are being threatened]</vi> <vi>Some of the governor's recent proposals are now <it>coming under</it> increased scrutiny. [=people are now looking more closely and critically at the proposals]</vi> <vi>The school is <it>coming under</it> pressure to change its policies.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be affected, controlled, or influenced by (something) <vi>an area that has <it>come under</it> the control of rebel forces [=an area that is now controlled by rebel forces]</vi> <vi>He was 30 years old when he first <it>came under</it> the care of a psychiatrist. [=when he first began to be treated by a psychiatrist]</vi> <vi>Many young people have <it>come under</it> his influence. [=many young people have been influenced by him]</vi> <vi>areas that <it>come under</it> his authority</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to identify the group or category that something belongs to <vi>These matters <it>come under</it> the heading of classified information.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move near to someone or something :to approach someone or something <vi>He <it>came</it> (right) <it>up</it> (to me) and introduced himself.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to be mentioned or thought of <vi>That issue never <it>came up</it>. [=<it>arose</it>]</vi> <vi>A question has <it>come up</it> about the budget.</vi> <vi>I was surprised when his name <it>came up</it> as a possible candidate for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to occur in usually a sudden or unexpected way <vi>She seems to be ready to deal with any problem that may <it>come up</it>. [=<it>arise</it>]</vi> <vi>Something has <it>come up</it> and I won't be able to attend the meeting.</vi> <vi>We need to be ready to take action if an opportunity <it>comes up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become visible in the sky :to rise <vi>She was already awake when the sun <it>came up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to first appear above the ground <vi>in the spring, when the daffodils and tulips are <it>coming up</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to finish in a specified condition or state <vi>I flipped the coin and it <it>came up</it> heads/tails.</vi> <vi>The shot <phrase>came up short</phrase>. [=the shot did not go far enough]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to move up in rank or status <vi>an officer who <phrase>came up from/through the ranks</phrase> [=who started as an ordinary soldier and rose to become an officer]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>coming up</phrase> will happen soon or will appear soon. <vi>With the election <it>coming up</it>, both candidates are spending all their time on the campaign trail.</vi> <vi>Our interview with the mayor is <it>coming</it> (right) <it>up</it> after this commercial.</vi> <vi>“I'd like a turkey sandwich and a glass of lemonade, please.” “<phrase>Coming right up</phrase>!” [=the sandwich and lemonade will be served to you very quickly]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be stopped or slowed by (something) <vi>The proposal has <it>come up against</it> some opposition. [=there is some opposition to the proposal]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up empty</dre> <def><dt>:to fail to get or find something or someone <vi>The police searched the area for clues but <it>came up empty</it>. [=they did not find any clues]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come upon</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>somewhat formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come upon (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to meet or find (someone or something) by chance <vi>As they turned the corner, they <it>came upon</it> an unexpected scene.</vi> <vi>While researching the town's history, she <it>came upon</it> some surprising new information about its first mayor.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a feeling</ssl> <dt>:to affect (someone) suddenly <vi>An urge to travel suddenly <it>came upon</it> him. [=he suddenly felt an urge to travel]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be as good as (something) <vi>The movie didn't <it>come up to</it> our expectations. [=was not as good as we expected it to be]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or think of (something that is needed or wanted) <vi>We finally <it>came up with</it> a solution (to our problem).</vi> <vi>He <it>came up with</it> an interesting new method of improving the factory's efficiency.</vi> <vi>He'll be in a lot of trouble if he doesn't <it>come up with</it> the money he owes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come what may</dre> <def><dt>:regardless of what happens <vi>He promised to support her, <it>come what may</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first come, first served</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>how come</dre> <dx>see <dxt>how</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to come</dre> <def><dt>:existing or arriving in the future <vi>No one knows what will happen in the days <it>to come</it>.</vi> <vi>There will be more trouble <it>to come</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="ever"> <hw highlight="yes">ev*er</hw> <sound><wav>ever0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛvɚ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at any time <vi>The crime rate is higher now than it has <it>ever</it> been.</vi> <vi>He's forgotten all he's <it>ever</it> learned about history.</vi> <vi>Have you <it>ever</it> been to France?</vi> <vi>She's doing fine and is as pretty as <it>ever</it>.</vi> <vi>No one has <it>ever</it> seen a better example of woodwork.</vi> <vi>We need your help now more than <it>ever</it> (before).</vi> <vi>Has this <it>ever</it> been done before?</vi> <vi>That was my best vacation <it>ever</it>. [=the best vacation I have ever had]</vi> <vi>Did it <it>ever</it> occur to you that I might like more myself?</vi> <vi>He's a born politician if <it>ever</it> I saw one. [=he is certainly a born politician]</vi> <vi>That was the worst movie I <it>ever</it> saw.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>ever</it> want to do that again. = (<it>informal</it>) I don't want to <it>ever</it> do that again. = I don't want to do that again, <it>ever</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:at all times <vi>He is <it>ever</it> [=<it>always</it>] faithful.</vi> <vi>moving <it>ever</it> westward</vi> <vi>a guard who is <it>ever</it> watchful = an <it>ever-</it>watchful guard</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to a greater degree <vi>Technology in recent years has become <it>ever</it> more sophisticated.</vi> <vi>The deadline draws <it>ever</it> closer.</vi> <vi>Millions of farmers were forced into <it>ever-</it>deeper debt during the Great Depression.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used after words like <it>where, who, how</it>, and <it>why</it> to make a question more forceful <vi>How <it>ever</it> can I (possibly) thank you?</vi> <vi>What <it>ever</it> happened to my former classmates?</vi> <vi>Where <it>ever</it> did I put my keys?</vi> <vi>“I can't do that.” “Why <it>ever</it> not?”</vi> <vi>Who <it>ever</it> would want to go there?</vi></un> <un>also used in indirect questions <vi>I can't imagine who <it>ever</it> would want to go there!</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to give stress to what follows <vi>Wow, was he <it>ever</it> funny! [=he was very funny]</vi> <vi>Am I <it>ever</it> embarrassed! [=I am very embarrassed]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>as ever</dre> <def><dt>:as has always been true :as usual <vi>The problem, <it>as ever</it>, is to find a better way to control spending.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ever after</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:from that time forward <vi>She remembered him fondly <it>ever after</it>.</vi> <snote>Fairy tales sometimes end by saying that the characters in the story <phrase>lived happily ever after</phrase>. <vi>The prince saved the queen and they all <it>lived happily ever after</it>.</vi> The phrase <it>live happily ever after</it> is also used to describe real people who are being compared in some way to characters in a fairy tale. <vi>His biography tells the story of a poor boy who grew up to be a millionaire and <it>lived happily ever after</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ever and anon</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned + literary</sl> <dt>:at different times :now and then <vi><it>Ever and anon</it> [=<it>every so often</it>] there came the sound of bells.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ever since</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:continually or often from a past time until now <vi>We both liked the idea and have been working on it <it>ever since</it>. [=<it>since then</it>]</vi> <vi>I went to the festival its first year and have been returning <it>ever since</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:continually from the time in the past when :<sx>since</sx> <vi>She's wanted to be a firefighter <it>ever since</it> she was a young girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ever so</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <vi>Thank you <it>ever so</it> much.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>ever so</it> glad that you got better.</vi> <vi>The violin was <phrase>ever so slightly</phrase> out of tune.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ever such</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a more forceful way to say “such” <vi>He's <it>ever such</it> a nice person! [=he's a very nice person]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for ever (and ever)</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>forever</sx> <vi>I'll love you <it>for ever and ever</it>!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hardly/scarcely ever</dre> <def><dt>:almost never :<sx>rarely</sx> <vi>She <it>hardly ever</it> sings anymore.</vi> <vi>I <it>scarcely ever</it> think of them now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>never ever</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used especially in speech as a more forceful way to say “never” <vi>He <it>never ever</it> wanted to grow up.</vi> <vi>I promise to <it>never ever</it> do it again.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rarely/seldom ever</dre> <def><dt>:almost never :<sx>rarely</sx> <vi>We <it>seldom ever</it> dine out these days.</vi> <vi>She <it>rarely ever</it> drinks wine.</vi> <snote>Some people regard <it>rarely ever</it> and <it>seldom ever</it> as incorrect, but these phrase are common in speech and in informal writing.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rarely/seldom if ever</dre> <def><dt><un>used as a more forceful way to say “rarely” or “seldom” <vi>I have <it>seldom if ever</it> been so embarrassed.</vi></un> <snote><it>Rarely if ever</it> and <it>seldom if ever</it> can be written both with or without commas <vi>Such radical opinions have <it>rarely</it>, <it>if ever</it>, been heard here before.</vi> <vi>She <it>rarely if ever</it> sings anymore.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>Yours ever</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>Ever yours</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt><un>used as a way to end an informal letter <vi><it>Yours ever</it>, Robert</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="every"> <hw highlight="yes">ev*ery</hw> <sound><wav>every001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛvri</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:including each person or thing in a group or series <vi>I heard <it>every</it> word you said.</vi> <vi>He devotes <it>every</it> spare moment to his hobby.</vi> <vi>His <it>every</it> move was carefully watched.</vi> <vi>She's beautiful in <it>every</it> way/respect.</vi> <vi>Ceramics of <it>every</it> kind were on display.</vi> <vi>We have <it>every</it> reason to believe (that) he's telling the truth. [=we have no reason not to believe him]</vi> <vi>He looked closely at <phrase>every last one</phrase> [=every one] of them.</vi> <vi>They were questioning <phrase>every little thing</phrase> [=<it>everything</it>] she said.</vi> <vi>He provided them with guidance <phrase>every step of the way</phrase>. [=throughout the entire process]</vi> <vi><phrase>Every time</phrase> [=<it>whenever</it>] I go there I learn something new.</vi> <vi>We're <phrase>making every effort</phrase> [=we're doing all that we can] to solve the problem.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe how often some repeated activity, event, etc., happens or is done <vi>She drives to town <it>every</it> few days.</vi> <vi><it>Every</it> day she starts work at 8 a.m.</vi> <vi>The fair is held <phrase>every other/second</phrase> year. [=the fair is held one year, not held the next year, held the following year, and so on]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe how far apart the things in a series of things are placed from each other <vi>They placed a marker <it>every</it> 20 yards or so.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>one in every three</phrase> to describe how common something is <vi>problems that affect <it>one in every three</it> people</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not lacking in any way <vi>I have <it>every</it> [=<it>complete, total</it>] confidence in you.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at every turn</dre> <dx>see <dxt>turn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>each and every</dre> <dx>see <dxt>each</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every bit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every expectation of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>expectation</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every man for himself</dre> <dx>see <dxt>man</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every now and then/again</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>every once in a while</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>every so often</va></vr> <def><dt>:sometimes but not often :from time to time :<sx>occasionally</sx> <vi>We still see each other <it>every now and then</it>.</vi> <vi>They would get together <it>every now and again</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Every so often</it> she'd come in to check on him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>every which way</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:in every direction <vi>Bullets were flying <it>every which way</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a disorderly manner <vi>The papers were stacked <it>every which way</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="go[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">go</hw> <sound><wav>go000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>goes</if> <sound><wav>go000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊz</pr></in> <in><if>went</if> <sound><wav>go000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>gone</if> <sound><wav>gone0001.wav</wav><wav>go000003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:n</pr></in> <in><if>go*ing</if> <sound><wav>go000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a place <vi>He <it>went</it> to the window and looked out at the yard.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes</it> to the office every morning and comes home in the evening.</vi> <vi>I'm tired. Let's <it>go</it> home.</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> downstairs to the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The train <it>goes</it> from New York to Chicago.</vi> <vi>Halt! <phrase>Who goes there</phrase>? [=who is there?; who is coming this way?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to travel to and stay in (a place) for a particular amount of time <vi>I <it>went</it> with my family to Rome last year.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going to</it> Iowa for a week.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move or travel in a particular way or for a particular distance <vi>The car was <it>going</it> too fast.</vi> <vi>How much farther do we have to <it>go</it>?</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> a long way to see him.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> many miles that day.</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> straight for two blocks, then <it>go</it> right/left at the light.</vi> <vi>The street is blocked, so we'll have to <it>go</it> around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their relationship doesn't seem to be <it>going</it> anywhere. [=doesn't seem to be making any progress]</vi> <vi><phrase>Where do we go from here</phrase>? [=what do we do now?]</vi> <vi>We've accomplished a lot, but we still have <phrase>a long way to go</phrase>. [=we have much more to do]</vi> <vi>She has a lot of talent. If she works hard, she should <phrase>go far</phrase>. [=she should be very successful]</vi> <vi>These changes will <phrase>go a long way</phrase> toward solving the dispute.</vi> <vi>Would you <phrase>go so far</phrase> as to call them dishonest? [=would you say that they are dishonest?]</vi> <vi>This time you've <phrase>gone too far</phrase>! [=you've done something that cannot be allowed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move to or be at a place (such as an office or school) for work, study, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> church on Sunday.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> work from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</vi> <vi>Their son is <it>going to</it> college in Florida. [=he is attending a college in Florida]</vi> <vi>He <it>went to</it> prison for his crimes.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something that involves moving or traveling to a place <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're <it>going on</it> vacation next week.</vi> <vi>The thieves <it>went on</it> a crime spree.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>The neighbors <it>went running</it> [=the neighbors ran] when they heard the screams.</vi> <vi>I like to <it>go walking/swimming/shopping</it>. [=I like to walk/swim/shop]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>go for <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or travel to a place for a particular purpose <vi>I <it>went</it> to see them last week.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> to see a movie last night. = We <it>went</it> to a movie last night.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> to the wedding? [=do you plan to attend the wedding?]</vi> <vi>I may <it>go</it> to see them next week. = I may <it>go</it> and see them next week. = (<it>US</it>) I may <it>go</it> see them next week.</vi> <snote>In informal spoken English, <phrase>go and</phrase> is used to emphasize a following verb. It usually expresses anger or annoyance. <vi>Now you've <it>gone and</it> ruined it!</vi> <vi>They <it>went and</it> changed it!</vi> <vi><it>Go and</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>go</it> by itself is also sometimes used this way. <vi>Why did you have to <it>go</it> ruin it?!</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to engage in (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>Don't <it>go telling</it> everyone what happened. [=don't tell everyone what happened]</vi> <vi>He <it>went blabbing</it> the news all over the place.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>It's getting late. I should <it>go</it> now.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>going</it> when the phone rang.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave a job, position, etc. <vi>Pack up your desk and <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>She's retiring soon, and it'll be sad for all of us to see her <it>go</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to lie or move along a particular route or in a particular direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>goes</it> from the town to the lake.</vi> <vi>His land <it>goes</it> almost all the way down to the river.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> my way? [=are you going in the same direction that I'm going in?]</vi> <vi>The car <it>went</it> the length of the street and then turned around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She <it>went</it> the conventional route [=she did the conventional thing] by going straight to college after high school.</vi> <vi>He has always <phrase>gone his own way</phrase>. [=he has always done the things he wants to do instead of the things that most people do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to provide a way to get to a place <vi>That door <it>goes</it> to the cellar. [=you can get to the cellar by going through that door]</vi> <vi>Where does this road <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be sent <vi>The message <it>went</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be lost, used, or spent <vi>I don't know where the money <it>goes</it>.</vi> <vi>I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they're <it>gone</it>. = (<it>Brit</it>) I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they've <it>gone</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>all</it> <vi>The money was <it>all gone</it> by Friday. = <it>All</it> (of) the money was <it>gone</it> by Friday.</vi> <vi>“Is there any ice cream left?” “No, it's <it>all gone</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to die <vi>She <it>went</it> peacefully at about midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The time/day seemed to <it>go</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen in a particular way <vi>The evening <it>went</it> well/badly.</vi> <vi>She worked hard to make the party <it>go</it> according to plan.</vi> <vi><phrase>The way things are going</phrase> [=if things keep happening this way], I may get laid off.</vi> <vi>We lost the game, but <phrase>that's the way it/life goes</phrase>. [=it is a fact that bad or disappointing things will happen sometimes]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to talk or ask about how you are feeling <vi>“How are things <it>going</it>? = How's everything <it>going</it>? = How's it <it>going</it>?” “Everything's <it>going</it> well/fine/great.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be given up, thrown away, etc. <vi>I want to keep these, but that one can <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>These old boxes <phrase>have got to go</phrase>. = These old boxes <phrase>have to go</phrase>. [=we have to get rid of these old boxes]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be sold <vi>The house <it>went</it> for a good price.</vi> <vi>The cabinets <it>go</it> for about $400.</vi> <vi>The painting will <it>go</it> to the highest bidder</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be willing to pay a certain price for something <vi>I'll <it>go</it> as high as $100, but not over that.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail or become weak because of use, age, etc. <vi>His hearing has started to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>The batteries in the flashlight are <it>going</it> and will have to be changed.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break because of force or pressure <vi>The dam/roof is weakening and it could <it>go</it> at any time.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>Everyone's here, so I think we're ready to <it>go</it>. = (<it>US, informal</it>) I think we're <phrase>good to go</phrase>. [=I think we're ready to start]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get going</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the result of a contest, election, decision, etc. <vi>The election <it>went</it> in her favor. [=she won the election]</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went</it> against him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to work in the usual or expected way <vi>I couldn't get the car to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I kept working on the engine until I finally got it <it>going</it>. [=I finally got it to work/run]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>keep going</tag> at <dxt>keep</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>18 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to become <un>used to describe a change <vi>The building has <it>gone</it> condo. [=the building has become a condominium]</vi> <vi>British currency <it>went</it> decimal in 1971.</vi></un> <un>used especially to describe a change that is not wanted <vi>The tire <it>went</it> flat.</vi> <vi>The bread has <it>gone</it> stale.</vi> <vi>The company <it>went</it> bankrupt.</vi> <vi>Everything keeps <it>going</it> wrong.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change <vi>The leaves here <it>go</it> from green to red in the fall.</vi> <vi>The situation <it>went</it> from bad to worse.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe someone's or something's condition <vi>I like to <it>go</it> barefoot in the summer.</vi> <vi>There was nothing to eat, so we had to <it>go</it> hungry.</vi> <vi>My letters have <it>gone</it> unanswered. [=have not been answered]</vi> <vi>Her excellent work has not <it>gone</it> unnoticed/unappreciated. [=someone has noticed/appreciated her excellent work]</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make a particular movement <vi>Can you <it>go</it> like this with your eyebrows? [=can you move your eyebrows like this?]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to talk about a story, song, etc. <vi>I can't remember how the story <it>goes</it>. [=I can't remember what happens in the story]</vi> <vi>The story/rumor/legend <it>goes</it> that he left home poor and came back rich.</vi> <vi>The tune <it>goes</it> like this.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to fit in or through a space <vi>Will these clothes <it>go</it> in your suitcase? [=is there enough room for these clothes in your suitcase?]</vi> <vi>The box was too big to <it>go</it> [=<it>fit</it>] through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a usual or proper place or position :<sx>belong</sx> <vi>These books <it>go</it> on the top shelf.</vi> <vi>Where do your keys <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have authority :to require you to do what is said or demanded <vi><phrase>What she says goes</phrase>! [=she is the boss; you have to do what she tells you to do]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use the toilet <vi>One of the children said he had to <it>go</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go to the bathroom</tag> at <dxt>bathroom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to make a sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The bell <it>went</it> and the class came to an end.</vi> <vi>The music was <it>going</it> full blast. [=the music was being played as loud as possible]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The gun <it>went</it> bang.</vi> <vi>The cow <it>went</it> “moo.”</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say (something) <un>used in describing what people said in a conversation <vi>So she <it>goes</it>, “Did you write this?” and I <it>go</it>, “Mind your own business!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a sports team or player</ssl> <dt>:to have a specified record <vi>The team <it>went</it> 11–2 last season. [=the team won 11 games and lost 2 games last year]</vi> <vi>The shortstop <it>went</it> two for four in yesterday's game. [=the shortstop had two hits in four times at bat in yesterday's game]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything goes</dre> <def><dt>:anything is acceptable :there are no rules for behavior, dress, etc. <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <it>anything goes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as (someone or something) goes</dre> <def><dt><un>used to compare someone or something with someone or something else of the same kind <vi><it>As lectures go</it>, it was very interesting.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be available <vi>There <it>are</it> no jobs <it>going</it> right now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going to</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about what will happen or could happen <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> be cold tomorrow. [=it will be cold tomorrow]</vi> <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> rain: if you don't take an umbrella, you<it>'re going to</it> get soaked.</vi> <vi>I <it>am</it> not <it>going to</it> tolerate [=I won't tolerate] any more bad behavior!</vi> <vi>I <it>was</it> just <it>going to</it> call him. [=I was about to call him]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>gonna</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go about (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) <vi>I'd like to fix this old radio but I don't know how to <it>go about</it> (doing) it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>Despite the threat of war, most people are just quietly <phrase>going about their business</phrase>. [=most people are just doing the things that they usually do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go a bundle on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bundle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to follow and try to stop or catch (someone) <vi>When the boy ran out the door, his mother quickly <it>went after</it> him.</vi> <vi>The police <it>went after</it> the escaped criminal.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to find and punish (someone) <vi>The government is <it>going after</it> people who cheat on their taxes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something or someone) <vi>If you want the job, you should just <it>go after</it> it.</vi> <vi>She accused her friend of <it>going after</it> her husband.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not agree with (something) <vi>I won't do anything that <it>goes against</it> my conscience/beliefs/principles.</vi> <vi>values that <it>go against</it> those of society</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to oppose (someone or something) <vi>He was surprised when some of his former supporters <it>went against</it> him.</vi> <vi>He was reluctant to <it>go against</it> his parents' wishes. [=he was reluctant to do something that his parents did not want him to do]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to compete against (a player or team) in a contest or game <vi>The Red Sox will be <it>going against</it> the Yankees in tonight's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not be good for (someone) :to not produce the result that is wanted by (someone) <vi>Everything seemed to be <it>going against</it> her but she didn't give up hope.</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went against</it> the defendant. [=the verdict was not in favor of the defendant]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do or begin to do something <vi>Instead of waiting for approval, they just <it>went ahead</it> and started working on the project.</vi> :to do something after planning to do it or after getting permission to do it <vi>Despite the bad weather, they decided to <it>go ahead</it> with the party.</vi> <vi>My boss told me to <it>go ahead</it> (with the work).</vi> <vi>“Could I sit here?” “Sure, <it>go</it> (right) <it>ahead</it>.”</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more cake.” “Oh, <it>go ahead</it>. It won't kill you.”</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go-ahead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to happen or proceed <vi>Despite the weather, the party <it>went ahead</it> as planned.</vi> <vi>After a brief delay, the work is now <it>going ahead</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before the other person or group that is with you <vi>I'll <it>go</it> (on) <it>ahead</it> and make sure that everything's ready when you arrive.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <def><dt>:to do something with as much effort as possible <vi>When he has a party, he likes to <it>go all out</it>. [=have a big and expensive party]</vi> <vi>Her company always <it>went all out</it> [=did everything possible] to make the customer happy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-out</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all the way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue or proceed <vi>The project is <it>going along</it> smoothly.</vi> <vi>On this job there's a lot to learn—but I'm sure you'll pick it up as you <it>go along</it>.</vi> <vi>He was just making up the story as he <it>went along</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel with someone <vi>They were going to the fair so I asked whether I could <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I asked whether I could <it>go along with</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept what other people want <vi>We tried to convince him to support us but he refused to <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> us.</vi> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> our plan.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be part of something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes along with</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ape</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ape</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>go round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to go to different places <vi>She and her friends <it>go around</it> (together) to lots of clubs. = She <it>goes around</it> with her friends to lots of clubs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place that is nearby <vi>I <it>went round</it> [=<it>went over</it>] <it>to</it> his flat.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way a person often dresses or behaves <vi>She <it>goes around</it> (dressed) in a miniskirt.</vi> <vi>You can't <it>go around</it> treating people so rudely.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go or pass from one person to another person <vi>There's a rumor <it>going around</it> (the office) that the boss is about to get fired.</vi> <vi>An amusing story is <it>going around</it>.</vi> <vi>There's a nasty cold <it>going around</it>: I hope you don't catch it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be long enough to pass all the way around (something or someone) <vi>This belt isn't long enough to <it>go around</it> (my waist).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>If people want something and there is <phrase>enough/plenty to go around</phrase>, there is enough for all of the people who want it or need it. <vi>There aren't <it>enough jobs to go around</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>what goes around comes around</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that if you treat other people badly you will eventually be treated badly by someone else</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>They <it>went at</it> each other viciously.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to fight or argue <vi>Our neighbors were arguing again last night. They <it>went at it</it> for almost an hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make an effort to do or deal with (something) <vi>They had to <it>go at</it> the problem from many different angles before they finally solved it.</vi> <vi>It was a tough job, and I was impressed by the energetic way he <it>went at</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place or person <vi>She angrily told him to <it>go away</it> and stop bothering her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for a period of time <vi>They're <it>going away</it> on vacation.</vi> <vi>After graduating from high school, he <it>went away</it> to college.</vi> <vi>a <it>going-away</it> present/party [=a present/party for someone who is leaving to live, study, or travel in a distant place]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop existing or happening :to end <vi>I just wish there was some way to make the pain <it>go away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I forgot my purse and had to <it>go back</it> for it.</vi> <vi>What was it like to <it>go back</it> after so many years?</vi> <vi>After college she <it>went back</it> home.</vi> <vi><it>Go back</it> inside! You'll catch cold.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin doing something again <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>I turned off the alarm and <it>went back to</it> sleep.</vi> <vi>He waved hello, then <it>went</it> right <it>back to</it> work.</vi> <vi>She <it>went back to</it> eating her dinner.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>there's no going back</phrase> means that you have done or decided something and cannot change it. <vi>I've already signed the contract, so <it>there's no going back</it> now.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to have existed for a particular amount of time or since a particular period <vi>These ruins <it>go back</it> hundreds of years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a tradition that <it>goes back</it> [=<it>dates back</it>] <it>to</it> colonial times</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have known each other for a particular amount of time <vi>We <it>go back</it> 30 years.</vi> <vi>He and I <phrase>go back a long way</phrase>. = He and I <phrase>go way back</phrase>. [=he and I have known each other for many years]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to think or talk about something from the past <vi>To fully understand the issues, we have to <it>go back</it> a few years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'd like to <it>go back to</it> your earlier comment. [=I'd like to discuss it further]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go back on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>She <it>went back on</it> her promise to help us. [=she failed to keep her promise]</vi> <vi>I would never <it>go back on</it> my word.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to happen or exist at an earlier time than (someone) <vi>We owe a great debt of gratitude to those who <it>went before</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be considered by (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>The contestants will <it>go before</it> the judges tomorrow.</vi> <vi>The case <it>went before</it> the court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go beyond</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go beyond (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do more than (something) <vi>She <it>went beyond</it> the call of duty. [=she did more than was required]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>go beyond</it> merely talking about the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The morning seemed to <it>go by</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi> <vi>Many years have <it>gone by</it> since the last time I saw her.</vi> <vi>They have many happy memories of days <it>gone by</it>. [=bygone days, days/times in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be guided or directed by (something, such as a rule) <vi>That's a good rule to <it>go by</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion from (something) <vi>She may be guilty but we have very little evidence to <it>go by</it>.</vi> <vi>You can't always <it>go by</it> appearances. [=you can't always judge people or things by the way they look]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (a name)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be known by (a name) <vi>His name is Edwin but he <it>goes by</it> Ed. [=people call him Ed]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go by (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go somewhere in order to visit someone <vi>I <it>went by</it> (her house) to see her after school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall or crash to the ground <vi>The airplane <it>went down</it> when one of its engines caught fire.</vi> <vi>The boxer took a punch and <it>went down</it> hard.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to sink into the water <vi>The ship <it>went down</it> after hitting an iceberg.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go down</it> soon.</vi> <vi>The quality of his work has been <it>going down</it>.</vi> <vi>She had a fever yesterday, but it <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become less or smaller <vi>It may take a few hours for the swelling to <it>go down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become less bright <vi>The lights <it>went down</it> [=the lights were turned down] as the movie started.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to stop being visible in the sky :to set <vi>The sun comes up in the morning and <it>goes down</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to eat or drink something <vi>The medicine <it>went down</it> easily. [=it was easy to swallow the medicine]</vi> <vi>I took a sip but it <it>went down</it> the wrong way. [=I choked on my drink]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to accept or agree to something <vi>His suggestion didn't <it>go down</it> [=<it>go over</it>] very well with his boss. [=his boss didn't like his suggestion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to lose or fail <vi>Last year's champion <it>went down</it> in the first round of the tournament this year.</vi> <vi>The regime finally <it>went down</it> [=<it>fell</it>] in a wave of popular protest.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>of a computer, system, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The network <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to be remembered or talked about as an important person, event, etc. <vi>He will <it>go down</it> as one of the greatest leaders this country has ever known.</vi> <vi>His name will <phrase>go down in history</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be sent to prison <vi>He <it>went down</it> [=went to jail] for six years for the robbery.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to travel to a place (especially one that is nearby or to the south) <vi>I need to <it>go down</it> to the store for milk.</vi> <vi>We <it>went down</it> south to visit relatives.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to happen <vi>We need to find out what's <it>going down</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>going on</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to perform oral sex on (someone)</dt> <sn>14</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>He <it>went down with</it> [=<it>caught</it>, <it>came down with</it>] measles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go easy, go easy on/with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go figure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>My dog <it>went for</it> the intruder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something) <vi><it>go for</it> the prize</vi> <vi>If you want to achieve success, you have to stop hesitating and just <phrase>go for it</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to accept or agree to (something, such as a plan or suggestion) <vi>I asked her to lend us some money, but she wouldn't <it>go for</it> it. [=she wouldn't agree to lend us money]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to like or be attracted to (someone or something) <vi>When I see how she looks at him, I can tell she really <it>goes for</it> him.</vi> <vi>I don't really <it>go for</it> modern art.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>could go for</phrase> [=I would like] a cup of coffee right now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relate to or apply to (someone or something) <vi>The rule <it>goes for</it> you, too. [=the rule also applies to you]</vi> <vi>“I'd like ice cream for desert.” “That <it>goes for</it> me too.” [=I'd like ice cream too]</vi> <vi>The economy here has been growing stronger, and <phrase>the same goes for</phrase> [=the same is true for] many other areas.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a price)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be sold for (a particular price) <vi>The painting <it>went for</it> more than a million dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a walk, a drive, etc.)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do an activity (such as walking or driving a car) that usually involves going somewhere <vi>She <it>went for</it> a walk/stroll after dinner.</vi> <vi>On Saturday mornings we like to <it>go for</it> a drive out in the countryside.</vi> <vi>Would anyone like to <it>go for</it> a swim?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>have something going for you</phrase>, you have a talent, skill, etc., that helps you. <vi>She's not as young as some of the other athletes, but experience helps, and she <it>has that going for</it> her. [=she has an advantage because of her experience]</vi> <vi>You should be more confident in yourself. You <phrase>have a lot going for you</phrase>! [=you have many talents, abilities, etc.]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go great guns</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become hidden by a cloud <vi>The afternoon got cooler after the sun <it>went in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to like or be interested in (something) <vi>She doesn't <it>go in for</it> sports.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help pay for (something, such as a present) <vi>Are you going to <it>go in on</it> the gift for her?</vi> <vi>We all <it>went in on</it> the gift together. [=we all gave some money towards buying the gift]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to join (someone) in a business, project, etc. <vi>His brother-in-law <it>went in with</it> him on his new business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to start to be in (a different state or condition) <vi>After she lost her job she <it>went into</it> a deep depression. [=she became very depressed]</vi> <vi>The criminal has <phrase>gone into hiding</phrase>. [=the criminal is hiding]</vi> <vi>After losing the election, she <phrase>went into seclusion</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go into effect</tag> at <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to start to move in (a different and usually bad way) <vi>The car <it>went into</it> a skid. [=the car began to skid]</vi> <vi>The plane <it>went into</it> a tailspin.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) as a job or career <vi>He wants to <it>go into</it> the priesthood. [=he wants to become a priest]</vi> <vi>Their daughter is planning to <it>go into</it> medicine. [=to be a doctor; to get a job in the medical field]</vi> <vi>Both his sons have <it>gone into</it> the army. [=joined the army]</vi> <vi>His dream is to <phrase>go into business</phrase> for himself. [=to start his own business]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll try to tell the story without <it>going into</it> too many details. = I'll try not to <it>go into</it> too much detail.</vi> :to talk about the details of (something) <vi>Having <it>gone into</it> the causes of the French Revolution, the book then discusses its effects.</vi> <vi>“I've had a long day.” “What happened?” “I'll tell you later. I don't feel like <it>going into</it> it right now.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to get information about (something) <un>usually used as <it>(be) gone into</it> <vi>A problem like that should really <it>be gone into</it> [=<it>looked into</it>] carefully.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be used for (something) <vi>Lots of time, energy, and money have <it>gone into</it> (completing) the project.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt><un>used to say how many times a number can be multiplied to produce a larger number <vi>6 <it>goes into</it> 18 three times. [=18 divided by 6 equals 3]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go it alone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a bomb</ssl> <dt>:to explode <vi>The building was evacuated before the bomb <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a gun</ssl> <dt>:to shoot <vi>The gun <it>went off</it> accidentally.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of an alarm</ssl> <dt>:to begin to make a sudden loud noise <vi>I woke up when the alarm <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The lights in the building suddenly <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place for a new place <vi>He <it>went off</it> to join the army after graduating from high school.</vi> <vi>She <it>went off</it> to America.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to occur or happen <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen a particular way <vi>The party <it>went off</it> well. [=the party was a success]</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> poorly.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin shouting at someone in an angry way <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>Her boss <it>went off on</it> her because she was late again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop liking (someone or something) <vi>She used to like him but now she's <it>gone off</it> him completely.</vi> <vi>My boss has <it>gone off</it> the idea, so it's been cancelled.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (a spouse, partner, etc.) for someone else <vi>He left his wife and <it>went off with</it> [=<it>ran off with</it>] some young thing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something that belongs to someone else) away with you :<sx>steal</sx> <vi>Someone <it>went off with</it> my pencil/wallet.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to continue on a journey <vi>We stopped briefly in Detroit, and then <it>went on</it> to Chicago.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue as time passes <vi>Life <it>goes on</it>.</vi> <vi>How much longer will the meeting <it>go on</it>? [=<it>last</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to continue doing something <vi>She <it>went on</it> working [=she continued to work] after everyone else had stopped.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to continue talking <vi>He <it>went on</it> (and on) about how unfairly he had been treated. [=he talked about it for a long time]</vi> :to talk too much or too long about something <vi>She's always <it>going on</it> about the importance of a good diet.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to continue to be in the same situation or relationship <vi>We can't <it>go on</it> like this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before another person or group that is with you <vi>You <it>go on</it> (ahead). I'll come later.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to do or say something else after you have finished doing or saying something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He accepted the nomination and <it>went on to</it> win the election.</vi> <vi>After I finished reading the first book I immediately <it>went on to</it> the next one.</vi> <vi>He <it>went on to</it> say that further tax increases would be necessary.</vi> <vi>Everyone expected that she would <phrase>go on to greater things</phrase>. [=that she would become very successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>What's <it>going on</it>?</vi> <vi>No one knows exactly what <it>went on</it> during their private meeting.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>goings-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>went on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion or conclusion from something <un>used in the phrase <phrase>to go on</phrase> <vi>There's very little evidence <it>to go on</it>. [=there's very little evidence that can be used to form an opinion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to urge someone to do something <vi><it>Go on</it> (and try it): you might actually like it!</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more ice cream.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>! It won't hurt you to have a little more.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to express disbelief <vi>“I used to be a spy.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>.”</vi> <vi>A spy? <phrase>Go on with you</phrase>, then. [=I don't believe you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>go on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) often or repeatedly <vi>Quit <it>going on at</it> me all the time!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>going on</tag> at <dxt>going</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go one better</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to achieve more :to move to a higher or better level <vi>She qualified for the finals, then <it>went one better</it> and took first place.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go (someone or something) one better</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do better or more than (someone or something) :to outdo (someone or something) <vi>The company has <it>gone</it> its competitors <it>one better</it> by offering new customers a special discount.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for an activity <vi>I'm <it>going out</it> for a walk. I'll be back soon.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going out</it> to get some lunch.</vi> <vi>On Saturday nights he <it>goes out</it> drinking with his friends.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be sent from a person or place <vi>The message <it>went out</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi> <vi>Word has <it>gone out</it> that snow is expected.</vi> <vi><phrase>Our thoughts and prayers go out to</phrase> all the victims of this tragedy. [=we are thinking of and praying for all the victims of this tragedy]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being popular or fashionable <vi>That hairstyle <it>went out</it> years ago.</vi> <vi>Short skirts have <phrase>gone out of fashion</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to meet someone for a romantic social activity :to go on a date with someone <vi>They <it>went out</it> a couple of times, but it was never serious.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with someone <vi>I've been <it>going out</it> with her for quite a while now. = We've been <it>going out</it> for quite a while now.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The electricity suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to stop shining or burning <vi>The fire/candle <it>went out</it>.</vi> <vi>All the lights suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to try to become a member of a team, group, etc. <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>He <it>went out for</it> football last year. = He <it>went out for</it> the football team last year.</vi> <vi>She <it>went out</it> [=<it>tried out</it>] <it>for</it> the school play.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of the tide</ssl> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>The tide is <it>going out</it> [=(more formally) <it>ebbing</it>] now.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be broadcast on the radio, television, etc. <vi>A distress call <it>went out</it> three hours ago.</vi> <un>often + <it>over</it> <vi>Warnings about the approaching storm <it>went out over</it> the radio.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a particular place or person <vi>He <it>went over</it> and stood by the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over</it> and hugged her.</vi> <vi>I think I see Jane. Let's <it>go over</it> and say hello.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> her and hugged her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change sides in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>After several years of supporting us, he <it>went over to</it> our competitors.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to be accepted or received in a particular way <vi>He tried to make a joke but it <it>went over</it> badly. [=no one thought his joke was funny]</vi> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well <it>with</it> the boss. [=the boss didn't like her proposal]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think about (something) carefully <vi>He <it>went over</it> all the arguments before making up his mind.</vi> <vi>We <it>went over</it> the accident again and again in our minds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look at or study (something) again in order to correct it, learn it, etc. <vi>The students were told to <it>go over</it> their essays.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go over</it> the instructions.</vi> <vi>an actress <it>going over</it> her lines</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go the distance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>distance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to start to talk or think about something <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>“Do you remember when we were dating?” “Let's not <it>go there</it>.” = “I don't want to <it>go there</it>.” = “Don't <it>go there</it>.” [=I don't want to talk about that]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to study or look at (something) in a careful way <vi>The book <it>goes through</it> every detail of the French Revolution.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go through</it> the plan one more time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look in or at (something) in order to find something :to search in or through (something) <vi>I found him <it>going through</it> my closet.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to experience (something) <vi>He's <it>going through</it> a painful divorce.</vi> <vi>I understand what you're <it>going through</it>.</vi> <vi>In order to learn the job well, you have to <it>go through</it> several months of training.</vi> <vi>The book has already <it>gone through</it> four editions. [=the publishers have already released four editions of the book]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>went through</it> all the money he inherited.</vi> <vi>They <it>went through</it> three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to occur throughout (something) <vi>A note of despair <it>goes through</it> the narrative. [=there is a note of despair throughout the narrative]</vi> <snote>If something (such as an idea or a song) is <phrase>going through your head/mind</phrase>, you are thinking about it or remembering it. <vi>I don't know what was <it>going through her mind</it> [=I don't know what her thoughts were; I don't know why she did this] when she agreed to help him.</vi> <vi>That song keeps <it>going through my head</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>It took him about an hour to <it>go through</it> his usual morning routine.</vi> <vi>Before we practice the next section, let's <it>go through</it> the chorus once again.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go through the motions</tag> at <dxt>motion</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>Something (such as a law or contract) that <phrase>goes through</phrase> is officially accepted and approved. <vi>The bill is expected to <it>go through</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The proposed deal failed to <it>go through</it>.</vi> <vi>The bill <phrase>went through Congress/Parliament</phrase> [=was passed by Congress/Parliament] without difficulty and soon became law.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something that you have thought or talked about) <vi>He was always threatening to quit his job, but I never thought he'd actually <it>go through with</it> it. [=I never thought he would actually do it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to be in (a particular state, condition, or situation) <vi>You need to <phrase>go to sleep</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The countries <phrase>went to war</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be given to (someone or something) <vi>First prize <it>went to</it> the team from Chicago.</vi> <vi>The property will <it>go to</it> his wife if he dies before she does.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (trouble or expense)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to do something that causes you (trouble or expense) <vi>You shouldn't <it>go to all this trouble</it> just for me.</vi> <vi>They <it>went to a lot of expense</it> [=they spent a lot of money] to make sure that the job was done correctly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be suited to or appropriate for each other <vi>The tie and his suit <it>go together</it> well.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship <vi>They've been <it>going together</it> for several years.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to show/prove</dre> <def><dt>:to help show or prove something <vi>Her success <phrase>goes to show</phrase> that if you work hard, you can make your dreams come true.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go toward(s)</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go toward(s) (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help pay for (something) <vi>My extra income is <it>going towards</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>Your donations will <it>go toward</it> better sanitation for refugees.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to sink below the surface of the water <vi>The ship <it>went under</it> after being struck by a torpedo.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail :to not succeed <vi>The company has been losing money and is in danger of <it>going under</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a higher level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go up</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become brighter <vi>The lights <it>went up</it> [=the lights were turned up] when the movie ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be built <vi>A new store is <it>going up</it> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place (especially one that is to the north) <vi>We <it>went up to</it> the lake for the weekend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with (someone) :to date (someone) <vi>I've been <it>going with</it> her for quite a while now.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go out <dxn>4b (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>go together <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be suitable for or appropriate with (something) <vi>The skirt she's wearing doesn't really <it>go with</it> [=<it>match</it>] her blouse.</vi> <vi>The tie <it>goes</it> (well) <it>with</it> his suit.</vi> <vi>Do you think this wine will <it>go</it> well <it>with</it> dinner?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go together <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to exist or occur as a necessary part of (something) <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes with</it> it.</vi> <vi>There are a lot of responsibilities that <it>go with</it> starting your own business.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go with the territory</tag> at <dxt>territory</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or use (someone or something) <vi>After thinking about who to offer the job to, they decided to <it>go with</it> the more experienced candidate.</vi> <vi>The golfer <it>went with</it> an iron off the tee. [=the golfer used an iron for her tee shot]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go without</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go without</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go without (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not have (something) :to live or continue without having (something) <vi>How long can you <it>go without</it> sleeping/sleep?</vi> <vi>If you can't afford a new car, you'll just have to <it>go without</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>here goes (nothing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>here</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>here/there you go (again)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is happening again or in the same way that it has happened before <vi><it>There you go</it>, making a big deal out of nothing.</vi> <vi>When I saw his name in the headlines I thought, “<it>Here we go again</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how goes it?</dre> <def><dt><un>used as an informal greeting <vi>Hi Paul. <it>How goes it</it>? [=how are you?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ready, set, go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ready</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>there go/goes</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is no longer available or possible <vi>Look at that traffic jam! <it>There goes</it> our only chance of arriving on time. [=our only chance of arriving on time is gone/lost]</vi> <vi>It's supposed to rain this weekend, so <it>there go</it> our plans for a barbecue. [=we won't be able to have a barbecue]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:still remaining <vi>There are only three more days <it>to go</it> until my birthday!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:sold to be taken away and eaten somewhere else <vi>“I'd like a hamburger.” “For here or <it>to go</it>?” “<it>To go</it>.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="half[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">half</hw> <sound><wav>half0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhæf, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑ:f</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>halves</if> <sound><wav>half0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhævz, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑvz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:one of two equal or nearly equal parts into which something can be divided <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She broke each cookie into <it>halves</it>.</vi> <vi>“Which <it>half</it> do you want?” “I'll take the smaller <it>half</it>.”</vi> <vi>Two <it>halves</it> make a whole.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The price has been reduced <phrase>by half</phrase>. [=by 50 percent; by an amount that is equal to one half of the original]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>better half</dxt> <dxt>other half</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:either of the two equal periods of playing time in sports like football and basketball <vi>The team fell behind in the first <it>half</it> but rallied in the second <it>half</it> to win the game.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the half</bnote> <dt>:the time when the first half of a game ends <vi>The score was tied at <it>the half</it>. [=at halftime]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:half a pint of a drink (such as beer) <vi>“What's yours?” “A <it>half</it> of lager, please.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and a half</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used in measurements of time, distance, weight, etc., to indicate one half of the unit of measurement <vi>My daughter is two and a <it>half</it> (years old). [=two years and six months old]</vi> <vi>The fish was a foot <it>and a half</it> long. [=one foot and six inches long]</vi> <vi>ten <it>and a half</it> pounds [=ten pounds and eight ounces]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that something is very good, large, difficult, etc. <vi>That was a meal <it>and a half</it>! [=that was a very big meal]</vi> <vi>Renovating a house is a job <it>and a half</it>. [=is a very difficult job]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by halves</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in an incomplete way <un>used in negative statements to say that someone does things with a lot of energy and effort <vi>She never does anything <it>by halves</it>—it's all or nothing!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go halves</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>go half and half</va></vr> <def><dt>:to share the cost of something equally <vi>We decided to <it>go halves</it> (with each other) on the expenses.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in half</dre> <def><dt>:into two equal parts :into two halves <vi>She cut the apple <it>in half</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the half of it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that a situation is even worse than you think it is or than it seems to be <vi>“It sounds like you've been having some problems.” “You don't know <it>the half of it</it>!”</vi> <vi>Sales are down but that's only <it>the half of it</it>—the company is closing several stores.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too…by half</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has too much of a particular quality usually in a way that is annoying <vi>an arrogant politician who is <phrase>too clever by half</phrase></vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="half[4]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="4">half</hw> <altpr>ˈhæf, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑ:f</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to an extent that is equal or nearly equal to half of something <vi>The glass of water is <it>half</it> full/empty.</vi> <vi>The crowd was <it>half</it> cheering and <it>half</it> jeering.</vi> <vi>She's <it>half</it> French and <it>half</it> Italian. [=one of her parents is French and the other is Italian]</vi> <vi>The meeting began at <phrase>half past</phrase> two. [=at 2:30] = (<it>Brit</it>) The meeting began at <it>half</it> two.</vi> <vi>We arrived at the station at noon, and the train departed at <it>half past</it>. [=at 12:30]</vi> <vi>The train departed at <it>half past</it> the hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not completely :to some degree :<sx>partially</sx> <vi>He was only <it>half</it> aware of what was happening.</vi> <vi>She had <it>half</it> persuaded me to stay.</vi> <vi>The door was <it>half</it> open.</vi> <vi>These eggs are only <it>half</it> cooked.</vi> <vi>I was <phrase>half asleep</phrase> [=very tired; not completely awake] when you called.</vi> <vi>She looked <phrase>half dead</phrase>. [=she looked very tired/ill]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>half again as much/many (etc.) as</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>half as much/many (etc.) again as</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that the size or amount of one thing is 50 percent more than another <vi>If 100 people were expected and 150 came, <it>half again as many</it> people came <it>as</it> were expected.</vi> <vi>This dress costs <it>half again as much as</it> that one.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>half as big/much/good (etc.) as</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that the size, amount, or quality of one thing is half or nearly half that of another <vi>The bush is <it>half as tall as</it> the tree. [=the tree is twice as tall as the bush]</vi> <vi>This dress costs <it>half as much as</it> that one.</vi> <vi>If 100 people were expected and 50 came, only <it>half as many</it> people came <it>as</it> were expected.</vi> <vi>If he can play the guitar <it>half as well as</it> he can sing, he should have quite a career. [=he will have a very successful career if he can play the guitar well, even if he doesn't play as well as he sings]</vi> <vi>The sequel isn't <it>half as good as</it> the original movie. [=the original movie was much better than the sequel]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>half off</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is being sold at half the original price <vi>Peaches are <it>half off</it> today.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not half</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not nearly <vi>He's <it>not half</it> the fool you think he is. = He's <it>not half</it> so foolish as you think he is. [=he is much smarter than you think he is]</vi> <vi>an aging baseball player who is <it>not half</it> the hitter he once was [=he is not nearly as good as a hitter as he once was]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a statement or description <vi>She <it>doesn't half</it> swear! [=she swears a lot]</vi> <vi>It's <it>not half</it> cold today! [=it is very cold today]</vi> <vi>“Is it cold out?” “<it>Not half</it>!” [=yes, it is very cold]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not half bad</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:surprisingly good <vi>Her singing was <it>not half bad</it>. [=not bad at all]</vi> <vi>The food there is <it>not half bad</it>. [=pretty good]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
