<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="aid[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">aid</hw> <sound><wav>aid00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈeɪd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>aids</if></in> <in><if>aid*ed</if></in> <in><if>aid*ing</if></in> <def><dt>:to provide what is useful or necessary :<sx>help</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They gave money in order to <it>aid</it> the cause.</vi> <vi>She <it>aided</it> them in their efforts.</vi> <vi>He jumped into the water to <it>aid</it> the drowning child.</vi> <vi>His position was <it>aided</it> [=<it>strengthened</it>] by the fact that he was right.</vi> <vi>a home run that was <it>aided</it> by the wind</vi> <vi><it>aiding</it> the poor</vi> <vi>She <it>aided</it> the government in the attempt to fight illiteracy.</vi> <vi>She is charged with <phrase>aiding and abetting</phrase> [=helping and encouraging] the thief in his getaway.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>in</it> <vi>She <it>aided in</it> the attempt to fight illiteracy.</vi> <vi>His research <it>aided in</it> the discovery of a new treatment for cancer.</vi> <vi>The research <it>aided in</it> establishing new theories.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="aid[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">aid</hw> <altpr>ˈeɪd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>aids</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of helping someone :help or assistance given to someone <vi>The teacher enlisted/sought the <it>aid</it> of several students for the project. [=the teacher asked several students to help with the project]</vi> <vi>The project was completed <phrase>with the aid of</phrase> several students.</vi> <vi>The work was done <it>with the aid of</it> a computer.</vi> <vi>I can no longer read <phrase>without the aid of</phrase> glasses. [=without using glasses]</vi> <vi>When the climbers became trapped by bad weather, a rescue party was sent <phrase>to their aid</phrase>. [=was sent to help/rescue them]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something (such as money, food, or equipment) that is given by a government or an organization to help the people in a country or area where many people are suffering because of poverty, disease, etc. <vi>The government has given millions of dollars in economic/foreign <it>aid</it> to these nations.</vi> <vi>humanitarian <it>aid</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>international <it>aid</it> organizations</vi> <vi>an <it>aid</it> worker [=a person who goes to a foreign country to help the people there]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:money that is given to a student to help pay for the cost of attending a school <vi>She applied for financial/student <it>aid</it> in order to go to college.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something that provides help or assistance <vi>The diagram is provided as an <it>aid</it> to understanding.</vi> <vi>The computer is an <it>aid</it> to keeping costs down.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a device, object, etc., that makes something easier to do <vi>He teaches art with visual <it>aids</it>.</vi> <vi><it>aids</it> to navigation = navigational <it>aids</it></vi> <vi>instructional/learning <it>aids</it></vi> <vi>a pill used as an <it>aid</it> for sleeping = a <phrase>sleeping aid</phrase></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>first aid</dxt> <dxt>hearing aid</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a person whose job is to assist someone :<sx>aide</sx> <vi>She works as a teacher's <it>aid</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in aid of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:in order to help (something or someone) <vi>The event is being held <it>in aid of</it> charity.</vi> <vi><it>in aid of</it> refugees</vi> <snote>The informal British expression <phrase>What's (all) this/that in aid of?</phrase> is used to ask about the purpose of something. <vi>“<it>What's all this rushing about in aid of</it>, then?” [=what's all this rushing about for?] “We're trying to get things ready for the boss's visit.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="Band-Aid[2]"> <hw hindex="2">Band–Aid</hw> <altpr>ˈbændˈeɪd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:able to help or improve something only for a short period of time <vi>a <it>Band-Aid</it> solution to the problem</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="financial aid"> <hw>financial aid</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:money that is given or lent to students in order to help pay for their education <vi>She needed <it>financial aid</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="first aid"> <hw>first aid</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:emergency treatment given to a sick or injured person <vi>She gave him <it>first aid</it> for his sprained ankle.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>first aid kit</phrase> is a set of materials and tools used for giving first aid.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hearing aid"> <hw>hearing aid</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ aids</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an electronic device worn in or on the ear to help a person who has hearing problems to hear better</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="legal aid"> <hw>legal aid</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:money provided by a special organization to pay legal fees for people who cannot pay them themselves</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="visual aid"> <hw>visual aid</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ aids</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something you look at (such as a chart or film) that is used to make something easier to understand</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Band-Aid[1]"> <hw hindex="1">Band–Aid</hw> <sound><wav>banda01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbændˈeɪd</pr> <fl>trademark</fl> <def><dt><un>used for a small bandage</un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="kit[1]"> <hw hindex="1">kit</hw> <sound><wav>kit00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɪt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>kits</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of tools or supplies that a person uses for a particular purpose or activity <vi>a makeup <it>kit</it></vi> <vi>shaving/sewing <it>kits</it></vi> <vi>an electrician's tool <it>kit</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>drum kit</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of parts that are put together to build something <vi>He built the shed from a <it>kit</it>.</vi> <vi>We bought some goldfish and an aquarium <phrase>starter kit</phrase>. [=a set of things needed to set up an aquarium]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a collection of written materials about a particular subject <vi>a tourist information <it>kit</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>press kit</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:clothing or equipment used for a particular purpose <vi>The team wore their new <it>kit</it>.</vi> <vi>cricket/football/sports <it>kit</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>first aid kit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first aid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get/take your kit off</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to take off your clothes <vi>She agreed to <it>get her kit off</it> for the photos.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the whole (kit and) caboodle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>caboodle</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
