<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="all[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">all</hw> <sound><wav>all00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑ:l</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the whole, entire, total amount, quantity, or extent of <vi>He stayed awake <it>all</it> night. [=the whole/entire night]</vi> <vi>She worked hard <it>all</it> day. [=throughout the entire day]</vi> <vi>I've been waiting <it>all</it> week to see her.</vi> <vi>He had to walk <it>all</it> the way home.</vi> <vi>She works <it>all</it> year round.</vi> <vi>He'll need <it>all</it> the help he can get.</vi> <vi>Someone took <it>all</it> the candy.</vi> <vi>It was one of the greatest victories of <it>all</it> time. [=one of the greatest victories ever]</vi> <vi>I think about her <phrase>all the time</phrase>. [=I think about her constantly]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:every member or part of <un>used with a plural noun or pronoun to mean that a statement is true of every person or thing in a group <vi><it>All</it> my friends were there.</vi> <vi>a film suitable for <it>all</it> ages</vi> <vi>They <it>all</it> came late.</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> need to work faster.</vi> <vi>I read <it>all</it> the magazines. = I read them <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> these eggs are ready.</vi> <vi>“…<it>all</it> men are created equal…” <aq><it>U.S. Declaration of Independence</it> (1776)</aq></vi> <vi>She thinks <it>all</it> teenagers are alike. = She thinks teenagers are <it>all</it> alike.</vi> <vi><phrase>Not all</phrase> teenagers are alike. = Teenagers are not <it>all</it> alike.</vi> <vi>They serve breakfast <phrase>at all hours</phrase>. [=at any hour, at any time of day]</vi> <vi>They were up <phrase>till/until all hours</phrase>. [=they were up very late]</vi> <vi>She has to deal with <phrase>all kinds/sorts/types</phrase> of people. [=with people of every kind/sort/type]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the whole number or sum of <un>used with a plural noun or pronoun to mean that a statement is true of a group of people or things considered together <vi>It was great to see him again after <it>all</it> these years.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:any whatever <vi>His guilt is beyond <it>all</it> doubt. [=he is certainly guilty]</vi> <vi>She denied <it>all</it> [=<it>any</it>] responsibility for the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:as much as possible of (something) <un>used to indicate the manner in which something is done <vi>He spoke in <it>all</it> seriousness/innocence. [=he spoke in a completely serious/innocent way]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having or showing only (some quality, feature, etc.) <vi>The students became <it>all</it> attention [=became very attentive] when the teacher came in.</vi> <vi>He was <it>all</it> smiles with the boss. [=he was smiling constantly when he was with the boss]</vi> <vi>This drink is too strong: it's <it>all</it> alcohol!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate that someone has or seems to have a lot of or too much of some physical feature <vi>an actress who is <it>all</it> legs [=an actress who has very long legs]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>all ears</tag> at <dxt>ear</dxt> <tag>all eyes</tag> at <dxt>eye</dxt> <tag>all heart</tag> at <dxt>heart</dxt> <tag>all mouth</tag> at <dxt>mouth</dxt> <tag>all thumbs</tag> at <dxt>thumb</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>chiefly Southern</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to refer to a group of people or things <vi>Who <it>all</it> is coming? [=who is coming?]</vi> <vi>What <it>all</it> do we need to do? [=what are the things that we need to do?]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>what all</dxt> <dxt>you-all</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <def><dt>:in spite of (something) <vi><it>For all</it> his confident talk, he is actually very unsure of himself.</vi> <vi>She still loves him, <it>for all</it> his faults.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of all (the)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used in phrases to express surprise, disapproval, anger, etc. <vi>Who should I meet in New York but Max <it>of all</it> people! = <it>Of all the</it> people in New York, who should I run into but Max! [=I was very surprised to meet Max in New York]</vi> <vi>Why did my car break down now <it>of all</it> times, when I can least afford it?!</vi> <vi>“He actually called you a fool!” “<phrase>Of all the nerve</phrase>!” [=I am shocked and offended that he called me a fool]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:entirely or completely <vi>She sat <it>all</it> alone.</vi> <vi>She has traveled <it>all</it> around the world.</vi> <vi>This money will be <it>all</it> yours when I die.</vi> <vi>He got <it>all</it> wet.</vi> <vi>She had buttons <it>all</it> down the side of her dress.</vi> <vi>I forgot <it>all</it> about paying the bill.</vi> <vi>The noise continued <it>all</it> through the night. [=all night long, throughout the night]</vi> <un>often used to make a statement more forceful <vi>I'm <it>all</it> in favor of trying again.</vi> <vi>His criticisms were <it>all</it> out of proportion.</vi> <vi>These problems have been occurring <phrase>all too</phrase> often. [=much too often]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for each side or player <un>used to indicate a tie score <vi>The score is 2 <it>all</it>. [=<it>apiece</it>]</vi> <vi>The game ended in a 5-<it>all</it> draw.</vi> <vi>We're tied at 3-<it>all</it> after seven innings.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <vi>The kids got <it>all</it> excited when they saw Santa Claus.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all along</dre> <dx>see <dxt>along</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all around</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>all round</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in every way :from every point of view <vi>It was a good deal <it>all around</it>: we made money and nobody lost out.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for everyone <vi>Let's have drinks <it>all around</it>, bartender.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-around</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not more than <un>used to stress that an amount is surprisingly small <vi>She learned to fly a plane when she was <it>all of</it> 16 years old.</vi> <vi>The team scored <it>all of</it> six points the entire game.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:as much as <un>used to stress that an amount is somewhat large <vi>The prize is now worth <it>all of</it> 10 million dollars.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all over</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:over an entire area <vi>We looked <it>all over</it> [=<it>everywhere</it>] for you.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in every part of (something) <vi>The flower can be found <it>all over</it> the island in spring and early summer.</vi> <vi>He's lived <it>all over</it> Texas.</vi> <vi>In his office there are books piled <phrase>all over the place</phrase>. [=<it>everywhere</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>allover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:very critical of (someone) <vi>She was <it>all over</it> me for being late.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:crowding around, pushing against, or touching (someone) in a very eager or aggressive way <vi>The band's fans were <it>all over</it> them.</vi> <vi>Look at that young couple. They're <it>all over</it> each other! [=they are kissing, touching, etc., very passionately]</vi> <vi>She tried to score, but the other team's defense was <it>all over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:in every way <vi>She's her mother <it>all over</it>. [=she's just like her mother]</vi> <vi>Late again, is she? That's her <it>all over</it>. [=that's very typical of her]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all that</dre> <def><dt>:to a high degree <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I wasn't <it>all that</it> [=<it>very</it>] interested in the story.</vi> <vi>The movie wasn't <it>all that</it> [=<it>so</it>] bad.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>all that</tag> at <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all the</dre> <def><dt><un>used to give added force to a word like “more” or “better” <vi>With the economy in such bad shape, it's <it>all the more</it> important [=it's even more important] that we correct these problems quickly.</vi> <vi>If we arrive early, <it>all the better</it>. [=it will be even better if we arrive early]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:with everything considered or included :in all <vi><it>All told</it>, it took us three full days to get there.</vi> <vi>There were seven of us <it>all told</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not all there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe a person who is somewhat strange or stupid <vi>Her aunt is very sweet but <it>not all there</it> (mentally).</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the entire number, quantity, or amount <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] that I have is yours.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] will be explained soon.</vi> <vi>She told us <it>all</it> about what happened.</vi> <vi>Her other books were good, but this one is the best of <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> are welcome! [=everyone is welcome]</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> enjoyed the movie. = <it>All</it> of us enjoyed the movie.</vi> <vi>Many people were invited and <it>all</it> came.</vi> <vi>His stories may be entertaining, but I don't think <it>all</it> (of them) are true.</vi> <vi>Thanks to <it>all</it> who helped out.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> of this money will be yours when I die.</vi> <vi>Not <it>all</it> of our students go on to college.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>was all (that) I could do</phrase> to keep from laughing! [=I had a hard time trying not to laugh]</vi> <vi>“Is there anything else to be done?” “No, <phrase>that's all</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He gave equal attention to <phrase>one and all</phrase>. [=to everyone]</vi> <vi><phrase>Come one, come all</phrase>. [=everyone is invited to come]</vi> <usageref>altogether</usageref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the only thing <vi>That's <it>all</it> I can do to help.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> I know is that the game was canceled. I don't know why.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>after</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>All aboard!</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aboard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all in all</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a general way :when everything is thought of or considered <vi><it>All in all</it> [=<it>in general, generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi> <vi>We did lose some money, but we got most of it back. So <it>all in all</it> things might have been a lot worse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>The cost of the repairs came to about $300 <it>all told</it>. [=<it>in all</it>] [=the total cost of the repairs was about $300]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>and all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:and everything else <vi>What with the noise outside, the fire <it>and all</it>, we got hardly any sleep.</vi> <vi>He endured everything, insults <it>and all</it>, without getting angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a response <vi>“It's really hot out!” “It is <it>and all</it>!” [=it certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>He will go anywhere <it>at all</it> to get a job.</vi> <vi>Did you find out anything <it>at all</it>?</vi></un> <un>used especially in negative statements <vi>“Did she say anything?” “No, nothing <it>at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't mind cooking <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>at all</it> what you think it is. It's something else entirely.</vi> <vi>I wasn't tired <it>at all</it>. = I wasn't <it>at all</it> tired. [=I wasn't even slightly tired]</vi> <vi>This chair is not <it>at all</it> comfortable.</vi> <vi>I didn't like it <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>That is not <it>at all</it> likely.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>not at all</phrase> is sometimes used as a polite response when someone thanks you. <vi>“Thank you for all your trouble.” “<it>Not at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>“That was very kind of you.” “<it>Not at all</it>. It was the least I could do.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your all</dre> <def><dt>:to do or give as much as you can to achieve something, to support a cause, etc. <vi>He <it>gave his all</it> for the cause. = He <it>gave his all</it> to help the cause.</vi> <vi>You'll never succeed in this business unless you <it>give (it) your all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>There were about a thousand people at the concert <it>in all</it>. [=<it>all told</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>once and for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <def><dt>:after considering or doing everything <un>used for a final general statement or judgment <vi>It won't be easy, but <it>when all is said and done</it>, we'll be glad we did it.</vi> <vi>The candidates claim to have different views but, <it>when all is said and done</it>, they're very much alike.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all-"> <hw>all-</hw> <fl>combining form</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:entirely :completely <vi>an <it>all</it>-wool suit</vi> <vi>an <it>all</it>-woman band</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:including everything <vi>an <it>all</it>-encompassing philosophy</vi> <vi>Her <it>all-</it>consuming passion was music.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:selected as the best at something (such as a sport) within an area or organization <vi>an <it>all</it>-league halfback</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all-American"> <hw>all–Amer*i*can</hw> <sound><wav>allam01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɑ:ləˈmerəkən</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having qualities that are thought to be typical of people in the U.S. or that are widely admired in the U.S. <vi>a wholesome <it>all-American</it> boy</vi> <vi>her <it>all-American</it> optimism</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:selected as one of the best in the U.S. in a particular sport <vi>an <it>all-American</it> football player</vi> <vi>He was <it>all-American</it> twice when he played college football.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having only all-American players <vi>an <it>all-American</it> football team</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:consisting entirely of Americans or of American elements <vi>The tennis tournament will have an <it>all-American</it> final. [=both players in the final are American]</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>all–American</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>all–Americans</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>He was an <it>all-American</it> in football.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="all-around"> <hw>all–around</hw> <sound><wav>allar01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɑ:ləˈraʊnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:relating to or involving many different things <vi>The computer has good <it>all-around</it> performance.</vi> <vi>There has been an <it>all-around</it> improvement in his work recently.</vi> :considered in a general way <vi>He is an <it>all-around</it> good guy.</vi> <vi>She is a teacher, writer, and <it>all-around</it> nice woman.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:skillful or useful in many ways <vi>She's the best <it>all-around</it> player on the team.</vi> <vi>a good <it>all-around</it> pickup truck</vi> <vi>The encyclopedia is an excellent <it>all-around</it> resource.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all but"> <hw>all but</hw> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:very nearly :<sx>almost</sx> <vi>Without you the job would have been <it>all but</it> impossible.</vi> <vi>We had <it>all but</it> given up hope.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all clear"> <hw>all clear</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the all clear</dre> <def><dt>:a signal telling you that a situation is no longer dangerous <vi>“How will we know when it's safe to leave?” “I'll give you <it>the all clear</it> by blowing a whistle.”</vi> <vi>Doctors have given her <it>the all clear</it> [=have told her that she is healthy] and she should be back at work next week.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all-day"> <hw>all–day</hw> <sound><wav>allda01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑlˈdeɪ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:lasting throughout the day <vi>an <it>all-day</it> trip/event</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all-encompassing"> <hw>all–encompassing</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <vi>We're unlikely to find an <it>all-encompassing</it> solution.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
