<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="allowance"> <hw highlight="yes">al*low*ance</hw> <sound><wav>allowa03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈlawəns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>al*low*anc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an amount of money that is given to someone regularly or for a specific purpose <vi>a monthly <it>allowance</it> for household expenses</vi> <vi>a clothing <it>allowance</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a small amount of money that is regularly given to children by their parents <vi>Each of their children gets a weekly <it>allowance</it> of five dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an amount of something (such as time) that is allowed or available <vi>The schedule provides a generous <it>allowance</it> of time for sightseeing. [=provides a generous amount of time for sightseeing]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an amount that is regarded as acceptable or desirable <vi>the recommended daily <it>allowance</it> of vitamin C</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:an amount that is subtracted from the price of something <vi>When we bought our new car we got a trade-in <it>allowance</it> of $2,000 on our old car. [=the price of our new car was reduced by $2,000 because we traded in our old car]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:an amount of your earnings that you do not have to pay taxes on <vi>the <phrase>tax allowance</phrase> for married couples</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of thinking about or including something when you make a plan, calculation, etc. <vi>When you're comparing costs from different decades, you need to <phrase>make allowance for</phrase> inflation. [=you need to allow for inflation]</vi> <vi>His theory <phrase>makes no allowance for</phrase> [=does not allow for] the possibility that the disease may be genetic.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the act of regarding bad behavior or a mistake as less serious or bad because of some special situation or condition <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She performed poorly, but we should <phrase>make some allowance for</phrase> her inexperience. = Some <phrase>allowance should be made for</phrase> her inexperience. [=because she is inexperienced, we should not blame her too much for performing poorly]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>They performed poorly, but <it>allowances should be made</it> for their inexperience.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:the act of allowing something <vi>The lawyer protested the judge's <it>allowance</it> of the evidence.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
