<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="among"> <hw highlight="yes">among</hw> <sound><wav>among001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈmʌŋ</pr> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>amongst</va> <sound><wav>among002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈmʌŋst</pr></vr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or through (a group of people or things) <vi>The disease spread quickly <it>among</it> the members of the community.</vi> <vi>The house is nestled <it>among</it> the trees.</vi> <vi>The ball was hidden <it>among</it> the leaves.</vi> <vi>There were ducks <it>among</it> the geese.</vi> <vi>There were several hecklers scattered <it>among</it> the crowd.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in the presence of (a group of people) <vi>The leader was standing <it>among</it> [=<it>amidst</it>] his supporters.</vi> <vi>She enjoys spending time at home <it>among</it> [=<it>with</it>] family and friends.</vi> <vi>He lived <it>among</it> artists and writers.</vi> <vi>The people of the town were frightened to think that a killer might be living <it>among</it> them.</vi> <vi>Relax. <phrase>You're among friends</phrase> here. [=the people here are your friends]</vi> <snote>When people do something <phrase>among themselves</phrase>, they do it as a group without involving others. <vi>The brothers are always quarreling <it>among themselves</it>. [=are always quarreling with each other]</vi> <vi>They were unable to agree <it>among themselves</it>.</vi> <vi>We were joking <it>among ourselves</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about the opinions, feelings, etc., of a group of people <vi>There is much unhappiness <it>among</it> voters. [=many voters are unhappy]</vi> <vi>attitudes that are common <it>among</it> older people [=attitudes that many older people have]</vi> <vi>There is debate <it>among</it> researchers about the causes of this disease.</vi> <vi>a TV show that is popular <it>among</it> young women</vi> <vi>He is known <it>among</it> his colleagues as a reliable worker.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the group of people or things involved in or affected by something <vi>The new policy has led to increased competition <it>among</it> local businesses.</vi> <vi>There has been a high rate of illness <it>among</it> the children in this community.</vi> <vi>No one <it>among</it> them expected to survive.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that a person or thing is part of a larger group <vi>He is <it>among</it> her greatest admirers. [=he is one of her greatest admirers]</vi> <vi>He can be counted <it>among</it> the greatest players in the game's history.</vi> <vi><it>Among</it> his good qualities is honesty.</vi> <vi>He has many good qualities. Chief <it>among</it> them is his honesty.</vi> <vi><phrase>Among other things</phrase> she was president of her college class.</vi> <vi>She met with the company's president and vice president, <phrase>among others</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the group of people or things being considered, compared, etc. <vi>They compared several new cars but found few differences <it>among</it> them.</vi> <vi>We were allowed to choose (from) <it>among</it> several options.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:in shares to each of (a group of people) <vi>The property was divided equally <it>among</it> the four survivors. [=each of the four survivors received an equal share of the property]</vi> <vi>The food was distributed <it>among</it> the people.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe someone who is unusual or excellent in some way <vi>He is an actor <it>among</it> actors. [=he is a great actor]</vi> <vi>He was a giant <it>among</it> men. [=he was very famous, powerful, successful, etc.]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="equal[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">equal</hw> <altpr>ˈi:kwəl</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>equals</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:someone or something that is as good, skillful, valuable, etc., as another person or thing <vi>I consider him my <it>equal</it>.</vi> <vi>They say they are producing wine that is the <it>equal</it> of the best wines in the world. [=that is as good as the best wines in the world]</vi> <vi>We are all <it>equals</it> here.</vi> <vi>He has no <it>equal</it> at chess. = He is <phrase>without equal</phrase> at chess. [=no one plays chess as well as he does]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>first among equals</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="first[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">first</hw> <sound><wav>first001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɚst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:coming before all others in time, order, or importance <vi>She won <it>first</it> prize.</vi> <vi>We sat in the <it>first</it> row.</vi> <vi>his <it>first</it> wife</vi> <vi>her <it>first</it> book/child</vi> <vi>in the <it>first</it> century</vi> <vi>his <it>first</it> offense</vi> <vi>her <it>first</it> kiss</vi> <vi>She succeeded on her <it>first</it> attempt/try.</vi> <vi>He was (the) <it>first</it> in line.</vi> <vi>We will correct these errors at the <it>first</it> opportunity. [=as soon as it is possible to do so]</vi> <vi>English is not my <it>first</it> [=<it>native</it>] language. [=it is not the language I learned first; I learned to speak another language before I learned to speak English]</vi> <vi>She's in <it>first</it> grade. [=the first level in school after kindergarten]</vi> <vi>I still remember the <it>first</it> time I saw her.</vi> <vi>You should leave at the <it>first</it> [=<it>earliest</it>] hint of trouble.</vi> <vi>My <it>first</it> [=<it>initial</it>] impulse was to say no.</vi> <vi>This is a matter of the <it>first</it> [=<it>highest</it>] importance.</vi> <vi>Your <it>first</it> [=<it>main</it>] concern should be to get well.</vi> <vi>the captain and the <phrase>first mate</phrase> [=the officer on a ship who is most important after the captain]</vi> <vi>She was accused of murder <phrase>in the first degree</phrase>. [=first-degree murder; the most serious kind of murder]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to refer to the lowest forward gear or speed of a vehicle <vi>I couldn't get the car out of <it>first</it> gear.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:having or playing the main part in a group of instruments <vi><it>first</it> violin</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at first blush</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>at first glance</va> <vl>also</vl> <va>at first sight</va></vr> <def><dt>:when first seen or considered <vi><it>At first blush</it>, the proposal seems ridiculous.</vi> <vi>It appears <it>at first glance/sight</it> to be a simple matter of hiring more people.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at first hand</dre> <def><dt>:in a direct way :<sx>firsthand</sx> <vi>I had a chance to verify his claims <it>at first hand</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>first among equals</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person who is <it>first among equals</it> is the leader of a group of people but is officially considered equal in rights and status to the other members of the group. <vi>As a director, he encourages collaboration and considers himself only (the) <it>first among equals</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>first thing</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the first thing</bnote> <dt>:anything at all <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't know/understand <it>the first thing</it> about the problems we've been having.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:before anything else :right away :very early <vi>I'll be back <it>first thing</it> (on) Monday morning.</vi> <vi>She promised to call <it>first thing</it> in the morning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>first things first</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that you should do the things that are most important before doing other things <vi>I know you're eager to start shopping for a car, but <it>first things first</it>—you need to find out how much you can afford to spend.</vi> <vi>You must set priorities and learn how to <phrase>put first things first</phrase>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the first flush of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>flush</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the first instance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>instance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the first place</dre> <dx>see <dxt>place</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>love at first sight</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
