<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="amount[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">amount</hw> <sound><wav>amount01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈmaʊnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>amounts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a quantity of something <vi>The drug is not being produced in adequate <it>amounts</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>They are not producing an adequate <it>amount of</it> the drug. [=they are not producing enough of the drug]</vi> <vi>A considerable/fair/great/large/tremendous <it>amount of</it> research went into the report.</vi> <vi>Be sure to add the right <it>amount of</it> salt.</vi> <vi>She spent amazing/enormous <it>amounts of</it> time planning her garden.</vi> <vi>There's a certain <it>amount of</it> truth to/in what you say. [=there is some truth in what you say]</vi> <vi>The new law limits the <it>amount of</it> money a candidate can spend.</vi> <vi>We have <phrase>any amount of</phrase> available resources. = We have a large <it>amount of</it> available resources.</vi> <vi><phrase>No amount of</phrase> money can make up for their loss. [=money cannot make up for their loss]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a quantity of money <vi>What is the <it>amount</it> to be paid?</vi> <vi>An <it>amount</it> was finally agreed upon.</vi> <vi>The new law limits the <it>amount</it> a candidate can spend.</vi> <vi>When he died we found he owed money <phrase>to/in the amount of</phrase> $250,000!</vi></dt> <usage><it>Amount</it> is chiefly used with noncount nouns. <vi>He lost a large <it>amount</it> of money.</vi> <vi>a minimum <it>amount</it> of effort</vi> <vi>They provided only a small <it>amount</it> of information.</vi> It is also sometimes used with plural count nouns, but this use is often criticized as an error. <vi>There were a large <it>amount</it> of mistakes.</vi> <it>Number</it> is the usual word in such contexts. <vi>a large <it>number</it> of mistakes</vi> <vi>an increasing <it>number</it> of problems</vi></usage></def></entry>

	<entry id="amount[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">amount</hw> <altpr>əˈmaʊnt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>amounts</if></in> <in><if>amount*ed</if></in> <in><if>amount*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>amount to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>amount to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to produce (a total) when added together <vi>The bill <it>amounted to</it> 10 dollars.</vi> <vi>They have debts <it>amounting to</it> thousands of dollars.</vi> <vi>The number of people taking part <it>amounted to</it> no more than a few hundred.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to turn out to be (something or someone important, impressive, etc.) <vi>The problems didn't <phrase>amount to much</phrase>. [=the problems were not very bad]</vi> <vi>I don't think he'll ever <phrase>amount to anything</phrase>. [=achieve success]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be the same in meaning or effect as (something) <vi>acts that <it>amount to</it> treason</vi> <vi>Anything less than total victory would <it>amount to</it> failure/failing. [=would be the same as failure/failing]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="thing"> <hw highlight="yes">thing</hw> <sound><wav>thing001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈθɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>things</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an object whose name is not known or stated <vi>What is that <it>thing</it> on the floor?</vi> <vi>That <it>thing</it> is loud.</vi> <vi>He is good at making <it>things</it> out of clay.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an object, animal, quality, etc., of any kind <vi>My doctor told me to avoid fatty <it>things</it> like donuts and potato chips.</vi> <vi>We must respect all living <it>things</it>.</vi> <vi>She loves all <it>things</it> chocolate. [=she loves anything made out of chocolate]</vi> <vi>Her voice is a <it>thing</it> of great beauty. [=her voice is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The disease is said to be <phrase>a thing of the past</phrase>. [=the disease no longer exists]</vi> <vi>The drawer has pens, paper clips, <phrase>and things (like that)</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a particular event, occurrence, or situation <vi>Birth is a miraculous <it>thing</it>.</vi> <vi>It was the worst <it>thing</it> that could have happened.</vi> <vi>That sunset was the most beautiful <it>thing</it> I have ever seen.</vi> <vi>Let's just forget about the whole <it>thing</it> and move on.</vi> <vi>The one <it>thing</it> I hate most is being lied to.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>a good thing</phrase> (that) no one was injured.</vi> <vi>Becoming friends with your boss is <phrase>not a bad thing</phrase>. = Becoming friends with your boss is <phrase>no bad thing</phrase>. [=becoming friends with your boss could have good results]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:objects that belong to a person :personal possessions or belongings <vi>Are all your <it>things</it> packed?</vi> <vi>I need a place to store my <it>things</it>.</vi> <vi>The children's <it>things</it> are always lying around on the floor.</vi> <vi>When she realized she was late for work, she quickly put on her <it>things</it> [=she put on her clothes, shoes, etc.] and left.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:objects that are used for a particular activity <vi>Put the cleaning <it>things</it> away when you are done.</vi> <vi>She got out the cooking <it>things</it> to bake some cookies.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an action that is done, that will be done, or that needs to be done <vi>I have many <it>things</it> to do today. = I have lots of <it>things</it> that need to get done today.</vi> <vi>There are a few <it>things</it> we still have to deal with.</vi> <vi>There is actually one <it>thing</it> you can do to help.</vi> <vi>Let's get this <it>thing</it> over with quickly.</vi> <vi>That was a mean/cruel/kind/generous/thoughtful <it>thing</it> to do.</vi> <vi>They expect great <it>things</it> from her. [=they expect her to be very successful]</vi> <vi>The boy did <phrase>the right thing</phrase> and gave back the toy he took.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>no easy thing</phrase> [=it's not easy] to raise three children by yourself.</vi> <vi>Cathy and I hit it off on our first date. <phrase>One thing led to another</phrase>, and pretty soon we were engaged.</vi> <un>sometimes used to say that one action is more serious, difficult, or important than another. <vi>It is one <it>thing</it> to say you're sorry but (it is) another (<it>thing</it>) to actually mean it.</vi> <vi>Planning a project is one <it>thing</it>; doing it is another.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an activity <vi>What <it>things</it> do you like to do in your spare time?</vi> <vi>I like hiking, biking—that sort of <it>thing</it>.</vi> <vi>The students are allowed to <phrase>do their own thing</phrase>. [=do the activities that they want to do]</vi> <vi>Just <phrase>do your thing</phrase> [=do what you usually do] and pretend I'm not here.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity that is done by a particular group of people <vi>They spent the evening doing guy <it>things</it>. [=doing the kind of things that guys/men tend to like doing]</vi> <vi>You wouldn't understand, Dad. It's a girl <it>thing</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity and everything that is related to it <un>usually singular <vi>He tried the college <it>thing</it> [=he tried going to college] but dropped out after the first semester.</vi> <vi>She's done with the whole rebellious teenager <it>thing</it>. [=she's done being a rebellious teenager]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity that someone enjoys or does well <un>usually singular <vi>Ballroom dancing is his <it>thing</it>, not mine.</vi> <vi>It's not really my (kind of) <it>thing</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the conditions that exist at a particular time and in a particular place <vi><it>Things</it> are improving. [=the situation is improving]</vi> <vi>How are <it>things</it> with the new baby?</vi> <vi>You're just making <it>things</it> more difficult for yourself.</vi> <vi>As <it>things</it> stand now [=in the current situation], we can't afford a new car.</vi> <vi>An apology would not change <it>things</it> between us.</vi> <vi><phrase>All things considered</phrase> [=<it>overall</it>; when you think about everything that happened], the party went very well.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a fact or piece of information about something or someone <vi>He checks every little <it>thing</it>. [=<it>detail</it>]</vi> <vi>There are a lot of <it>things</it> you don't know about us.</vi> <vi>The <it>thing</it> I don't understand is why the car costs so much.</vi> <vi>When buying a car, price and performance are important <it>things</it> to consider.</vi> <vi>There is one more <it>thing</it> I'd like to ask you.</vi> <vi>Several <it>things</it> were discussed at the meeting.</vi> <vi>I'll give you a couple of days to <phrase>think things over</phrase>. [=to think about the situation and make a decision]</vi> <vi>We are always arguing, but <phrase>the (funny) thing is</phrase>, I think I love him.</vi> <vi><it>The thing is</it> that [=it is important to understand that] you can never predict who will win.</vi> <vi>I make excellent chili. <it>The thing is</it> to pick the right peppers. [=to make excellent chili, you need to pick the right peppers]</vi> <vi><phrase>The thing with/about</phrase> him [=an important characteristic to know about him] is that he is not reliable.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thought, idea, or opinion <vi>He just says the first <it>thing</it> that pops into his mind.</vi> <vi>Don't say <it>things</it> you might regret later.</vi> <vi>That was a terrible <it>thing</it> to say.</vi> <vi>He had some interesting <it>things</it> to suggest.</vi> <vi>She always knows the right <it>thing</it> to say.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a reason for something <vi>I can't stand being around him. <phrase>For one thing</phrase>, he smokes. For another, he's rude.</vi> <vi>OK, <phrase>here's the thing</phrase>: I don't have enough money to go to college.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I didn't call you. <phrase>The thing is</phrase>, I've been really busy with work and school.</vi> <vi><phrase>The thing is that</phrase> I haven't had time to call you.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a goal or purpose <vi>The <it>thing</it> is to get well, and then you can think about playing again.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a way of reaching or achieving a goal <vi>There is only one <it>thing</it> left for us to do: fight back!</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) <phrase>There's only one thing for it</phrase>: we must fight.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used for a person, animal, or object that causes strong feelings of affection or dislike in you <vi>You poor <it>thing</it>, you must be freezing.</vi> <vi>She's a pretty little <it>thing</it>, isn't she!</vi> <vi>Get that dirty <it>thing</it> out of my house!</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a strong feeling of liking or disliking something or someone <un>usually singular</un> <un>used with <it>have</it> <vi>She <it>has</it> a <it>thing</it> about snakes. [=she's afraid of snakes]</vi> <vi>He has always <it>had</it> this <it>thing</it> with flying.</vi> <vi>My teacher <it>had</it> this/a <it>thing</it> against me. [=my teacher disliked me for some unknown reason]</vi> <vi>He <it>has</it> a <it>thing</it> for [=he likes] women with red hair.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <bnote>the thing</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the item that is the most fashionable or popular <vi>Long skirts are <it>the thing</it> to wear this season.</vi> <vi>It's <it>the</it> newest/latest <it>thing</it> in fashion.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the fashionable or proper way of behaving, talking, or dressing <vi>It's <it>the thing</it> this year to buy products made from recycled materials.</vi> <vi>Wearing athletic shoes with a suit is not quite <it>the thing</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all/other things being equal</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt><un>used to say what should happen or be true if two situations, products, etc., are different in a specified way but not in other ways <vi><it>All things being equal</it>, a person with a PhD should be getting a higher salary than someone with only a Master's degree.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all things to all people/men</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that makes all people happy by giving them what they want or need <vi>It was clear that the senator was trying to be <it>all things to all people</it> in her campaign.</vi> <vi>The museum is <it>all things to all people</it>, young and old.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>amount to the same thing</dre> <def><dt><snote>If two or more things <it>amount to the same thing</it>, there is very little difference between them. <vi>“Lying and cheating <it>amount to the same thing</it>,” she said.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a thing</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>anything</sx> <un>used in negative statements <vi>I can't see <it>a thing</it> [=I can see nothing] without my glasses on.</vi> <vi>The guests will be here soon, and I don't have <it>a thing</it> (that is appropriate) to wear.</vi> <vi>Don't worry about <it>a thing</it>. I'll take care of everything.</vi> <vi>I can't do <it>a thing</it> to stop them!</vi> <vi>I got there early so I wouldn't miss <it>a thing</it>.</vi> <vi>The police couldn't get <it>a thing</it> out of him.</vi> <vi>She refused to tell me <it>a thing</it> about it.</vi> <vi>I haven't heard <it>a thing</it> from him since graduation.</vi> <vi>We haven't had <it>a thing</it> to eat all day.</vi> <vi>Forget what he said—<phrase>it doesn't mean a thing</phrase>. [=it has no meaning or importance; it's not true]</vi> <vi>None of this will <it>mean a thing</it> if we lose.</vi> <vi>She doesn't look <phrase>a thing like</phrase> [=<it>anything like</it>] her older sister.</vi> <vi>His new album doesn't sound <it>a thing like</it> his last one. [=his new album sounds nothing like his old one]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a thing or two</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:some useful information <vi>I know <it>a thing or two</it> about cars.</vi> <vi>When it comes to cooking, she could teach you <it>a thing or two</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the center of things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>center</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be hearing things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>chance would be a fine thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first things first</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have another thing coming</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone is wrong or mistaken <vi>If he thinks he can fool me, he <it>has another thing coming</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just the thing</dre> <def><dt>:the thing that is most likely to be helpful <vi>Chicken soup is <it>just the thing</it> for a cold.</vi> <vi>I know <it>just the thing</it> to cheer you up—ice cream!</vi> <vi>He always does/says <phrase>just the right thing</phrase> to make me feel better.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>last thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>last</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make a big thing</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you <it>make a big thing (out) of (something)</it> or <it>make a big thing about (something)</it>, you act as if something is very important or serious when it is not. <vi>It was a minor error, but she <it>made a big thing out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> such <it>a big thing about</it> missing the bus: there'll be another one along in a minute.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no such thing</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that a particular person, object, etc., does not really exist <vi>A perfect person? There's <it>no such thing</it>.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>There is <it>no such thing as</it> a unicorn.</vi> <vi>There is <it>no such thing as</it> bad publicity. All publicity is good.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you did not say or do something that someone believes or says you did <vi>“Why did you invite her?” “I did <it>no such thing</it>. She just showed up.”</vi> <vi>“He said that you're not going with us.” “I said <it>no such thing</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of all things</dre> <def><dt><un>used to emphasize that the thing you are referring to is the thing you would least expect <vi>The coach is making the entire football team take, <it>of all things</it>, ballet classes.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one of those things</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to refer to a bad or unfortunate experience that happened and to say that such experiences happen to everyone <vi>I missed the train and had to take a later one. It was just <it>one of those things</it>, I guess.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one thing after another</dre> <def><dt><un>used to complain about the large number of bad or unfortunate events that happen to someone <vi>It's <it>one thing after another</it> with him. Now he's in jail for drunk driving.</vi> <vi>First I locked my keys in the car, and then I spilled coffee all over myself. It was just <it>one thing after another</it> today!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>push things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>push</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>see</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sure thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the real thing</dre> <def><dt>:something that is genuine and not a copy or imitation :something that is truly valuable or important <vi>The diamond turned out to be <it>the real thing</it>.</vi> <vi>a substitute for <it>the real thing</it></vi> <vi>You've done very well in your training. Let's just hope you're ready for <it>the real thing</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(what) with one thing and another</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you have been very busy doing or dealing with many things <vi><it>What with one thing and another</it>, I have very little free time.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
