<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="angle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">an*gle</hw> <sound><wav>angle001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæŋgəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>an*gles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the difference between the direction of two lines or surfaces that come together :the space or shape formed when two lines or surfaces meet each other <vi>The two lines form a sharp <it>angle</it>. = The two lines meet/intersect at a sharp <it>angle</it> (to each other).</vi> <vi>The two lines meet at a 30-degree <it>angle</it> to each other. = There is a 30-degree <it>angle</it> between the two lines.</vi> <vi>The lines are at sharp <it>angles</it> to each other.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>geometry</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>right angle</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a surface that is not level <vi>The hill slopes down/up at an <it>angle</it> of about 30 degrees.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that leans or goes to the side rather than straight up or directly forward <vi>The pole stood <phrase>at an angle</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The road goes off <phrase>at a sharp/slight angle</phrase> to the right/left.</vi> <vi>The rays of light shone through the window <it>at an angle</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the position from which something is approached, looked at, etc. <vi>Critics love the clever camera <it>angles</it> the director used in the film.</vi> <vi>She took pictures of the same scene from several different <it>angles</it>.</vi> <vi>The soldiers were being attacked from every <it>angle</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a way of thinking about, describing, or discussing something <vi>We need to approach the problem from a new/different <it>angle</it>.</vi> <vi>They considered the question from all <it>angles</it>.</vi> <vi>The reporter tried to work that <it>angle</it> into his story.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a secret and often improper reason for doing something <vi>I don't trust that guy, but I can't figure out what his <it>angle</it> is yet.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a clever and often improper way of doing or getting something <vi>a salesman who's always looking for an <it>angle</it> [=looking for a way to convince people to buy the things he is selling]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="angle[2]"> <hw hindex="2">angle</hw> <altpr>ˈæŋgəl</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>angles</if></in> <in><if>an*gled</if></in> <in><if>an*gling</if> <sound><wav>anglin01.wav</wav><wav>anglin01.wav</wav><wav>anglin01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæŋglɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to turn, move, or point something so that it is not straight or flat <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>One spotlight was put high in the corner and <it>angled</it> [=<it>pointed</it>] down toward the floor.</vi> <vi>The seats in the theater were <it>angled</it> so that we were looking almost straight up.</vi> <vi>The road was <it>angled</it> down toward the river.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>angled</it> [=<it>sloped</it>] down toward the river.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to present (something, such as a news story) in a particular way or from a particular point of view <vi>You should try to <it>angle</it> the story so that it appeals to younger readers.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) angled</it> <vi>The story <it>was angled</it> to appeal to younger readers.</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>angle</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="angle[3]"> <hw hindex="3">angle</hw> <altpr>ˈæŋgə</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>angles</if></in> <in><if>angled</if></in> <in><if>angling</if> <altpr>ˈæŋglɪŋ</altpr></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fish with a hook and line <vi>go <it>angling</it> for trout</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>angler</dxt> <dxt>angling</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to try to get what you want in a clever or indirect way <vi>She's been <it>angling</it> to get a promotion.</vi> <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>She's <it>angling for</it> a promotion.</vi> <vi>They're all <it>angling for</it> a place on the committee.</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>angle</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="angle bracket"> <hw>angle bracket</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:either one of a pair of punctuation marks 〈 〉 used to enclose written material</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="oblique angle"> <hw>oblique angle</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ angles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>mathematics</sl> <dt>:an angle that is not 90 degrees :an acute or obtuse angle <vi>The dancer held his leg at an <it>oblique</it> angle to his body.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="right angle"> <hw>right angle</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ angles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an angle formed by two lines that are perpendicular to each other :an angle that measures 90° <vi>A square has four <it>right angles</it>.</vi> <vi>Hold the nail <phrase>at a right angle to</phrase> the board.</vi> <vi>The two boards are joined <phrase>at right angles to</phrase> each other.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="wide-angle lens"> <hw>wide–angle lens</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ lenses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a camera lens that you use to take pictures that show a wider view than other lenses</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
