<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="announce"> <hw highlight="yes">an*nounce</hw> <sound><wav>announ01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈnaʊns</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>an*nounc*es</if></in> <in><if>an*nounced</if></in> <in><if>an*nounc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) known in a public or formal way :to officially tell people about (something) <vi>The government <it>announced</it> a cut in taxes.</vi> <vi>They <it>announced</it> plans to move the company out of the state.</vi> <vi>The company president has <it>announced</it> her retirement.</vi> <vi>Their engagement was formally <it>announced</it> in the newspaper.</vi> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>The government <it>announced that</it> there would be a cut in taxes.</vi> <vi>A voice on the loudspeaker <it>announced that</it> the store was closing in 10 minutes.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The sound of the door slamming <it>announced</it> his departure. [=I knew he had left when I heard the door slam]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say (something) in a loud and definite way <vi>When everyone was sitting down, she abruptly <it>announced</it> [=<it>declared</it>] (to us) her intention to quit school.</vi> <vi>He suddenly stood up and <it>announced</it>, “I'm leaving.” = He suddenly stood up and <it>announced</it> that he was leaving.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say in a formal or official way that something or someone has arrived or is present or ready <vi>She <it>announced</it> dinner [=said that dinner was ready] promptly at six o'clock.</vi> <vi>Don't enter the president's office until you've been <it>announced</it>. [=until the president has been told that you are there]</vi> <vi>A man in a tuxedo <it>announced</it> each guest [=loudly told everyone the guests' names] as they arrived.</vi> <vi>We only had to wait a few minutes before our flight was <it>announced</it> [=<it>called</it>] over the loudspeaker.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to say that you are a candidate for a political office <vi>He is expected to <it>announce</it> for President [=to say that he is going to run for President] tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to describe (a sports event) on radio or television :to be the announcer for (a sports event) <vi>Do you know who's going to <it>announce</it> tonight's game?</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
