<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="answer[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">an*swer</hw> <sound><wav>answer01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈænsɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:nsə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>an*swers</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something you say or write when someone asks you a question <vi>I asked him a simple question and he gave me a long and confusing <it>answer</it>.</vi> <vi>I didn't believe her <it>answer</it>.</vi> <vi>They wouldn't give me a straight <it>answer</it> to my question.</vi> <vi>There will be a <phrase>question and answer session</phrase> [=a period of time when people can have their questions answered] following the speech.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a response to a question that is meant to show whether or not you know something (such as a question asked as part of an exam) <vi>I didn't know the right/correct <it>answer</it>.</vi> <vi>That is the wrong/incorrect <it>answer</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the correct response to a question <vi>Do you know the <it>answer</it> to this question?</vi> <vi>He knew the <it>answers</it> to only 3 of the 10 questions.</vi> <vi>The <it>answers</it> are listed in the back of the book.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something you say or write as a reaction to something someone else has said or done <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I sent a letter of complaint but I never got an <it>answer</it>. [=<it>response</it>]</vi> <vi>I finally received an <it>answer</it> [=<it>reply</it>] to my letter.</vi> <vi>When I say something to you I expect an <it>answer</it>. [=<it>response</it>]</vi> <vi>I called out her name but I got no <it>answer</it>. [=<it>reply</it>]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi><phrase>In answer</phrase> [=<it>in response</it>] to your request we are sending a catalog.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something you do in response to something that has happened :a reaction to something <un>usually singular <vi>I called several times but there was no <it>answer</it>. [=no one answered the phone when I called]</vi> <vi>I got no <it>answer</it> when I called.</vi> <vi>I knocked on the door but there was no <it>answer</it>. [=no one opened the door when I knocked on it]</vi> <vi>The company had no <it>answer</it> when its competitors lowered their prices.</vi> <vi>When she called him a liar, his only <it>answer</it> was to walk out.</vi> <vi>Our team had no <it>answer</it> for the other team's strong offense. [=our team could not win because of the other team's strong offense]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a solution to a problem :something that makes a bad situation better <vi>More money is not the <it>answer</it> (to our problems).</vi> <vi>It's a very difficult problem, and I don't know what the <it>answer</it> is.</vi> <vi>They don't have <it>answers</it> for everything. = They don't have an <it>answer</it> for everything.</vi> <vi>For a tough issue like this there are no easy <it>answers</it>.</vi> <vi>He thinks he <phrase>has/knows all the answers</phrase>. [=he thinks that he knows the solution to every problem]</vi> <snote>Someone or something that is <phrase>the answer to (all) your prayers</phrase> provides you with something that you want or need. <vi>If you've been wanting to get your schedule organized, this new software is <it>the answer to (all) your prayers</it>.</vi> <vi>They were desperate to find a good lawyer, and they thought she might be <it>the answer to their prayers</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something or someone that resembles a well-known or successful thing or person <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>The program is television's <it>answer to</it> newsmagazines. [=the program is similar to a newsmagazine]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="answer[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">answer</hw> <altpr>ˈænsɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:nsə</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>answers</if></in> <in><if>answered</if></in> <in><if>answer*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to say or write something when someone asks you a question :to give an answer to (a question) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>answered</it> all my questions.</vi> <vi>He <it>answered</it> only three of the test questions correctly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>When the police asked him his name, he refused to <it>answer</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>answered</it> correctly/incorrectly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or write (something) as a reply <vi>When asked if she would run for office, she <it>answered</it> that she hadn't decided. = When asked if she would run for office, she <it>answered</it> “I haven't decided.”</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to reply to (someone) :to say or write something as a response to (someone) <vi>When I ask you a question I expect you to <it>answer</it> me!</vi> <vi><it>Answer</it> me this: where have you put my money?</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to write a response to a letter, e-mail message, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I sent her a letter asking for her help, but she never <it>answered</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She never <it>answered</it> my letter. = She never <it>answered</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to pick up (a ringing telephone) <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The phone rang repeatedly, but no one <it>answered</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Would somebody please <it>answer</it> the phone?</vi> <vi><it>answer</it> a phone call</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to open a door when someone knocks on it <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I knocked on the door but no one <it>answered</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>No one <it>answered</it> the door.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to act in response to (something) :to react to (something) by taking some action <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I got the job by <it>answering</it> a “help wanted” ad in the newspaper.</vi> <vi>When the war began, thousands of young men <it>answered</it> the call to arms. [=thousands of young men joined the armed forces]</vi> <vi>He <it>answered</it> her anger with indifference. [=he responded to her anger by acting indifferent]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The home team scored first but the visiting team <it>answered</it> quickly. [=the visiting team also scored soon after the home team scored]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say something in response to (something, such as an accusation) :to defend yourself against (something) <vi>The police chief will appear in court today to <it>answer</it> charges of corruption.</vi> <vi><it>answer</it> criticism</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be the same as (something) :to be in agreement with (something, such as a description) <vi>The suspect <it>answered</it> [=<it>matched</it>] the description that had been given by the witness.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>answer to <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be what is needed for (something) <vi>We don't have a sink, but this bucket will <it>answer</it> [=(more commonly) <it>serve</it>] the purpose. [=we can use this bucket as a sink]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>answer for <dxn>1c (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>answer back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to reply to someone especially in a rude way <vi>impolite children who <it>answer back</it> [=<it>talk back</it>] when their teacher corrects them</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer (someone) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reply rudely to (someone) <vi>He became angry when she <it>answered him back</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>answer for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take responsibility for (something) <vi>I can't <it>answer for</it> their safety. [=I can't promise that they will be safe]</vi> :to be responsible for (something) <vi>The company will have to <it>answer for</it> any damage done by its employees.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>has a lot to answer for</phrase>. [=she is responsible for many bad things that have happened]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be punished for (something) <vi>He must <it>answer for</it> his crimes.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to be used as (something) :to serve as (something) <vi>The old bucket <it>answered for</it> a sink. [=the old bucket was used as a sink]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>answer <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say what someone else thinks :to give the opinion of (someone else) <vi>I like the proposal myself, but I can't <it>answer for</it> my boss.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>answer someone's prayers</dre> <def><dt>:to provide what someone hopes or prays for <vi>They hoped that God would <it>answer their prayers</it> and restore their son's health.</vi> <vi><it>Their prayers were answered</it> when their son's health was restored.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>answer to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be the same as (something) :to be in agreement with (something, such as a description) <vi>The suspect <it>answers to</it> [=<it>answers, matches</it>] the description perfectly.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>answer <dxn>5 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be required to explain your actions to (someone) <vi>He has to <it>answer to</it> a tough boss.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>answer to a name</pva></phrasev> <dt><snote>If an animal, such as a dog, <it>answers to a name</it>, it responds when it is called by that name. <vi>This dog <it>answers to the name</it> (of) “Rover.”</vi> This phrase is also used to refer to the name used by a person. <vi>My uncle's real name is “Edwin,” but he doesn't <it>answer to that name</it>. He prefers to be called “Ed.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>an*swer*er</ure> <sound><wav>answer03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈænsɚɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>an*swer*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
