<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="anybody"> <hw highlight="yes">any*body</hw> <sound><wav>anybod01.wav</wav><wav>anybod02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛniˌbɑ:di, ˈɛniˌbʌdi</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:any person :<sx>anyone</sx> <vi>Did <it>anybody</it> call?</vi> <vi>I don't know how <it>anybody</it> can believe that.</vi> <vi>I thought I heard someone outside, but when I looked there wasn't <it>anybody</it> there. [=no one was there]</vi> <vi>An accident like that could happen to <it>anybody</it>.</vi> <vi>You have to be a member to go there. They won't let <phrase>just anybody</phrase> in.</vi> <vi><phrase>Everybody who's anybody</phrase> [=every important or well-known person] was there.</vi> <vi>She arrived 10 minutes before <phrase>anybody else</phrase>. [=before any other person]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used when asking a question that could be answered by any of the people in a group <vi>Does <it>anybody</it> know where my keys are? [=do any of you know where my keys are?]</vi> <vi>Would <it>anybody</it> like more coffee?</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="guess[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">guess</hw> <altpr>ˈgɛs</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>guesses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an attempt to give an opinion or answer about something when you do not know much about it or are not sure about it <vi>I'm not sure how old he is, but I'm willing to hazard/venture a <it>guess</it>.</vi> <vi>My <it>guess</it> is that he'll change his story when he realizes how much trouble he's in.</vi> <vi>There might be about 20 people there, but that's just a (rough) <it>guess</it>.</vi> <vi>If you don't know the answer, <phrase>make a guess</phrase>. = (<it>US</it>) If you don't know the answer, <phrase>take a guess</phrase>. = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) If you don't know the answer, <phrase>have a guess</phrase>.</vi> <vi>“How many people will be there?” “I don't know. <phrase>Your guess is as good as mine</phrase>.” [=I don't know any more than you do]</vi> <vi>“I have no idea how many peanuts are in the jar.” “Take a <phrase>wild guess</phrase>.” [=a guess based on no knowledge or information]</vi> <snote>An <phrase>educated/informed guess</phrase> is a guess that is probably close to being correct because it is based on some amount of knowledge. <vi>Forecasters will be making an <it>educated guess</it> about the demand for electricity this summer.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>anybody's/anyone's guess</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that is <it>anybody's/anyone's guess</it> is something that is very uncertain or that no one knows. <vi>What causes these changes is <it>anybody's guess</it>. [=no one knows what causes these changes]</vi> <vi>It's <it>anyone's guess</it> what his next book will be about.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
