<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="anything"> <hw highlight="yes">any*thing</hw> <sound><wav>anythi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛniˌθɪŋ</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a thing of any kind <vi>We were allowed to do <it>anything</it> we wanted to.</vi> <vi>If you're not sure what to say, just say <it>anything</it> that comes to mind.</vi> <vi>She didn't say <it>anything</it> at all. [=she said nothing at all]</vi> <vi>That dog will eat almost/nearly/practically/virtually <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>We didn't talk about <it>anything</it> much.</vi> <vi>The new stadium is spectacular. There's never been <it>anything</it> like it.</vi> <vi>She never does <it>anything</it> but complain. [=all she does is complain]</vi> <vi>I'll do <it>anything</it> I can to help.</vi> <vi>They were ready for <it>anything</it> (that might happen).</vi> <vi>You can't tell him <it>anything</it> about computers. He thinks he's an expert.</vi> <vi>I can't think of her as <it>anything</it> but a good friend. [=I can only think of her as a good friend]</vi> <vi>He'll do <it>anything</it> for a laugh.</vi> <vi>I'd do/give <it>anything</it> to see her again.</vi> <vi>He won't take <it>anything</it> from anyone. [=he won't allow anyone to mistreat him, to be rude to him, etc.]</vi> <vi>She ate hardly <it>anything</it>. [=she ate almost nothing]</vi> <vi>He said he was sorry, but that doesn't really mean <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>I don't have <it>anything</it> against them. [=I don't have any reason for disliking them]</vi> <vi>She thought it was funny but I didn't see <it>anything</it> funny about it. [=I didn't think it was funny at all]</vi> <vi>They've been doing <phrase>everything and anything</phrase> to finish on time. = They've been doing <phrase>anything and everything</phrase> to finish on time.</vi> <vi>The problems were caused by lack of time <phrase>as much as anything</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <phrase>anything goes</phrase>. [=anything is acceptable; there are no rules that have to be followed]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>something</sx> <un>used in questions <vi>Would you like <it>anything</it> else?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> wrong?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> (good/interesting) on TV tonight?</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Do you want some pretzels <phrase>or anything</phrase>? [=or a similar thing]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything but</dre> <def><dt>:not at all <vi>He looked <it>anything but</it> happy. [=he looked very unhappy]</vi> <vi>Though he said he was happy, he looked <it>anything but</it> (happy).</vi> <vi>This problem is <it>anything but</it> new.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>anything like</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at all like <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>anything near</va></svr> <dt>:in any way :at all <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi> <vi>The movie wasn't <it>anything like/near</it> what I expected it to be. [=the movie was completely different from what I expected it to be]</vi> <vi>We don't have <it>anything like/near</it> enough time. [=we don't have nearly enough time]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:as any person or thing <un>used to make a statement more forceful <vi>He was (<it>as</it>) calm <it>as anything</it>. [=he was very calm]</vi> <vi>It was as obvious <it>as anything</it> [=it was extremely obvious] that she didn't want to go.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for anything</dre> <def><dt>:for any reason <un>used in negative statements <vi>I like my life, and I wouldn't change it <it>for anything</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if anything</dre> <dx>see <dxt>if</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very much :very forcefully <vi>It was raining <it>like anything</it>. [=it was raining very hard]</vi> <vi>She was hoping <it>like anything</it> that the weather would be good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than anything</dre> <def><dt>:very much :very badly <vi>I wanted to believe her <it>more than anything</it> [=I very much wanted to believe her], but I couldn't.</vi> <vi><it>More than anything</it> (in the world), I'd like to visit Paris again. [=the thing I most want to do is to visit Paris again]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="go[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">go</hw> <sound><wav>go000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>goes</if> <sound><wav>go000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊz</pr></in> <in><if>went</if> <sound><wav>go000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>gone</if> <sound><wav>gone0001.wav</wav><wav>go000003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:n</pr></in> <in><if>go*ing</if> <sound><wav>go000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a place <vi>He <it>went</it> to the window and looked out at the yard.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes</it> to the office every morning and comes home in the evening.</vi> <vi>I'm tired. Let's <it>go</it> home.</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> downstairs to the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The train <it>goes</it> from New York to Chicago.</vi> <vi>Halt! <phrase>Who goes there</phrase>? [=who is there?; who is coming this way?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to travel to and stay in (a place) for a particular amount of time <vi>I <it>went</it> with my family to Rome last year.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going to</it> Iowa for a week.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move or travel in a particular way or for a particular distance <vi>The car was <it>going</it> too fast.</vi> <vi>How much farther do we have to <it>go</it>?</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> a long way to see him.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> many miles that day.</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> straight for two blocks, then <it>go</it> right/left at the light.</vi> <vi>The street is blocked, so we'll have to <it>go</it> around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their relationship doesn't seem to be <it>going</it> anywhere. [=doesn't seem to be making any progress]</vi> <vi><phrase>Where do we go from here</phrase>? [=what do we do now?]</vi> <vi>We've accomplished a lot, but we still have <phrase>a long way to go</phrase>. [=we have much more to do]</vi> <vi>She has a lot of talent. If she works hard, she should <phrase>go far</phrase>. [=she should be very successful]</vi> <vi>These changes will <phrase>go a long way</phrase> toward solving the dispute.</vi> <vi>Would you <phrase>go so far</phrase> as to call them dishonest? [=would you say that they are dishonest?]</vi> <vi>This time you've <phrase>gone too far</phrase>! [=you've done something that cannot be allowed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move to or be at a place (such as an office or school) for work, study, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> church on Sunday.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> work from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</vi> <vi>Their son is <it>going to</it> college in Florida. [=he is attending a college in Florida]</vi> <vi>He <it>went to</it> prison for his crimes.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something that involves moving or traveling to a place <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're <it>going on</it> vacation next week.</vi> <vi>The thieves <it>went on</it> a crime spree.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>The neighbors <it>went running</it> [=the neighbors ran] when they heard the screams.</vi> <vi>I like to <it>go walking/swimming/shopping</it>. [=I like to walk/swim/shop]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>go for <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or travel to a place for a particular purpose <vi>I <it>went</it> to see them last week.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> to see a movie last night. = We <it>went</it> to a movie last night.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> to the wedding? [=do you plan to attend the wedding?]</vi> <vi>I may <it>go</it> to see them next week. = I may <it>go</it> and see them next week. = (<it>US</it>) I may <it>go</it> see them next week.</vi> <snote>In informal spoken English, <phrase>go and</phrase> is used to emphasize a following verb. It usually expresses anger or annoyance. <vi>Now you've <it>gone and</it> ruined it!</vi> <vi>They <it>went and</it> changed it!</vi> <vi><it>Go and</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>go</it> by itself is also sometimes used this way. <vi>Why did you have to <it>go</it> ruin it?!</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to engage in (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>Don't <it>go telling</it> everyone what happened. [=don't tell everyone what happened]</vi> <vi>He <it>went blabbing</it> the news all over the place.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>It's getting late. I should <it>go</it> now.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>going</it> when the phone rang.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave a job, position, etc. <vi>Pack up your desk and <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>She's retiring soon, and it'll be sad for all of us to see her <it>go</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to lie or move along a particular route or in a particular direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>goes</it> from the town to the lake.</vi> <vi>His land <it>goes</it> almost all the way down to the river.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> my way? [=are you going in the same direction that I'm going in?]</vi> <vi>The car <it>went</it> the length of the street and then turned around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She <it>went</it> the conventional route [=she did the conventional thing] by going straight to college after high school.</vi> <vi>He has always <phrase>gone his own way</phrase>. [=he has always done the things he wants to do instead of the things that most people do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to provide a way to get to a place <vi>That door <it>goes</it> to the cellar. [=you can get to the cellar by going through that door]</vi> <vi>Where does this road <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be sent <vi>The message <it>went</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be lost, used, or spent <vi>I don't know where the money <it>goes</it>.</vi> <vi>I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they're <it>gone</it>. = (<it>Brit</it>) I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they've <it>gone</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>all</it> <vi>The money was <it>all gone</it> by Friday. = <it>All</it> (of) the money was <it>gone</it> by Friday.</vi> <vi>“Is there any ice cream left?” “No, it's <it>all gone</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to die <vi>She <it>went</it> peacefully at about midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The time/day seemed to <it>go</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen in a particular way <vi>The evening <it>went</it> well/badly.</vi> <vi>She worked hard to make the party <it>go</it> according to plan.</vi> <vi><phrase>The way things are going</phrase> [=if things keep happening this way], I may get laid off.</vi> <vi>We lost the game, but <phrase>that's the way it/life goes</phrase>. [=it is a fact that bad or disappointing things will happen sometimes]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to talk or ask about how you are feeling <vi>“How are things <it>going</it>? = How's everything <it>going</it>? = How's it <it>going</it>?” “Everything's <it>going</it> well/fine/great.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be given up, thrown away, etc. <vi>I want to keep these, but that one can <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>These old boxes <phrase>have got to go</phrase>. = These old boxes <phrase>have to go</phrase>. [=we have to get rid of these old boxes]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be sold <vi>The house <it>went</it> for a good price.</vi> <vi>The cabinets <it>go</it> for about $400.</vi> <vi>The painting will <it>go</it> to the highest bidder</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be willing to pay a certain price for something <vi>I'll <it>go</it> as high as $100, but not over that.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail or become weak because of use, age, etc. <vi>His hearing has started to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>The batteries in the flashlight are <it>going</it> and will have to be changed.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break because of force or pressure <vi>The dam/roof is weakening and it could <it>go</it> at any time.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>Everyone's here, so I think we're ready to <it>go</it>. = (<it>US, informal</it>) I think we're <phrase>good to go</phrase>. [=I think we're ready to start]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get going</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the result of a contest, election, decision, etc. <vi>The election <it>went</it> in her favor. [=she won the election]</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went</it> against him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to work in the usual or expected way <vi>I couldn't get the car to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I kept working on the engine until I finally got it <it>going</it>. [=I finally got it to work/run]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>keep going</tag> at <dxt>keep</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>18 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to become <un>used to describe a change <vi>The building has <it>gone</it> condo. [=the building has become a condominium]</vi> <vi>British currency <it>went</it> decimal in 1971.</vi></un> <un>used especially to describe a change that is not wanted <vi>The tire <it>went</it> flat.</vi> <vi>The bread has <it>gone</it> stale.</vi> <vi>The company <it>went</it> bankrupt.</vi> <vi>Everything keeps <it>going</it> wrong.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change <vi>The leaves here <it>go</it> from green to red in the fall.</vi> <vi>The situation <it>went</it> from bad to worse.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe someone's or something's condition <vi>I like to <it>go</it> barefoot in the summer.</vi> <vi>There was nothing to eat, so we had to <it>go</it> hungry.</vi> <vi>My letters have <it>gone</it> unanswered. [=have not been answered]</vi> <vi>Her excellent work has not <it>gone</it> unnoticed/unappreciated. [=someone has noticed/appreciated her excellent work]</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make a particular movement <vi>Can you <it>go</it> like this with your eyebrows? [=can you move your eyebrows like this?]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to talk about a story, song, etc. <vi>I can't remember how the story <it>goes</it>. [=I can't remember what happens in the story]</vi> <vi>The story/rumor/legend <it>goes</it> that he left home poor and came back rich.</vi> <vi>The tune <it>goes</it> like this.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to fit in or through a space <vi>Will these clothes <it>go</it> in your suitcase? [=is there enough room for these clothes in your suitcase?]</vi> <vi>The box was too big to <it>go</it> [=<it>fit</it>] through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a usual or proper place or position :<sx>belong</sx> <vi>These books <it>go</it> on the top shelf.</vi> <vi>Where do your keys <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have authority :to require you to do what is said or demanded <vi><phrase>What she says goes</phrase>! [=she is the boss; you have to do what she tells you to do]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use the toilet <vi>One of the children said he had to <it>go</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go to the bathroom</tag> at <dxt>bathroom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to make a sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The bell <it>went</it> and the class came to an end.</vi> <vi>The music was <it>going</it> full blast. [=the music was being played as loud as possible]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The gun <it>went</it> bang.</vi> <vi>The cow <it>went</it> “moo.”</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say (something) <un>used in describing what people said in a conversation <vi>So she <it>goes</it>, “Did you write this?” and I <it>go</it>, “Mind your own business!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a sports team or player</ssl> <dt>:to have a specified record <vi>The team <it>went</it> 11–2 last season. [=the team won 11 games and lost 2 games last year]</vi> <vi>The shortstop <it>went</it> two for four in yesterday's game. [=the shortstop had two hits in four times at bat in yesterday's game]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything goes</dre> <def><dt>:anything is acceptable :there are no rules for behavior, dress, etc. <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <it>anything goes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as (someone or something) goes</dre> <def><dt><un>used to compare someone or something with someone or something else of the same kind <vi><it>As lectures go</it>, it was very interesting.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be available <vi>There <it>are</it> no jobs <it>going</it> right now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going to</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about what will happen or could happen <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> be cold tomorrow. [=it will be cold tomorrow]</vi> <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> rain: if you don't take an umbrella, you<it>'re going to</it> get soaked.</vi> <vi>I <it>am</it> not <it>going to</it> tolerate [=I won't tolerate] any more bad behavior!</vi> <vi>I <it>was</it> just <it>going to</it> call him. [=I was about to call him]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>gonna</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go about (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) <vi>I'd like to fix this old radio but I don't know how to <it>go about</it> (doing) it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>Despite the threat of war, most people are just quietly <phrase>going about their business</phrase>. [=most people are just doing the things that they usually do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go a bundle on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bundle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to follow and try to stop or catch (someone) <vi>When the boy ran out the door, his mother quickly <it>went after</it> him.</vi> <vi>The police <it>went after</it> the escaped criminal.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to find and punish (someone) <vi>The government is <it>going after</it> people who cheat on their taxes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something or someone) <vi>If you want the job, you should just <it>go after</it> it.</vi> <vi>She accused her friend of <it>going after</it> her husband.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not agree with (something) <vi>I won't do anything that <it>goes against</it> my conscience/beliefs/principles.</vi> <vi>values that <it>go against</it> those of society</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to oppose (someone or something) <vi>He was surprised when some of his former supporters <it>went against</it> him.</vi> <vi>He was reluctant to <it>go against</it> his parents' wishes. [=he was reluctant to do something that his parents did not want him to do]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to compete against (a player or team) in a contest or game <vi>The Red Sox will be <it>going against</it> the Yankees in tonight's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not be good for (someone) :to not produce the result that is wanted by (someone) <vi>Everything seemed to be <it>going against</it> her but she didn't give up hope.</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went against</it> the defendant. [=the verdict was not in favor of the defendant]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do or begin to do something <vi>Instead of waiting for approval, they just <it>went ahead</it> and started working on the project.</vi> :to do something after planning to do it or after getting permission to do it <vi>Despite the bad weather, they decided to <it>go ahead</it> with the party.</vi> <vi>My boss told me to <it>go ahead</it> (with the work).</vi> <vi>“Could I sit here?” “Sure, <it>go</it> (right) <it>ahead</it>.”</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more cake.” “Oh, <it>go ahead</it>. It won't kill you.”</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go-ahead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to happen or proceed <vi>Despite the weather, the party <it>went ahead</it> as planned.</vi> <vi>After a brief delay, the work is now <it>going ahead</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before the other person or group that is with you <vi>I'll <it>go</it> (on) <it>ahead</it> and make sure that everything's ready when you arrive.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <def><dt>:to do something with as much effort as possible <vi>When he has a party, he likes to <it>go all out</it>. [=have a big and expensive party]</vi> <vi>Her company always <it>went all out</it> [=did everything possible] to make the customer happy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-out</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all the way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue or proceed <vi>The project is <it>going along</it> smoothly.</vi> <vi>On this job there's a lot to learn—but I'm sure you'll pick it up as you <it>go along</it>.</vi> <vi>He was just making up the story as he <it>went along</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel with someone <vi>They were going to the fair so I asked whether I could <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I asked whether I could <it>go along with</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept what other people want <vi>We tried to convince him to support us but he refused to <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> us.</vi> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> our plan.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be part of something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes along with</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ape</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ape</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>go round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to go to different places <vi>She and her friends <it>go around</it> (together) to lots of clubs. = She <it>goes around</it> with her friends to lots of clubs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place that is nearby <vi>I <it>went round</it> [=<it>went over</it>] <it>to</it> his flat.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way a person often dresses or behaves <vi>She <it>goes around</it> (dressed) in a miniskirt.</vi> <vi>You can't <it>go around</it> treating people so rudely.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go or pass from one person to another person <vi>There's a rumor <it>going around</it> (the office) that the boss is about to get fired.</vi> <vi>An amusing story is <it>going around</it>.</vi> <vi>There's a nasty cold <it>going around</it>: I hope you don't catch it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be long enough to pass all the way around (something or someone) <vi>This belt isn't long enough to <it>go around</it> (my waist).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>If people want something and there is <phrase>enough/plenty to go around</phrase>, there is enough for all of the people who want it or need it. <vi>There aren't <it>enough jobs to go around</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>what goes around comes around</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that if you treat other people badly you will eventually be treated badly by someone else</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>They <it>went at</it> each other viciously.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to fight or argue <vi>Our neighbors were arguing again last night. They <it>went at it</it> for almost an hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make an effort to do or deal with (something) <vi>They had to <it>go at</it> the problem from many different angles before they finally solved it.</vi> <vi>It was a tough job, and I was impressed by the energetic way he <it>went at</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place or person <vi>She angrily told him to <it>go away</it> and stop bothering her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for a period of time <vi>They're <it>going away</it> on vacation.</vi> <vi>After graduating from high school, he <it>went away</it> to college.</vi> <vi>a <it>going-away</it> present/party [=a present/party for someone who is leaving to live, study, or travel in a distant place]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop existing or happening :to end <vi>I just wish there was some way to make the pain <it>go away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I forgot my purse and had to <it>go back</it> for it.</vi> <vi>What was it like to <it>go back</it> after so many years?</vi> <vi>After college she <it>went back</it> home.</vi> <vi><it>Go back</it> inside! You'll catch cold.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin doing something again <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>I turned off the alarm and <it>went back to</it> sleep.</vi> <vi>He waved hello, then <it>went</it> right <it>back to</it> work.</vi> <vi>She <it>went back to</it> eating her dinner.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>there's no going back</phrase> means that you have done or decided something and cannot change it. <vi>I've already signed the contract, so <it>there's no going back</it> now.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to have existed for a particular amount of time or since a particular period <vi>These ruins <it>go back</it> hundreds of years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a tradition that <it>goes back</it> [=<it>dates back</it>] <it>to</it> colonial times</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have known each other for a particular amount of time <vi>We <it>go back</it> 30 years.</vi> <vi>He and I <phrase>go back a long way</phrase>. = He and I <phrase>go way back</phrase>. [=he and I have known each other for many years]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to think or talk about something from the past <vi>To fully understand the issues, we have to <it>go back</it> a few years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'd like to <it>go back to</it> your earlier comment. [=I'd like to discuss it further]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go back on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>She <it>went back on</it> her promise to help us. [=she failed to keep her promise]</vi> <vi>I would never <it>go back on</it> my word.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to happen or exist at an earlier time than (someone) <vi>We owe a great debt of gratitude to those who <it>went before</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be considered by (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>The contestants will <it>go before</it> the judges tomorrow.</vi> <vi>The case <it>went before</it> the court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go beyond</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go beyond (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do more than (something) <vi>She <it>went beyond</it> the call of duty. [=she did more than was required]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>go beyond</it> merely talking about the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The morning seemed to <it>go by</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi> <vi>Many years have <it>gone by</it> since the last time I saw her.</vi> <vi>They have many happy memories of days <it>gone by</it>. [=bygone days, days/times in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be guided or directed by (something, such as a rule) <vi>That's a good rule to <it>go by</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion from (something) <vi>She may be guilty but we have very little evidence to <it>go by</it>.</vi> <vi>You can't always <it>go by</it> appearances. [=you can't always judge people or things by the way they look]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (a name)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be known by (a name) <vi>His name is Edwin but he <it>goes by</it> Ed. [=people call him Ed]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go by (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go somewhere in order to visit someone <vi>I <it>went by</it> (her house) to see her after school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall or crash to the ground <vi>The airplane <it>went down</it> when one of its engines caught fire.</vi> <vi>The boxer took a punch and <it>went down</it> hard.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to sink into the water <vi>The ship <it>went down</it> after hitting an iceberg.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go down</it> soon.</vi> <vi>The quality of his work has been <it>going down</it>.</vi> <vi>She had a fever yesterday, but it <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become less or smaller <vi>It may take a few hours for the swelling to <it>go down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become less bright <vi>The lights <it>went down</it> [=the lights were turned down] as the movie started.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to stop being visible in the sky :to set <vi>The sun comes up in the morning and <it>goes down</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to eat or drink something <vi>The medicine <it>went down</it> easily. [=it was easy to swallow the medicine]</vi> <vi>I took a sip but it <it>went down</it> the wrong way. [=I choked on my drink]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to accept or agree to something <vi>His suggestion didn't <it>go down</it> [=<it>go over</it>] very well with his boss. [=his boss didn't like his suggestion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to lose or fail <vi>Last year's champion <it>went down</it> in the first round of the tournament this year.</vi> <vi>The regime finally <it>went down</it> [=<it>fell</it>] in a wave of popular protest.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>of a computer, system, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The network <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to be remembered or talked about as an important person, event, etc. <vi>He will <it>go down</it> as one of the greatest leaders this country has ever known.</vi> <vi>His name will <phrase>go down in history</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be sent to prison <vi>He <it>went down</it> [=went to jail] for six years for the robbery.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to travel to a place (especially one that is nearby or to the south) <vi>I need to <it>go down</it> to the store for milk.</vi> <vi>We <it>went down</it> south to visit relatives.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to happen <vi>We need to find out what's <it>going down</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>going on</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to perform oral sex on (someone)</dt> <sn>14</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>He <it>went down with</it> [=<it>caught</it>, <it>came down with</it>] measles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go easy, go easy on/with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go figure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>My dog <it>went for</it> the intruder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something) <vi><it>go for</it> the prize</vi> <vi>If you want to achieve success, you have to stop hesitating and just <phrase>go for it</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to accept or agree to (something, such as a plan or suggestion) <vi>I asked her to lend us some money, but she wouldn't <it>go for</it> it. [=she wouldn't agree to lend us money]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to like or be attracted to (someone or something) <vi>When I see how she looks at him, I can tell she really <it>goes for</it> him.</vi> <vi>I don't really <it>go for</it> modern art.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>could go for</phrase> [=I would like] a cup of coffee right now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relate to or apply to (someone or something) <vi>The rule <it>goes for</it> you, too. [=the rule also applies to you]</vi> <vi>“I'd like ice cream for desert.” “That <it>goes for</it> me too.” [=I'd like ice cream too]</vi> <vi>The economy here has been growing stronger, and <phrase>the same goes for</phrase> [=the same is true for] many other areas.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a price)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be sold for (a particular price) <vi>The painting <it>went for</it> more than a million dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a walk, a drive, etc.)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do an activity (such as walking or driving a car) that usually involves going somewhere <vi>She <it>went for</it> a walk/stroll after dinner.</vi> <vi>On Saturday mornings we like to <it>go for</it> a drive out in the countryside.</vi> <vi>Would anyone like to <it>go for</it> a swim?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>have something going for you</phrase>, you have a talent, skill, etc., that helps you. <vi>She's not as young as some of the other athletes, but experience helps, and she <it>has that going for</it> her. [=she has an advantage because of her experience]</vi> <vi>You should be more confident in yourself. You <phrase>have a lot going for you</phrase>! [=you have many talents, abilities, etc.]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go great guns</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become hidden by a cloud <vi>The afternoon got cooler after the sun <it>went in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to like or be interested in (something) <vi>She doesn't <it>go in for</it> sports.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help pay for (something, such as a present) <vi>Are you going to <it>go in on</it> the gift for her?</vi> <vi>We all <it>went in on</it> the gift together. [=we all gave some money towards buying the gift]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to join (someone) in a business, project, etc. <vi>His brother-in-law <it>went in with</it> him on his new business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to start to be in (a different state or condition) <vi>After she lost her job she <it>went into</it> a deep depression. [=she became very depressed]</vi> <vi>The criminal has <phrase>gone into hiding</phrase>. [=the criminal is hiding]</vi> <vi>After losing the election, she <phrase>went into seclusion</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go into effect</tag> at <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to start to move in (a different and usually bad way) <vi>The car <it>went into</it> a skid. [=the car began to skid]</vi> <vi>The plane <it>went into</it> a tailspin.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) as a job or career <vi>He wants to <it>go into</it> the priesthood. [=he wants to become a priest]</vi> <vi>Their daughter is planning to <it>go into</it> medicine. [=to be a doctor; to get a job in the medical field]</vi> <vi>Both his sons have <it>gone into</it> the army. [=joined the army]</vi> <vi>His dream is to <phrase>go into business</phrase> for himself. [=to start his own business]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll try to tell the story without <it>going into</it> too many details. = I'll try not to <it>go into</it> too much detail.</vi> :to talk about the details of (something) <vi>Having <it>gone into</it> the causes of the French Revolution, the book then discusses its effects.</vi> <vi>“I've had a long day.” “What happened?” “I'll tell you later. I don't feel like <it>going into</it> it right now.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to get information about (something) <un>usually used as <it>(be) gone into</it> <vi>A problem like that should really <it>be gone into</it> [=<it>looked into</it>] carefully.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be used for (something) <vi>Lots of time, energy, and money have <it>gone into</it> (completing) the project.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt><un>used to say how many times a number can be multiplied to produce a larger number <vi>6 <it>goes into</it> 18 three times. [=18 divided by 6 equals 3]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go it alone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a bomb</ssl> <dt>:to explode <vi>The building was evacuated before the bomb <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a gun</ssl> <dt>:to shoot <vi>The gun <it>went off</it> accidentally.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of an alarm</ssl> <dt>:to begin to make a sudden loud noise <vi>I woke up when the alarm <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The lights in the building suddenly <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place for a new place <vi>He <it>went off</it> to join the army after graduating from high school.</vi> <vi>She <it>went off</it> to America.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to occur or happen <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen a particular way <vi>The party <it>went off</it> well. [=the party was a success]</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> poorly.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin shouting at someone in an angry way <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>Her boss <it>went off on</it> her because she was late again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop liking (someone or something) <vi>She used to like him but now she's <it>gone off</it> him completely.</vi> <vi>My boss has <it>gone off</it> the idea, so it's been cancelled.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (a spouse, partner, etc.) for someone else <vi>He left his wife and <it>went off with</it> [=<it>ran off with</it>] some young thing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something that belongs to someone else) away with you :<sx>steal</sx> <vi>Someone <it>went off with</it> my pencil/wallet.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to continue on a journey <vi>We stopped briefly in Detroit, and then <it>went on</it> to Chicago.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue as time passes <vi>Life <it>goes on</it>.</vi> <vi>How much longer will the meeting <it>go on</it>? [=<it>last</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to continue doing something <vi>She <it>went on</it> working [=she continued to work] after everyone else had stopped.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to continue talking <vi>He <it>went on</it> (and on) about how unfairly he had been treated. [=he talked about it for a long time]</vi> :to talk too much or too long about something <vi>She's always <it>going on</it> about the importance of a good diet.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to continue to be in the same situation or relationship <vi>We can't <it>go on</it> like this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before another person or group that is with you <vi>You <it>go on</it> (ahead). I'll come later.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to do or say something else after you have finished doing or saying something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He accepted the nomination and <it>went on to</it> win the election.</vi> <vi>After I finished reading the first book I immediately <it>went on to</it> the next one.</vi> <vi>He <it>went on to</it> say that further tax increases would be necessary.</vi> <vi>Everyone expected that she would <phrase>go on to greater things</phrase>. [=that she would become very successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>What's <it>going on</it>?</vi> <vi>No one knows exactly what <it>went on</it> during their private meeting.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>goings-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>went on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion or conclusion from something <un>used in the phrase <phrase>to go on</phrase> <vi>There's very little evidence <it>to go on</it>. [=there's very little evidence that can be used to form an opinion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to urge someone to do something <vi><it>Go on</it> (and try it): you might actually like it!</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more ice cream.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>! It won't hurt you to have a little more.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to express disbelief <vi>“I used to be a spy.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>.”</vi> <vi>A spy? <phrase>Go on with you</phrase>, then. [=I don't believe you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>go on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) often or repeatedly <vi>Quit <it>going on at</it> me all the time!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>going on</tag> at <dxt>going</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go one better</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to achieve more :to move to a higher or better level <vi>She qualified for the finals, then <it>went one better</it> and took first place.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go (someone or something) one better</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do better or more than (someone or something) :to outdo (someone or something) <vi>The company has <it>gone</it> its competitors <it>one better</it> by offering new customers a special discount.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for an activity <vi>I'm <it>going out</it> for a walk. I'll be back soon.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going out</it> to get some lunch.</vi> <vi>On Saturday nights he <it>goes out</it> drinking with his friends.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be sent from a person or place <vi>The message <it>went out</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi> <vi>Word has <it>gone out</it> that snow is expected.</vi> <vi><phrase>Our thoughts and prayers go out to</phrase> all the victims of this tragedy. [=we are thinking of and praying for all the victims of this tragedy]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being popular or fashionable <vi>That hairstyle <it>went out</it> years ago.</vi> <vi>Short skirts have <phrase>gone out of fashion</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to meet someone for a romantic social activity :to go on a date with someone <vi>They <it>went out</it> a couple of times, but it was never serious.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with someone <vi>I've been <it>going out</it> with her for quite a while now. = We've been <it>going out</it> for quite a while now.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The electricity suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to stop shining or burning <vi>The fire/candle <it>went out</it>.</vi> <vi>All the lights suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to try to become a member of a team, group, etc. <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>He <it>went out for</it> football last year. = He <it>went out for</it> the football team last year.</vi> <vi>She <it>went out</it> [=<it>tried out</it>] <it>for</it> the school play.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of the tide</ssl> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>The tide is <it>going out</it> [=(more formally) <it>ebbing</it>] now.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be broadcast on the radio, television, etc. <vi>A distress call <it>went out</it> three hours ago.</vi> <un>often + <it>over</it> <vi>Warnings about the approaching storm <it>went out over</it> the radio.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a particular place or person <vi>He <it>went over</it> and stood by the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over</it> and hugged her.</vi> <vi>I think I see Jane. Let's <it>go over</it> and say hello.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> her and hugged her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change sides in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>After several years of supporting us, he <it>went over to</it> our competitors.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to be accepted or received in a particular way <vi>He tried to make a joke but it <it>went over</it> badly. [=no one thought his joke was funny]</vi> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well <it>with</it> the boss. [=the boss didn't like her proposal]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think about (something) carefully <vi>He <it>went over</it> all the arguments before making up his mind.</vi> <vi>We <it>went over</it> the accident again and again in our minds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look at or study (something) again in order to correct it, learn it, etc. <vi>The students were told to <it>go over</it> their essays.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go over</it> the instructions.</vi> <vi>an actress <it>going over</it> her lines</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go the distance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>distance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to start to talk or think about something <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>“Do you remember when we were dating?” “Let's not <it>go there</it>.” = “I don't want to <it>go there</it>.” = “Don't <it>go there</it>.” [=I don't want to talk about that]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to study or look at (something) in a careful way <vi>The book <it>goes through</it> every detail of the French Revolution.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go through</it> the plan one more time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look in or at (something) in order to find something :to search in or through (something) <vi>I found him <it>going through</it> my closet.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to experience (something) <vi>He's <it>going through</it> a painful divorce.</vi> <vi>I understand what you're <it>going through</it>.</vi> <vi>In order to learn the job well, you have to <it>go through</it> several months of training.</vi> <vi>The book has already <it>gone through</it> four editions. [=the publishers have already released four editions of the book]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>went through</it> all the money he inherited.</vi> <vi>They <it>went through</it> three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to occur throughout (something) <vi>A note of despair <it>goes through</it> the narrative. [=there is a note of despair throughout the narrative]</vi> <snote>If something (such as an idea or a song) is <phrase>going through your head/mind</phrase>, you are thinking about it or remembering it. <vi>I don't know what was <it>going through her mind</it> [=I don't know what her thoughts were; I don't know why she did this] when she agreed to help him.</vi> <vi>That song keeps <it>going through my head</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>It took him about an hour to <it>go through</it> his usual morning routine.</vi> <vi>Before we practice the next section, let's <it>go through</it> the chorus once again.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go through the motions</tag> at <dxt>motion</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>Something (such as a law or contract) that <phrase>goes through</phrase> is officially accepted and approved. <vi>The bill is expected to <it>go through</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The proposed deal failed to <it>go through</it>.</vi> <vi>The bill <phrase>went through Congress/Parliament</phrase> [=was passed by Congress/Parliament] without difficulty and soon became law.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something that you have thought or talked about) <vi>He was always threatening to quit his job, but I never thought he'd actually <it>go through with</it> it. [=I never thought he would actually do it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to be in (a particular state, condition, or situation) <vi>You need to <phrase>go to sleep</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The countries <phrase>went to war</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be given to (someone or something) <vi>First prize <it>went to</it> the team from Chicago.</vi> <vi>The property will <it>go to</it> his wife if he dies before she does.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (trouble or expense)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to do something that causes you (trouble or expense) <vi>You shouldn't <it>go to all this trouble</it> just for me.</vi> <vi>They <it>went to a lot of expense</it> [=they spent a lot of money] to make sure that the job was done correctly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be suited to or appropriate for each other <vi>The tie and his suit <it>go together</it> well.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship <vi>They've been <it>going together</it> for several years.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to show/prove</dre> <def><dt>:to help show or prove something <vi>Her success <phrase>goes to show</phrase> that if you work hard, you can make your dreams come true.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go toward(s)</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go toward(s) (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help pay for (something) <vi>My extra income is <it>going towards</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>Your donations will <it>go toward</it> better sanitation for refugees.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to sink below the surface of the water <vi>The ship <it>went under</it> after being struck by a torpedo.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail :to not succeed <vi>The company has been losing money and is in danger of <it>going under</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a higher level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go up</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become brighter <vi>The lights <it>went up</it> [=the lights were turned up] when the movie ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be built <vi>A new store is <it>going up</it> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place (especially one that is to the north) <vi>We <it>went up to</it> the lake for the weekend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with (someone) :to date (someone) <vi>I've been <it>going with</it> her for quite a while now.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go out <dxn>4b (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>go together <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be suitable for or appropriate with (something) <vi>The skirt she's wearing doesn't really <it>go with</it> [=<it>match</it>] her blouse.</vi> <vi>The tie <it>goes</it> (well) <it>with</it> his suit.</vi> <vi>Do you think this wine will <it>go</it> well <it>with</it> dinner?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go together <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to exist or occur as a necessary part of (something) <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes with</it> it.</vi> <vi>There are a lot of responsibilities that <it>go with</it> starting your own business.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go with the territory</tag> at <dxt>territory</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or use (someone or something) <vi>After thinking about who to offer the job to, they decided to <it>go with</it> the more experienced candidate.</vi> <vi>The golfer <it>went with</it> an iron off the tee. [=the golfer used an iron for her tee shot]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go without</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go without</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go without (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not have (something) :to live or continue without having (something) <vi>How long can you <it>go without</it> sleeping/sleep?</vi> <vi>If you can't afford a new car, you'll just have to <it>go without</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>here goes (nothing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>here</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>here/there you go (again)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is happening again or in the same way that it has happened before <vi><it>There you go</it>, making a big deal out of nothing.</vi> <vi>When I saw his name in the headlines I thought, “<it>Here we go again</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how goes it?</dre> <def><dt><un>used as an informal greeting <vi>Hi Paul. <it>How goes it</it>? [=how are you?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ready, set, go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ready</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>there go/goes</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is no longer available or possible <vi>Look at that traffic jam! <it>There goes</it> our only chance of arriving on time. [=our only chance of arriving on time is gone/lost]</vi> <vi>It's supposed to rain this weekend, so <it>there go</it> our plans for a barbecue. [=we won't be able to have a barbecue]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:still remaining <vi>There are only three more days <it>to go</it> until my birthday!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:sold to be taken away and eaten somewhere else <vi>“I'd like a hamburger.” “For here or <it>to go</it>?” “<it>To go</it>.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="if[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">if</hw> <sound><wav>if000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪf</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about the result or effect of something that may happen or be true <vi><it>If</it> it rains, (then) we won't go to the park.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> he actually did commit the crime, he deserves to be punished.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you believe that, you'll believe anything!</vi> <vi>Come to the party <it>if</it> you can.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you really want to know, you should ask.</vi> <vi>What will happen <it>if</it> I fail the test?</vi> <vi>You should study. <phrase>If not</phrase>, you won't pass the test. = <it>If</it> you don't (study), you won't pass the test.</vi> <vi>Please arrive early <phrase>if possible</phrase>. = Please arrive early <it>if</it> it is possible.</vi> <vi>I'll do the work myself <phrase>if necessary</phrase>. = I'll do the work myself <it>if</it> it is necessary.</vi> <vi><phrase>If and when</phrase> he comes, you can ask him. = <phrase>When and if</phrase> he comes, you can ask him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to discuss the imaginary result or effect of something that did not happen or that is or was not true <vi><it>If</it> you had studied, you would have passed the test.</vi> <vi>The situation would be funny <it>if</it> it weren't so tragic. = (<it>informal</it>) The situation would be funny <it>if</it> it wasn't so tragic.</vi> <vi>The harvest would have been good <it>if</it> it had rained.</vi> <vi>The news would be interesting <it>if</it> (it were) true, but it's not true.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something must happen before another thing can happen <vi>He said he'll come to the party <it>if</it> she comes too. = (more strongly) He said he'll come to the party <phrase>only if</phrase> she comes too. = (most strongly) He says he'll come to the party <phrase>if and only if</phrase> she comes too.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a result that always occurs when something happens <vi>He gets angry <it>if</it> [=<it>when</it>] you disagree with him.</vi> <vi>The engine stalls <it>if</it> you let it get too hot.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:even though :<sx>although</sx> <vi>It was an interesting <it>if</it> unbelievable story.</vi> <vi>Her actions were understandable, <it>if</it> not forgivable.</vi> <vi>He had to perform an annoying, <it>if</it> necessary, task.</vi> <vi>a fair, <it>if</it> tough, boss</vi> <vi>The weather was good, <it>if</it> not great.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement or question about something that is not certain <vi>I'll see <it>if</it> [=<it>whether</it>] I can come.</vi> <vi>Do you know <it>if</it> he'll come to the party?</vi> <vi>I wonder <it>if</it> it's true (or not).</vi> <vi>Frankly, I doubt <it>if</it> he'll pass the exams.</vi> <vi>She asked <it>if</it> the mail had come.</vi> <vi>We should determine/decide <it>if</it> it is safe to go swimming.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used to make a polite request or suggestion <vi>Would you mind <it>if</it> I sat here? [=may I sit here?]</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you will/would (be good enough to) follow me, ladies and gentlemen, I'll take you to your seats.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> I could make a suggestion, why don't we sit closer to the front of the theater?</vi> <vi>I'd like to stay a little longer, <phrase>if you don't mind</phrase>. = I'd like to stay a little longer, <phrase>if it's/that's all right with you</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to state an opinion in a polite way <vi>You're looking particularly lovely today, <phrase>if I may say so</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used in statements that describe feelings (such as regret) about a possible situation <vi>I'm sorry <it>if</it> you think I insulted you.</vi> <vi>I'd be sorry <it>if</it> you thought I had insulted you.</vi> <vi>I don't care <it>if</it> we're late.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used in statements and questions that express doubt <vi>I met Brenda last week—<it>if</it> that is/was in fact her real name.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you're so smart, why aren't you rich?</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce an even stronger alternative to what has just been said <vi>These changes will have little <phrase>if any</phrase> impact on the problem.</vi> <vi>Few <it>if any</it> of the town's original settlers are left.</vi> <vi>Rarely, <phrase>if ever</phrase>, does that happen.</vi> <vi>His efforts have helped to save thousands, <phrase>if not</phrase> millions, of lives.</vi> <vi>My car is as fast as yours <it>if not</it> (even) faster.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt><un>used to express surprise about meeting someone when it is not expected <vi>So I went to the game and who should I see there <phrase>if not</phrase> [=<it>but</it>] my old friend Tom!</vi> <vi>Well, <phrase>if it isn't</phrase> my old friend Tom!</vi> <vi>So I went to the game and who did I see there <phrase>if it wasn't</phrase> my old friend Tom!</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize the truth of a statement <vi>The idea is true <it>if</it> any idea has ever been! [=the idea is certainly true]</vi> <vi>“He claims that he's never met her.” “Well, <it>if</it> that isn't the biggest load of nonsense I've ever heard!” [=that is a lot of nonsense; that is completely untrue]</vi> <vi>I'll get my revenge <phrase>if it's the last thing I do</phrase>! [=I am determined to get my revenge]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>as if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>as</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>even if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if anything</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement that strongly disagrees or contrasts with a preceding statement <vi>We don't see each other too often—<it>if anything</it> we don't see each other often enough!</vi> <vi>The economy has not improved. It has gotten worse, <it>if anything</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if it comes to that</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if I were you</dre> <def><dt><un>used when giving advice to people about how they should behave <vi>I'd study more <it>if I were you</it>. [=I think you should study more]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if not for</dre> <def><dt>:in the absence of (something or someone) :<sx>without</sx> <vi><it>If not for</it> modern medicine, fewer babies would survive.</vi> <vi><it>If not for</it> him, I wouldn't be where I am today.</vi> <un>often used in the phrases <phrase>if it were not for</phrase> and <phrase>if it had not been for</phrase> <vi><it>If it were not for</it> your donations, many more children would go hungry.</vi> <vi><it>If it hadn't been for</it> him, I wouldn't be where I am today.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if nothing else</dre> <def><dt>:at least <un>used to stress that an approving statement is true even though a stronger statement might not be <vi><it>If nothing else</it>, he's polite!</vi> <vi>The food was hot, <it>if nothing else</it>. [=the food may not have been very good, but at least it was hot]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if only</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about something that you want to happen or be true <vi><it>If only</it> she loved me in return!</vi> <vi><it>If only</it> it would stop raining.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you ask me</dre> <def><dt><un>used in statements that express an opinion <vi><it>If you ask me</it> [=in my opinion], he's a liar.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you must</dre> <dx>see <dxt>must</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>what if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>what</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="say[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">say</hw> <sound><wav>say00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈseɪ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>says</if> <sound><wav>say00004.wav</wav><wav>say00006.wav</wav><wav>say00006.wav</wav><wav>say00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛz</pr></in> <in><if>said</if> <sound><wav>say00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛd</pr></in> <in><if>say*ing</if> <sound><wav>say00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsejɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use your voice to express (something) with words <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>“Is anybody there?” he <it>said</it>.</vi> <vi>“Good morning,” <it>said</it> the woman behind the counter.</vi> <vi>I <it>said</it> three words before he interrupted me again.</vi> <vi>I just stopped by to <it>say</it> hello.</vi> <vi>He left without <it>saying</it> goodbye.</vi> <vi>I wanted to <it>say</it> thank you for all you've done for me.</vi> <vi>She <it>said</it> something about going to the store after work.</vi> <vi>He <it>said</it> something in French.</vi> <vi>Anything you <it>say</it> to the police can be used as evidence against you.</vi> <vi>Don't believe a word he <it>says</it>.</vi> <vi>Please be quiet. I have something to <it>say</it>.</vi> <vi>Listen closely, because I'm not going to <it>say</it> this again/twice.</vi> <vi>What did you <it>say</it>?</vi> <vi>Who shall I <it>say</it> is calling, Sir?</vi> <vi>Did she <it>say</it> how to get there?</vi> <vi>I <it>said</it> to myself, “I can do it.”</vi> <vi>He <it>said</it> (that) he was a doctor.</vi> <vi>I can honestly <it>say</it> (that) I had never seen that man before today.</vi> <vi>I already <it>said</it> (that) I was sorry.</vi> <vi>You know what they <it>say</it>, “If you can't beat 'em, join 'em.”</vi> <vi>As people/they <it>say</it>, “You can't teach an old dog new tricks.”</vi> <vi>Her eyes are hazel, <phrase>which is to say</phrase> [=which means that] they are greenish brown.</vi> <vi>“A word of advice: don't mention the war.” “<phrase>Say no more</phrase> [=I understand you; you do not need to explain it further]—I'll stay off the subject!”</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“What happened next?” “I'd rather not <it>say</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to express (an opinion) <vi>She thinks I should break up with him. What do you <it>say</it>? [=what's your opinion?]</vi> <vi>What would/do you <it>say</it> to seeing a movie tonight? [=would you like to see a movie tonight?]</vi> <vi>“After all, he was the last person to see her alive.” “Are you <it>saying</it> that (you think) he killed her?”</vi> <vi>I <it>say</it> you're wrong. [=my opinion is that you're wrong]</vi> <vi>I wouldn't <it>say</it> (that) he's a great guitarist [=I don't think he's a great guitarist]; he's just OK.</vi> <vi>They <it>say</it> (that) you should drink eight glasses of water a day. = It's <it>said</it> that you should drink eight glasses of water a day. [=the opinion of people who know about this subject is that you should drink eight glasses of water a day]</vi> <vi>New England is <it>said</it> to be [=many people think New England is] very beautiful in the Fall.</vi> <vi>“Is the island nice?” “<phrase>So they/people say</phrase>.”</vi> <vi><phrase>I must say</phrase> it was quite a surprise to hear from him. = <phrase>I have to say</phrase> it was quite a surprise to hear from him.</vi> <vi>I'm not <it>saying</it> we shouldn't buy the car. <phrase>All I'm saying</phrase> is that we should think about it some more.</vi> <vi>I didn't really enjoy the movie, but <phrase>that's not to say</phrase> it was bad.</vi> <vi><phrase>Say what you like</phrase> (about it), I thought it was a good movie.</vi> <vi>Seeing your reaction, <phrase>I would say</phrase> that you're jealous that he has a new girlfriend.</vi> <vi>The dress seems too fancy for the party, <phrase>wouldn't you say</phrase>? [=don't you agree?; do you think the same thing?]</vi> <vi><phrase>I'll say this for him</phrase>—he's very generous with his money.</vi> <vi>“She's a great singer!” “<phrase>If you say so</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to express (a fact) with certainty <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>No one can <it>say</it> for sure whether it will happen.</vi> <vi>It is <phrase>hard to say</phrase> what caused the injury.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no saying</phrase> [=it is impossible to know] how many people died in the earthquake.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“When will you be done?” “<phrase>I couldn't/can't say</phrase>.” [=I don't know]</vi> <snote>This sense is often used in indirect questions beginning with <it>who</it> to express disagreement or to say that something cannot be known for sure. <vi>Who <it>says</it> I can't do it? I can do anything if I put my mind to it.</vi> <vi>Who's to <it>say</it> they wouldn't have won if their team was healthy?</vi> <vi>Who can <it>say</it> what will happen? [=no one knows what will happen]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to give (an order) :to tell someone to do (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>said</it> leave me alone!</vi> <vi>“Why do we have to go?” “Because your father and I <it>said</it> so.”</vi> <vi>Mom <it>said</it> to wait here.</vi> <vi>She's the boss. <phrase>What she says goes</phrase>! [=you have to do what she tells you to do]</vi> <vi>“Let's try installing the program one more time.” “<phrase>Whatever you say</phrase>—you're the expert.”</vi> <vi>“Don't you ever bring that subject up again, do you hear me?!” “Okay, okay. <it>Whatever you say</it>.”</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Don't start until I <it>say</it> (so/to).</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to pronounce (a word) <vi>How do you <it>say</it> your name?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to repeat or recite (something) <vi>We always <it>say</it> our prayers before going to bed.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>say</it> the poem from memory?</vi> <vi>A new priest <it>said</it> Mass this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use written words to give (information) <vi>What does the card <it>say</it>?</vi> <vi>Does the article <it>say</it> how the fire happened?</vi> <vi>The letter <it>says</it> that I've been accepted to the college.</vi> <vi>It <it>says</it> here that there will be a special guest at the concert.</vi> <vi>The instructions <it>say</it> to add two eggs.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to show or indicate (something) by using numbers, pictures, etc. <vi>The clock <it>says</it> five minutes after ten.</vi> <vi>The calendar <it>says</it> that Christmas falls on a Monday.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to express (a meaning, emotion, etc.) without using words <vi>She likes art that really <it>says</it> something.</vi> <vi>The kind of car you drive <it>says</it> a lot about the kind of person you are.</vi> <vi>The look on her face <it>said</it> “I'm sorry.”</vi> <vi>His face <phrase>said it all</phrase>. = His face <phrase>said everything</phrase>. [=his face showed how he felt]</vi></dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <dt><un>used to suggest an example or possibility <vi>Let's pick a math problem. <it>Say</it> problem number 3.</vi> <vi><it>Say</it> you do get accepted to the college. Will you go?</vi> <vi>We could leave on any day—<it>say</it> on Monday.</vi> <vi><phrase>Let's say</phrase> you're right, for argument's sake.</vi> <vi>Suppose you won, <phrase>shall we say</phrase>, one million dollars. What would you do with it?</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to suggest a possible or approximate amount, value, etc. <vi>The property is worth, <it>say</it>, four million dollars. = The property is worth four million dollars, <it>say</it>. [=the property is worth about four million dollars]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>can't say fairer than that</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you cannot make a better offer than the one you have made <vi>What do you think? I <it>can't say fairer than that</it>, now, can I?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>enough said</dre> <dx>see <dxt>enough</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fair to say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go without saying</dre> <def><dt>:to be obvious and true <vi>It <it>goes without saying</it> that I'll do whatever I can to help you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hasten to say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hasten</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have anything/something (etc.) to say about</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have an opinion to express about (something) <vi>I asked what she thought about the movie, but she didn't <it>have anything to say about</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to have the ability to influence (something) <vi>“I'm going to the party.” “Not if I <it>have anything/something to say about it</it>.” [=not if I can stop you]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have something/nothing/much (etc.) to say for yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to be able or unable to say something that explains what you are doing, have done, etc. <vi>I asked him about school, but he didn't <it>have much to say for himself</it>.</vi> <vi>Your teacher says you were caught cheating. What do you <it>have to say for yourself</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>having said that</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>that said</va></vr> <def><dt>:despite what I just said <vi>Their work has been fairly good. <it>Having said that</it>, I still think there's a lot of room for improvement.</vi> <vi>Much of the book was very dull. <it>That said</it>, I have to admit that the ending was extremely clever.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I dare say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dare</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if I may say so</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>if I might say so</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to express criticism or disagreement in a polite way <vi>The whole affair—<it>if I may say so</it>—was a waste of time.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if I say so myself</dre> <def><dt><un>used when you are saying something that praises your own work, skill, etc. <vi>I did a fine job painting the room, <it>if I say so myself</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a pretty good golfer, <it>if I say so myself</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I hear what you're saying</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>I'll say</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to indicate that you completely agree with something just said <vi>“Isn't it hot today!” “<it>I'll say</it> (it is). It's unbearable!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I say</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to express surprise, shock, etc. <vi><it>I say</it>! Isn't that your friend over there?</vi> <vi><it>I say</it>! That's a wonderful idea.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to attract the attention of someone <vi><it>I say</it> (there). Can you help me?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>needless to say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>needless</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>never say die</dre> <dx>see <dxt>die</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>never say never</dre> <dx>see <dxt>never</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not to say</dre> <def><dt><un>used to introduce a more forceful or critical way of describing someone or something <vi>His manner was discourteous, <it>not to say</it> offensive.</vi> <vi>He was impolite, <it>not to say</it> downright rude!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>say cheese</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cheese</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>say no</dre> <def><dt>:to say that you will not accept or agree to something <vi>We requested more time, but she <it>said no</it>. [=she refused to allow us to have more time]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>said no to</it> our request.</vi> <vi>I never <it>say no to</it> dessert.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>say something/little/a lot (etc.) for</dre> <def><dt>:to show that (someone or something) does or does not deserve to be praised, admired, etc. <vi>It <it>says a lot for</it> her that she stayed in the game even though she was injured.</vi> <vi>The students' low test scores don't <it>say much for</it> the education they're receiving. [=the low test scores show/suggest that the students are not getting a good education]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>say the word</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>say what</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise at what someone has just said <vi>“I'm moving out.” “<it>Say what</it>?”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>say yes</dre> <def><dt>:to say that you accept or agree to something <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>They <it>said yes to</it> our plan.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>say your piece</dre> <dx>see <dxt>piece</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>suffice (it) to say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>suffice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is to say</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that said</dre> <dx>see <dxt>having said that <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that's not saying much</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that a fact, achievement, etc., is not unusual or impressive <vi>He is a better golfer than me, but <it>that's not saying much</it> (because I'm not a good golfer).</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>there is something/a lot/much (etc.) to be said for</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that something has advantages which deserve to be considered when you are thinking about what to do <vi><it>There is something to be said for</it> small weddings.</vi> <vi>It is not necessary, but <it>there is something to be said for</it> traveling abroad to learn a language.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to say nothing of</dre> <def><dt><un>used when referring to another thing that relates to what you have just said <vi>We need more time, <it>to say nothing of</it> [=<it>not to mention</it>] money. [=we also need more money]</vi> <vi>The restaurant makes its own delicious bread, <it>to say nothing of</it> a great spaghetti sauce.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to say the least</dre> <dx>see <dxt>least</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <dx>see <dxt>all</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>you can say that again</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to indicate that you completely agree with something just said <vi>“She's in a bad mood.” “<it>You can say that again</it>.” [=she certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you don't say</dre> <def><dt><un>used to express surprise <vi>“She ran off with another man.” “<it>You don't say</it>!”</vi></un> <un>often used ironically to show that you are not at all surprised by something <vi>“They lost again.” “<it>You don't say</it>. What's that, eight in a row?”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you might say</dre> <def><dt><un>used to suggest a possible way of describing or thinking about something <vi>The experience was, <it>you might say</it>, a glimpse into the future.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you said it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to indicate that you completely agree with something just said <vi>“That was a pretty selfish thing for him to do.” “<it>You said it</it>.”</vi> <vi>“Let's grab something to eat.” “<it>You said it</it>. I'm starving.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="start[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">start</hw> <sound><wav>start001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstɑɚt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>starts</if></in> <in><if>start*ed</if></in> <in><if>start*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to do the first part of something :to begin doing something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>started</it> clearing land for the new housing development.</vi> <vi>He <it>started</it> the speech (out) with a joke.</vi> <vi>He <it>started</it> studying music at the age of five.</vi> <vi>She saw her divorce as an opportunity to <it>start</it> a new life. = She saw her divorce as an opportunity to <it>start</it> life anew/afresh/over.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>As soon as you're ready to play, we'll <it>start</it>.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>start</it> with some warm-up exercises.</vi> <vi>He deleted what he wrote and <it>started</it> fresh/again/over.</vi> <vi>Nothing like this had ever been done before, so we had to <phrase>start from scratch</phrase>. [=we had to begin from a point at which nothing had been done yet]</vi> <vi>Olympic athletes <phrase>start young</phrase> and train hard.</vi> <vi>The tire tracks at the scene of the crime were a <phrase>starting point</phrase> for investigators. [=investigators used the tire tracks to start their investigation]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to work on, produce, or give attention to (something) <vi>I <it>started</it> the quilt last month.</vi> <vi>Have you <it>started</it> your book report?</vi> <vi>Did you <it>start</it> (reading) the book yet?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin <vi>We <it>started</it> the meeting at 6:30.</vi> :to cause (something) to begin in a specified way <vi>She started the meeting with a brief review of the previous meeting.</vi> <vi>He <it>starts</it> every day with a cup of coffee.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have a feeling, thought, etc. <un>usually followed by <it>to</it> + <it>verb</it> <vi>She <it>started to feel</it> dizzy soon after the accident.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>starting to think</it> the oversight was intentional.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>She <it>started feeling</it> dizzy soon after the accident.</vi> <vi>He <it>started having</it> chest pains.</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to begin working at a new job or going to school <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>start</it> my new job next Monday.</vi> <vi>When does she <it>start</it> school?</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I just got a new job. I <it>start</it> next week.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to begin to happen, to exist, to be done, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The fire <it>started</it> in the cellar.</vi> <vi>The rain will <it>start</it> soon and should end sometime this evening.</vi> <vi>The game <it>started</it> late.</vi> <vi><it>Starting</it> next week, all employees will be required to wear ID tags.</vi> <vi>The movie just <it>started</it>.</vi> <vi>What is the movie's <it>starting</it> time?</vi> <vi>When does school <it>start</it>?</vi> <vi>The game was just <it>starting</it> when it began to rain.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often followed by <it>to</it> + <it>verb</it> <vi>It <it>started to rain</it>.</vi> <vi>The leaves are <it>starting to change</it> colors.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>It <it>started raining</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to exist or happen <vi>He <it>started</it> a scholarship fund.</vi> <vi>The tradition was <it>started</it> many years ago.</vi> <vi>“Stop fighting, you two!” “He <it>started</it> it.” [=he did something to cause the fight]</vi> <vi>She's always <it>starting</it> arguments.</vi> <vi>They want to <phrase>start a family</phrase> [=begin to have children] soon.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to function or operate <vi>The car/engine won't <it>start</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to function or operate <vi>She <it>started</it> the car and drove away.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin the use of (something) <vi>You'll have to <it>start</it> a new roll of tape. This one's empty.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have a particular beginning :to begin at a specified place or in a specified way <vi>The English alphabet <it>starts</it> with A and ends with Z.</vi> <vi>The first word in a sentence should <it>start</it> with a capital letter.</vi> <vi>The parade <it>starts</it> at the intersection of First and Main.</vi> <vi>The path/trail <it>starts</it> here and ends at the lake.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a specified quality, identity, job, etc., at the beginning <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>What <it>started</it> (off) <it>as</it> a simple idea has become an expensive and complicated project.</vi> <vi>She <it>started</it> (out) <it>as</it> a sales assistant but is now the marketing director.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to move toward a particular place or in a particular direction <vi>We'll <it>start</it> for home soon.</vi> <vi>We should <it>start</it> back to the camp before it gets dark.</vi> <vi>He <it>started</it> toward the door.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>started</it> after the squirrel.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to indicate the beginning of a range, series, etc.</un> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>The rates <it>start at</it> $10 per hour.</vi> <vi>At his company, salaries <it>start at</it> around $30,000. [=$30,000 is the lowest salary]</vi> <vi>Interest rates for CDs were <it>starting at</it> 3.9 percent.</vi> <vi>What is the <phrase>starting salary</phrase> for the job? [=what is the salary people are paid when they start the job?]</vi> <vi>The <phrase>starting price</phrase> [=the basic price when nothing extra has been added] for the car is $18,000.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:to participate in a game or contest at its beginning <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Despite his injury, he'll <it>start</it> in center field today.</vi> <vi>The manager removed the <phrase>starting pitcher</phrase> [=the pitcher who was playing at the beginning of the game] in the third inning.</vi> <vi>He's in the <phrase>starting lineup</phrase>. [=a list of the players who will be playing when the game begins]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Who's <it>starting for</it> the home team?</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He'll <it>start</it> today's game in center field.</vi> <vi>a pitcher who has <it>started</it> five games so far this year</vi> <vi>She <it>started</it> the race but wasn't able to finish.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put (someone or something) into a game or contest at its beginning <vi>The coach is <it>starting</it> him at quarterback for the next game.</vi> <vi>He plans to <it>start</it> [=<it>enter</it>] the horse in only a few races this year.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to begin doing something <vi>Her questions <it>started</it> me thinking.</vi> :to cause (someone) to begin a job or activity in a particular way, at a particular level, etc. <vi>The company <it>started</it> him at the same salary he had been getting at his previous job.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to begin talking about a particular subject <vi>“What do you think of the new boss?” “<phrase>Don't get me started</phrase>. I can't stand him.”</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><phrase>Don't get him started on</phrase> the war: he'll never stop!</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move suddenly and quickly because you are surprised or frightened <vi>The loud noise made him <it>start</it>. [=<it>jump</it>]</vi> <vi>The horse <it>started</it> when the shot rang out.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin complaining, arguing, etc. <vi>He <phrase>started with me</phrase>, so I hit him.</vi> <vi><phrase>Don't (you) start (with me)</phrase>. I made a mistake—that's the end of it.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get started</dre> <def><dt>:to begin doing or working on something <vi>You (had) better <it>get started</it> if you want to finish on time.</vi> <vi>newlyweds who are just <it>getting started</it> [=who are just starting their lives together]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start doing a particular activity or action <vi>He took a break from painting to eat lunch, then <it>started in</it> again.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>She <it>started in on</it> another book.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>start in on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to criticize (someone) about something <vi>My dad <it>started in on</it> me about not having a job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>start off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start or cause (something) to start in a specified way <vi>He <it>started off</it> by introducing himself.</vi> <vi>She <it>started off</it> (her run) at a slow jog.</vi> <vi>The performance <it>started off</it> badly.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I <it>started off</it> my speech <it>with</it> a joke.</vi> <vi>We <it>started off</it> the meal <it>with</it> shrimp cocktails.</vi> <vi>The team <it>started</it> the season <it>off with</it> a 10-game winning streak.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to have a specified quality, identity, job, etc., at the start <vi>She <it>started off</it> as a sales assistant but is now the marketing director.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin an important period in your life or career <vi>The house is perfect for a couple just <it>starting off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to begin to move toward a particular place or in a particular direction <vi>She ate breakfast before <it>starting off</it> for work.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>start (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to begin doing a particular activity or action <vi>He <it>started</it> his daughter <it>off</it> on the piano.</vi> <vi>The game-show host <it>started</it> her <it>off</it> with some easy questions.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>start on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin doing (something) <vi>Did you <it>start on</it> your homework yet?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>start (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to start doing or using (something) <vi>The doctor <it>started</it> him <it>on</it> [=made him start taking] antibiotics.</vi> <vi>When should we <it>start</it> the baby <it>on</it> solid food? [=start feeding the baby solid food]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>start on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) about something <vi>Don't <it>start on at</it> me again about spending money!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin in a specified way <vi>He <it>started out</it> by introducing himself.</vi> <vi>She <it>started out</it> at a slow jog.</vi> <vi>The day <it>started out</it> hot and humid.</vi> <vi>The story <it>started out</it> good, but I didn't like the ending.</vi> <vi>She <it>started out</it> wanting to be a doctor but became a midwife instead.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I <it>started out with</it> $100 but I have only $10 left.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>start out with</it> some warm-up exercises.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to have a specified quality, identity, job, etc., at the start <vi>What <it>started out</it> as a simple idea has become an expensive and complicated project.</vi> <vi>He <it>started out</it> in teaching before becoming a lawyer.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin an important period in your life or career <vi>The couple is just <it>starting out</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>started out</it> on a career in teaching.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to begin to travel <vi>They <it>started out</it> in the early morning.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to have a particular place as a beginning point <vi>The parade <it>starts out</it> at the intersection of First and Main.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>start over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start (something) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin doing something again <vi>I'm sorry, but you'll have to <it>start over</it>. = I'm sorry, but you'll have to <phrase>start (all) over again</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She saw her divorce as an opportunity to <it>start</it> (her life) <it>over</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to begin to happen again <vi>In the spring, the eggs hatch, and the cycle <it>starts over</it>. = The cycle <phrase>starts (all) over again</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start something</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>start anything</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to do something that causes trouble <vi>She is always trying to <it>start something</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>start anything</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>start the ball rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>start up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin to happen or exist <vi>New businesses are <it>starting up</it> all over the state.</vi> <vi>The rain <it>started up</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>start up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>start up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to function or to make (something) begin to function <vi>The car/engine won't <it>start up</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>started</it> the lawn mower <it>up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to start with</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that is the first in a series of statements <vi>“I don't think we should buy the car.” “Why not?” “<it>To start with</it>, I'm not sure we can afford it.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:at the beginning :before the current time or situation <vi>She has lost a lot of weight, and she wasn't very heavy <it>to start with</it>.</vi> <vi>He didn't like his job <it>to start with</it> [=<it>at first, initially</it>], but he got used to it eventually.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="think[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">think</hw> <sound><wav>think001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈθɪŋk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>thinks</if></in> <in><if>thought</if> <sound><wav>think002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈθɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>think*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to believe that something is true, that a particular situation exists, that something will happen, etc. <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>I <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) I heard your voice.</vi> <vi>She <it>thinks</it> (<it>that</it>) she knows the answer.</vi> <vi>I <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) you can do it.</vi> <vi>We didn't <it>think</it> [=<it>expect</it>] (<it>that</it>) we would have any trouble.</vi> <vi>Did you really/honestly <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) I would agree with you?</vi> <vi>I never <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) I would become a teacher.</vi> <vi>Who would have <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) we would meet each other here?</vi> <vi>He never <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) she would leave him.</vi> <vi>I hate to <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) we will never see each other again.</vi> <vi>It was once <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) the Earth was flat. = The Earth was once <it>thought</it> to be flat.</vi> <vi>He is <it>thought</it> to have drowned.</vi> <vi>“Has she accepted the job?” “<phrase>I (don't) think so</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>Am I right <phrase>in thinking</phrase> (<it>that</it>) you used to work there?</vi> <vi>“I can beat you.” “<phrase>That's what you think</phrase>.” [=you might believe that you can beat me, but you're wrong]</vi> <vi>“Where is he?” “He's still at home.” “<phrase>I thought as much</phrase>.” [=I thought he was still at home]</vi> <vi>Well, yes. <it>I</it> <phrase>should think</phrase> so.</vi> <vi>You <phrase>would think</phrase> (<it>that</it>) the school would have dictionaries in the classrooms. [=the school should have dictionaries in the classroom]</vi> <vi>$50 is enough, I <phrase>would have thought</phrase>.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>It's going to be much more difficult than they <it>think</it>. [=<it>suspect, expect</it>]</vi> <vi>We may finish sooner than you <it>think</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to have an opinion about someone or something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>It's hot in here, don't you <it>think</it>? [=don't you agree?]</vi> <vi>People <it>think</it> he is one of the greatest jazz musicians of all time. = He is <it>thought</it> to be one of the greatest jazz musicians of all time.</vi> <vi>I <it>think</it> he should apologize. = I <phrase>should/would think</phrase> he would apologize.</vi> <vi>Is this a good use of our tax dollars? <phrase>I think not/so</phrase>. [=I don't/do believe that it is]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>think yourself</phrase> [=<it>consider yourself</it>] lucky/fortunate to have gotten off with only a warning!</vi> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>I <it>thought</it> (<it>that</it>) the movie was excellent.</vi> <vi>He <it>thinks</it> (<it>that</it>) he is a good writer.</vi> <vi>Where do you <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) we should eat?</vi> <vi>Do you <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) we should buy the house?</vi> <vi>They <it>think</it> (<it>that</it>) it is unfair to have a rule like that. = They <it>think</it> it unfair to have a rule like that.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>about</it> or <it>of</it> <vi>What did you <it>think about/of</it> the movie? [=did you like or dislike the movie?]</vi> <vi>I told him exactly what I <it>thought of</it> him!</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to form or have (a particular thought) in your mind <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>“He's handsome,” she <it>thought</it> (to herself).</vi> <vi>You should relax and try to <it>think</it> pleasant thoughts.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>thinking</it> what it would be like to be a doctor.</vi> <vi>I dread to <it>think</it> how he will react.</vi> <vi>Why do you always <phrase>think the worst</phrase>?</vi> <vi><phrase>Just think</phrase> how nice it would be to live here.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Just think</it>—in two days we'll be on vacation, lying on the beach.</vi> <un>usually + <it>about</it> or <it>of</it> <vi>I was just <it>thinking about</it> you.</vi> <vi>I was <it>thinking of</it> the time we rented that cabin in the mountains.</vi> <vi>Just <it>think about</it> how much money we'll save.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to use your mind to understand or decide something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Think</it> before you answer the question.</vi> <vi>The game teaches students how to <it>think</it>.</vi> <vi>Let me <it>think</it>. Where did I see your car keys?</vi> <vi>We <it>thought</it> long and hard about it before we reached our decision.</vi> <vi>Don't disturb him: he's <it>thinking</it>.</vi> <vi>You have to <phrase>think positive/positively</phrase> if you want to succeed.</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>The lecture gave the students a lot to <it>think about</it>.</vi> <vi>I have <it>thought</it> very deeply <it>about</it> this problem, trying to find an answer.</vi> <vi><it>Think about</it> the offer. You might change your mind.</vi> <vi>Do you ever <it>think about</it> what you are going to do after you graduate?</vi> <vi>If/When you <it>think about</it> it, the argument does make sense.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Give me a minute to <it>think</it> what to do.</vi> <vi>He couldn't <it>think</it> where they would have gone.</vi> <vi>You're awfully quiet. What are you <it>thinking</it>?</vi> <vi>I can't believe he did that! What was he <it>thinking</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have thoughts about (something) <vi>She talks and <it>thinks</it> business all the time.</vi> <vi>He is always <it>thinking</it> [=thinking about] money.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remember (something) <vi>Can you <it>think</it> where you put it?</vi> <vi>She was trying to <it>think</it> where she had heard that name before.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to</it> + <it>verb</it> <vi>Neither of us <it>thought to close</it> the garage door.</vi> <vi>She never <it>thinks to call</it> home.</vi> <vi>He never <it>thought to ask</it> how we are doing.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have thoughts about possibly doing (something) :to have the intention of doing (something) <vi>I <it>think</it> I'll give him a call today.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to make a statement or suggestion less definite <vi>They used to live here, I <it>think</it>. [=I believe that they used to live here, although I'm not sure]</vi> <vi>I <it>thought</it> maybe we could go for a walk in the park.</vi> <vi>I was <it>thinking</it> we might have dinner together some time.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to politely ask someone to do something or give you something <vi><phrase>Do you think (that)</phrase> you could give me a ride to the airport? [=could you give me a ride to the airport?]</vi> <vi><it>Do you think</it> I could borrow the car tonight, Dad?</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in questions that show anger or surprise about what someone has done or is doing <vi>What do you <it>think</it> you're doing? I just said you couldn't have one.</vi> <vi>Where do you <it>think</it> you're going? [=where are you going?] No one gave you permission to leave.</vi> <vi>Who do you <it>think</it> you are, barging in here like that?</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>come to think of it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>don't even think about (doing) it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell someone in a forceful way that something is not allowed <vi>It's illegal to park here. <it>Don't even think about it</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not think anything of</dre> <def><dt>:to not think of (something) as being important or unusual <vi>I <it>didn't think anything of</it> it at the time—but it turned out to be the clue that would solve the case.</vi> <vi>I <it>didn't think anything of</it> his wearing a long coat since it was cold outside.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not think much of</dre> <def><dt>:to not like (someone or something) very much <vi>They <it>didn't think much of</it> my idea.</vi> <vi>Though the singer was very popular, she <it>didn't think much of</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think again</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that what someone believes, expects, etc., is not true or will not happen <vi>If you think you can get away with this, <it>think again</it>. [=you are wrong]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think ahead</dre> <def><dt>:to prepare for a future event or situation by thinking about what might happen <vi>We should have <it>thought ahead</it> and brought an umbrella.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think aloud</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>think out loud</va></vr> <def><dt>:to say your thoughts so that other people can hear them <vi>No, I wasn't talking to you. I was just <it>thinking out loud</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to think about something that happened in the past <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi><it>Thinking back to</it> my childhood, I remember summers at the beach.</vi> <vi><it>Think back to</it> that night. What were you doing?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think better of</dre> <def><dt>:to decide not to do (something) after thinking further about it <vi>She was going to make a comment but <it>thought better of</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think big</dre> <dx>see <dxt>big</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>think fit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>think for yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to form opinions and make decisions without help from other people <vi>Don't let others tell you what to believe. You need to learn to <it>think for yourself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think less of</dre> <def><dt>:to not respect (someone) as much as you did before :to have a worse opinion of (someone) <vi>I hope you don't <it>think</it> (any) <it>less of</it> me now that you know about the trouble I got into when I was younger.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think nothing of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not hesitate at all about (doing something that other people think is very difficult or dangerous) <vi>She <it>thinks nothing of</it> running 10 miles.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>think nothing of it</bnote> <dt><un>used as a polite response when someone has apologized to you or thanked you <vi>“Thanks for the ride.” “<it>Think nothing of it</it>—I was going in this direction anyway.”</vi> <vi>“I'm so sorry.” “It's all right. <it>Think nothing of it</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>think of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have thoughts about possibly doing (something) <vi>She is <it>thinking of</it> applying to grad school.</vi> <vi>He <it>thought of</it> sending an e-mail but decided against it.</vi> <vi>She couldn't <it>think of</it> ever leaving her children.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use your mind to form or invent (something) <vi>The best plan they could <it>think of</it> was to leave.</vi> <vi>“Can you give me an example?” “I'll <it>think of</it> something.”</vi> <vi>I can't <it>think of</it> one reason why you shouldn't do it.</vi> <vi>Cell phones that can access the Internet and take pictures—what will they <it>think of</it> next?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to remember (something) <vi>I can <it>think of</it> plenty of other times when you were wrong.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>think of</it> her name at the moment.</vi> <vi>I just <it>thought of</it> a good joke.</vi> <vi>She <it>thought of</it> her old home when she saw the picture.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>think of (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have a particular kind of opinion about (someone or something) <vi>The hiring committee <phrase>thought highly of</phrase> her. [=had a high opinion of her]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>thinks a great deal of</phrase> her doctor. [=she likes/respects her doctor very much]</vi> <vi>I wouldn't want you to <phrase>think badly of</phrase> me.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>thinks the world of</phrase> his family. [=his family is very important to him]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form or have an idea about (someone or something) <vi>People are <it>thinking of</it> her for president. [=are thinking that she should be the president]</vi> <vi>Are you <it>thinking of</it> any place in particular?</vi> <vi>I am <it>thinking of</it> a number between 1 and 10.</vi> <vi>I'll be <it>thinking of</it> you in my prayers.</vi> <vi>He <it>thinks of</it> them with great affection.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be concerned about (someone or something) when you make decisions about what to do <vi>I must <it>think</it> first <it>of</it> my family.</vi> <vi>You should <it>think of</it> your job security.</vi> <vi>She is always <it>thinking of</it> the welfare of others.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>think of (someone or something) as (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to believe that (someone or something) is (a particular type of person or thing) or has (a particular quality) <vi>He <it>thinks of</it> himself <it>as</it> a good writer. [=he thinks/believes that he is a good writer]</vi> <vi>I <it>think of</it> you guys <it>as</it> my family.</vi> <vi>Play can be <it>thought of as</it> a child's work since it is through play that children learn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>think out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>think (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think about (something, such as a problem) for a period of time in an effort to find a solution, make a decision, etc. <vi>He spent hours <it>thinking out</it> the solution to the physics problem.</vi> <vi>I need time to <it>think</it> things <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>The details of the contract have been carefully <it>thought out</it>.</vi> <vi>Your argument is well <it>thought out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think outside the box</dre> <dx>see <dxt>box</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>think over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>think (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>think over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think about (something) for a period of time especially in an effort to understand or make a decision about it <vi>I'll give you time to <it>think</it> the matter <it>over</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Think</it> it <it>over</it>, and let me know what you decide.</vi> <vi>I've <it>thought over</it> what you said, and you're right.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>think (something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>think through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think about all the different parts or effects of (something) for a period of time especially in an effort to understand or make a decision about it <vi>I need time to <it>think</it> this <it>through</it>.</vi> <vi>We have <it>thought through</it> the matter and have come to a decision.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think twice</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to think seriously about whether you really want to do something before you do it <vi>I'd <it>think twice</it> about/before doing that if I were you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>think up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>think up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>think (something) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use your mind to form or invent (something) <vi>Quick! We have to <it>think up</it> an excuse.</vi> <vi>They <it>thought up</it> a new way of raising money for charity.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to think</dre> <def><dt><un>used to express surprise or shock <vi><it>To think</it> (that) he lied to you!</vi> <vi><it>To think</it>, all we needed to do was to wait a few more days.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
