<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="anywhere[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">any*where</hw> <sound><wav>anywhe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛniˌweɚ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in, at, or to any place <vi>This type of plant can grow just about <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>It's a small camera that you can take practically/virtually <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>They gave her permission to go <it>anywhere</it> she wanted to.</vi> <vi>This kind of thing could happen <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>You can sit <it>anywhere</it> you like.</vi> <vi>He seems to be at home <it>anywhere</it> in the world.</vi> <vi>I can't find my keys <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>I'd know/recognize her <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>They produce some of the finest wines made <it>anywhere</it>.</vi> <vi>He never walks <it>anywhere</it>. He always drives.</vi> <vi>I'll take you <it>anywhere</it> you want to go.</vi> <vi>I heard that she might be quitting, but she says she's not going <it>anywhere</it>. [=she says that she's staying]</vi> <vi>This bird species is not found <phrase>anywhere else</phrase> in the world. [=the bird is not found at any other place in the world]</vi> <vi>I wouldn't want to live <it>anywhere else</it>.</vi> <vi>These plants don't grow <phrase>just anywhere</phrase>. They need lots of sun.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His career isn't <phrase>going anywhere</phrase>. [=his career is not making progress; his career is not becoming more successful; his career is going nowhere]</vi> <vi>It seemed like a good idea, but it never <phrase>went anywhere</phrase>. [=it never produced any useful results]</vi> <vi>We're working hard but we don't seem to be <phrase>getting anywhere</phrase>. [=we don't seem to be making progress]</vi> <vi>Arguing will not <phrase>get us anywhere</phrase>. [=arguing will not help us solve the problem]</vi> <vi>Our efforts to get more information didn't <phrase>lead anywhere</phrase>. [=our efforts were not successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>somewhere</sx> <un>used in questions <vi>Did you go <it>anywhere</it> while on your vacation?</vi> <vi>Have you been <phrase>anywhere else</phrase> in Europe?</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to give added emphasis to <it>near</it> and <it>close</it> <vi>The police wouldn't let us get <it>anywhere near</it> the accident scene.</vi> <vi>The dog barks if you come <it>anywhere near</it> him.</vi> <vi>The company hasn't come <it>anywhere near/close</it> to meeting its goals.</vi> <vi>We're not <it>anywhere close</it> to being done. [=we're very far from being done]</vi> <vi>The movie was not <it>anywhere near</it> as good [=the movie was not nearly as good] as I expected it to be.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a range of amounts, values, etc. <vi>The house's value is estimated at <it>anywhere</it> from $200,000 to $220,000.</vi> <vi>The plants can live <it>anywhere</it> between 50 and 100 years.</vi> <vi>The procedure can take <it>anywhere</it> from/between two to four hours to complete.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="anywhere[2]"> <hw hindex="2">anywhere</hw> <altpr>ˈɛniˌweɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:any place <un>usually used after <it>from</it> <vi>It's a short drive <it>from anywhere</it> in the region.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>They live <phrase>miles from anywhere</phrase>. [=they live in a place that is very far from other people]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>somewhere</sx> <un>used in questions <vi>Do you know <it>anywhere</it> I can buy cheap furniture?</vi> <vi>Do you need <it>anywhere</it> to stay tonight?</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
