<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="appoint"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*point</hw> <sound><wav>appoin01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpoɪnt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ap*points</if></in> <in><if>ap*point*ed</if></in> <in><if>ap*point*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to choose (someone) to have a particular job :to give (someone) a position or duty <vi>The President <it>appointed</it> [=<it>named</it>, <it>designated</it>] him (as) Secretary of Education.</vi> <vi>She was <it>appointed</it> professor of chemistry at the university.</vi> <vi>After his parents died, the boy's uncle was <it>appointed</it> as his guardian.</vi> <vi>Every year, the group <it>appoints</it> three new members.</vi> <vi>a committee <it>appointed</it> by Congress</vi> <vi>the company's newly <it>appointed</it> assistant director</vi> <vi>The defendant will be represented by a <phrase>court-appointed attorney</phrase>. [=a lawyer chosen by a court to defend someone who has been accused of a crime]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi><it>appointing</it> women <it>to</it> positions of power</vi> <vi>She was <it>appointed to</it> the position last year.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>He has been <it>appointed to serve</it> as president of the club.</vi> <vi>A young lawyer was <it>appointed to represent</it> the accused man.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>self-appointed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to decide or establish (something) in an official way <un>usually used as <it>appointed</it> <vi>She wasn't able to accomplish her <it>appointed</it> tasks. [=the things that she was supposed to do]</vi> <vi>We will not deviate/stray from our <it>appointed</it> course.</vi> <vi>doctors on their <it>appointed</it> rounds</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to decide (the time or place at which something will happen or be done) <un>usually used as <it>appointed</it> <vi>We were all ready at the <it>appointed</it> time/hour.</vi> <vi>on the <it>appointed</it> day</vi> <vi>Call me when you reach the <it>appointed</it> place/location.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to decorate and put furniture in (a room or space) <un>usually used as <it>(be) appointed</it> <vi>Each suite <it>is appointed</it> with handmade furniture and original artwork.</vi> <vi>We stayed in one of the hotel's beautifully <it>appointed</it> rooms.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>well-appointed</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>ap*poin*tee</ure> <sound><wav>appoin02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˌpoɪnˈti:</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*poin*tees</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>presidential <it>appointees</it> [=people chosen by the President to fill a position]</vi> <vi>He was a political <it>appointee</it>, not an elected official.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
