<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="approach[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ap*proach</hw> <sound><wav>approa01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈproʊtʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ap*proach*es</if></in> <in><if>ap*proached</if></in> <in><if>ap*proach*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move or become near or nearer to something or someone <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The cat <it>approached</it> the baby cautiously.</vi> <vi>We are <it>approaching</it> [=<it>nearing</it>] our destination.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The cat <it>approached</it> cautiously.</vi> <vi>Ease off the gas pedal to slow down as the bend in the road <it>approaches</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move or become near or nearer in time to something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We are <it>approaching</it> the end of the fiscal year.</vi> <vi>She is <it>approaching</it> retirement. [=she will soon be retiring from her job]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Your birthday is <it>approaching</it> fast. = Your birthday is fast <it>approaching</it>. [=your birthday is soon]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to get close to (an amount or level) <vi>This weekend we're expecting temperatures <it>approaching</it> 100 degrees.</vi> <vi>The success rates <it>approach</it> 90 percent.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be almost the same as (something or someone) <vi>We were never treated with anything even remotely <it>approaching</it> rudeness. [=no one was at all rude to us]</vi> <vi>He has a wild laugh that sometimes <it>approaches</it> hysteria.</vi> <vi>a reproduction that <it>approaches</it> the quality of the original painting</vi> <vi>When it comes to cooking Italian food, no one can <it>approach</it> her. [=no one is as good at cooking Italian food as she is]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to start talking to (someone) for some purpose (such as to ask a question or make a request) <vi>The supervisor is quite easy to <it>approach</it>, so don't hesitate to bring up any problems you have.</vi> <vi>We were advised to never be too aggressive when <it>approaching</it> a potential client.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) approached</it> <vi>He <it>was approached</it> about the job but he didn't take it.</vi> <vi>I <it>was approached</it> by a young boy asking me to make a donation.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to deal with or think about (something) <vi>When writing, consider the way your reader will <it>approach</it> the text.</vi> <vi>She <it>approached</it> the problem from a different angle.</vi> <vi>I will <it>approach</it> the idea with an open mind.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="approach[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">approach</hw> <altpr>əˈproʊtʃ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>approaches</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of dealing with something :a way of doing or thinking about something <vi>a traditional <it>approach</it></vi> <vi>trying a more healthy <it>approach</it></vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I really admire your direct <it>approach to</it> the problem.</vi> <vi>Some doctors are trying a radical new <it>approach to</it> cancer treatment.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the act of moving or becoming near or nearer to someone or something :the act of approaching <vi>The cat made a cautious <it>approach</it>.</vi> :an act or occurrence in which something comes nearer <vi>The quiet afternoon was interrupted by the <it>approach</it> of a motorboat.</vi> <vi>A loud growl warned us of the bear's <it>approach</it>.</vi> <vi>With the <it>approach</it> of summer came longer, hotter days.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of speaking to someone for some purpose (such as to ask a question or make a request) <un>often plural <vi>A group of businessmen has made <it>approaches</it> to the owners of the club with an offer to buy it.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a road or path that leads to a place <vi>This road is the only <it>approach</it> to the cabin (that is) not blocked by snow.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is similar <it>to</it> another thing <vi>These potted herbs are the nearest <it>approach to</it> a garden I can manage.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the final part of a flight just before landing <vi>The pilot lowered the landing gear as the plane began its <it>approach</it>.</vi> <vi>The plane was <phrase>on final approach</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
