<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="appreciate"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*pre*ci*ate</hw> <sound><wav>apprec05.wav</wav><wav>apprec04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpri:ʃiˌeɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ap*pre*ci*ates</if></in> <in><if>ap*pre*ci*at*ed</if></in> <in><if>ap*pre*ci*at*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to understand the worth or importance of (something or someone) :to admire and value (something or someone) <vi>The company strives to make its employees feel <it>appreciated</it>.</vi> <vi>Living in the city has taught me to <it>appreciate</it> the differences between people.</vi> <vi>Those who <it>appreciate</it> fine wine will enjoy reading the restaurant's wine list.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be grateful for (something) <vi>I really <it>appreciated</it> the information you gave me.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>appreciate</it> being ignored. [=I do not like to be ignored]</vi> <vi>Your help the other day was greatly <it>appreciated</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to make a polite request <vi>I <phrase>would appreciate it</phrase> if you would tell your father to call me. [=please tell your father to call me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be aware of (something) :to recognize or understand (something) <vi>I'm not sure you <it>appreciate</it> [=<it>understand</it>] how crucial it is that we find these documents.</vi> <vi>The tiny creature contributes to its ecosystem in ways we are only just beginning to <it>appreciate</it>.</vi> <vi>I don't think you <it>appreciate</it> the complexity of the situation.</vi> <vi>I <it>appreciate</it> what the artist is trying to do, but I think the painting fails to do it.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to increase in value <vi>Given the history of the company, your investment should <it>appreciate</it> (in value) over time.</vi> <vi>rapidly <it>appreciating</it> assets</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>depreciate</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>ap*pre*cia*tive</ure> <sound><wav>apprec11.wav</wav><wav>apprec10.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpri:ʃətɪv</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more ap*pre*cia*tive; most ap*pre*cia*tive</gram> <utxt><vi>I'm very <it>appreciative</it> of your efforts on my behalf. [=I'm very grateful for your efforts]</vi> <vi>She gave an <it>appreciative</it> nod. [=a nod that showed that she appreciated something]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>ap*pre*cia*tive*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>She listened to the story, nodding <it>appreciatively</it>.</vi></utxt></uro> <syns><sc>appreciate</sc>, <sc>value</sc>, <sc>prize</sc>, <sc>treasure</sc>, and <sc>cherish</sc> mean to feel that something is important and worth treating with special care. <sc>appreciate</sc> often suggests knowledge that makes it possible to enjoy or admire how excellent something is. <vi>Over the years, I've come to <it>appreciate</it> fine wine.</vi> <sc>value</sc> suggests that a thing is worth a lot simply because of what it is. <vi>I <it>value</it> our friendship so much.</vi> <sc>prize</sc> is used when you are very proud of something you have or own. <vi>Despite the time and money it demands, he <it>prizes</it> that sailboat.</vi> <sc>treasure</sc> suggests that you enjoy having or owning something and are careful about keeping it in good condition. <vi>You'll <it>treasure</it> these pictures.</vi> <sc>cherish</sc> describes a very strong love and desire to care for something or someone. <vi>She <it>cherishes</it> her children above all.</vi></syns></entry>

</entry_list>
