<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="approval"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*prov*al</hw> <sound><wav>approv03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpru:vəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*prov*als</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the belief that something or someone is good or acceptable :a good opinion of someone or something <vi>children who never gained/won their parents' <it>approval</it></vi> <vi>He nodded in full <it>approval</it> of their decision. [=he nodded to show that he agreed with their decision]</vi> <vi>I hope that these arrangements <phrase>meet with your approval</phrase>. [=I hope that these arrangements are acceptable to you; I hope that you approve of these arrangements]</vi> <vi>The governor's <phrase>approval rating</phrase> with the voters is going up. [=a larger number of voters say that the governor is doing a good job]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disapproval</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:permission to do something :acceptance of an idea, action, plan, etc. <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Do I have your <it>approval</it> to make the changes?</vi> <vi>The change is subject to the committee's <it>approval</it>. [=the change must be approved by the committee]</vi> <vi>The rally will be on May 19, provided the city gives its <it>approval</it>.</vi> <vi>The company is seeking <it>approval</it> of the drug [=is seeking official permission to sell the drug] as a treatment for cancer.</vi> <vi>The government has so far withheld <it>approval</it> of the drug.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We were required to get <it>approvals</it> at each stage of the project.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>seal of approval</tag> at <dxt>seal</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>on approval</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you buy something <it>on approval</it>, you can return it after using it for a period of time if you decide that you do not want it. <vi>We bought the new furniture <it>on approval</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="seal[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">seal</hw> <altpr>ˈsi:l</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>seals</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:an official mark that is stamped on paper or on a small piece of wax to show that something (such as a document) is genuine and has been officially approved <vi>The paperwork must have a notary's <it>seal</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a small piece of stamped wax or a small sticker that is put on a letter or envelope to keep it closed or to show that it has not been opened</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a device with a raised design that can be pressed into something (such as paper or wax) to make a seal</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a piece of material (such as rubber) that is used on the lid of a container to keep air, water, etc., out of the container or to show the container has not been opened <vi>a rubber <it>seal</it> on the jar</vi> <vi>The plastic <it>seal</it> on the bottle was broken.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the state of being closed tightly so that no air, water, etc., can pass through <vi>The caulk gives the window an airtight <it>seal</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>seal of approval</dre> <def><dt>:an action or statement that shows approval or official acceptance <vi>The bill has the President's <it>seal of approval</it>.</vi> <vi>Fans have given the band's new song their <it>seal of approval</it>. [=fans like the band's new song]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set the seal on</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to make (something) final or definite <vi>The goal <it>set the seal on</it> their victory. [=the goal sealed/assured their victory]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>under seal</dre> <def><sl>law</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:having an official seal that prevents the public from seeing or reading it <vi>a document/contract <it>under seal</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>seal</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
