<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="argue"> <hw highlight="yes">ar*gue</hw> <sound><wav>argue001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚgju</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ar*gues</if></in> <in><if>ar*gued</if></in> <in><if>ar*gu*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to give reasons for or against something :to say or write things in order to change someone's opinion about what is true, what should be done, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>argued</it> against the proposed law.</vi> <vi>The senator <it>argued</it> in favor of lowering taxes.</vi> <vi>They <it>argued</it> (convincingly/persuasively) against cutting the budget.</vi> <vi>He's always willing to <it>argue</it> for what is right.</vi> <vi><it>argue</it> for better funding</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>argued</it> that the proposed law should be defeated.</vi> <vi>He <it>argued</it> that it's far too early to make a decision.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to decide to do or not do something by giving reasons <vi>They tried to <it>argue</it> their parents into getting a new car. [=to persuade their parents to get a new car]</vi> <vi>No one can <it>argue</it> me out of doing this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to disagree or fight by using angry words :<sx>quarrel</sx> <vi>Their neighbors <it>argued</it> (with each other) all the time.</vi> <vi>They started <it>arguing</it> about/over politics/religion.</vi> <vi>She would <it>argue</it> with anyone.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to express doubt or disagreement about something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>You <phrase>can't argue with</phrase> her success. [=you can't deny that she is successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to show that something is or is not necessary, appropriate, etc. <un>usually + <it>for</it> or <it>against</it> <vi>The result <it>argues for</it> a new approach. [=the result shows that we need a new approach]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give evidence of (something) <vi>The facts <it>argue</it> [=<it>indicate, show</it>] his innocence.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>argue the toss</dre> <dx>see <dxt>toss</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>ar*gu*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ar*gu*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="toss[2]"> <hw hindex="2">toss</hw> <altpr>ˈtɑ:s</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>tosses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act of throwing or tossing something with a quick, light motion <vi>a bouquet <it>toss</it></vi> <vi>He gave the salad a quick <it>toss</it>. [=he tossed the salad]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>ring toss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of throwing a coin up into the air in order to make a decision about something based on which side of the coin is shown after it lands <vi>They decided what to do by a coin <it>toss</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>toss</it> of a coin</vi> <vi>She won the <it>toss</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the act of moving your head suddenly upward and backward <vi>She threw her hair back with a <it>toss</it> of her head.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>argue the toss</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to argue or disagree about something that is not important, that cannot be changed, etc.</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not give a toss</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to not care at all about something <vi>He does<it>n't give a toss</it> about our problems.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
