<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="around[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">around</hw> <sound><wav>around01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈraʊnd</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in a circle <vi>The wheel went/turned <it>around</it> (and <it>around</it>).</vi> <vi>We kept going <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] in circles without getting anywhere.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in, along, or through a curving path <vi>The road goes <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] by the lake.</vi> <vi>Don't take the long way <it>around</it>: I know a shortcut.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt><un>used to indicate a measurement that is made along the outer surface of something circular <vi>“How big <it>around</it> is the tree?” “It's five feet <it>around</it>.” [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] [=the circumference of the tree is five feet]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate that a number, amount, time, etc., is not exact or certain <vi>The price of dinner was <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly US</it>) <it>about</it>] $50.</vi> <vi>It lasted <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly US</it>) <it>about</it>] a century.</vi> <vi>The repair should cost <it>around</it> [=<it>approximately, roughly</it>] $200.</vi> <vi>We should leave in <it>around</it> 10 minutes.</vi> <vi>We got home at <it>around</it> 8 o'clock. = (<it>US</it>) We got home <phrase>around about</phrase> 8 o'clock. [=it was approximately 8 o'clock when we got home]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:in close from all sides so as to surround someone or something <vi>People crowded <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] to hear her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in many different directions <vi>They wandered <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>about</it>] for several hours.</vi> <vi>He entered the room and looked <it>around</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:in or to many different places <vi>People were standing <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>about</it>], talking quietly in small groups.</vi> <vi>His tools were scattered <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>about</it>] carelessly.</vi> <vi>She travels <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>about</it>] on business quite a lot.</vi> <vi>This is a very interesting town: let me show you <it>around</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:in or near a particular area or place <vi>We went to the store, but there was no one <it>around</it>. [=there was no one there; (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) there was no one about]</vi> <vi>Let's wait/stay/stick <it>around</it> awhile.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure where it is, but it must be <it>around</it> somewhere.</vi> <vi>It's safer when there are other people <it>around</it>.</vi> <vi>I'd like to speak to him if he's <it>around</it>.</vi> <vi>So long, then! <phrase>(I'll) See you around</phrase>! [=I'll see you later]</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to a particular place <vi>Why don't you come <it>around</it> (to my house) for dinner?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:in the opposite direction <vi>She turned (completely) <it>around</it>. [=(less commonly) <it>about</it>, (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used with some verbs to indicate repeated or continued action or behavior that does not have a clear or definite purpose <vi>He's always joking <it>around</it> when he should be serious.</vi> <vi>Don't play/fool <it>around</it> with your food like that!</vi> <vi>I was just standing <it>around</it>, waiting for the train to arrive.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that returns in a regular or repeated way <vi>Winter has come <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to describe how two things are arranged or ordered <vi>You put the fork on the left and the knife on the right. They should be the other way <it>around</it>. [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] [=the fork should be on the right and the knife on the left]</vi> <vi>You've got them the wrong way <it>around</it>. [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>come around</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="around[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">around</hw> <altpr>əˈraʊnd</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:on all sides of (something or someone) <vi>a house with trees (all) <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] it</vi> <vi>The people were seated <it>around</it> the table.</vi> <vi>A crowd gathered <it>around</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:so as to circle or surround (something or someone) <vi>He tied the rope <it>around</it> his waist.</vi> <vi>They wrapped the blanket <it>around</it> [=<it>about</it>] her.</vi> :moving so as to circle (something or someone) <vi>The Earth revolves/goes/moves <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] the Sun.</vi> <vi>We went all <it>around</it> the lake enjoying the different views.</vi> <vi>They sailed <it>around</it> the world.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:over or in different parts of (a place) <vi>He traveled (all) <it>around</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>round</it>] the country.</vi> <vi>He's a well-known figure <it>around</it> the town.</vi> <vi>We drove all <it>around</it> the town looking for him.</vi> <vi>This is a very interesting town: let me show you <it>around</it> it.</vi> <vi>We took a tour <it>around</it> New England.</vi> <vi>You can find lots of good restaurants <it>around</it> here.</vi> <vi>I help her out sometimes <it>around</it> the house.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:on or to another side of (something) <vi>We were surprised by what we saw when we walked <it>around</it> the corner.</vi> <vi>There's another door <it>around</it> the back of the house.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:in the area near to (something or someone) <vi>Fish are abundant <it>around</it> [=<it>about, near</it>] the reefs.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure where it is, but it must be somewhere <it>around</it> here. = It must be <it>around</it> here somewhere.</vi> <vi>I feel happier when I'm <it>around</it> her.</vi> <vi>It happened in Naples—or (somewhere) <it>around</it> there.</vi> <vi>I can tell from/by your accent that you're not from <it>around</it> here.</vi> <vi>It's safer when there are other people <it>around</it> you.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:near or not far from (something) in time <vi>The company was founded (at) <it>around</it> [=<it>about</it>] the turn of the century.</vi> <vi>a night <it>around</it> [=<it>about</it>] midsummer</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:so as to avoid or get past (something) <vi>She went <it>around</it> the puddle to avoid getting dirty.</vi> <vi>We found a way <it>around</it> their objections.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the central part or idea used for building or organizing something <vi>a society built/organized <it>around</it> kinship ties</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="around[3]"> <hw hindex="3">around</hw> <altpr>əˈraʊnd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:existing or active <vi>She is among the most creative of the artists <it>around</it> [=<it>active, working</it>] today.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>been around</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that has <it>been around</it> for a long time has existed or been available for a long time. <vi>I'm surprised you haven't read that book yet. It's <it>been around</it> [=<it>been out</it>] for ages!</vi> A person who has <it>been around</it> has had a lot of different experiences and knows a lot about the world. <vi>You're a man of the world: I can tell you've <it>been around</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up and around</dre> <dx>see <dxt>up</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="around-the-clock"> <hw>around–the–clock</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:happening or continuing all day and all night <vi>The prisoner requires <it>around-the-clock</it> [=<it>round-the-clock, constant</it>] surveillance.</vi> <vi><it>around-the-clock</it> care</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all-around"> <hw>all–around</hw> <sound><wav>allar01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɑ:ləˈraʊnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:relating to or involving many different things <vi>The computer has good <it>all-around</it> performance.</vi> <vi>There has been an <it>all-around</it> improvement in his work recently.</vi> :considered in a general way <vi>He is an <it>all-around</it> good guy.</vi> <vi>She is a teacher, writer, and <it>all-around</it> nice woman.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:skillful or useful in many ways <vi>She's the best <it>all-around</it> player on the team.</vi> <vi>a good <it>all-around</it> pickup truck</vi> <vi>The encyclopedia is an excellent <it>all-around</it> resource.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="go-around"> <hw>go–around</hw> <sound><wav>goarou01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowəˌraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>go–arounds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>go-round</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:entirely or completely <vi>She sat <it>all</it> alone.</vi> <vi>She has traveled <it>all</it> around the world.</vi> <vi>This money will be <it>all</it> yours when I die.</vi> <vi>He got <it>all</it> wet.</vi> <vi>She had buttons <it>all</it> down the side of her dress.</vi> <vi>I forgot <it>all</it> about paying the bill.</vi> <vi>The noise continued <it>all</it> through the night. [=all night long, throughout the night]</vi> <un>often used to make a statement more forceful <vi>I'm <it>all</it> in favor of trying again.</vi> <vi>His criticisms were <it>all</it> out of proportion.</vi> <vi>These problems have been occurring <phrase>all too</phrase> often. [=much too often]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for each side or player <un>used to indicate a tie score <vi>The score is 2 <it>all</it>. [=<it>apiece</it>]</vi> <vi>The game ended in a 5-<it>all</it> draw.</vi> <vi>We're tied at 3-<it>all</it> after seven innings.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <vi>The kids got <it>all</it> excited when they saw Santa Claus.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all along</dre> <dx>see <dxt>along</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all around</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>all round</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in every way :from every point of view <vi>It was a good deal <it>all around</it>: we made money and nobody lost out.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for everyone <vi>Let's have drinks <it>all around</it>, bartender.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-around</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not more than <un>used to stress that an amount is surprisingly small <vi>She learned to fly a plane when she was <it>all of</it> 16 years old.</vi> <vi>The team scored <it>all of</it> six points the entire game.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:as much as <un>used to stress that an amount is somewhat large <vi>The prize is now worth <it>all of</it> 10 million dollars.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all over</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:over an entire area <vi>We looked <it>all over</it> [=<it>everywhere</it>] for you.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in every part of (something) <vi>The flower can be found <it>all over</it> the island in spring and early summer.</vi> <vi>He's lived <it>all over</it> Texas.</vi> <vi>In his office there are books piled <phrase>all over the place</phrase>. [=<it>everywhere</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>allover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:very critical of (someone) <vi>She was <it>all over</it> me for being late.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:crowding around, pushing against, or touching (someone) in a very eager or aggressive way <vi>The band's fans were <it>all over</it> them.</vi> <vi>Look at that young couple. They're <it>all over</it> each other! [=they are kissing, touching, etc., very passionately]</vi> <vi>She tried to score, but the other team's defense was <it>all over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:in every way <vi>She's her mother <it>all over</it>. [=she's just like her mother]</vi> <vi>Late again, is she? That's her <it>all over</it>. [=that's very typical of her]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all that</dre> <def><dt>:to a high degree <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I wasn't <it>all that</it> [=<it>very</it>] interested in the story.</vi> <vi>The movie wasn't <it>all that</it> [=<it>so</it>] bad.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>all that</tag> at <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all the</dre> <def><dt><un>used to give added force to a word like “more” or “better” <vi>With the economy in such bad shape, it's <it>all the more</it> important [=it's even more important] that we correct these problems quickly.</vi> <vi>If we arrive early, <it>all the better</it>. [=it will be even better if we arrive early]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:with everything considered or included :in all <vi><it>All told</it>, it took us three full days to get there.</vi> <vi>There were seven of us <it>all told</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not all there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe a person who is somewhat strange or stupid <vi>Her aunt is very sweet but <it>not all there</it> (mentally).</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all-round"> <hw>all–round</hw> <sound><wav>allro01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑ:lˈraʊnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>all-around</sx> <vi>a good <it>all-round</it> effort/athlete</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ask"> <hw highlight="yes">ask</hw> <sound><wav>ask00002.wav</wav><wav>ask00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæsk, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:sk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>asks</if></in> <in><if>asked</if></in> <in><if>ask*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say or write something to someone as a way of gaining information :to request an answer to a question <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I need to <it>ask</it> a question.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>ask</it> you a question. = (less commonly) I need to <it>ask</it> a question of you.</vi> <vi>Are there any questions you would like to <it>ask</it> (me)?</vi> <vi>Did you <it>ask</it> her yet?</vi> <vi>“Have you seen the movie yet?” he <it>asked</it>.</vi> <vi>a list of frequently <it>asked</it> questions</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>We always <it>ask</it> him <it>about</it> his mother.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>He <it>asked</it> (them) <it>if</it> they had seen the movie.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> (me) <it>if</it> I was worried.</vi> <vi>They were <it>asked whether</it> they would like to buy the car.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>why</it>, <it>what</it>, etc. <vi>You should <it>ask</it> (him) <it>why</it> he didn't come.</vi> <vi>He always <it>asks</it> (her) <it>what</it> she thinks.</vi> <vi>May I <it>ask what</it> time it is?</vi> <vi>It's not polite to <it>ask how</it> much a person weighs.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“If you don't mind me/my <it>asking</it>, how old are you?” “I'm 35 years old. Why do you <it>ask</it>?”</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>ask</it> again.</vi> <vi>“Do they have any soda?” “I don't know. I'll go <it>ask</it>.”</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>I <it>asked about</it> her plans for the future.</vi> <vi>The police were here <it>asking about</it> you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to tell someone in the form of a question that you want to be given something or that you want something to happen :to request something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you want something to drink, just <it>ask</it>. [=just tell me that you want something to drink]</vi> <vi>I would have given it to him, but he never <it>asked</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Let's stop and <it>ask for</it> directions.</vi> <vi>I'll have to <it>ask for</it> permission to leave.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked for</it> their forgiveness/help.</vi> <vi>She ate all of her food and <it>asked for</it> more.</vi> <vi>His lawyers are <it>asking for</it> the case to be dismissed.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We had to stop and <it>ask</it> directions.</vi> <vi>May I <it>ask</it> the time?</vi> <vi>Did you <it>ask</it> permission to leave?</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> their forgiveness.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>We had to <it>ask</it> someone <it>for</it> directions.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> her <it>for</it> permission.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> them <it>for</it> their forgiveness.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>He <it>asked if</it> he could use my telephone.</vi> <vi>They <it>asked</it> us <it>whether</it> we might stay an extra day.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>She <it>asked that</it> I not say anything about it.</vi> <vi>His lawyers are <it>asking that</it> the case be dismissed.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She <it>asked</it> (for permission) <it>to borrow</it> her father's car for the day.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> (for permission) <it>to leave</it> work early.</vi> <vi>You should <it>ask</it> your teacher <it>to help</it> you.</vi> <vi>Unhappy with the service, he <it>asked to see</it> the manager.</vi> <vi>He <it>asked</it> me <it>to marry</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry, but I need to <it>ask</it> you <it>to leave</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> me not <it>to say</it> anything about it to anyone.</vi> <vi>I wanted to say something about it, but she <it>asked</it> me not <it>to</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to invite (someone) to go somewhere or do something <vi>He's <it>asking</it> just a few friends to the party.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> him to lunch.</vi> <vi>They <it>asked</it> me over for dinner.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>ask someone out</phrase> is to ask someone to go on a date with you. <vi>I <it>asked her out</it> (on a date), but she turned me down.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to believe that you should receive (something) from someone <vi>She doesn't <it>ask</it> [=<it>expect</it>, <it>require</it>] a lot. She <it>asks</it> very little in return for her hard work.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The school <it>asks</it> much <it>of</it> its students. [=the school expects its students to do a lot]</vi> <vi>He says that people <it>ask</it> too little <it>of</it> their politicians.</vi> <vi>He was ready to go to war, should the government <it>ask</it> it <it>of</it> him. [=should the government ask him to go to war]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to set (a specific amount of money) as a price <vi>The dealer originally <it>asked</it> [=<it>wanted</it>] $20,000 for the car, but he sold it to me for $18,000.</vi> <vi>They're asking [=<it>charging</it>] $100 or more per concert ticket.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>asking price</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>ask after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>ask after (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask about (someone or something) <vi>He <it>asked after</it> my wife's health.</vi> <vi>He greeted us warmly and <it>asked after</it> our families. [=he asked how our families were]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to ask many people to tell you information about someone or something <vi>Maybe you should <it>ask around</it> to find out more about this guy.</vi> <vi>We usually <it>ask around</it> before trying a new restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to request to see or talk to (someone) <vi>Unhappy with the service, he <it>asked for</it> the store manager.</vi> <vi>There's someone on the phone <it>asking for</it> you.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a way that makes someone want to hurt or punish you <vi>You're <it>asking for it</it>, kid! If you keep misbehaving, you're going to get punished.</vi> <vi>All right. You <it>asked for it</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for trouble</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a way that is likely to result in trouble <vi>If you invest your money without doing careful research, you're just <it>asking for trouble</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>ask for the moon</tag> at <dxt>moon</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask yourself</dre> <def><dt><snote>To <it>ask yourself</it> something is to think about the true answer to a question. <vi><it>Ask yourself</it> what you would do in that situation.</vi> <vi>Before buying an expensive item, he needs to <it>ask himself</it> if/whether he can afford it.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>don't ask</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is too strange, embarrassing, or complicated to explain <vi>“She married and divorced a man in the same day? How is that possible?” “<it>Don't ask</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>don't ask me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not know the answer to a question <vi>“Why are they having a company meeting?” “<it>Don't ask me</it>. I only work here.”</vi> <vi><it>Don't ask me</it> why they're changing the system. I think it's fine the way it is.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for the asking</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is yours <it>for the asking</it>, you can have it if you want it or ask for it. <vi>This job is hers <it>for the asking</it>. [=she can have the job if she wants it]</vi> <vi>Our services are available/free <it>for the asking</it>. [=our services are available/free for anyone who wants them]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I ask you</dre> <def><dt><snote>People use the phrase <it>I ask you</it> before or after a question when they want someone to agree or sympathize with them. <vi>(Now) <it>I ask you</it>, is that fair? [=I don't think it's fair; do you?]</vi> <vi>Look at that hat! Who would wear such a thing, <it>I ask you</it>?</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you ask me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She looks ridiculous in that hat, <it>if you ask me</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>who asked you?</dre> <def><sl>informal + impolite</sl> <dt><un>used as a response when someone gives an opinion that is not wanted <vi>“I think you should break up with that guy.” “<it>Who asked you</it>?” [=<it>mind your own business</it>; I don't want to hear your opinion]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bandy"> <hw>ban*dy</hw> <sound><wav>bandy001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbændi</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ban*dies</if></in> <in><if>ban*died</if></in> <in><if>ban*dy*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>bandy about</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bandy around</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bandy (something) about/around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bandy about/around (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to discuss or mention (something) in a casual or informal way <vi>The candidate hasn't chosen a running mate yet, but some names have been <it>bandied about</it>.</vi> <vi>The idea had been <it>bandied about</it> several years earlier.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bandy words</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to say angry words in an argument :<sx>argue</sx> <vi>I don't want to <it>bandy words</it> with you.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
