<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="arrival"> <hw>ar*riv*al</hw> <sound><wav>arriva01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈraɪvəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ar*riv*als</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act of coming to or reaching a place :the act of arriving <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They were awaiting the <it>arrival</it> of guests.</vi> <vi>We checked into the hotel upon (our) <it>arrival</it>.</vi> <vi>The flight's estimated time of <it>arrival</it> is 11:30. = The flight's estimated <it>arrival</it> time is 11:30.</vi> <vi>When is the mail scheduled for <it>arrival</it>?</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>They track the number of airport <it>arrivals</it> and departures.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:someone or something that has come to a place :someone or something that has arrived <vi>They were late <it>arrivals</it> at the party.</vi> <vi>Have you had a look at the bookstore's new <it>arrivals</it>? [=the books that have recently come to the bookstore]</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>new arrival</phrase> is often used to refer to a baby that has recently been born. <vi>Everyone gathered at the hospital to see the family's <it>new arrival</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the time when something begins or happens <vi>They are eagerly awaiting the <it>arrival</it> of their wedding day.</vi> <vi>the changes that occur with the <it>arrival</it> of spring</vi> <vi>the <it>arrival</it> of new technology</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="dead[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dead</hw> <sound><wav>dead0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer alive or living :no longer having life <vi>Her husband is <it>dead</it>. He died last year.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>dead</it> for over 10 years now. [=she died more than 10 years ago]</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> insect/bird/dog</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> trees/leaves/skin</vi> <vi>the <it>dead</it> [=<it>lifeless</it>] bodies of the soldiers</vi> <vi>He was found <it>dead</it> in his apartment yesterday.</vi> <vi>He lay <it>dead</it> on the floor.</vi> <vi>The lost mountain climbers were believed/presumed <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>She shot him <it>dead</it>. [=she killed him by shooting him]</vi> <vi>When we found her, she was <phrase>more dead than alive</phrase>. [=almost dead; very close to death]</vi> <vi>The poster said that the robbers were wanted <phrase>dead or alive</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>as good as dead</phrase>. [=he was almost dead]</vi> <vi>She taught her dog to <phrase>play dead</phrase>. [=to lie on its back and pretend to be dead]</vi> <usageref>deceased</usageref> <snote>To <phrase>leave (someone or something) for dead</phrase> is to leave a person or animal that you know will probably die instead of trying to help. <vi>They hit the dog with their car and <it>left it for dead</it> on the side of the road.</vi> <vi>He had been badly beaten and <it>left for dead</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sin><if>dead*er</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:not able to feel or move <vi>My hand was <it>dead</it> [=<it>numb</it>] after holding the bag for so long.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very tired <vi>Our legs were completely <it>dead</it> after hiking all day.</vi> <vi>I arrived home from work <phrase>half dead</phrase>. [=<it>exhausted</it>]</vi> <vi>By the end of the day the workers were <phrase>dead on their feet</phrase>. [=very tired but still standing, working, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:feeling no emotions <vi>After the war, I was emotionally <it>dead</it>. [=I was no longer able to feel happiness, sadness, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:certain to be punished or hurt <vi>I'm <it>dead</it> if I come in late for work again.</vi> <vi>If I ever get my hands on you, you're <it>dead</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a machine or device</ssl> <dt>:no longer working especially because of not having electricity <vi>The car's battery is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> electrical outlets</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> telephone line</vi> <vi>The phones <phrase>went dead</phrase> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:no longer active or operating <vi>a <it>dead</it> [=<it>extinct</it>] volcano</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> companies</vi> <vi>That plan is <it>dead</it> for now. We've started developing a new one.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> deal</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:naturally not living <vi>rocks and other <it>dead</it> [=<it>inanimate</it>] matter</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sin><if>deader</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:lacking in activity or excitement <vi>The store's been <it>dead</it> [=<it>quiet</it>] all day.</vi> <vi>This party's completely <it>dead</it>. [=it is not lively]</vi> <vi>The audience was kind of <it>dead</it> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a time when nothing is being said or done <vi>We played cards to fill in the <it>dead</it> time between the two performances.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:no longer performed or enjoyed <vi>He says that disco is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> art form</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>of a language</ssl> <dt>:no longer spoken <vi>Latin is a <it>dead</it> language.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe a situation in which play stops during a game <vi>In American football, the ball is <it>dead</it> [=<it>out of play</it>] after an incomplete forward pass.</vi> <vi>The ball is <it>dead</it> if it goes beyond the white line.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <dt>:complete, total, or absolute <vi>There was <it>dead</it> silence in the room.</vi> <vi>She spoke with <it>dead</it> certainty.</vi> <vi>I chased them at a <it>dead</it> run for three miles.</vi> <vi>The camera is a <phrase>dead giveaway</phrase> [=clearly shows] that you're a tourist.</vi> <vi>She fell to the floor in a <phrase>dead faint</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The evening wasn't all I had hoped for, but is wasn't a <phrase>dead loss</phrase>. [=it wasn't completely bad]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>a dead ringer for</phrase> [=he looks exactly like] his father.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) They're <phrase>a dead cert</phrase> [=<it>a sure thing, a sure bet</it>] to win. [=they are certain to win]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:sudden and complete <vi>The bus came to a <it>dead</it> [=<it>abrupt</it>] stop.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:perfect or exact <vi>Her arrow hit the <it>dead</it> [=<it>very</it>] center of the target.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) dead as a doornail</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) dead as a dodo</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to stress that someone or something is dead <vi>The old captain was <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The negotiations are <it>as dead as a doornail</it>.</vi> <vi>The deal is <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat a dead horse</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>flog a dead horse</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch/see (someone) dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that people <phrase>wouldn't/won't catch/see you dead</phrase> or that you <phrase>wouldn't/won't be caught/seen dead</phrase> doing something, you refuse to let others see you doing it because it would cause you to be embarrassed. <vi>I <it>wouldn't be caught/seen dead</it> wearing that hideous outfit.</vi> <vi>She <it>won't be caught dead</it> going to the movies with her obnoxious brother.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead and buried</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>dead and gone</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer living :<sx>dead</sx> <vi>He's been <it>dead and buried</it> for 50 years.</vi> <vi>relatives long <it>dead and gone</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:no longer used or accepted <vi>Those old family traditions are <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>That idea is <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>The days of our childhood are <it>dead and gone</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead from the neck up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very stupid or foolish <vi>Most of his friends are <it>dead from the neck up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead in the water</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not making any progress :not having any chance of success <vi>The peace talks were <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi> <vi>His election campaign is <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead men tell no tales</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tale</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead on arrival</dre> <def><dt>:having died before getting to a hospital, emergency room, etc. <vi>The victim was <it>dead on arrival</it> at the hospital.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Some are saying that any new tax proposal would be <it>dead on arrival</it>. [=would have no chances of being approved]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead to rights</dre> <dx>see <dxt>right</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead to the world</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:sleeping very deeply <vi>You can't wake him up. He's <it>dead to the world</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall to the ground and die very suddenly <vi>She <it>dropped dead</it> while playing basketball.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used as a rude way to tell someone to leave you alone <vi>“He asked you for help after being such a jerk? You should have told him to <it>drop dead</it>!”</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>drop-dead</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>over my dead body</dre> <dx>see <dxt>body</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>dead*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="new[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">new</hw> <sound><wav>new00001.wav</wav><wav>new00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnu:, <it>Brit</it> ˈnju:</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>new*er</if></in> <in><if>new*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:not old :recently born, built, or created <vi>They visited the <it>new</it> library.</vi> <vi>She was looking for the <it>new</it> [=most recent] issue of the magazine.</vi> <vi>I saw their <it>new</it> baby for the first time.</vi> <vi>They planted <it>new</it> trees on the campus.</vi> <vi>a <it>new</it> kind of music</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not used by anyone else previously <vi>She couldn't afford a <it>new</it> car, so she bought a used one.</vi> <vi>He bought the car <it>new</it>.</vi> <vi>shiny <it>new</it> shoes</vi> <vi>This watch is <it>new</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>brand-new</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:recently bought, rented, etc. <vi>She is eager to see his <it>new</it> apartment/house/dog.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having recently become someone's relative, friend, employee, etc. <vi>This is my <it>new</it> stepsister.</vi> <vi>the young man and his <it>new</it> wife</vi> <vi>Come meet our <it>newest</it> [=most recently hired] employee.</vi> <vi>I made a <it>new</it> friend today.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:recently added to an existing group, organization, etc. <vi>There was a <it>new</it> kid in school today.</vi> <vi>The union voted in 10 <it>new</it> members.</vi> <vi>The company created a <it>new</it> department to run its Web site.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She is <it>new to</it> this school.</vi> <vi>Don't worry about it. You are still <it>new to</it> the job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:replacing someone or something that came before <vi>The team has a <it>new</it> coach.</vi> <vi>Have you met his <it>new</it> girlfriend?</vi> <vi>He starts his <it>new</it> job on Monday.</vi> <vi>I like your <it>new</it> haircut.</vi> <vi>The tree is growing <it>new</it> leaves.</vi> <vi>Waiter, could I please have a <it>new</it> fork? This one is dirty.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:recently discovered or learned about :not known or experienced before <vi>Scientists discovered a <it>new</it> comet.</vi> <vi>a <it>new</it> species of fish</vi> <vi>The promotion gave her a <it>new</it> sense of optimism.</vi> <vi>This drug gives <it>new</it> hope to patients.</vi> <vi>This is a <it>new</it> experience for me.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>This kind of work is still <it>new to</it> me. [=I have been doing this kind of work for only a short time]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a time, period, etc., that is beginning again and that is different from what came before <vi>A <it>new</it> day has begun.</vi> <vi>We are looking forward to the <it>new</it> year.</vi> <vi>A <it>new</it> semester starts in the fall.</vi> <vi>After college, he moved to the city to begin <phrase>a new life</phrase>. [=a time in a person's life that is different in some important way from what came before]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:healthier or more energetic <vi>I felt like a <it>new</it> man/woman after my vacation.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) good as new</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>like new</va></vr> <def><dt>:in very good condition :like something that has recently been made <vi>He painted the bicycle, and now it's <it>as good as new</it>.</vi> <vi>Once the jewelry has been cleaned, it'll be <it>like new</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>new arrival</dre> <dx>see <dxt>arrival</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>new kid on the block</dre> <dx>see <dxt>kid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pastures new</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pasture</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the new</dre> <def><dt>:new things <vi>The band played a good mix of the old and <it>the new</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn over a new leaf</dre> <dx>see <dxt>leaf</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>what else is new?</dre> <dx>see <dxt>else</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>what's new?</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a friendly greeting <vi>Hey man, <it>what's new</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>new*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>The couple admired the shiny <it>newness</it> of their remodeled kitchen.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
