<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="ask"> <hw highlight="yes">ask</hw> <sound><wav>ask00002.wav</wav><wav>ask00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæsk, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:sk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>asks</if></in> <in><if>asked</if></in> <in><if>ask*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say or write something to someone as a way of gaining information :to request an answer to a question <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I need to <it>ask</it> a question.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>ask</it> you a question. = (less commonly) I need to <it>ask</it> a question of you.</vi> <vi>Are there any questions you would like to <it>ask</it> (me)?</vi> <vi>Did you <it>ask</it> her yet?</vi> <vi>“Have you seen the movie yet?” he <it>asked</it>.</vi> <vi>a list of frequently <it>asked</it> questions</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>We always <it>ask</it> him <it>about</it> his mother.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>He <it>asked</it> (them) <it>if</it> they had seen the movie.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> (me) <it>if</it> I was worried.</vi> <vi>They were <it>asked whether</it> they would like to buy the car.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>why</it>, <it>what</it>, etc. <vi>You should <it>ask</it> (him) <it>why</it> he didn't come.</vi> <vi>He always <it>asks</it> (her) <it>what</it> she thinks.</vi> <vi>May I <it>ask what</it> time it is?</vi> <vi>It's not polite to <it>ask how</it> much a person weighs.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“If you don't mind me/my <it>asking</it>, how old are you?” “I'm 35 years old. Why do you <it>ask</it>?”</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>ask</it> again.</vi> <vi>“Do they have any soda?” “I don't know. I'll go <it>ask</it>.”</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>I <it>asked about</it> her plans for the future.</vi> <vi>The police were here <it>asking about</it> you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to tell someone in the form of a question that you want to be given something or that you want something to happen :to request something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you want something to drink, just <it>ask</it>. [=just tell me that you want something to drink]</vi> <vi>I would have given it to him, but he never <it>asked</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Let's stop and <it>ask for</it> directions.</vi> <vi>I'll have to <it>ask for</it> permission to leave.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked for</it> their forgiveness/help.</vi> <vi>She ate all of her food and <it>asked for</it> more.</vi> <vi>His lawyers are <it>asking for</it> the case to be dismissed.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We had to stop and <it>ask</it> directions.</vi> <vi>May I <it>ask</it> the time?</vi> <vi>Did you <it>ask</it> permission to leave?</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> their forgiveness.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>We had to <it>ask</it> someone <it>for</it> directions.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> her <it>for</it> permission.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> them <it>for</it> their forgiveness.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>He <it>asked if</it> he could use my telephone.</vi> <vi>They <it>asked</it> us <it>whether</it> we might stay an extra day.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>She <it>asked that</it> I not say anything about it.</vi> <vi>His lawyers are <it>asking that</it> the case be dismissed.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She <it>asked</it> (for permission) <it>to borrow</it> her father's car for the day.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> (for permission) <it>to leave</it> work early.</vi> <vi>You should <it>ask</it> your teacher <it>to help</it> you.</vi> <vi>Unhappy with the service, he <it>asked to see</it> the manager.</vi> <vi>He <it>asked</it> me <it>to marry</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry, but I need to <it>ask</it> you <it>to leave</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>asked</it> me not <it>to say</it> anything about it to anyone.</vi> <vi>I wanted to say something about it, but she <it>asked</it> me not <it>to</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to invite (someone) to go somewhere or do something <vi>He's <it>asking</it> just a few friends to the party.</vi> <vi>I <it>asked</it> him to lunch.</vi> <vi>They <it>asked</it> me over for dinner.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>ask someone out</phrase> is to ask someone to go on a date with you. <vi>I <it>asked her out</it> (on a date), but she turned me down.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to believe that you should receive (something) from someone <vi>She doesn't <it>ask</it> [=<it>expect</it>, <it>require</it>] a lot. She <it>asks</it> very little in return for her hard work.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The school <it>asks</it> much <it>of</it> its students. [=the school expects its students to do a lot]</vi> <vi>He says that people <it>ask</it> too little <it>of</it> their politicians.</vi> <vi>He was ready to go to war, should the government <it>ask</it> it <it>of</it> him. [=should the government ask him to go to war]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to set (a specific amount of money) as a price <vi>The dealer originally <it>asked</it> [=<it>wanted</it>] $20,000 for the car, but he sold it to me for $18,000.</vi> <vi>They're asking [=<it>charging</it>] $100 or more per concert ticket.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>asking price</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>ask after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>ask after (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask about (someone or something) <vi>He <it>asked after</it> my wife's health.</vi> <vi>He greeted us warmly and <it>asked after</it> our families. [=he asked how our families were]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to ask many people to tell you information about someone or something <vi>Maybe you should <it>ask around</it> to find out more about this guy.</vi> <vi>We usually <it>ask around</it> before trying a new restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to request to see or talk to (someone) <vi>Unhappy with the service, he <it>asked for</it> the store manager.</vi> <vi>There's someone on the phone <it>asking for</it> you.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a way that makes someone want to hurt or punish you <vi>You're <it>asking for it</it>, kid! If you keep misbehaving, you're going to get punished.</vi> <vi>All right. You <it>asked for it</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>ask for trouble</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a way that is likely to result in trouble <vi>If you invest your money without doing careful research, you're just <it>asking for trouble</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>ask for the moon</tag> at <dxt>moon</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ask yourself</dre> <def><dt><snote>To <it>ask yourself</it> something is to think about the true answer to a question. <vi><it>Ask yourself</it> what you would do in that situation.</vi> <vi>Before buying an expensive item, he needs to <it>ask himself</it> if/whether he can afford it.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>don't ask</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is too strange, embarrassing, or complicated to explain <vi>“She married and divorced a man in the same day? How is that possible?” “<it>Don't ask</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>don't ask me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not know the answer to a question <vi>“Why are they having a company meeting?” “<it>Don't ask me</it>. I only work here.”</vi> <vi><it>Don't ask me</it> why they're changing the system. I think it's fine the way it is.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for the asking</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is yours <it>for the asking</it>, you can have it if you want it or ask for it. <vi>This job is hers <it>for the asking</it>. [=she can have the job if she wants it]</vi> <vi>Our services are available/free <it>for the asking</it>. [=our services are available/free for anyone who wants them]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I ask you</dre> <def><dt><snote>People use the phrase <it>I ask you</it> before or after a question when they want someone to agree or sympathize with them. <vi>(Now) <it>I ask you</it>, is that fair? [=I don't think it's fair; do you?]</vi> <vi>Look at that hat! Who would wear such a thing, <it>I ask you</it>?</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you ask me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She looks ridiculous in that hat, <it>if you ask me</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>who asked you?</dre> <def><sl>informal + impolite</sl> <dt><un>used as a response when someone gives an opinion that is not wanted <vi>“I think you should break up with that guy.” “<it>Who asked you</it>?” [=<it>mind your own business</it>; I don't want to hear your opinion]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="if[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">if</hw> <sound><wav>if000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪf</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about the result or effect of something that may happen or be true <vi><it>If</it> it rains, (then) we won't go to the park.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> he actually did commit the crime, he deserves to be punished.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you believe that, you'll believe anything!</vi> <vi>Come to the party <it>if</it> you can.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you really want to know, you should ask.</vi> <vi>What will happen <it>if</it> I fail the test?</vi> <vi>You should study. <phrase>If not</phrase>, you won't pass the test. = <it>If</it> you don't (study), you won't pass the test.</vi> <vi>Please arrive early <phrase>if possible</phrase>. = Please arrive early <it>if</it> it is possible.</vi> <vi>I'll do the work myself <phrase>if necessary</phrase>. = I'll do the work myself <it>if</it> it is necessary.</vi> <vi><phrase>If and when</phrase> he comes, you can ask him. = <phrase>When and if</phrase> he comes, you can ask him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to discuss the imaginary result or effect of something that did not happen or that is or was not true <vi><it>If</it> you had studied, you would have passed the test.</vi> <vi>The situation would be funny <it>if</it> it weren't so tragic. = (<it>informal</it>) The situation would be funny <it>if</it> it wasn't so tragic.</vi> <vi>The harvest would have been good <it>if</it> it had rained.</vi> <vi>The news would be interesting <it>if</it> (it were) true, but it's not true.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something must happen before another thing can happen <vi>He said he'll come to the party <it>if</it> she comes too. = (more strongly) He said he'll come to the party <phrase>only if</phrase> she comes too. = (most strongly) He says he'll come to the party <phrase>if and only if</phrase> she comes too.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a result that always occurs when something happens <vi>He gets angry <it>if</it> [=<it>when</it>] you disagree with him.</vi> <vi>The engine stalls <it>if</it> you let it get too hot.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:even though :<sx>although</sx> <vi>It was an interesting <it>if</it> unbelievable story.</vi> <vi>Her actions were understandable, <it>if</it> not forgivable.</vi> <vi>He had to perform an annoying, <it>if</it> necessary, task.</vi> <vi>a fair, <it>if</it> tough, boss</vi> <vi>The weather was good, <it>if</it> not great.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement or question about something that is not certain <vi>I'll see <it>if</it> [=<it>whether</it>] I can come.</vi> <vi>Do you know <it>if</it> he'll come to the party?</vi> <vi>I wonder <it>if</it> it's true (or not).</vi> <vi>Frankly, I doubt <it>if</it> he'll pass the exams.</vi> <vi>She asked <it>if</it> the mail had come.</vi> <vi>We should determine/decide <it>if</it> it is safe to go swimming.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used to make a polite request or suggestion <vi>Would you mind <it>if</it> I sat here? [=may I sit here?]</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you will/would (be good enough to) follow me, ladies and gentlemen, I'll take you to your seats.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> I could make a suggestion, why don't we sit closer to the front of the theater?</vi> <vi>I'd like to stay a little longer, <phrase>if you don't mind</phrase>. = I'd like to stay a little longer, <phrase>if it's/that's all right with you</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to state an opinion in a polite way <vi>You're looking particularly lovely today, <phrase>if I may say so</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used in statements that describe feelings (such as regret) about a possible situation <vi>I'm sorry <it>if</it> you think I insulted you.</vi> <vi>I'd be sorry <it>if</it> you thought I had insulted you.</vi> <vi>I don't care <it>if</it> we're late.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used in statements and questions that express doubt <vi>I met Brenda last week—<it>if</it> that is/was in fact her real name.</vi> <vi><it>If</it> you're so smart, why aren't you rich?</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce an even stronger alternative to what has just been said <vi>These changes will have little <phrase>if any</phrase> impact on the problem.</vi> <vi>Few <it>if any</it> of the town's original settlers are left.</vi> <vi>Rarely, <phrase>if ever</phrase>, does that happen.</vi> <vi>His efforts have helped to save thousands, <phrase>if not</phrase> millions, of lives.</vi> <vi>My car is as fast as yours <it>if not</it> (even) faster.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt><un>used to express surprise about meeting someone when it is not expected <vi>So I went to the game and who should I see there <phrase>if not</phrase> [=<it>but</it>] my old friend Tom!</vi> <vi>Well, <phrase>if it isn't</phrase> my old friend Tom!</vi> <vi>So I went to the game and who did I see there <phrase>if it wasn't</phrase> my old friend Tom!</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize the truth of a statement <vi>The idea is true <it>if</it> any idea has ever been! [=the idea is certainly true]</vi> <vi>“He claims that he's never met her.” “Well, <it>if</it> that isn't the biggest load of nonsense I've ever heard!” [=that is a lot of nonsense; that is completely untrue]</vi> <vi>I'll get my revenge <phrase>if it's the last thing I do</phrase>! [=I am determined to get my revenge]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>as if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>as</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>even if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if anything</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement that strongly disagrees or contrasts with a preceding statement <vi>We don't see each other too often—<it>if anything</it> we don't see each other often enough!</vi> <vi>The economy has not improved. It has gotten worse, <it>if anything</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if it comes to that</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if I were you</dre> <def><dt><un>used when giving advice to people about how they should behave <vi>I'd study more <it>if I were you</it>. [=I think you should study more]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if not for</dre> <def><dt>:in the absence of (something or someone) :<sx>without</sx> <vi><it>If not for</it> modern medicine, fewer babies would survive.</vi> <vi><it>If not for</it> him, I wouldn't be where I am today.</vi> <un>often used in the phrases <phrase>if it were not for</phrase> and <phrase>if it had not been for</phrase> <vi><it>If it were not for</it> your donations, many more children would go hungry.</vi> <vi><it>If it hadn't been for</it> him, I wouldn't be where I am today.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if nothing else</dre> <def><dt>:at least <un>used to stress that an approving statement is true even though a stronger statement might not be <vi><it>If nothing else</it>, he's polite!</vi> <vi>The food was hot, <it>if nothing else</it>. [=the food may not have been very good, but at least it was hot]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if only</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about something that you want to happen or be true <vi><it>If only</it> she loved me in return!</vi> <vi><it>If only</it> it would stop raining.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you ask me</dre> <def><dt><un>used in statements that express an opinion <vi><it>If you ask me</it> [=in my opinion], he's a liar.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you must</dre> <dx>see <dxt>must</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>what if</dre> <dx>see <dxt>what</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="it[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">it</hw> <sound><wav>it000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪt, ət</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:that one just mentioned <un>used to refer to an object or substance <vi>I caught the ball and threw <it>it</it> back.</vi> <vi>He saw the car and immediately wanted to buy <it>it</it>.</vi> <vi>She tasted the powder and <it>it</it> was sweet.</vi></un> <un>used to refer to a living thing whose sex is unknown or is being ignored <vi>I don't know who <it>it</it> is.</vi> <vi>“Who is <it>it</it>?” “<it>It's</it> only me.”</vi> <vi>There is a rosebush near the fence, and <it>it</it> is now blooming.</vi> <vi>A fly landed on the table and I swatted <it>it</it>.</vi> <vi>He heard the baby crying and brought <it>it</it> some milk.</vi></un> <un>used to refer to an idea, quality, emotion, etc. <vi>Beauty is everywhere, and <it>it</it> is a source of great joy.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used as the subject of a verb that describes a condition or occurrence <vi><it>It</it> is cold/hot/raining/snowing outside.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is (getting) late/dark.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> will soon be summer.</vi> <vi>What time is <it>it</it>?</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is ten (minutes) after four (o'clock).</vi> <vi><it>It</it> hurts when I sneeze.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is almost summer.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is only a short walk to the beach from here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in the place of a noun, phrase, or clause that usually comes later <vi><it>It</it> hurts me to sneeze. [=to sneeze hurts me]</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is not necessary (for you) to repeat the whole thing.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> makes me happy just to think about her.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is wonderful being back here again!</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is a long way to the next town.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is said/believed that he died of a broken heart.</vi> <vi>They made <it>it</it> clear that they needed our help.</vi> <vi>I take <it>it</it> that there was some problem.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> is me you are looking for. = (<it>formal</it>) <it>It</it> is I you are looking for.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> was here that I lost my way.</vi> <vi><it>It</it> was in this city that the treaty was signed.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to refer to something that has been done or is being done or is going to be done <vi>We're going to have to do <it>it</it> again.</vi> <vi>Quit <it>it</it>! [=stop doing what you are doing]</vi> <vi>You've been arguing all afternoon. Now cut <it>it</it> out! [=stop arguing]</vi> <vi>Please do <it>it</it> right away.</vi> <vi>Okay, go to <it>it</it>! [=do the thing you are going to do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used as a direct object with little or no meaning <vi>We hoofed <it>it</it> all the way back to camp. [=we walked all the way back to camp]</vi> <vi>We decided to rough <it>it</it> on vacation this year. [=to have our vacation somewhere where we would not have our normal comforts]</vi> <vi>living <it>it</it> up [=doing exciting and enjoyable things; spending money freely while enjoying life]</vi> <vi>She offered to come with me, but I decided to go <it>it</it> alone. [=to go by myself; to go alone]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the general situation :things in general <vi>How's <it>it</it> going?</vi> <vi><it>It</it> hasn't been the same since you left.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:something previously discussed or known <vi>When the bell rings, <it>it</it> means that class is over.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>ask for it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ask</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>do</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in for it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>nothing to it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nothing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>out of it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>out</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is it</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>that's it</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is finished or completed <vi>Okay, <it>that's it</it>. You can go now.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is all that is needed or wanted <vi>I came here to visit the museum and <it>that's it</it>. [=that is all I wanted to do here]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is correct <vi>“I can't remember his name.” “I think it was Brian Johnson.” “Yes, <it>that's it</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used in an angry or annoyed way to say that you will not accept any more of something <vi><it>That's it</it>! I'm leaving!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>this is it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that this is the most important or final point <vi>Well, <it>this is it</it>—the day we've been waiting for.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="moon[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">moon</hw> <sound><wav>moon0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmu:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>moons</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the moon</bnote> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the Moon</va></svr> <dt>:the large round object that circles the Earth and that shines at night by reflecting light from the sun <vi>The telescope makes the craters on the surface of the <it>moon</it> incredibly clear.</vi> <vi>The <it>moon</it> isn't out tonight. = There's no <it>moon</it> tonight. [=the moon cannot be seen tonight]</vi> <vi>the first <it>moon</it> [=<it>lunar</it>] landing [=the first time people landed a spacecraft on the moon]</vi> <vi>the orbit of the <it>Moon</it> around the Earth</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blue moon</dxt> <dxt>full moon</dxt> <dxt>half-moon</dxt> <dxt>harvest moon</dxt> <dxt>new moon</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large round object like the moon that circles around a planet other than the Earth <vi>Europa and Io are both <it>moons</it> of Jupiter.</vi> <vi>a planet orbited by one <it>moon</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>ask for the moon</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>cry for the moon</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to ask for something that is very difficult or impossible to get <vi>The striking workers say they just want to be paid what they're worth. They're not <it>asking for the moon</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>many moons</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a very long time <vi>I visited my old school yesterday for the first time in <it>many moons</it>.</vi> <vi>But that was all <it>many moons</it> ago.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over the moon</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very happy or pleased about something <vi>She's <it>over the moon</it> at being chosen for the award.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>promise (someone) the moon</dre> <dx>see <dxt>promise</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>reach/shoot for the moon</dre> <def><dt>:to try to do or get something that is very difficult to do or get <vi>an ambitious businessman who is always <it>shooting for the moon</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>moon*less</ure> <sound><wav>moonle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmu:nləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>moonless</it> night [=a night during which the moon cannot be seen]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="trouble[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">trou*ble</hw> <sound><wav>troubl01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtrʌbəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>trou*bles</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:problems or difficulties <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The new system is giving me <it>trouble</it>.</vi> <vi>He was having <it>trouble</it> with his homework.</vi> <vi>I had a little <it>trouble</it> finding the place.</vi> <vi>He had no <it>trouble</it> finding a new job.</vi> <vi>This decision could <phrase>spell trouble</phrase> [=cause problems] for all of us.</vi> <vi>So far, the trip has been <phrase>trouble free</phrase>. [=so far, there have been no problems on the trip]</vi> <vi>gangs looking to <phrase>make/cause trouble</phrase></vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually plural <vi>She told me all her personal <it>troubles</it>.</vi> <vi>Your <it>troubles</it> are over now that he's out of your life.</vi> <vi>I have my own <it>troubles</it> to worry about.</vi> <vi>They've had some financial <it>troubles</it> since he lost his job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a situation that is difficult or has a lot of problems <vi>When the new CEO arrived, the company was <phrase>in trouble</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She's <it>in</it> big/deep financial <it>trouble</it>. [=she has serious problems with her money]</vi> <vi>She got <phrase>into trouble</phrase> with her credit cards.</vi> <vi>Can anyone help get the company <phrase>out of trouble</phrase>? [=solve the company's problems]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a situation that occurs if you do something wrong or break a rule and which will make someone angry or cause you to be punished <vi>He's always <phrase>getting in/into trouble</phrase> at school.</vi> <vi>He promised to <phrase>keep/stay out of trouble</phrase>. [=behave well, not do anything bad]</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>She was <it>in trouble with</it> the police.</vi> <vi>He will be <it>in trouble with</it> his mom if he's late.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a physical pain or illness <vi>heart/stomach <it>trouble</it></vi> <vi>She has been having <it>trouble</it> with her knee.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a situation in which a machine does not work correctly <vi>He's been having car/engine/computer <it>trouble</it>.</vi> <vi>She was having <it>trouble</it> with her computer.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a bad feature, characteristic, quality, etc. <vi>His <it>trouble</it> is that he's lazy and unreliable.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The <it>trouble with</it> driving into the city is finding a place to park.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:extra effort or work <vi>You didn't have to <phrase>go to all that trouble</phrase> for me. [=you didn't have to do all the extra work for me]</vi> <vi>Thank you for <phrase>taking the trouble</phrase> [=making the effort] to write.</vi> <vi>They didn't even <it>take the trouble</it> to call and let me know they'd be late.</vi> <vi>I decided that upgrading the software was <phrase>more trouble than it's worth</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>not worth the trouble</phrase>.</vi> <vi>If it's <phrase>no trouble</phrase> [=if it is not too difficult or inconvenient], could you bring us some more coffee?</vi> <vi>“I'm sorry to bother you.” “It's <it>no trouble</it>. I'm happy to help.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>ask for trouble</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ask</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look for trouble</dre> <dx>see <dxt>look</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
