<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="asleep"> <hw highlight="yes">asleep</hw> <sound><wav>asleep01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsli:p</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a state of sleep :sleeping <vi>“Are you <it>asleep</it>?” “No, I'm awake.”</vi> <vi>He tries to clean up the house while the kids are <it>asleep</it>.</vi> <vi>The cats are <it>asleep</it> on the floor.</vi> <vi>She was still <it>asleep</it> at noon.</vi> <snote>When people are <phrase>fast asleep</phrase> or <phrase>sound asleep</phrase>, they are sleeping very deeply. <vi>It was late at night and everyone was <it>fast asleep</it>.</vi> <vi>One moment she was <it>sound asleep</it>, the next she was wide awake!</vi></snote> <snote>If you are <phrase>half asleep</phrase>, you are very tired and not completely awake. <vi>We were still <it>half asleep</it> when we went to school the next morning.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:lacking any feeling <snote>If a part of your body (such as a foot or leg) is <it>asleep</it>, it is not able to feel anything for a brief time, usually because you have kept it in an awkward position for too long. <vi>My foot's <it>asleep</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>fall asleep</dre> <def><dt>:to begin sleeping <vi>She <it>fell asleep</it> during the movie.</vi> <vi>I woke up and I couldn't <it>fall</it> back <it>asleep</it>. [=I couldn't go to sleep again]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="fast[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">fast</hw> <altpr>ˈfæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈfɑ:st</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>faster</if></in> <in><if>fastest</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with great speed <vi>The boss expects this to be done this afternoon, so you'd better work <it>fast</it>.</vi> <vi>You're driving too <it>fast</it>!</vi> <vi>He ran as <it>fast</it> as he could.</vi> <vi>a <it>fast-</it>paced story</vi> :in a very short time :very quickly <vi>This is <it>fast</it> becoming a national problem.</vi> <vi>You need to act <it>fast</it> to take advantage of this offer.</vi> <vi>species that are <it>fast</it> disappearing = species that are disappearing <it>fast</it></vi> <vi>I don't know what caused the accident. It all happened so <it>fast</it>.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>slow</dxt> <dxt>slowly</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:in a quick and intelligent way <vi>She's a woman who can think <it>fast</it> in a crisis.</vi> <vi>You catch on <it>fast</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:quickly and in a way that is meant to deceive or persuade someone <vi>He's going to have to talk <it>fast</it> to get himself out of this mess.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fast-talk</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in a way that is not easily moved or changed <vi>The window was stuck <it>fast</it>.</vi> <vi>She held <it>fast</it> to her belief in justice.</vi> <vi>We must stand <it>fast</it> and not surrender!</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>fast and furious</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fast asleep</dre> <dx>see <dxt>asleep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>going/getting nowhere fast</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>To be <it>going/getting nowhere fast</it> is to be failing to make progress or to produce a desired result. <vi>The plan for a new stadium is <it>going nowhere fast</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not so fast</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used in speech to say that you disagree with what someone has said or to tell someone to stop or slow down <vi>“This proves they're wrong.” “<it>Not so fast</it>. There's other evidence to consider.”</vi> <vi>“The discussion is closed.” “<it>Not so fast</it>. I have a few more things to say.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
