<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="assignment"> <hw>as*sign*ment</hw> <sound><wav>assign10.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsaɪnmənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>as*sign*ments</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a job or duty that is given to someone :a task someone is required to do <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>My <it>assignment</it> was to clean the equipment. = They gave me the <it>assignment</it> of cleaning the equipment.</vi> <vi>The students were given a homework <it>assignment</it>.</vi> <vi>The reporter's <it>assignment</it> is to interview the candidate.</vi> <vi>The reporter is here on an <it>assignment</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The reporter is here <phrase>on assignment</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of assigning something or someone: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of sending someone to a particular group or place as part of a job <vi>The article discusses the recent <it>assignment</it> of senators to some of the more powerful committees.</vi> <vi>her <it>assignment</it> to the embassy in India</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the act of giving a particular value, identity, etc., to something <vi>the computer's <it>assignment</it> of a number to each image</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the act of saying that someone has something (such as blame) <vi>the <it>assignment</it> of blame/responsibility</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:the act of officially giving property or a legal right to another person <vi>the <it>assignment</it> of property</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something (such as a particular position or seat) that is chosen for you to use or have <vi>She asked if she could change her seating <it>assignment</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="self-"> <hw>self-</hw> <pr>ˌsɛlf</pr> <fl>combining form</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-pitying</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-destructive</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-sacrifice</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:by, to, with, for, or toward yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-made</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-evident</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-propelled</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-addressed</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-respect</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
