<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="associate[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">as*so*ci*ate</hw> <sound><wav>associ01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsoʊʃiˌeɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>as*so*ci*ates</if></in> <in><if>as*so*ci*at*ed</if></in> <in><if>as*so*ci*at*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to think of one person or thing when you think of another person or thing <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>I <it>associate</it> flowers <it>with</it> spring.</vi> <vi>She will always <it>associate</it> that place <it>with</it> her youth.</vi> <vi>People <it>associate</it> the company <it>with</it> televisions but it also makes computers.</vi></un> <snote>When one thing is <phrase>associated with</phrase> another, they happen together or are related or connected in some way. <vi>There are several dangers/risks <it>associated with</it> [=<it>connected with</it>] that approach.</vi> <vi>plants <it>associated with</it> the desert</vi> <vi>He has symptoms <it>associated with</it> lung disease.</vi> <vi>There are health problems that are often <it>associated with</it> poverty.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be together <it>with</it> another person or group as friends, partners, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>associates with</it> [=is friends with] some pretty strange people.</vi> <vi>They denied <it>associating with</it> terrorists. [=they denied being involved with terrorists]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He was <it>associated</it> [=<it>connected, identified</it>] <it>with</it> a group of radicals in the government.</vi> <vi>I no longer wish to be <it>associated with</it> people like him.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>associates herself</phrase> <it>with</it> some pretty strange people.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>associate yourself with</phrase> something, such as a political movement, you show or say that you support and agree with it. <vi>He was reluctant to <it>associate himself with</it> the government's position.</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="associate[2]"> <hw hindex="2">as*so*ci*ate</hw> <sound><wav>associ02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsoʊʃijət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>as*so*ci*ates</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a person who you work with or spend time with <vi>business <it>associates</it> [=<it>colleagues</it>]</vi> <vi>Her <it>associates</it> respected her for her hard work.</vi> <vi>He is a known <it>associate</it> of criminals. [=he is known to associate with criminals; people know that he works with or spends time with criminals]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a member of a group or organization who is at a level that is below the highest level <vi>She started as an <it>associate</it> at the law firm.</vi> <un>sometimes used in the names of companies <vi>He works for Jones and <it>Associates</it>, a consulting firm in Santa Fe.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="associate[3]"> <hw hindex="3">as*so*ci*ate</hw> <sound><wav>associ03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsoʊʃijət</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:having a rank or position that is below the highest level in a group, organization, etc. <vi>He's an <it>associate</it> member of the club but he hopes to become a full member soon.</vi> <vi>She was promoted from assistant editor to <it>associate</it> editor and may soon be promoted to senior editor.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="associate professor"> <hw>associate professor</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -sors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a teacher at a U.S. college or university who has a rank above an assistant professor and below a full professor</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="associate's degree"> <hw>associate's degree</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -grees</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a degree that is given to a student who has completed two years of study at a junior college, college, or university in the U.S.</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
