<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attach"> <hw highlight="yes">at*tach</hw> <sound><wav>attach01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtætʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>at*tach*es</if></in> <in><if>at*tached</if></in> <in><if>at*tach*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to fasten or join one thing <it>to</it> another <vi>I've <it>attached</it> an application <it>to</it> the brochure for you.</vi> <vi>She <it>attached</it> a note <it>to</it> the package.</vi> <vi>I <it>attached</it> the file <it>to</it> the e-mail.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) attached</it> <vi>A hook <it>is attached to</it> the back of the picture frame.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The man <it>attached</it> the blame <it>to</it> the two boys. [=said the two boys should be blamed]</vi> <vi>The lawyer <it>attached</it> [=<it>added</it>] new conditions <it>to</it> the contract.</vi> <vi>The shy child <it>attached</it> herself <it>to</it> her mother [=stayed close to her mother] during the whole party.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be or become joined or connected <vi>The handle <it>attaches</it> here on the top.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>detach</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to associate or connect one thing with another <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>It's obvious in the way he dresses that he <it>attaches</it> great importance <it>to</it> appearance. [=he thinks appearance is very important]</vi> <vi>People <it>attach</it> different meanings <it>to</it> the poem. [=people understand the meaning of the poem in different ways]</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) attached</it> <vi>Magical powers were once thought to <it>be attached to</it> the stone. [=the stone was once thought to have magical powers]</vi> <vi>Little credibility <it>was attached to</it> his story. [=people did not think that his story was very credible]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to associate or connect (yourself) with someone or something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>attached</it> himself <it>to</it> an older, wealthy woman.</vi> <vi>She <it>attached</it> herself <it>to</it> the cause.</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) attached</it> <vi>His doctor <it>is attached to</it> the clinic. [=his doctor is associated with the clinic]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
