<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attention"> <hw highlight="yes">at*ten*tion</hw> <sound><wav>attent01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtɛnʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>at*ten*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act or power of carefully thinking about, listening to, or watching someone or something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>We focused our <it>attention</it> on this particular poem.</vi> <vi>My <it>attention</it> wasn't really on the game.</vi> <vi>The game was boring and my <it>attention</it> began to wander. [=I was losing interest in the game and started thinking about other things]</vi> <vi>You need to <phrase>pay more attention</phrase> in school.</vi> <vi>Please give me your <phrase>undivided/full/complete attention</phrase>. [=please listen carefully and concentrate on what I am saying and doing]</vi> <vi>The movie <phrase>keeps/holds your attention</phrase> [=<it>interest</it>] right to the very end.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Her job requires careful <it>attention to</it> detail.</vi> <vi>You need to <phrase>pay more attention to</phrase> the teacher.</vi> <vi><phrase>Don't pay any attention to</phrase> what the other kids say. [=ignore what the other kids say]</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>turn/give our attention to</phrase> the next project.</vi> <vi><phrase>Pay (close/careful) attention to</phrase> what he says.</vi></un> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Lately she's been focusing her <it>attentions</it> on making sales.</vi> <snote>This sense is sometimes used as an interjection. <vi><it>Attention</it>, please! [=please give me your attention]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:notice, interest, or awareness <vi>She likes all the <it>attention</it> she is getting from the media/press.</vi> <vi>The actor avoids drawing <it>attention</it> to himself.</vi> <vi>The book has received/attracted national <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The trial is getting a lot of public <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The children were competing for the teacher's <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>A cat on a leash is sure to attract <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>Your hard work and dedication have not <phrase>escaped my attention</phrase>. [=I have noticed your hard work and dedication]</vi> <vi>The book's title <phrase>grabbed/caught my attention</phrase>. [=the title caused me to look at the book]</vi> <vi>He was trying to <phrase>divert/distract attention</phrase> away from his friend's mistake. [=he was trying to keep people from noticing or thinking about his friend's mistake]</vi> <vi>We tried to <phrase>attract/get your attention</phrase> [=we tried to get you to see us], but you didn't hear us calling you.</vi> <vi>Thank you for <phrase>bringing the matter to my attention</phrase>. [=making me aware of the matter]</vi> <vi>It has been <phrase>brought to my attention</phrase> [=I've been made aware] that the meeting has been canceled.</vi> <vi>I would like to <phrase>call/bring your attention to</phrase> a problem we are having.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>came to my attention</phrase> [=I noticed] that several items were missing from my office.</vi> <vi>It has <phrase>come to my attention</phrase> [=I have been made aware] that some people were offended by my comments.</vi> <vi>He loves being the <phrase>center of attention</phrase>. [=he loves being noticed and watched by many people]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:special care or treatment <vi>Be sure the dog gets plenty of <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The house is in good shape, but the porch needs some <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The victim needed immediate medical <it>attention</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>attentions</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:acts of kindness, care, or courtesy :acts that show affection or admiration for someone <vi>She found his <it>attentions</it> flattering.</vi> <vi>She has been receiving unwanted <it>attentions</it> from a coworker.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way a soldier stands with the body stiff and straight, the feet together, and both arms at the sides <un>often used as a command <vi><it>Attention</it>!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at attention</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>to attention</va></svr> <dt>:standing silently with the body stiff and straight, the feet together, and both arms at the sides <vi>(<it>US</it>) The troops <phrase>stood at attention</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) The troops stood <phrase>to attention</phrase>.</vi> <dx>compare <tag>at ease</tag> at <dxt>ease</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a position that shows careful listening or attention <vi>The dog sat <it>at attention</it>, listening for something in the distance.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="attention deficit disorder"> <hw>attention deficit disorder</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>medical</sl> <dt>:a condition in which someone (such as a child) has problems with learning and behavior because of being unable to think about or pay attention to things for very long <un>abbr. <it>ADD</it></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="attention span"> <hw>attention span</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ spans</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the length of time during which someone is able to think about or remain interested in something <vi>people with short <it>attention spans</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="snap[1]"> <hw hindex="1">snap</hw> <sound><wav>snap0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsnæp</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>snaps</if></in> <in><if>snapped</if></in> <in><if>snap*ping</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to break quickly with a short, sharp sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The branch <it>snapped</it> and fell to the ground.</vi> <vi>The cable suddenly <it>snapped</it>.</vi> <vi>The earpiece of his glasses <it>snapped</it> off.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>snapped</it> the twig in two.</vi> <vi>The boy <it>snapped</it> the wing off his toy airplane.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to move into a specified position with a short, sharp sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The trap <it>snapped</it> shut.</vi> <vi>The bent tree <it>snapped</it> back into an upright position.</vi> <vi>The pieces <it>snap</it> [=<it>click</it>] easily into place.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>snapped</it> the lid shut.</vi> <vi>She <it>snapped</it> the pieces together.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to close (something) with a fastener and especially with a snap <vi>She <it>snapped</it> her handbag shut.</vi> <vi>He <it>snapped</it> (up) his jacket.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to turn (something) <it>on</it> or <it>off</it> with a switch <vi><it>snap on/off</it> the lights</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to make a short, sharp sound or to cause (something) to make a short, sharp sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>A fire <it>snapped</it> [=<it>crackled</it>] in the wood stove.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The driver <it>snapped</it> [=<it>cracked</it>] the whip to get the horses moving.</vi> <vi>a bored student <it>snapping</it> her chewing gum</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to use your thumb and fingers to make a short, sharp sound <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>People <phrase>snapped their fingers</phrase> to the beat.</vi> <vi>He <it>snapped his fingers</it> to get the waiter's attention.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>People in the audience <it>snapped</it> to the beat.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to take (a photograph) <vi>tourists <it>snapping</it> pictures</vi> <vi>The images were <it>snapped</it> by a satellite camera.</vi> :to photograph (someone or something) <vi>A photographer <it>snapped</it> the famous couple leaving a London club last week.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to speak using short, angry sentences or phrases <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>at</it> <vi>They argued and <it>snapped at</it> each other all the time.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>snapped</it> that I was lucky to have a job at all.</vi> <vi>“Leave me alone!” he <it>snapped</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to suddenly no longer be able to control your emotions because of a difficult situation, circumstance, etc. <vi>She <it>snapped</it> under the pressure of the job.</vi> <vi>He just <it>snapped</it> and started swearing at everybody.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:to move with a quick, short movement or to cause (something) to move with a quick, short movement <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Flags <it>snapped</it> in the wind.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>When you're throwing, <it>snap</it> your wrist as you release the ball.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause the end of (a series of wins, losses, successes, etc.) <vi>They <it>snapped</it> [=<it>broke</it>] a 10-game losing streak. [=they won a game after losing 10 games]</vi> <vi>His hitting streak was <it>snapped</it> at 18 games.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:to pass (the ball) back to a teammate and especially to the quarterback by passing it between your legs at the start of a play <vi>The center <it>snapped</it> [=<it>hiked</it>] the ball.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to try to bite someone or something suddenly and quickly <un>usually + <it>at</it> <vi>The dog <it>snapped at</it> a fly.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>snap out of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>snap out of (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>snap (someone) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop being in or to cause (someone) to stop being in (an unhappy condition or mood, a daydream, etc.) <vi>I don't know how to get her to <it>snap out of</it> her depression. [=to stop being depressed]</vi> <vi>The sound of a door slamming <it>snapped me out of</it> my daydream.</vi> <vi>Come on, <phrase>snap out of it</phrase>! You can't let your breakup get you so depressed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>snap to attention</dre> <def><dt><snote>A soldier who <it>snaps to attention</it> moves quickly to a position of standing silently with the body stiff and straight, the feet together, and both arms at the sides. The phrase is also used figuratively. <vi>The children <it>snapped to attention</it> [=suddenly stopped moving around, talking, etc.] when the teacher clapped his hands.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>snap to it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to start working harder or more quickly <vi>You'll have to <it>snap to it</it> if you want to finish on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>snap up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>snap (something or someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>snap up (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to buy or take (something or someone) quickly or eagerly <vi>Shoppers came to the store to <it>snap up</it> bargains after the holidays.</vi> <vi>When they see your work history, they'll <it>snap</it> you <it>up</it>! [=hire you immediately]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
