<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attitude"> <hw highlight="yes">at*ti*tude</hw> <sound><wav>attitu01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈætəˌtu:d, <it>Brit</it> ˈætəˌtju:d</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>at*ti*tudes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the way you think and feel about someone or something <vi>He has a positive/negative <it>attitude</it> about the changes.</vi> <un>often + <it>to, toward</it>, or <it>towards</it> <vi>I don't understand your <it>attitude to</it> money.</vi> <vi>She's studying how <it>attitudes toward</it> death vary from culture to culture.</vi> <vi>He wants to change the hostile <it>attitude</it> they have <it>toward</it> technology.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a feeling or way of thinking that affects a person's behavior <vi>He has an aggressive/rebellious <it>attitude</it>. [=he behaves toward other people in an aggressive/rebellious way]</vi> <vi>She's friendly and has a good <it>attitude</it>.</vi> <vi>You need to change your bad <it>attitude</it>.</vi> <vi>There's been a change/shift in his <it>attitude</it> since his accident.</vi> <vi>She has an <phrase>attitude problem</phrase>. [=she is not friendly or cooperative]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a way of thinking and behaving that people regard as unfriendly, rude, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I don't know what her problem is. She has a real <it>attitude</it>.</vi> <vi>I suggest you get rid of that <it>attitude</it> and shape up.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He was showing some <it>attitude</it> during practice today, so the coach benched him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a strong, confident, or impressive quality <vi>a band/movie with <it>attitude</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:a particular way of positioning your body <vi>She bowed her head in an <it>attitude</it> of prayer.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cop an attitude</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cop</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cop[2]"> <hw hindex="2">cop</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:p</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cops</if></in> <in><if>copped</if></in> <in><if>cop*ping</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to get (something desirable) <vi>I managed to <it>cop</it> an invitation.</vi> <vi>She <it>copped</it> [=<it>took</it>] first prize in the competition.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to steal or take (something) from someone <vi>Somebody <it>copped</it> my watch.</vi> <vi>He <it>copped</it> the idea from me.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to receive (something undesirable) <vi>They expected me to <it>cop</it> all the blame!</vi> <vi>He <it>copped</it> the full force of the blow.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cop a feel</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt>:to touch someone in an unwanted and unexpected sexual way <vi>Some guy on the bus tried to <it>cop a feel</it>! [=some guy on the bus tried to grope me]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop an attitude</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to show that you believe you are more important or better than other people by behaving in a rude or unpleasant way <vi>The students tried to <it>cop an attitude</it> with the new teacher.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop a plea</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to admit to doing a less serious crime than the one you are accused of :to agree to a plea bargain <vi>Her lawyers convinced her to <it>cop a plea</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop hold of</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to grab or take hold of (something) <vi><it>Cop hold of</it> this part while I tighten the screw.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop it</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be punished for doing something wrong <vi>When dad gets home, you're going to <it>cop it</it>! [=(<it>US</it>) <it>get it</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop off</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit slang</sl> <dt>:to have sexual intercourse <it>with</it> someone <vi>He <it>copped off with</it> one of the girls at the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop out</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not do something that you are expected to do <vi>She said she would come, but then she <it>copped out</it> at the last minute.</vi> <vi>You'd better not <it>cop out</it> on me!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail to deal with a problem or situation <vi>He accused the mayor of <it>copping out</it> on the issue of homelessness.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cop-out</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cop to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cop to (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <dt>:to admit to doing (something) <vi>He agreed to <it>cop to</it> a misdemeanor.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
