<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attract"> <hw highlight="yes">at*tract</hw> <sound><wav>attrac01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtrækt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>at*tracts</if></in> <in><if>at*tract*ed</if></in> <in><if>at*tract*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to choose to do or be involved in something <vi>The company has a difficult time <it>attracting</it> good employees because of its poor pay and benefits.</vi> <vi>The chance to travel around the world <it>attracted</it> me to a career as a flight attendant.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to like or be interested in something <un>usually used as <it>(be) attracted</it> <vi>He <it>is attracted</it> to hockey because of the constant action of the game.</vi> <vi>I <it>was attracted</it> by the town's vibrant art community.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to go to or move to or toward a place <vi>The museum <it>attracts</it> visitors from all over the world.</vi> <vi>The smell of freshly baked cookies <it>attracted</it> the children (to the kitchen).</vi> <vi>The scent will <it>attract</it> certain insects.</vi> <vi>Certain insects are <it>attracted</it> by the scent.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to cause sexual or romantic feeling in (someone or something) <vi>Short men <it>attract</it> her.</vi> <vi>Her bright blue eyes <it>attracted</it> me.</vi> <vi>The bird's colorful feathers are used to <it>attract</it> a mate.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) attracted</it> <vi>She <it>is attracted</it> to short men.</vi> <vi>I <it>was attracted</it> by her bright blue eyes.</vi> <vi>I felt very <it>attracted</it> to her.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>opposites attract</tag> at <dxt>opposite</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to cause (a particular reaction) :to get or create (attention, notice, interest, etc.) <vi>The trial is <it>attracting</it> a lot of attention.</vi> <vi>Her comment <it>attracted</it> criticism.</vi> <vi>The bird uses its call to <it>attract</it> the attention of a mate.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>physics</ssl> <dt>:to pull (something) to or toward something else <vi>A magnet <it>attracts</it> iron.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="opposite[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">opposite</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:pəzət</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>opposites</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:someone or something that is completely different from someone or something else <vi>We thought the job might be difficult, but it was quite the <it>opposite</it>. [=it was easy]</vi> <vi>He said that the disease is becoming more common, but really the <it>opposite</it> is true. [=the disease is not becoming more common; it is becoming less common]</vi> <vi>My two sisters are polar/complete/exact <it>opposites</it> (of each other)—one is very friendly while the other is very shy.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a word with a meaning that is completely different from the meaning of another word :<sx>antonym</sx> <vi>“Wet” is the <it>opposite</it> of “dry.”</vi> <vi>The terms “black” and “white” are <it>opposites</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>opposites attract</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that people who are very different from each other are often attracted to each other</un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
