<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attraction"> <hw>at*trac*tion</hw> <sound><wav>attrac06.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtrækʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>at*trac*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something interesting or enjoyable that people want to visit, see, or do <vi>The waterfall continues to be the main <it>attraction</it> at the park.</vi> <vi>The town's big <it>attraction</it> for movie lovers is the annual film festival.</vi> <vi>Buses take visitors to all the city's best <phrase>tourist attractions</phrase>. [=things tourists usually like to see or do]</vi> <snote>A <phrase>coming attraction</phrase> is a movie, show, or other interesting thing that is going to happen or be available soon. <vi>Before the movie began, we saw previews of <it>coming attractions</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a performer who people want to see <vi>She is the star <it>attraction</it> of the show.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a feeling that makes someone romantically or sexually interested in another person <vi>There's a strong sexual <it>attraction</it> between them.</vi> <vi>His <it>attraction</it> to her grew over the course of their time together.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a feature or quality that makes someone or something interesting or enjoyable <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>A good relationship is based on more than just physical <it>attraction</it>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I understand the <it>attraction</it> of skydiving, but I could never do it.</vi> <vi>What are the <it>attractions</it> of owning your own business?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>physics</ssl> <dt>:a force that pulls something to or toward something else <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>magnetic/gravitational <it>attraction</it></vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi><it>attractions</it> among particles</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>repulsion</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="coming[1]"> <hw hindex="1">com*ing</hw> <sound><wav>coming01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌmɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:happening soon or next <vi>The company has many plans for the <it>coming</it> year.</vi> <vi>An official announcement will be made in the <it>coming</it> days.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:becoming more important or popular <vi>new technology that's considered the <it>coming</it> [=<it>up-and-coming</it>] thing/trend in the industry</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>coming attraction</dre> <dx>see <dxt>attraction</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
