<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="available"> <hw highlight="yes">avail*able</hw> <sound><wav>availa02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈveɪləbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more avail*able; most avail*able</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:easy or possible to get or use <vi>The family kept emergency supplies <it>available</it>.</vi> <vi>The dress is also <it>available</it> in larger sizes.</vi> <vi>The articles are <it>available</it> at any drugstore.</vi> <vi>Fresh fruit is <it>available</it> during/through the summer.</vi> <vi>The drug is readily/widely/easily <it>available</it> in Europe.</vi> <vi>The report will soon be made <it>available</it> to the public.</vi> <vi>I missed the plane, and the <phrase>next available</phrase> flight doesn't leave until tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:present or ready for use <vi>All <it>available</it> resources were used.</vi> <vi>She spent every <it>available</it> dollar on her hobby.</vi> <vi>Parking is <it>available</it> for people staying at the hotel.</vi> <vi>Tickets are <it>available</it> from the box office at the theater.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:present and able or willing to talk to someone <vi>She was not <it>available</it> for comment, according to the newspaper.</vi> <vi>The woman who answered the phone said, “I'm sorry, but Mr. Adams is not <it>available</it> right now. May I take a message?”</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:not being used or occupied by someone or something else <vi>Toys covered every <it>available</it> space in the room.</vi> <vi>the last <it>available</it> seat</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:free to do something <vi>We interviewed many <it>available</it> candidates for the job.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>available</it> to give speeches.</vi> <vi>We should go out for lunch. Are you <it>available</it> next Tuesday?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not involved in a romantic relationship. <vi>He wanted to ask her on a date, but wasn't sure if she was <it>available</it>. [=<it>single</it>]</vi> <vi>a great way to meet <it>available</it> men/women/singles</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>avail*abil*i*ty</ure> <sound><wav>availa01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˌveɪləˈbɪləti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>The drug's lack of <it>availability</it> presents a serious problem for them.</vi> <vi>She's the perfect candidate for the job, but I need to confirm her <it>availability</it>. [=I need to make sure she is available]</vi> <vi>The <it>availability</it> of affordable housing attracted us to this town.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
