<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="average[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">av*er*age</hw> <sound><wav>averag01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈævrɪʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>av*er*ag*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a number that is calculated by adding quantities together and then dividing the total by the number of quantities <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The <it>average</it> of 16, 8, and 6 is 10.</vi> <vi>Take all these temperatures and find their <it>average</it>.</vi> <vi>An <it>average</it> of 2,000 people attended the show each night.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Prices have increased <phrase>on average</phrase> about eight percent.</vi> <vi><it>On average</it>, women live longer than men.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He saves <phrase>on the average</phrase> about five percent of his income.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>grade point average</dxt> <tag>the law of averages</tag> at <dxt>law</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a level that is typical of a group, class, or series :a middle point between extremes <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>His work has been better/worse than <it>average</it>. = His work has been <phrase>above/below average</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>His work has been above the <it>average</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:<sx>batting average</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="average[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">average</hw> <altpr>ˈævrɪʤ</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:calculated by adding quantities together and then dividing by the number of quantities <vi>Take all these temperatures and find their <it>average</it> temperature.</vi> <vi>The investment had a higher <it>average</it> return.</vi> <vi>The <it>average</it> age of the company's employees is 36.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:ordinary or usual <vi>The <it>average</it> woman lives longer than the <it>average</it> man.</vi> <vi>Do you know what the <it>average</it> person earns?</vi> <vi>an <it>average</it> day</vi> <vi>the <it>average</it> American family/home buyer</vi> <un>often used informally with <it>your</it> <vi>He's just <it>your average</it> guy. [=he is a typical or ordinary guy]</vi> <vi>It wasn't <it>your average</it> snow storm. [=it was worse than an ordinary snowstorm]</vi> <vi>He's not <it>your average</it> salesman. [=he is unusual]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:not unusually large or small <vi>Sales were about <it>average</it> for the industry on the whole.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not unusually good or bad <vi><it>Average</it> grades are not good enough to get you into graduate school.</vi> <vi>She was an <it>average</it> student.</vi> <vi>She thought the performance was just <it>average</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="average[3]"> <hw hindex="3">average</hw> <altpr>ˈævrɪʤ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>averages</if></in> <in><if>averaged</if></in> <in><if>averag*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have (a specified number) as an average <vi>The children in that class <it>average</it> four feet in height. [=the average height of the children is 4 feet]</vi> <vi>Her daily commute <it>averages</it> 40 minutes. [=the average length of her daily commute is 40 minutes]</vi> <vi>We <it>average</it> six calls a day. [=we get six calls a day on average]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to calculate the average of (something) <vi>The teacher <it>averaged</it> the students' grades.</vi> <vi>What figure do you get when you <it>average</it> the amount of rainfall for the last three months?</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>average out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to produce a result that is even and balanced when looked at over a period of time <vi>The irregularities <it>averaged out</it> over the course of the study.</vi> <vi>Sometimes you win, and sometimes you lose. It all <it>averages out</it> [=<it>evens out</it>] in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>average out to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be equal to (a specified average amount) over a period of time <vi>The gain <it>averaged out to</it> 20 percent.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="batting average"> <hw>batting average</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ averages</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:a number that shows how often a batter gets a base hit <vi>an excellent hitter with a <it>batting average</it> above .300</vi> <vi>a low/high <it>batting average</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a movie director with a high <it>batting average</it> [=a director who has created many successful movies and few unsuccessful movies]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Dow Jones Industrial Average"> <hw>Dow Jones Industrial Average</hw> <pr>ˌdaʊˌʤoʊnz-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the Dow Jones Industrial Average</dre> <def><dt>:the daily average of the stock prices of a group of large American companies</dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="grade point average"> <hw>grade point average</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ages</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a number that indicates a student's average grade <un>abbr. <it>GPA</it></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
