<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="backward[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">back*ward</hw> <sound><wav>backwa01.wav</wav></sound> <hsl>chiefly US</hsl> <pr>ˈbækwɚd</pr> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>back*wards</va> <sound><wav>backwa02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækwɚdz</pr></vr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:toward the back :to or toward what is behind <vi>a sudden movement <it>backward</it>, not forward</vi> <vi>I heard a noise behind me and glanced <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>He pushed the throttle <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>She took a small step <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>Can you skate <it>backward</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:opposite to the usual way :in reverse <vi>Count <it>backward</it> from 10.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:toward the past <vi>a journey <it>backward</it> in time</vi> <vi>The narrative moves <it>backward</it> and forward in time.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to or toward a less advanced state or condition :toward a worse state <vi>His new job, which paid less and had fewer responsibilities, felt like a step <it>backward</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bend over backward</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>lean over backward</va> <vl>also</vl> <va>fall over backward</va></vr> <def><dt>:to make a great effort to help someone or to reach agreement with someone <vi>The salesman said he would <it>bend over backward</it> to make the deal.</vi> <vi>I've <it>leaned over backward</it> to please you—and you haven't even said thank you!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know something backward and forward</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="know[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">know</hw> <sound><wav>know0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnoʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <lb>not used in progressive tenses</lb> <in><if>knows</if></in> <in><if>knew</if> <sound><wav>knew0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnu:, <it>Brit</it> ˈnju:</pr></in> <in><if>known</if> <sound><wav>known002.wav</wav><wav>known001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnoʊn</pr></in> <in><if>know*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to have (information of some kind) in your mind <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>knows</it> a lot about the history of the town.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know</it> the answer?</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know</it> her name.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know</it> what time it is?</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know</it> the words to that song.</vi> <vi>They <it>knew</it> a good deal about the problem.</vi> <vi>She <it>knows</it> the rules of the game.</vi> <vi>He <it>knows</it> everything about horses. = He <phrase>knows all/everything there is to know</phrase> about horses.</vi> <un>often + <it>how, why, where</it>, etc. <vi>Do you <it>know why</it> she left this suitcase here?</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know where</it> she went?</vi> <vi>No one <it>knows</it> (for sure) <it>how</it> long it will take the fix the problem.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>knows perfectly/full well</phrase> <it>how</it> to do it.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you want the answer, ask someone who <it>knows</it>.</vi> <vi>“What is she doing?” “Believe me, <phrase>you don't want to know</phrase>.” [=you would be shocked or upset to learn what she is doing]</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>He <it>knows</it> (all) <it>about</it> horses.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to understand (something) :to have a clear and complete idea of (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I don't <it>know</it> much about art, but I <it>know</it> what I like.</vi> <un>usually + <it>how, why, where</it>, etc. <vi>Scientists don't yet <it>know why</it> this happens.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know what</it> to do.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know what</it> you want me to do.</vi> <vi>We had almost no money in those days. I don't <it>know how</it> we managed.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know how</it> you could be so careless.</vi> <vi>You <phrase>know perfectly/full well</phrase> <it>what</it> I am trying to say.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“How could she do that?” “<phrase>How should/would I know</phrase>?!” [=I don't know, and you should not expect me to know]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have learned (something, as a skill or a language) <vi>She <it>knows</it> karate/CPR.</vi> <vi>He <it>knows</it> Spanish.</vi> <un>often + <it>how</it> <vi>Do you <it>know how</it> to type?</vi> <vi>I would go swimming with you, but I don't <it>know how</it> (to swim). [=I never learned to swim]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be aware of (something) :to realize (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>knows</it> that many people will not believe her.</vi> <vi>I <it>know</it> (that) this isn't easy for you, but you have to keep trying.</vi> <vi>As soon as I turned on the light I <it>knew</it> that something was missing.</vi> <vi>There was no way for me to <it>know</it> that he was your brother. = <phrase>How was I to know</phrase> that he was your brother?</vi> <vi>It's wrong and you <phrase>know it</phrase>! [=you are aware that it is wrong]</vi> <vi>“I'm sorry I threw out those bags.” “It's okay: you <phrase>couldn't have known</phrase> that I needed them.” = “It's okay: you <phrase>had no way of knowing</phrase> that I needed them.” = (<it>Brit</it>) “It's okay: you <phrase>weren't to know</phrase> that I needed them.”</vi> <vi>You <phrase>ought to know by now</phrase> that she is always late.</vi> <vi>It's impossible to <it>know</it> what will happen next. = There's <phrase>no way of knowing</phrase> what will happen next. = There's <phrase>no knowing</phrase> what will happen next.</vi> <vi>If you've never been to Venice, <phrase>you don't know what you're missing</phrase>. [=you would enjoy going to Venice very much]</vi> <vi><phrase>You know as well as I do</phrase> that they expect us at 8:00.</vi> <vi><phrase>You don't know</phrase> how happy I am to see you. [=I am extremely happy to see you]</vi> <vi><phrase>You'll never know</phrase> what this means to me. = <phrase>You can't know</phrase> how much this means to me. [=this means a great deal to me]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><phrase>As far as I know</phrase>, they plan to arrive on Monday. [=I believe that they plan to arrive on Monday, but I am not sure]</vi> <vi>We're planning a party for George. <phrase>As you know</phrase>, he'll be leaving the company next month.</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> or <it>of</it> <vi>I <it>knew about</it> the problem. [=I was aware of the problem]</vi> <vi>Does she <it>know about</it> the meeting?</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know of</it> any job openings right now. [=I am not aware of any job openings right now]</vi> <vi>I <it>know of</it> her as a poet but not as a novelist. [=I am familiar with her poetry but not with her novels]</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know of</it> a good lawyer? [=can you recommend a good lawyer?]</vi> <vi>“Does he have relatives nearby?” “<phrase>Not that I know of</phrase>.” [=I don't think he has any relatives nearby]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be certain of (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Everyone else believes him, but I just <it>know</it> (that) he's lying.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>know</it> if I can trust her. [=I am not sure that I can trust her]</vi> <vi>It's hard to <it>know</it> exactly where the candidate stands on this issue.</vi> <vi>I <it>knew</it> he'd forget.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>know</it> if they are coming.</vi> <vi>“She says she's not coming.” “<phrase>I knew it</phrase>!” [=I was sure that she wouldn't come]</vi> <vi><phrase>I knew it all along</phrase>. [=I was always sure of it]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“They're coming.” “Do you <it>know</it> [=are you certain], or are you just guessing?” = “Do you <phrase>know for sure/certain</phrase>, or are you just guessing?”</vi> <vi>He thinks he got the job but he doesn't <it>know for sure</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have met and talked to (someone) :to be acquainted or familiar with (a person) <vi>“Do you <it>know</it> Clara?” “Yes, we've met.”</vi> <vi>“Do you <it>know</it> Clara?” “We've met but I wouldn't say that I really <it>know</it> her.” [=I am not close to her; I don't know much about her]</vi> <vi>I've <it>known</it> him for years. He's one of my best friends.</vi> <vi><it>Knowing</it> you, you'll be the first one there. [=because I know you so well, I expect you to be the first one there]</vi> <vi>She's the kindest person I <it>know</it>.</vi> <vi><phrase>To know him is to love him</phrase>. [=the people who know him feel great affection for him]</vi> <vi>We just bought a house here last month, and we're still <phrase>getting to know</phrase> our neighbors. [=we're still meeting our neighbors; we're still becoming acquainted with our neighbors]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have experience with (something) :to be acquainted or familiar with (something) <vi>She <it>knows</it> the city very well.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know</it> her painting/writing/work?</vi> <vi>Do you <it>know</it> any good restaurants in this area?</vi> <vi>We're still <phrase>getting to know</phrase> the neighborhood.</vi> <vi>The building <phrase>as we know it</phrase> [=as it exists now] is quite different from how it looked when it was first built.</vi> <vi>This is the end of the organization <it>as we know it</it>. [=the organization has changed and will never again be the same as it was]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to have experienced (something) <vi>someone who <it>knows</it> grief well [=someone who has experienced a lot of grief]</vi> <un>usually used as <it>known</it> <vi>I've <it>known</it> failure and I've <it>known</it> success. [=I have failed and I have succeeded]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to recognize (someone or something) :to identify (someone or something) accurately <vi>“How will I <it>know</it> her?” “She'll be wearing a red sweater.”</vi> <vi>I would <it>know</it> [=<it>recognize</it>] that voice anywhere.</vi> <vi>I <it>know</it> his face [=his face is familiar to me] but I don't remember his name.</vi> <vi>I feel like I <it>know</it> this house, but I've never been here before.</vi> <vi>I <it>know</it> many of the customers at the café by sight. [=I see them often enough that I recognize them]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to recognize the difference between two things :to be able to distinguish (one thing) <it>from</it> another <vi><it>know</it> right <it>from</it> wrong</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be sure that (someone or something) has a particular quality, character, etc., because of your experiences with that person or thing <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I've worked with him for many years, and I <it>know</it> him <it>to be</it> an honest man.</vi> <vi>I <it>know</it> the business <it>to be</it> legitimate.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to think of (someone or something) as having a particular quality, character, etc. <un>+ <it>as</it> <vi>His neighbors <it>knew</it> him <it>as</it> a quiet and friendly person, but the people he worked with saw a different side of him.</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) known as</it> <vi>She <it>is known as</it> an expert in the field. [=people consider her an expert]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the name that people know or use for someone or something</un> <un>+ <it>as</it> <vi>Her neighbors <it>knew</it> her <it>as</it> Jill Brown, but her real name was Amy Smith.</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) known as</it> <vi>Samuel L. Clemens <it>was</it> better/otherwise <it>known as</it> Mark Twain. [=most people called him Mark Twain]</vi> <vi>Beethoven's Third Symphony <it>is</it> widely <it>known as</it> the “Eroica.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has a particular quality, feature, ability, etc., that people know about</un> <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>Fans of the blues <it>know</it> the city <it>for</it> its live blues clubs.</vi></un> <un>usually used as <it>(be) known for</it> <vi>The restaurant <it>is known for</it> its desserts. [=the restaurant's desserts are popular, well-known, etc.]</vi> <vi>She <it>is known for</it> her ability to work quickly. = She <it>is known for</it> working quickly.</vi> <vi>He<it>'s known for</it> being late. [=he is often late]</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><snote>Someone who has been <phrase>known to be</phrase> or <phrase>known to do</phrase> something has been or done that thing in the past. <vi>We've <it>known</it> him <it>to work</it> all night to meet a deadline. = He's been <it>known to work</it> all night to meet a deadline.</vi> <vi>I've never <it>known</it> her <it>to be</it> wrong. [=I do not know of any time when she has been wrong]</vi> <vi>He's been <it>known to do</it> this kind of thing before.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>before you know it</dre> <def><dt>:very quickly or soon <vi>We'll be there <it>before you know it</it>.</vi> <vi>The game was over <it>before I knew it</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>better the devil you know than the devil you don't</dre> <dx>see <dxt>devil</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>don't I know it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you agree with what has just been said <vi>“It's freezing in here!” “<it>Don't I know it</it>.” [=I agree]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you have little or no knowledge of something <vi><it>For all I know</it>, he left last night. [=I don't know when he left; it's possible that he left last night]</vi> <vi>She may have already accepted another job, <it>for all we know</it>. [=we don't know what she has done; it's possible that she has already accepted another job]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>God knows</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>goodness knows</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>heaven knows</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>Lord knows</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to stress that something is not known <vi>How long will the meeting last? <it>Heaven knows</it>.</vi> <vi><it>God</it> (only) <it>knows</it> if the reports are true.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to make a statement more forceful <vi>He finally got a raise. <it>Goodness knows</it> he deserved one. [=he certainly deserved one]</vi> <vi>She didn't win, but <it>Lord knows</it> she tried.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have known better days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>I don't know</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you do not have the information someone is asking for <vi>“What time does the library close?” “<it>I don't know</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to express disagreement, doubt, or uncertainty <vi>“I don't like that guy.” “Oh, <it>I don't know</it>, he's not really so bad.”</vi> <vi>“Which one is your favorite?” “Um, <it>I don't know</it>, maybe the red one.”</vi> <vi>She thinks we should go now, but <it>I don't know</it>. [=I'm not sure] Maybe we should wait.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you are uncertain <it>about</it> someone or something <vi><phrase>I don't know about you</phrase> [=you may think or feel differently than I do about this], but I'm leaving.</vi> <vi>“She said she'd be here by 5:00.” “<phrase>I don't know about that</phrase>.” [=I'm not sure that will happen]</vi> <vi><phrase>I don't know about him</phrase>—he's hard to figure out.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you must know</dre> <def><dt><un>used when you are answering a question that you do not want to answer because the information is personal, embarrassing, etc. <vi>“How much did you pay for your car?” “Well, <it>if you must know</it>, it cost about $20,000.”</vi> <vi>“Why did you leave that job?” “<it>If you must know</it>, I was fired.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I'll have you know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>I know (it)</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to express agreement <vi>“Hurry up, we're going to be late.” “<it>I know</it>, but I can't find my shoe.”</vi> <vi>“This place is such a mess.” “<it>I know it</it>.” [=I agree]</vi> <vi>“I can't believe he lied.” “<it>I know, I know</it>.”</vi> <vi>“The whole situation is just so stupid.” “<it>I know</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a suggestion <vi>“What should we do tonight?” “<it>I know</it> [=I have an idea]—how about a movie?”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I wouldn't know</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that you have not experienced something <vi>“That restaurant has the best desserts!” “<it>I wouldn't know</it>. I've never been there.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know best</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>know what's best</va></vr> <def><dt>:to know or understand better than someone else what should be done <vi>I would take the highway myself, but you live here so you <it>know best</it>.</vi> <vi>I'll do whatever you say. You <it>know what's best</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know better</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be smart or sensible enough not to do something <vi>You walked home alone? Don't you <it>know better</it> (than that)?</vi> <vi>She'll <phrase>know better than to</phrase> trust them again. [=she will not trust them again]</vi> <vi>There's no excuse for his behavior. He's <phrase>old enough to know better</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Don't blame him. He's just a child and he <phrase>doesn't know (any) better</phrase>. [=he is too young, inexperienced, etc., to be expected to behave properly]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to know or understand the truth about something <vi>She tried to tell me that it wasn't her fault, but I <it>know better</it>. [=I know that it really was her fault]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to know or understand more than other people <vi>You can't tell him what to do. He always thinks that he <it>knows better</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know different/otherwise</dre> <def><dt>:to know that something that people think or say is true is not really true <vi>She says she has no money but I <it>know otherwise</it>. [=I know that she does have money]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>know from (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to know anything about or care at all about (someone or something) <un>used in negative statements <vi>kids who don't <it>know from</it> sports</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know no boundaries</dre> <dx>see <dxt>boundary</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know no bounds</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bound</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know (something) backward and forward</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>know (something) backwards</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>know (something) inside out</va> <vl>or US</vl> <va>know (something) inside and out</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>know (something) like the back of your hand</va></vr> <def><dt>:to know something completely <vi>He <it>knew the process backward and forward</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>knows the business inside and out</it>.</vi> <vi>I <it>know this town like the back of my hand</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know (something or someone) for what it/he/she is</dre> <def><dt>:to understand what something or someone truly is <vi>Now I <it>know them for what they are</it>—liars.</vi> <vi>before scientists <it>knew the disease for what it is</it>—a virus</vi> <vi>the friends who <it>know me for what I am</it> [=who truly know and understand me]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know (something) when you see it/one</dre> <def><dt>:to be able to recognize or identify something immediately <vi>She <it>knows a bargain when she sees it</it>.</vi> <vi>I <it>know a liar when I see one</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure what I want but I'll <it>know it when I see it</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know the drill</dre> <dx>see <dxt>drill</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know the score</dre> <dx>see <dxt>score</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know what hit you</dre> <def><dt><un>used in negative statements to say that something you did not expect surprised you very much <vi>I did<it>n't know what hit me</it>—suddenly I just felt so dizzy.</vi> <vi>The company came out with an entirely new line of products last year, and their competitors <it>never knew what hit them</it>. [=their competitors were not prepared and were completely surprised]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know what it is</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>to know what it's like</va></vr> <def><dt>:to have experience with a situation, activity, or condition <vi>He <it>knows what it is to be</it> poor. [=he has been poor]</vi> <vi>They <it>know what it's like to</it> have no privacy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know what you are talking about</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>you know what you are talking about</it>, you deserve to be listened to because you have actual knowledge or experience with something and what you are saying is correct. <vi>Take her advice. She <it>knows what she's talking about</it>.</vi> <vi>“He said the movie is boring.” “Don't listen to him. He <phrase>doesn't know what he's talking about</phrase>.” [=he is wrong]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know which side your bread is buttered on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bread</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know your own heart/mind</dre> <def><dt>:to be sure of what you want, like, think, etc. <vi>She's a woman who <it>knows her own mind</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to understand yourself fully :to understand your own emotions, desires, abilities, etc. <vi>I was so young then. I really didn't <it>know myself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know your stuff</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stuff</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know your way around</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>know your way around</it> a place or thing, you are very familiar with it or are good at using or operating it. <vi>He <it>knows his way around</it> Boston.</vi> <vi>She really <it>knows her way around</it> a sailboat. [=she knows how to sail; she is a very good sailor]</vi> <vi>They <it>know their way around</it> computers.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let (someone) know</dre> <def><dt>:to tell something to someone <vi><it>Let me know</it> [=tell me] if you're going to the party.</vi> <vi>Please <it>let me know</it> if there's anything I can do to help. [=I would like to help; please tell me if you need help]</vi> <vi>He's not sure what time he'll arrive—he is going to <it>let us know</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>let the staff know</it> her decision. [=she told the staff her decision]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let (something) be known</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make (something) known</va></vr> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to tell people something <vi>He <it>let it be known</it> [=he announced] that he intends to run for mayor.</vi> <vi>She <it>made her decision known</it> to the staff. [=she told the staff her decision]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make yourself known</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to introduce yourself :to cause people to know who you are <vi>The candidate <it>made herself known</it> to voters through an aggressive ad campaign.</vi> <vi>the movie in which the actor first <it>made himself known</it> to the world</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>might/should have known</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that you are not surprised to learn of something <vi>I <it>should have known</it> it would be too expensive.</vi> <vi>“She says she's going to be late.” “I <it>might have known</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not know someone from Adam</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to have never met with someone :to not know someone at all <vi>Why should she trust me? She <it>doesn't know me from Adam</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not know the first thing about</dre> <def><dt>:to have little or no knowledge about (something or someone) <vi>I <it>don't know the first thing about</it> cooking/sports/children.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not know the meaning of (the word)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>meaning</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not know your ass from your elbow</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>not know your arse from your elbow</va></vr> <def><sl>informal + impolite</sl> <dt>:to know nothing :to be stupid <vi>Don't take his word for it—he <it>doesn't know his ass from his elbow</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what do you know</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to express surprise <vi>She's an astronaut? Well, <it>what do you know</it>!</vi> <vi>“He's going to law school in the fall.” “Well <phrase>what do you know about that</phrase>?” [=I am surprised that he is going to law school]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone is wrong about something <vi>“She thinks I should take the job.” “<it>What does she know</it>? You should do what you want.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wouldn't you know (it)?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something annoying that has happened is the kind of thing that often happens <vi>I was running late and—<it>wouldn't you know</it>?—I rushed off without my purse.</vi> <vi>“He's late again.” “<it>Wouldn't you know it</it>?!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you know</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used when you are trying to help someone remember something <vi>They live on the other side of town. <it>You know</it>—near the golf course.</vi> <vi>He was in our history class—<it>you know</it> [=<it>you remember</it>]—the tall blond guy in the front row.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis <vi><it>You know</it>, we really have to go.</vi> <vi>It's cold outside, <it>you know</it>.</vi> <vi><it>You know</it>, you really should write a novel.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used when you are not sure of what to say or how to say it <vi>Would you like to, <it>you know</it>, go out sometime?</vi> <vi>We're planning to go shopping and, <it>you know</it>, just hang out.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you know something/what?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize the statement that comes after it <vi><it>You know something</it>? I never trusted her.</vi> <vi>She lied to me again, but <it>you know what</it>? I really just don't care any more.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to get someone's attention <vi>Hey, <it>you know what</it>? I'm hungry.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you know what I mean</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to suggest that the hearer agrees with and understands what has been said or to ask if he or she does or not <vi>I grew up there, <it>you know what I mean</it>, so I know what it's like.</vi> <vi>He's kind of strange. Do <it>you know what I mean</it>?</vi> <vi>He's kind of strange, <phrase>if you know what I mean</phrase>.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in the shortened form <it>know what I mean</it> <vi>He's kind of strange—<it>know what I mean</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you know what they say</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to introduce a common saying or a statement that expresses a common belief <vi>Keep trying, and you'll figure it out. <it>You know what they say</it>: if at first you don't succeed, try, try again.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you never know</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is impossible to be sure about what will happen <vi><it>You never know</it>—you might win the lottery.</vi> <vi><it>You never know</it> who will show up.</vi> <vi><it>You never know</it> with her parties: anyone could show up.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
