<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="background"> <hw>back*ground</hw> <sound><wav>backgr01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækˌgraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>back*grounds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the part of a scene or picture that is farthest from the viewer :the part of a scene that is behind a main figure or object in a painting, photograph, etc. <vi>Objects in the foreground are drawn larger than those in the <it>background</it>.</vi> <vi>a photograph of a house with mountains in the <it>background</it></vi> <vi>The mountains provided a perfect <it>background</it> [=<it>backdrop</it>] for the wedding photos.</vi> <vi><it>background</it> scenery</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a surface or color that is behind or around something (such as a printed design) <vi>red letters printed on a white <it>background</it></vi> <vi>a <it>background</it> color</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a position that attracts little attention <vi>He was a shy man who always tried to keep/stay <phrase>in the background</phrase>. [=tried to avoid attracting attention]</vi> <vi>The war has pushed all other issues <phrase>into the background</phrase>. [=has made all other issues less important]</vi> <vi>An ethnic conflict that was simmering away <it>in the background</it> finally erupted into civil war.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that occurs without requiring attention while something else is also occurring <vi>The software was automatically updated <phrase>in the background</phrase> while we continued to work on the data.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that is heard while something else is being listened to <vi>It was hard to enjoy the music because I could hear a dog barking <phrase>in the background</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the events and conditions that help to explain why something happens :the situation in which something occurs <un>usually singular <vi>We learned about the social and economic <it>background</it> of the American Civil War.</vi> <vi>The meetings took place <phrase>against a background</phrase> of increasing tension.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:information needed to understand a problem or situation <vi>Let me provide you with some <it>background</it> on this problem.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>background</it> information</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the experiences, knowledge, education, etc., in a person's past <vi>What is your academic <it>background</it>?</vi> <vi>We need to know more about his <it>background</it> before we hire him.</vi> <vi>He and his wife come from similar social <it>backgrounds</it>. [=they were raised in similar social environments]</vi> <vi>His writing is influenced by his ethnic <it>background</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>They ran a <it>background</it> check to make sure the job candidate had no criminal record.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="background music"> <hw>background music</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:music that is played in a movie, television show, etc., to go along with and add to the story or mood</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="background noise"> <hw>background noise</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:undesired sound that is heard in a radio broadcast, a tape recording, etc. <vi>The recording had a lot of <it>background noise</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
