<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="back[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">back</hw> <sound><wav>back0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>backs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the rear part of the body :the part of the body that is opposite to the stomach and chest and that goes from the neck to the top of the legs <vi>She was carrying her little daughter on her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He injured his <it>back</it>. = He suffered a <it>back</it> injury.</vi> <vi>She has a pain in the small of her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>an aching <it>back</it></vi> <vi>I slapped/patted him on his/the <it>back</it> to congratulate him.</vi> <vi>He broke his <it>back</it> [=<it>spine</it>] in a fall.</vi> <vi>She stabbed/shot him in the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He was handcuffed with his hands behind his <it>back</it>.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an animal that is like a person's back <vi>a bird with a spotted <it>back</it></vi> <vi>riding on the <it>back</it> of a horse/donkey/camel</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>horseback</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something that is opposite the front or face :the rear side or surface of something <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>back</it> of the head</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of a mirror/spoon</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of the hand/leg/foot</vi> <vi>The book has fallen down the <it>back</it> of the couch.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something (such as a piece of paper) that is not usually used or seen first <un>usually singular <vi>She wrote something on the <it>back</it> of an envelope.</vi> <vi>He signed his name on the <it>back</it> of the check.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a place, position, or area that is at or near the rear of something <un>usually singular <vi>He put the letter in the <it>back</it> of the drawer.</vi> <vi>The kitchen is at/in the <it>back</it> of the house and the living room is at/in the front.</vi> <vi>Since our plane was leaving soon we were moved to the front of the line while others remained at the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>Please move to the <it>back</it> of the elevator to make room for others.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of a chair or seat that supports a person's back <vi>a comfortable chair with a padded <it>back</it></vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the section of a book, magazine, etc., that includes the last pages <un>usually singular <vi>There is an index in the <it>back</it> of the book.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a book's cover that can be seen when the book is on a shelf <vi>The title of the book is shown on its <it>back</it>. [=<it>spine</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a player in some games (such as soccer and American football) who is positioned behind the front line of players <vi>a defensive <it>back</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fullback</dxt> <dxt>halfback</dxt> <dxt>quarterback</dxt> <dxt>running back</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a pat on the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a stab in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at/in the back of your mind</dre> <def><dt>:in the part of your mind where thoughts and memories are kept <un>used to describe ideas, memories, etc., that someone has but that are not usually thought about or not perfectly remembered <vi>The thought of retiring and moving out into the country has been <it>in the back of her mind</it> for many years, and now she's finally doing it.</vi> <vi>Somewhere <it>in the back of my mind</it> I knew I'd met him before.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back is to/against the wall</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your back is to/against the wall</it> or <it>you have your back to/against the wall</it> you are in a bad position in which you are forced to do something in order to avoid failure. <vi><it>With our backs to the wall</it> we made a last desperate effort to finish the project on time.</vi> <vi>We knew that with so little time and money left to finish the project <it>we had our backs to the wall</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to back</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with backs opposite or against each other <vi>The soldiers stood <it>back to back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:happening one after the other <vi>She won the annual competition two times <it>back to back</it>. [=<it>in a row</it>]</vi> <vi>He's had two victories <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <vi>I've scheduled two appointments <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back-to-back</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to front</dre> <def><sl>of a piece of clothing</sl> <dt>:with the back where the front should be <vi>He accidentally put the sweater on <it>back to front</it>. [=<it>front to back, backwards</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>behind someone's back</dre> <def><dt>:without someone's knowledge :in secret <vi>You shouldn't gossip about people <it>behind their back(s)</it>.</vi> <vi>If you have something to say, why not say it to my face instead of whispering it <it>behind my back</it>?!</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went behind his back</phrase> and spoke directly to his supervisor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break the back of</dre> <def><dt>:to get control of (something you are trying to stop or defeat) :to greatly weaken or subdue (something) <vi>He says the government's new policies will <it>break the back of</it> inflation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your back up</dre> <def><dt>:to become angry or annoyed and want to fight or argue <vi>He <it>gets his back up</it> and becomes defensive whenever someone questions his work.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>put someone's back up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>watch someone's back <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in back</dre> <def><dt>:in an area at the back of something <vi>There was only room for one passenger in front. The rest of us sat <it>in back</it>. [=<it>in the back</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in back of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:directly behind (something or someone) <vi>There's a small yard <it>in back of</it> the house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the back of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:because of (something) <vi>Profits have increased <it>on the back of</it> [=<it>on the strength of</it>] improved international sales.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>disapproving</ssl> <dt>:by using the efforts of (other people) <vi>The company has achieved record profits <it>on the back of</it> cheap labor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/off your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who is always or frequently criticizing you or telling you what to do is <it>on your back</it> and won't <phrase>get off your back</phrase>. <vi>He says his wife is always <it>on his back</it> about doing chores around the house.</vi> <vi><it>Get off my back</it>! I'm working as hard as I can!</vi> <vi>My boss is always criticizing me. I wish I knew some way to <it>get him off my back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>(flat) on your back</it> you are lying with your back against the ground, on a bed, etc. <vi>The accident left him (lying) <it>flat on his back</it> (in bed) for two weeks.</vi> This phrase is sometimes used figuratively. <vi>The stock market has been <it>flat on its back</it> [=has been doing very poorly] in recent weeks.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out back</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>out the back</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>round the back</va></vr> <def><dt>:in the area behind something (such as a building) <vi>In my youth we didn't have a toilet in the house but there was one <it>out back</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put someone's back up</dre> <def><dt>:to offend or annoy someone :to make someone angry or ready to argue <vi>I don't want to question his decision because that will just <it>put his back up</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>get your back up <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your back into</dre> <def><dt>:to work very hard at (something) :to put a lot of effort into (something) <vi>If you want to get that floor clean you'll have to <it>put your back into</it> it.</vi> <vi>You'll really have to <it>put your back into</it> this project if you want it to succeed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>scratch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the back of</dre> <def><dt><snote>In British English, to be <phrase>glad/happy (etc.) to see the back of</phrase> someone is to be glad to see someone finally going away. <vi>He's done nothing but make trouble and I'll be <it>glad to see the back of</it> him! [=I'll be glad when he has gone]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stab (someone) in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the shirt off your back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shirt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn your back</dre> <def><dt>:to turn so that you are facing away from someone <vi>He <it>turned his back</it> and walked away from me.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>turned his back on</it> me and walked away.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His former supporters have <it>turned their backs on</it> him. [=have abandoned him]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch someone's back</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>have someone's back</va></vr> <def><dt>:to protect someone who is doing something that is dangerous or risky <vi>The police officer's partner always <it>watches his back</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't worry, <phrase>I've got your back</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If people tell you to <it>watch your back</it>, they are telling you to be careful. <vi>I hear the boss is in a bad mood this morning, so you'd better <it>watch your back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>back*less</ure> <sound><wav>back0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>backless</it> evening gown</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="back[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">back</hw> <altpr>ˈbæk</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in, toward, or at the back or rear <vi>The soldiers moved <it>back</it> from the front lines.</vi> <vi>The police asked the crowd to move/step <it>back</it> from the scene of the accident.</vi> <vi>He left his friends two miles <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>She turned around and looked <it>back</it> toward him.</vi> <vi>a chapter beginning several pages <it>back</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to, toward, or in the place where someone or something was previously <vi>He left his home and never went <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>I had to go <it>back</it> (to the office) for some papers I had left behind.</vi> <vi>It's time to go <it>back</it> home.</vi> <vi>She took the book off the shelf and forgot to put it <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>She left earlier but she should <phrase>be back</phrase> [=<it>return</it>] soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or into the past :backward in time <vi>In the opening chapter the author looks <it>back</it> on his youth.</vi> <vi>an event <it>back</it> in the last century</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:<sx>ago</sx> <vi>It happened several years <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>I met him in the city two days <it>back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to or toward a former state or condition <vi>He has decided to go <it>back</it> to private life. [=to return to private life]</vi> <vi>Good farming practices were needed to bring the fields <it>back</it> (to good condition). [=to restore the fields]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in return or reply <vi>I gave the book to him and he gave it <it>back</it> (to me).</vi> <vi>He refused to give <it>back</it> the borrowed money.</vi> <vi>He hit his brother and his brother hit him right <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>talk <it>back</it></vi> <vi>She refused to take <it>back</it> her accusations.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe someone or something that is being held or kept from moving forward or happening <vi>He would have jumped if his friends had not held him <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He vowed that he wouldn't allow poverty to hold/keep him <it>back</it>. [=to keep him from succeeding]</vi> <vi>She struggled to hold <it>back</it> a laugh. [=to keep from laughing]</vi> <vi>Landslides set the construction job <it>back</it> many days. [=caused the construction job to be delayed many days]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that is being kept instead of being given or revealed <vi>They held <it>back</it> part of the money.</vi> <vi>keep <it>back</it> the truth</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to or at an angle <vi>The banks slant evenly <it>back</it> from the highway.</vi> <vi>The doctor told her to <phrase>lie back</phrase> on the couch. [=to lie down on the couch]</vi> <vi>When I get home from work I like to just <phrase>sit/lean back</phrase> on the couch and relax.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>back of</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:on the rear side of (something) :<sx>behind</sx> <vi>There's an old tractor out <it>back of</it> [=<it>in back of</it>] the barn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your own back</dre> <dx>see <tag>get back</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="back[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">back</hw> <altpr>ˈbæk</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:of or relating to the back :located at the back <vi>the front door, not the <it>back</it> door [=the door at the back of a building]</vi> <vi>He keeps his wallet in his <it>back</it> pocket.</vi> <vi>She likes to sit in the front/first row, not the <it>back</it> [=<it>last</it>] row.</vi> <vi>We came in through the <it>back</it> entrance.</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> pages [=the last pages] of the newspaper</vi> <vi><it>back</it> teeth</vi> <vi>a <it>back</it> room</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:far from a central or main area <vi>We drove on the <it>back</it> roads instead of the main roads.</vi> <vi>a <it>back</it> alley</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not yet paid :owed from an earlier time <vi>The company owes him several months in <it>back</it> pay.</vi> <vi><it>back</it> rent</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:published at an earlier time :no longer current <vi>a <it>back</it> issue/number of a magazine</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>golf</ssl> <dt><un>used to refer to the final 9 holes of an 18-hole golf course <vi>He was two over par on the front nine and three over par on the <it>back</it> nine.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back[4]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="4">back</hw> <altpr>ˈbæk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>backs</if></in> <in><if>backed</if></in> <in><if>back*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give help to (someone) :<sx>support</sx> <vi>I'm <it>backing</it> him (against the Establishment) in his struggle for reform.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>backing</it> him for President.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bet on (someone or something) <vi>She <it>backed</it> the winner of the race and won a lot of money.</vi> <vi>The pundits are all <it>backing</it> him to become the next President. [=the pundits all think that he will become the next President]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to provide evidence that supports (something) <vi>She <it>backed</it> her argument with written evidence.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to provide the money that is needed for (something) <vi><it>back</it> a new company</vi> <vi><it>back</it> a Broadway play</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to sing or play music that supports (a main singer or musical instrument) <vi>She <it>backed</it> the singer on the guitar.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>A guitarist <it>backed up</it> the singer.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>back up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to move backward <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>backed</it> into a parking space.</vi> <vi>She <it>backed</it> out of the garage.</vi> <vi>The dog kept growling but <it>backed</it> off/away cautiously.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Could you <it>back</it> [=(more commonly) <it>back up</it>] your car a little to give me some room?</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The reporter <phrase>backed her into a corner</phrase> [=put her into a difficult position that was hard to get out of] with his probing questions.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to provide (something) with a back <vi><it>back</it> a skirt with stiff material</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the back toward something <vi>The house fronts onto Main Street and <it>backs</it> onto/on the golf course. [=the back of the house faces the golf course]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>back away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to move away from something or someone by walking backward <vi>The robber pointed a gun at the policeman and told him to <it>back away</it> slowly.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The policeman slowly <it>backed away from</it> the robber.</vi> <vi>She <it>backed away from</it> the growling dog.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The government seems to be <it>backing away from</it> its earlier proposal.</vi> <vi>She has <it>backed away from</it> her controversial position on the death penalty.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to stop arguing or fighting for something <vi>When threatened with a revolt of its own supporters, the government <it>backed down</it>.</vi> <vi>The strike is expected to continue because neither side is willing to <it>back down</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The government <it>backed down from</it> its position.</vi> <vi>He'll never <it>back down from</it> a fight.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>back into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become involved in (something) without planning to become involved <vi>He <it>backed into</it> the antiques business almost by accident when he sold some old furniture he'd inherited.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop arguing or fighting for something :to back down <vi>He has refused to <it>back off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to decide not to do something that you had agreed to do :to back out <vi>The deal fell through when investors <it>backed off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop bothering someone <vi>She was getting irritated, so I <it>backed off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to decide not to do something that you had agreed to do <vi>The deal fell through when investors <it>backed out</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The investors <it>backed out of</it> the deal.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move backward <vi>The car <it>backed up</it> slowly.</vi> <vi>Could you <it>back up</it> a little to give me some room?</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Wait, let's <it>back up</it> for a second. [=let's go back to what we were discussing earlier]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>back (a vehicle) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>back up (a vehicle)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move (a vehicle) backward <vi>Could you <it>back</it> your car <it>up</it> a little to give me some room?</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become blocked so that movement or flow is slowed or stopped <vi>Traffic <it>backed up</it> for miles because of the accident.</vi> <vi>The drain <it>backed up</it> [=<it>clogged</it>] and had to be unclogged by a plumber.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>back (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>back up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to become blocked <vi>The accident <it>backed up</it> traffic for miles. = Traffic was <it>backed up</it> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>tailed back</it>] for miles because of the accident.</vi> <vi>The drain was <it>backed up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>back (someone or something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>back up (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give help or support to (someone or something) <vi>I'll <it>back</it> you <it>up</it> if I think you're right.</vi> <vi>She <it>backed</it> her argument <it>up</it> with written evidence. = Written evidence <it>backed</it> her argument <it>up</it>.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>back up</it> your words with deeds!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back <dxn>1e (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>back (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>back up (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:to make a copy of (a computer file or data) to protect it from being lost <vi>Remember to <it>back up</it> your work before you log off.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>backup</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="back and forth"> <hw>back and forth</hw> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:toward the back and then toward the front :backward and forward <vi>The chair rocked <it>back and forth</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:between two places or people <vi>The children were shuttled <it>back and forth</it> between school and home.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back-and-forth"> <hw>back–and–forth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:talk or discussion about something <vi>An agreement was finally reached after a lot of <it>back-and-forth</it> between the two sides.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back burner"> <hw>back burner</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>on the back burner</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:in the position of something that will not receive immediate attention and action <vi>She put her singing career <it>on the back burner</it> to pursue her dream of being a movie star.</vi> <vi>The President has put tax reduction <it>on the back burner</it> because he has more urgent problems to deal with.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>front burner</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="back door"> <hw>back door</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ doors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a door at the back of a building <un>often used figuratively <vi>He managed to get into the private club <phrase>through the back door</phrase> [=in a secret or indirect way] because he has a friend who works there.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back matter"> <hw>back matter</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the pages at the end of a book following the main part <vi>A list of geographical names appears in the <it>back matter</it> of the dictionary.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>front matter</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back of beyond"> <hw>back of beyond</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the back of beyond</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a place that is very far from other places and people :a remote place <vi>He lives by himself in a cabin out in <it>the back of beyond</it>. [=<it>the boondocks</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
