<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bat[1]"> <art><artref id="bat.eps"/><capt/><dim>80,116</dim></art> <hw hindex="1">bat</hw> <sound><wav>bat00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a long rounded stick that is used to hit the ball in baseball <vi>a baseball <it>bat</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a long flattened stick that is used to hit the ball in cricket</dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>paddle <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <vi>a table tennis <it>bat</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at bat</dre> <def><sl>baseball</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the player or team that is batting <vi>He got a home run on his first time <it>at bat</it>.</vi> <vi>It's the bottom of the first inning and the home team is <it>at bat</it>. [=is batting]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of batting <vi>She has two hits in three <it>at bats</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to bat</dre> <def><sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:to be the player or team that is batting <vi>The visiting team <it>goes to bat</it> first. [=the visiting team bats first]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to bat for</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to try to help, support, or defend (someone or something) in an active way <vi>Many of his friends <it>went to bat for him</it> while he was under investigation for fraud.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the bat</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:without any delay :<sx>immediately</sx> <un>usually used with <it>right</it> <vi>I could tell it was fake <phrase>right off the bat</phrase>. [=<it>right away</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off your own bat</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:through your own efforts <vi>He didn't need my help—he made good <it>off his own bat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bat</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bat[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bat</hw> <altpr>ˈbæt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bats</if></in> <in><if>bat*ted</if></in> <in><if>bat*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (something, such as a ball) with a bat, club, etc., or with your hand <vi>The ball was <it>batted</it> down.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>batted ball</phrase> [=a ball that has been hit by a batter in baseball]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to try to hit a ball with a bat in baseball, cricket, or a similar game <vi>It's your turn to <it>bat</it>.</vi> <vi>She was <it>batting</it> when it began to rain.</vi> <vi>Who's <it>batting</it>? = Who's <phrase>up to bat</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to have a specified batting average <vi>This year he's <it>batting</it> [=<it>hitting</it>] .300. [=his batting average is .300]</vi> <vi>She has five hits in five at bats, so she's <phrase>batting a thousand</phrase>. [=her batting average is 1.000]</vi> <snote>In figurative use, to <it>bat a thousand</it> is to succeed in every attempt. This is an informal phrase that is used chiefly in U.S. English. <vi>So far in her career, she's <it>batting a thousand</it>. [=she has succeeded in everything she has done in her career]</vi> <vi>No one <it>bats a thousand</it> in this business.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>bat around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bat (something) around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bat around (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to think about or talk about (something, such as an idea) for a period of time <vi>The plan was <it>batted around</it> for a while, but it was finally rejected.</vi> <vi>We've been <it>batting</it> the idea <it>around</it> for a few years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bat in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bat in (a run)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>bat (a run) in</pva></phrasev> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to hit the ball in a way that makes it possible for a run to score <vi>He <it>batted in</it> 70 runs last year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bat</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>batting</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi><it>batting</it> practice</vi> <vi>a <it>batting</it> coach</vi> <vi><it>batting</it> gloves/helmets</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bat[3]"> <art><artref id="bat.tif"/><capt>bat</capt><dim>83.3,94.3</dim></art> <hw hindex="3">bat</hw> <altpr>ˈbæt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an animal that has wings and a furry body like a mouse</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an unpleasant old woman <vi>Don't take any notice of that <phrase>old bat</phrase>!</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bats in the/your belfry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>belfry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(as) blind as a bat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like a bat out of hell</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very quickly <vi>He ran out of the house <it>like a bat out of hell</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bat</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bat[4]"> <hw hindex="4">bat</hw> <altpr>ˈbæt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bats</if></in> <in><if>batted</if></in> <in><if>batting</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to close and open (your eyes or eyelashes) very quickly several times especially as a way of flirting <vi>She smiled and <it>batted</it> her eyelashes at him.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>not bat an eye/eyelash</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>not bat an eyelid</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to show no surprise, fear, concern, etc. <vi>He thought the news would make her upset, but she <phrase>never batted an eye</phrase>. [=she did not appear to be upset at all]</vi> <vi>He listened <phrase>without batting an eyelash</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bat</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bat mitzvah"> <hw>bat mitz*vah</hw> <sound><wav>batmi01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɑtˈmɪtsvə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -vahs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a ceremony and celebration for a Jewish girl usually on her 13th birthday when she takes on the religious duties and responsibilities of an adult</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a girl for whom a bat mitzvah is held <ca>called also <cat>bas mitzvah</cat></ca> <dx>compare <dxt>bar mitzvah</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="fruit bat"> <hw>fruit bat</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a large bat that eats fruit and lives in hot parts of the world</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="vampire bat"> <hw>vampire bat</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a bat from Central and South America that sucks the blood of people and animals</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bas mitzvah"> <hw>bas mitz*vah</hw> <sound><wav>basmi01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɑsˈmɪtsvə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -vahs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>bat mitzvah</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blind[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">blind</hw> <sound><wav>blind001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblaɪnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>blind*er</if></in> <in><if>blind*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:unable to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> person</vi> <vi>He was born <it>blind</it>.</vi> <vi>She is <it>blind</it> in one eye. [=she can see with one of her eyes but not with the other]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went blind</phrase> [=she became unable to see] at age 67.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>color-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:unable to notice or judge something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He is <it>blind to</it> his son's faults.</vi> <vi>Each party was <it>blind to</it> the other's concerns.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>usually disapproving</ssl> <dt>:accepting the actions or decisions of someone or something without any questions or criticism <vi><it>blind</it> loyalty/allegiance/obedience</vi> <vi>I'm not sure <it>blind</it> faith [=unquestioning belief] in our leaders is wise.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe strong emotions that make someone unable to think clearly or to act reasonably <vi>a <it>blind</it> fury/rage</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:done in a way that prevents participants, judges, etc., from seeing or knowing certain things that might influence them <vi>a <it>blind</it> taste test [=a test in which people taste something without knowing what it is, who made it, etc.]</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> clinical trial for the new medicine</vi> <vi><it>blind</it> auditions</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind date</dxt> <dxt>double-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:difficult for a driver to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> driveway/drive</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> curve</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind spot</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) blind as a bat</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to see well at all :having very poor vision <vi>Without glasses I'm <it>blind as a bat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>love is blind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not a blind bit</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not even a very small amount :not the slightest bit <vi>I told them what I wanted, but they <it>didn't</it> take <it>a blind bit</it> of notice. [=they didn't notice at all; they did not listen to me]</vi> <vi>It does <it>not</it> make <it>a blind bit</it> of difference what you do. [=it does not matter at all what you do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the blind</dre> <def><dt>:blind people :people who are not able to see <vi>The agency provides assistance to <it>the blind</it>.</vi> <snote>The expression <phrase>the blind leading the blind</phrase> is used informally to describe a situation in which someone who is not sure about how to do something is helping another person who also is not sure about how to do it. <vi>I'll try to help, but it's <it>the blind leading the blind</it> because I've never done this before either.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <def><dt>:to ignore a problem instead of dealing with it <vi>Corruption in the police force is rampant, but authorities are <it>turning a blind eye</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Colleges can't afford to <it>turn a blind eye to</it> alcohol abuse.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>blind*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>a leading cause of <it>blindness</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="eye[1]"> <art><artref id="eye.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,72.5</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">eye</hw> <sound><wav>eye00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈaɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>eyes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you see with <vi>Her <it>eyes</it> slowly became accustomed to the dark.</vi> <vi>He wears a patch over one <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>I have something in my <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has (a pair of) bright blue <it>eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>bright/sad/sleepy <it>eyes</it></vi> <vi>She has good/strong/bad/weak <it>eyes</it>. [=<it>eyesight</it>]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes lit up</phrase> [=she looked excited and happy] when he showed her the ring.</vi> <vi>His <phrase>eyes were popping out of his head</phrase> with astonishment [=he looked very astonished] when he saw how big it was!</vi> <vi>He punched him <phrase>right between the eyes</phrase>. [=punched him hard in the face]</vi> <vi>She looked me (right) <phrase>in the eye</phrase> [=she looked directly at me] and told me I was fired.</vi> <vi>The garden is <phrase>a feast for the eyes</phrase>. [=the garden is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The display was very pleasing <phrase>to the eye</phrase>. [=pleasing to look at]</vi> <vi>I measured the distance <phrase>by eye</phrase>. = I measured the distance <phrase>with my eye</phrase>. [=by looking at it to get a rough idea of its size]</vi> <vi>Their daughter came home from school <phrase>with tears in her eyes</phrase>. [=she was crying]</vi> <vi>Seeing her again <phrase>brought tears to my eyes</phrase>. = Seeing her again <phrase>brought a tear to my eye</phrase>. [=made me shed tears]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>had/kept half an eye on</phrase> [=he occasionally looked at] the TV while he read the paper.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something seen <vi>Only a trained <it>eye</it> can tell the difference between the original painting and a good copy.</vi> <vi>For decorating, they rely on her discerning/discriminating/expert <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has an artist's <it>eye</it> for color.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>have an eye for</phrase> something or <phrase>a good/keen/sharp eye for</phrase> something, you have a special ability to recognize a particular thing or quality. <vi>He <it>has a keen eye for</it> detail.</vi> <vi>He <it>has a good eye</it> for quality.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something looks to you <vi>It looks a little awkward to my <it>eye</it>. [=it looks awkward to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a way of looking at or judging something <vi>He reviewed the proposal with a jaundiced/critical <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>The biographer <phrase>cast a cold/critical/skeptical eye</phrase> on the artist's life.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe where someone is looking <vi>Her <it>eye</it> was attracted to the bright colors in the painting.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>dropped her eyes</phrase> [=she looked down] when he looked at her. = Her <phrase>eyes fell</phrase> when he looked at her.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>averted his eyes</phrase> [=he looked away] when she approached him.</vi> <vi>I saw something moving <phrase>out of the corner of my eye</phrase>. [=to the side of where I was looking]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes fell on</phrase> [=she noticed] a piece of evidence no one had noticed before.</vi> <vi><phrase>All eyes were on her</phrase> [=everyone was looking at her] as she entered the room.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>fixed her eyes on</phrase> me [=she kept looking or staring at me] for a long time before answering.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of looking at or thinking about something <vi>We need to look at this problem with a fresh <it>eye</it>. [=to look at the problem in a new way]</vi> <vi><phrase>Beauty is in the eye of the beholder</phrase>. [=different people have different ideas about what is beautiful]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He was guilty in the <it>eyes</it> of the police. [=the police considered him guilty]</vi> <vi>He was handsome in her <it>eyes</it>. [=she thought he was handsome]</vi> <vi>In the <it>eyes</it> [=<it>opinion</it>] of many, he is the best person for the job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hole through the top of a needle <vi>the <it>eye</it> of a needle</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a loop that a hook fits into to fasten or attach something</dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area on a potato from which a new plant can grow :a bud on a potato</dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the center of a storm (such as a hurricane) where there is little wind or rain and sometimes there is clear sky <vi>The <it>eye</it> of the storm should reach the coast by morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all eyes</dre> <def><dt>:watching something or someone closely :very attentive <vi>She was <it>all eyes</it> as I opened the box.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an eye for an eye</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that a person who has committed a crime should be given punishment that is the same as or as serious as the crime <vi>The ancient code of law called for punishment in the form of <it>an eye for an eye</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as far as the eye could see</dre> <def><dt>:as far as could be seen <vi>The crowd stretched away <it>as far as the eye could see</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a sight for sore eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a twinkle in your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twinkle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bawl your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bawl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>before your eyes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>in front of your eyes</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If something happens (<it>right</it>) <it>before your eyes</it> or <it>in front of your (very) eyes</it>, it happens in a very open and visible way so that you can see it very clearly. <vi>Technology is changing <it>right before our eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>We were watching a disaster take place <it>in front of our very eyes</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast/run your eye over</dre> <def><dt>:to read it or look at (something) quickly. <vi>Please <it>run your eye over</it> this and let me know what you think.</vi> <vi>She <it>cast her eye over</it> the apartment, appalled by the mess.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close/shut your eyes to</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to notice or accept the truth or existence of (something) :to ignore (something) <vi>Our legislators have <it>closed their eyes to</it> the poverty that surrounds them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cry your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy on the eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people are surprised that you have seen or noticed something that is behind you, they may say that you have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>. <vi>How did you know we were here? You must have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feast your eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>feast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for your eyes only</dre> <def><dt>:intended to be seen only by you <vi>This memo is <it>for your eyes only</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Several men were <it>giving her the eye</it> across the bar.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep an/your eye out for</dre> <def><dt>:to be looking for (someone or something) :to hope to see or find (someone or something) <vi>I'm <it>keeping my eye out for</it> a good cheap used car.</vi> <vi>He'll be here soon, so <it>keep your eye out for</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:to have (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>She <it>has an eye to</it> attending graduate school. [=she hopes to attend graduate school]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(have) stars in your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>star</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have your eye on</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to watch (someone or something) closely <vi>I'll <it>have my eye on</it> the kids while they're swimming.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be thinking about buying (something) <vi>I <it>have my eye on</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>She's <it>had her eye on</it> that house for a long time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a pig's eye</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt><un>used to express strong disagreement <vi>You want me to apologize to him? <it>In a pig's eye</it>! [=<it>Never!</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the blink of an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blink</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the public eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a position that receives a lot of public notice and attention <vi>The job requires someone who is comfortable being <it>in the public eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a very short time :very quickly <vi>He was back <it>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your mind's eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you see something <it>in your mind's eye</it>, you imagine or remember how it looks. <vi>I can still see the old playground <it>in my mind's eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep an/your eye on</dre> <def><dt>:to watch or take care of (someone or something) <vi>Will you <it>keep an eye on</it> my suitcase (for me) while I get something to eat?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eye on the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes glued to</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to watch (something) very closely for a long time <vi>They <it>kept their eyes glued to</it> the television, waiting for more news about the accident.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes open</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>keep your eyes peeled</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>keep your eyes skinned</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look or watch closely in order to see or find (something) <vi>We <it>kept our eyes peeled</it> for a sign that would tell us where to turn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/set eyes on</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>clap eyes on</va></vr> <def><dt>:to see or look at (someone or something) <vi>I hope never to <it>lay eyes on</it> him again!</vi> <vi>We liked the house from the moment we <it>set eyes on</it> it. [=the moment when we first saw it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Some guy was <it>making eyes at</it> her from across the room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than meets the eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>more than meets the eye</it> or there is <phrase>more to something than meets the eye</phrase>, there is more to it than there appears to be at first. <vi>There is <it>more to this proposal than meets the eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>my eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise or mild disagreement <vi>A diamond, <it>my eye</it>! That's glass!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not bat an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>only have eyes for</dre> <def><dt>:to only be attracted to (a particular person) :to only feel love for (someone) <vi>He <it>only has eyes for</it> you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open someone's eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to notice or be aware of something important <vi>The experience really <it>opened his eyes</it> and changed the way he felt about his life.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>It's time they <it>opened their eyes to</it> the truth.</vi> <vi>His film helped <it>open people's eyes to</it> the problem.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to notice or be aware of something important <vi>You need to <it>open your eyes</it> and face the truth.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We have to <it>open our eyes to</it> these problems and stop ignoring them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull the wool over someone's eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wool</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roving eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roving</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>run your eye down</dre> <def><dt>:to quickly read or look at (something, such as a list) <vi>She <it>ran her eye down</it> the list looking for her name.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see eye to eye</dre> <def><dt>:to have the same opinion :<sx>agree</sx> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>They don't <it>see eye to eye</it> (with each other) on this issue.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your eyes off</dre> <def><dt>:to stop looking at (someone or something) <vi>I <it>took my eyes off</it> the road for one second.</vi> <vi>She was so beautiful, he <phrase>couldn't take his eyes off</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the apple of someone's eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>apple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>under the eye of</dre> <def><dt>:while being watched by (someone) <vi>Students work <phrase>under the watchful/vigilant eye of</phrase> their teacher.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in or affected by something <vi>We're <it>up to our eyes</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi> <vi>They're <it>up to their eyes</it> in debt.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:with (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>They hired him <it>with an eye toward</it> increased sales.</vi> <vi>They bought the house <it>with an eye toward</it> its restoration.</vi> <vi>He took the job <phrase>with an eye to the future</phrase>. [=he took the job because he felt it would help him in the future]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your/both eyes open</dre> <def><dt>:fully aware of what could happen <vi>I went into the job <it>with my eyes (wide) open</it>.</vi> <vi>If you do this, you need to do it <it>with both eyes open</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes shut/closed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:with little or no effort :very easily <vi>She could run that company <it>with her eyes shut</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</it>, you have taken more food than you can possibly eat. <vi>I can't finish my meal—I guess <it>my eyes were bigger than my stomach</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>black eye</dxt> <dxt>evil eye</dxt> <dxt>private eye</dxt> <dxt>rib eye</dxt> <dxt>seeing eye</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
