<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="be"> <hw highlight="yes">be</hw> <sound><wav>be000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><il>present first singular</il> <if>am</if> <sound><wav>be000006.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæm, əm</pr></in> <in><il>second singular</il> <if>are</if> <sound><wav>be000007.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚ, ɚ</pr></in> <in><il>third singular</il> <if>is</if> <sound><wav>be000008.wav</wav><wav>i0000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɪz, əz</pr></in> <in><il>plural</il> <if>are</if> <sound><wav>be000007.wav</wav></sound></in> <in><il>past tense for first and third singular</il> <if>was</if> <sound><wav>be000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwəz</pr></in> <in><il>second singular</il> <if>were</if> <sound><wav>were0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɚ</pr></in> <in><il>plural</il> <if>were</if> <sound><wav>were0003.wav</wav></sound></in> <in><il>past participle</il> <if>been</if> <sound><wav>be000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪn, <it>Brit</it> ˈbi:n</pr></in> <in><il>present participle</il> <if>be*ing</if> <sound><wav>be000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:jɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the identity of a person or thing <vi>Today <it>is</it> Wednesday.</vi> <vi>John <it>is</it> my brother.</vi> <vi>The first person I met <it>was</it> Susan. = Susan <it>was</it> the first person I met.</vi> <vi>Who <it>are</it> you?</vi> <vi>“There's someone at the door.” “Who <it>is</it> it?” “It'<it>s</it> David.”</vi> <vi>Your responsibility <it>is</it> to keep this area clean. = Keeping this area clean <it>is</it> your responsibility.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the qualities of a person or thing <vi>My hands <it>are</it> cold.</vi> <vi>He <it>is</it> 35 years old and six feet tall.</vi> <vi>I'<it>m</it> hungry.</vi> <vi>The leaves <it>are</it> green, and so <it>is</it> the grass.</vi> <vi>The noise <it>was</it> very loud.</vi> <vi>The way he behaves <it>is</it> foolish.</vi> <vi>How foolish he <it>is</it>!</vi> <vi>“(<it>Are</it>) You hungry?” “Yes, I <it>am</it>.”</vi> <vi>The book <it>is</it> about English grammar.</vi> <vi>These people <it>are</it> with me.</vi> <vi>The letter <it>is</it> for you.</vi> <vi>They asked the students not to <it>be</it> late. = They asked that the students not <it>be</it> late.</vi> <vi>Treat people with respect, whether they <it>are</it> rich or poor. = (formal) Treat people with respect, whether they <it>be</it> rich or poor. = (formal) Treat people with respect, <it>be</it> they rich or poor.</vi> <vi>Our neighbors are <it>being</it> unusually friendly lately.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>be</it> such a fool! [=don't act in such a foolish way]</vi> <vi><phrase>To be</phrase> perfectly/quite honest/frank (with you), I didn't like the movie. [=I am speaking honestly/frankly when I say that I didn't like the movie]</vi> <vi>The book <it>is</it> mine.</vi> <vi>I'd do it <phrase>if I were you</phrase>. [=I think you should do it]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the condition of a person or thing <vi>“Hi. How <it>are</it> you?” “Fine, thanks. How <it>are</it> you?”</vi> <vi>How <it>is</it> your father? = How <it>is</it> your father's health?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to indicate the group, class, category, etc., that a person or thing belongs to <vi>I'<it>m</it> a doctor and my sister <it>is</it> a lawyer.</vi> <vi>That fish <it>is</it> a trout.</vi> <vi>The trout <it>is</it> a (kind of) fish.</vi> <vi>Apes <it>are</it> mammals.</vi> <vi>She'<it>s</it> a hard worker. [=she works hard]</vi> <vi>What a fool he <it>is</it>! [=he is a fool]</vi> <vi><it>Being</it> an artist herself [=because she is an artist herself], she tends to look at other people's paintings very critically.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to indicate the place, situation, or position of a person or thing <vi>The book <it>is</it> on the table.</vi> <vi>“Where'<it>s</it> John?” “He'<it>s</it> in the living room.”</vi> <vi>The house <it>is</it> past the bridge.</vi> <vi>It was great <it>being</it> here. = It was great <it>to be</it> here.</vi> <vi>I must <it>be</it> on my way. [=I must go]</vi> <vi>Here'<it>s</it> the book. = Here it <it>is</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases with <it>there</it> to describe a situation, occurrence, etc. <vi><it>There is</it> a book on the table. [=a book is on the table]</vi> <vi><it>There are</it> concerts several times a week. [=concerts are held several times a week]</vi> <vi><it>There</it> will <it>be</it> concerts next week.</vi> <vi>“<it>There's</it> someone at the door.” “Who is it?” “It's John.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases with <it>it</it> to indicate a time or place or to describe a current, past, or future condition <vi><it>It's</it> 12 o'clock. [=the time is 12 o'clock]</vi> <vi><it>It's</it> noon/early/late.</vi> <vi><it>It's</it> Wednesday today. [=today is Wednesday]</vi> <vi><it>It was</it> noon when we arrived. [=we arrived at noon]</vi> <vi><it>It was</it> here that I lost my way. [=I lost my way here]</vi> <vi><it>It's</it> raining.</vi> <vi><it>It's</it> hot out!</vi> <vi><it>It's</it> odd that he didn't see us. [=the fact that he didn't see us was odd]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to say how much something costs <vi>“I like this painting. How much <it>is</it> it?” [=how much does it cost?] “<it>It's</it> 600 dollars.” [=it costs 600 dollars]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to say that one amount or number is the same as another <vi>Three plus two <it>is</it> [=<it>equals</it>] five.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to happen or take place <vi>The concert <it>was</it> last night.</vi> <vi>The concert <it>is</it> [=<it>will be</it>] tomorrow night. [=the concert will take place tomorrow night]</vi> <vi>“When <it>was</it> the Battle of Waterloo?” “(It <it>was</it>) In 1815.”</vi> <vi>“When <it>is</it> Christmas?” “<it>It's</it> on a Wednesday this year.”</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to come or go <un>used in perfect tenses <vi>She has already <it>been</it> [=<it>come</it>] and gone.</vi> <vi>Have you ever <it>been</it> [=<it>gone</it>] to Rome?</vi> <vi>I haven't <it>been</it> there for several years.</vi> <vi>I've been waiting for you for half an hour. <phrase>Where have you been</phrase>? [=where were you?; why weren't you here?]</vi></un> <snote>People who have <phrase>been there, done that</phrase> are bored about the idea of going somewhere or doing something because they have already done it before. This is an informal phrase that is often used in a joking way. <vi>I suggested to my cousin that she go to Florida for her vacation, but she said, “<it>Been there, done that</it>.”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to exist or live <vi>I think, therefore I <it>am</it>. [=<it>exist</it>]</vi> <vi>Once upon a time there <it>was</it> [=<it>lived</it>] a knight.</vi> <vi>There once <it>was</it> a man who dwelt alone in a small village.</vi> <vi>all the things that <it>are</it> [=<it>exist</it>]</vi> <vi>“To <it>be</it>, or not to <it>be</it>: that is the question.” <aq>Shakespeare, <it>Hamlet</it> (1600)</aq></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used with the past participle of a verb to form passive constructions <vi>The money <it>was found</it> by a child.</vi> <vi>They <it>were</it> [=<it>got</it>] <it>married</it> by a priest.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>be fooled</it> by what he says.</vi> <vi>Please <it>be seated</it>. [=please sit down]</vi> <vi>The election <it>was expected</it> to produce a very close result.</vi> <vi>God <it>be praised</it>! [=let God be praised]</vi> <vi>I <it>was surprised</it> by her rudeness.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used with the present participle of a verb to express continuous action <vi>They <it>are studying</it>.</vi> <vi>I have <it>been sleeping</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>was reading</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Are</it> you <it>getting</it> hungry?</vi> <vi>Our neighbors <it>are being</it> unusually friendly.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used with the present participle of a verb to express future or later action <vi>I'<it>m seeing</it> him tomorrow. [=I will see him tomorrow]</vi> <vi>We <it>are leaving</it> soon. [=we will leave soon]</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>to + verb</it> to say what will happen or was going to happen in the future <vi>The best <it>is</it> yet/still <it>to come</it>. [=the best has not yet happened]</vi> <vi>No one realized that she <it>was</it> one day <it>to become</it> famous. [=that she would become famous one day]</vi> <vi>She <it>was</it> not/never <it>to see</it> him again. [=she would never see him again]</vi> <vi>There <it>are to be</it> two concerts next week. [=there will be two concerts next week]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>to + verb</it> to say what should happen or be done <vi>People like that <it>are to be</it> pitied, not hated. [=people like that should be pitied]</vi> <vi>You <it>are</it> not (allowed) <it>to smoke</it> in here!</vi> <vi>What <it>am</it> I <it>to do</it>? [=what should I do?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in negative statements with <it>to + verb</it> to say what is or was possible <vi>The truth of their argument <it>was not to be</it> denied. [=could not be denied]</vi> <vi>You're not to blame: you <it>weren't to know</it> he'd be offended. [=you could not have known that he would be offended]</vi> <vi>The book <phrase>was nowhere to be found</phrase>. [=could not be found]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>to + verb</it> to say that one thing must happen or be true so that another thing can happen or be true <vi>He must study if he <it>is to pass</it> his exams. [=he must study in order to pass his exams]</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>have</it> with the past participle of some verbs to form perfect tenses <vi>He isn't here: he <it>is</it> [=<it>has</it>] gone.</vi></un> <un>now often considered archaic <vi>Christ <it>is</it> risen. [=Christ has risen]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>be yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to behave in a normal or natural way <vi>You<it>'re</it> not <it>yourself</it> today. What's the matter?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>be myself</it> again once I've had something to eat.</vi> <vi>“How can I impress her?” “Just <it>be yourself</it>!”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave (someone or something) be</dre> <dx>see <dxt>leave</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>let (someone or something) be</dre> <dx>see <dxt>let</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the best is yet to be</dre> <dx>see <dxt>best</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the powers that be</dre> <dx>see <dxt>power</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to be sure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sure</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="am"> <hw>am</hw> <dx>see <dxt>be</dxt></dx></entry>

	<entry id="are"> <hw>are</hw> <dx>see <dxt>be</dxt></dx></entry>

	<entry id="been"> <hw>been</hw> <cx><cl>past participle of</cl> <ct>be</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="borrow"> <hw highlight="yes">bor*row</hw> <sound><wav>borrow01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑroʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bor*rows</if></in> <in><if>bor*rowed</if></in> <in><if>bor*row*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take and use (something that belongs to someone else) for a period of time before returning it <vi>Can I <it>borrow</it> your camera? [=will you lend me your camera]</vi> <vi>The twins often <it>borrow</it> each other's clothes.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>borrowing</it> a friend's car for the weekend.</vi> <vi>He <it>borrowed</it> the book from the library.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take and use up (something) with the promise to give back something of equal value <vi>Will you see if we can <it>borrow</it> a cup of sugar from the neighbors?</vi> <vi>She <it>borrowed</it> $20 from me.</vi> <snote>When people borrow money from a bank they pay back the same amount over a number of months or years plus an added amount that is called <it>interest</it>. <vi>He <it>borrowed</it> money from the bank to buy the car.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (an idea, saying, etc.) that was thought up by someone else <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The speech was peppered with phrases <it>borrowed</it> from Winston Churchill.</vi> <vi>She <it>borrowed</it> the technique from local artisans.</vi> <vi>The company is <phrase>borrowing a page from</phrase> [=using a technique or idea first used by] its largest competitor.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>borrows</it> heavily [=includes many ideas] from other philosophers in the book.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use (a word or phrase from another language) in a language <vi>The English word “entrepreneur” was <it>borrowed</it> from (the) French.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>in subtracting from a number with two or more digits</ssl> <dt>:to take 1 from a digit and add it as 10 to the digit in the next lower place</dt></def> <dro><dre>beg, borrow, or/and steal</dre> <dx>see <dxt>beg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be living on borrowed time</dre> <def><dt>:to continue to be alive after you were expected to die <vi>After his heart attack, my grandfather always felt that he was <it>living on borrowed time</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bor*row*er</ure> <sound><wav>borrow02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑrəwɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bor*row*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>Each <it>borrower's</it> payments will vary according to the terms of the loan.</vi> <vi>the library's <it>borrowers</it> [=people who borrow books from the library]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bottom[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tom</hw> <sound><wav>bottom01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:təm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*toms</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the lowest part, point, or level of something <un>usually singular <vi>He's waiting at the <it>bottom</it> of the stairs.</vi> <vi>Our house is at the <it>bottom</it> of the hill.</vi> <vi>The top of the wall is painted and the <it>bottom</it> is covered in wood paneling.</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the page/screen/list</vi> <vi>Please fill out this form and sign your name at the <it>bottom</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of something that is below or under the other parts <un>usually singular <vi>the ship's <it>bottom</it> [=<it>underside</it>]</vi> <vi>The bowl was signed on the <it>bottom</it> [=<it>base</it>] by the artist.</vi> <vi>There's a small cut on the <it>bottom</it> [=<it>sole</it>] of his foot.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the lowest point or surface inside something :the part of something hollow that is furthest from the top <un>usually singular <vi>I think there is still a little sugar left in the <it>bottom</it> of the box/container.</vi> <vi>The pool is so deep I could not touch the <it>bottom</it>.</vi> <vi>One of the drawers has a <phrase>false bottom</phrase>. [=a panel that looks like the drawer's bottom but that can be removed to expose more space]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:the part of something that is furthest away <vi>We sailed to the <it>bottom</it> of the bay.</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the garden</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body on which you sit :<sx>buttocks</sx> <vi>The poor baby has a rash all over his little <it>bottom</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a position of little power in a company or organization <vi>The company's new CEO started at the <it>bottom</it> and worked her way up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a low rank or position <vi>Why do I always find myself rooting for the team at the <it>bottom</it> of the league?</vi> <vi>She graduated <phrase>at the bottom of her/the class</phrase>. [=her grades were among the lowest in her graduating class]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the worst position, level, or condition <vi>at the <it>bottom</it> of the pay scale</vi> <vi>After weeks of losing value, the company's stocks have <phrase>hit bottom</phrase>. [=reached the bottom; lost all value]</vi> <vi>Jim has finally <phrase>scraped bottom</phrase>. [=has finally reached the worst possible condition]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rock bottom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the surface that is under a body of water <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the ocean</vi> <vi>the sandy river/lake <it>bottom</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>bottoms</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the flat, low land along a river or stream :<sx>bottomland</sx> <vi>grazing in grassy river <it>bottoms</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of clothing that is worn on the lower part of the body <vi>a bikini <it>bottom</it></vi> <un>often plural <vi>pajama <it>bottoms</it></vi></un> <dx>see color picture on page C13</dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the second half of an inning in baseball <vi>They tied the score in the <it>bottom</it> of the ninth inning.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:the lowest gear of a car <vi>Stay in <it>bottom</it> [=<it>bottom gear</it>] until you reach the top of the hill.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at bottom</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:in reality :<sx>really</sx> <vi>The song is, <it>at bottom</it> [=<it>in truth</it>], a lullaby.</vi> <vi>He is very shy, <it>at bottom</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the bottom of the pile</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pile</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be/lie at the bottom of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to be the source or originator of (something) <vi>I think I know who's <it>at the bottom of</it> [=<it>behind</it>] these pranks.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bottoms up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a toast or to tell people to finish their drinks <vi>Here's to the groom-to-be! <it>Bottoms up</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from the bottom of your heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from top to bottom</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get to the bottom of</dre> <def><dt>:to find out the true reason for or cause of (something) <vi>Police are working furiously to <it>get to the bottom of</it> this recent string of violent crimes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the bottom drop/fall out</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>the bottom drops/falls out</it> of something, it suddenly fails or becomes unable to continue in a normal and effective way. <vi>Analysts warn that recent changes in the region may result in <it>the bottom dropping out</it> of the oil market. [=may cause the oil market to collapse]</vi> <vi>When the accident happened, she felt <it>the bottom drop out</it> of her world. [=she felt her world collapse]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the bottom of the barrel</dre> <def><dt>:the lowest possible condition, level, etc. <vi>After the divorce, Tim felt he had reached/hit <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>.</vi> <vi>The excessive coverage of the scandal signals that the news media may have finally hit/reached <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>.</vi> <vi>Salaries in the industry are scraping/hitting <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>. [=salaries in the industry are very low]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tomed</ure> <sound><wav>bottom02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:təmd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>flat <it>bottomed</it> boats</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="burst[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">burst</hw> <sound><wav>burst001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚst</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bursts</if></in> <in><if>burst</if> <il>also</il> <if>burst*ed</if></in> <in><if>burst*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break open or into pieces in a sudden and violent way <vi>The balloon <it>burst</it>. [=<it>popped</it>]</vi> <vi>We could hear bombs <it>bursting</it> [=<it>exploding</it>] in the distance.</vi> <vi>Two of the water pipes <it>burst</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to break open or into pieces <vi>Be careful not to <it>burst</it> [=<it>pop</it>] the balloon.</vi> <vi>He <it>burst</it> a blood vessel.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to open suddenly <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The doors suddenly <phrase>burst open</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The cops <it>burst</it> the door <it>open</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to come or go very quickly and suddenly <vi>He <it>burst</it> into the room.</vi> <vi>The sun <it>burst</it> through the clouds.</vi> <vi>She <it>burst</it> through the door and yelled “Surprise!”</vi> <vi>They just <phrase>burst in on</phrase> us [=they suddenly entered the room we were in] without even knocking on the door.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>burst onto/on/upon the scene</phrase> is to suddenly become very well known. <vi>They <it>burst onto the</it> music <it>scene</it> in 1995 with a very successful debut album.</vi> <vi>when the technology first <it>burst on the scene</it></vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>of a river, stream, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to flow over the surrounding land because of a flood <vi>The stream <phrase>burst its banks</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be bursting</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be filled <it>with</it> something <vi>The crate <it>was bursting with</it> fruit.</vi> <vi>The dish <it>is bursting with</it> flavors.</vi> <vi>The kids <it>are</it> just <it>bursting with</it> energy/excitement.</vi> <vi>Her parents <it>were</it> practically <it>bursting with</it> pride.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to want very much <it>to do</it> (something you are not yet able to do) <vi>I'm <it>bursting to tell you</it> the news, but I have to talk to Ken first.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to need to urinate very badly</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be bursting at the seams</dre> <def><dt>:to be very full or crowded <vi>The nightclub <it>was bursting at the seams</it>.</vi> <vi>The garden <it>is bursting at the seams</it> with colorful flowers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burst into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>burst into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to produce or do (something) suddenly <vi>She <it>burst into</it> [=<it>broke into</it>] laughter/tears.</vi> <vi>The house <it>burst into</it> flame(s).</vi> <vi>The entire cast <it>burst into</it> [=<it>broke into</it>] song.</vi> <vi>The audience <it>burst into</it> applause.</vi> <vi>The flowers were <it>bursting into</it> bloom.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burst out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>burst out (doing something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin (doing something) suddenly <vi>They both <it>burst out</it> [=<it>busted out</it>] laughing.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>burst out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say (something) suddenly <vi>Everyone <it>burst out</it> “Surprise!” as he walked through the door.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burst someone's bubble</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bubble</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fit to burst</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fit</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="card[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">card</hw> <sound><wav>card0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑɚd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cards</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small piece of stiff paper that is marked with symbols or pictures to show its value, comes in a set, and is used for playing games (such as poker) <vi>Each player is dealt five <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi>Shuffle the <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi><it>card</it> tricks</vi> <vi>He bought a deck/pack of <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi>poker and other <phrase>card games</phrase> [=games that use a deck of cards]</vi> <ca>called also <cat>playing card</cat></ca> <dx>see also <dxt>cardsharp</dxt> <dxt>card table</dxt> <dxt>face card</dxt> <dxt>house of cards</dxt> <dxt>picture card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>cards</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:a game played with a deck of cards :a card game <vi>Do you want to play (a game of) <it>cards</it>?</vi> <vi>We played <it>cards</it> until midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used figuratively to refer to something that gives you an advantage when you are trying to make a deal or reach an agreement <vi>The fact that he was supported by big firms was his strongest/best <it>card</it> during the negotiations.</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt><un>used figuratively to refer to an emotional issue (such as race) that is mentioned in a particular situation in order to give you an advantage <vi>She used/played the gender <it>card</it> and said we didn't hire her because she's a woman.</vi> <vi>She was accused of <phrase>playing the race card</phrase> to defend her client. [=she was accused of saying that her client was treated unfairly because of his race]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a thick piece of paper that is usually folded in half and decorated on one side and that contains a greeting, an invitation, etc. <vi>He sent me a <it>card</it> for my birthday. = He sent me a birthday <it>card</it>.</vi> <vi>a get well <it>card</it></vi> <vi>a <it>card</it> shop/store</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>christmas card</dxt> <dxt>greeting card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>postcard</sx> <vi>She sent us a <it>card</it> from Japan.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a rectangular piece of plastic that is used to buy goods or services or to get money from a bank or a machine <vi>“Will you be paying cash?” “No, please put it on my <it>card</it>.” [=I will pay for it using my credit/debit card]</vi> <vi>an ATM <it>card</it></vi> <vi>Insert your <it>card</it> into the machine. = Swipe/Pass your <it>card</it> through the machine.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a rectangular piece of paper or plastic with information about a person written on it <vi>a membership/library/appointment <it>card</it></vi> <vi>Let me give you my <it>card</it>. [=<it>business card</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a small piece of paper that is used for writing down information <vi>He wrote his notes on 3 x 5 <it>cards</it>. [=cards that are 3 inches tall and 5 inches wide]</vi> <vi>You may use <phrase>note cards</phrase> [=cards with notes on them] during your speech.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>trading card</sx> <vi>a collection of baseball/football/basketball <it>cards</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thin, hard board that has small electronic devices on it and that can be added to the inside of a computer to make the computer perform different tasks <vi>a memory/sound/video <it>card</it></vi> <vi>an <phrase>expansion card</phrase> [=a device that allows a computer to do more things than it originally could]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a list of the individual competitions that will happen at a sports event :a sports program <vi>a racing <it>card</it> [=a list of races]</vi> <vi>a boxing <it>card</it> [=a list of boxing matches]</vi> <vi>Three fights are <phrase>on the card</phrase> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a funny or amusing person <vi>He's such a <it>card</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>cardboard</sx> <vi>a piece of <it>card</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get your card</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>be given your card</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be told that you no longer have a job <vi>Thousands of factory workers have <it>been given their cards</it> [=have been laid off; have lost their jobs] in recent months.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold (all/all of) the cards</dre> <def><dt>:to be in control of a situation and have the power to make decisions <vi>It's your decision. You're <it>holding all the cards</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the cards</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>on the cards</va></vr> <def><dt>:certain or likely to happen in the future <vi>No one knows what's <it>in the cards</it> for the economy next year. [=what will happen to the economy next year]</vi> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>It's not <it>in the cards</it> for him to win the election. [=he's not going to win the election]</vi> <vi>Success just wasn't <it>in the cards</it> for her. [=she wasn't meant/supposed to succeed]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/put (all/all of) your cards on the table</dre> <def><dt>:to be honest with other people and to tell them your thoughts, plans, etc., in a very open way <vi>Before we can talk further, you need to <it>put all your cards on the table</it>. [=you need to tell me what you are really thinking]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>overplay your cards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>overplay</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>play/hold/keep your cards close to the/your chest/vest</dre> <def><dt>:to keep your plans, ideas, etc., hidden from other people <vi>No one knows if he's going to run for reelection. He's still <it>playing his cards close to his chest</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play your cards right</dre> <def><dt>:to do things in an intelligent and well-planned way <vi>If I <it>play my cards right</it>, I'll be able to graduate next year.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="carry[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">car*ry</hw> <sound><wav>carry001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeri</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>car*ries</if></in> <in><if>car*ried</if></in> <in><if>car*ry*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (something) while holding and supporting it <vi>She helped me <it>carry</it> [=<it>transport</it>] the boxes out to my car.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>carry</it> your luggage to your room.</vi> <vi>He was <it>carrying</it> his baby daughter in his arms.</vi> <vi>For two months, I <it>carried</it> the book around with me everywhere I went.</vi> <vi>The waitress <it>carried</it> away our empty dinner plates.</vi> <vi>The wind <it>carried</it> the smoke away from the campsite.</vi> <vi>These planes can <it>carry</it> up to 300 passengers.</vi> <vi>a ship <it>carrying</it> thousands of gallons of oil</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Your talent will <it>carry</it> you far. [=it will make you very successful]</vi> <vi>She intended the play to <it>carry</it> audiences toward a sense of peace and understanding.</vi> <vi>She still <it>carries</it> the memories of an unhappy childhood.</vi> <vi>The song <phrase>carries me back to</phrase> [=it makes me remember] my first year of college.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to contain and direct the flow of (water, electricity, etc.) <vi>Oil is <it>carried</it> to the factory through these pipes.</vi> <vi>We installed gutters that will <it>carry</it> water away from the house.</vi> <vi>blood vessels that <it>carry</it> blood to the heart</vi> <vi>These cables <it>carry</it> electricity to hundreds of homes.</vi> <vi>The bridge <it>carries</it> traffic in two directions.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) with you or on your body <vi>Do police officers <it>carry</it> guns when they're off duty?</vi> <vi>This bus driver doesn't <it>carry</it> change, so please have the exact fare ready.</vi> <vi>I always <it>carry</it> $20 in case of an emergency.</vi> <vi>tourists <it>carrying</it> cameras</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be able to give (a disease or a gene) to others even though you may not be affected by it <vi>One percent of the population now <it>carries</it> the virus, and one in three will suffer symptoms of the disease.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be pregnant with (a baby) <vi>She's <it>carrying</it> her second child.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hold (your body or your head) in a particular way <vi>He's over 80 years old and still <it>carries</it> himself erect/upright like a soldier.</vi> <vi>Be proud of yourself. Walk tall and <it>carry</it> your head high!</vi> <vi>She always <it>carries</it> [=(more formally) <it>comports</it>] herself with dignity and grace.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) in a store and ready to be sold :to keep (something) in stock <vi>Our grocery store <it>carries</it> a good selection of wines.</vi> <vi>We no longer <it>carry</it> that brand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have (someone or something) on a list or record <vi>The company <it>carries</it> nearly 200 employees on its payroll.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) as a quality or characteristic <vi>All of our products <it>carry</it> a lifetime guarantee.</vi> <vi>Your promises would <phrase>carry more weight</phrase> [=they would be more meaningful] if you didn't break them so often.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be marked or labeled with (something) <vi>Cigarettes are required to <it>carry</it> a government health warning.</vi> <vi>men who <it>carry</it> the physical scars of war</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a result or consequence <vi>Such crimes <it>carry</it> [=<it>entail</it>, <it>involve</it>] a heavy penalty.</vi> <vi>The surgery does <it>carry</it> certain risks.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>You must understand that the job <it>carries with</it> it <it>g</it>reat responsibility.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a duty or responsibility <vi>I'm <it>carrying</it> a full course load this semester.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>carries the weight of the world on his shoulders</phrase>. [=he feels much pressure because he has great responsibilities]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be responsible for the success of (something or someone) <vi>He's a player that's capable of <it>carrying</it> a team on his own.</vi> <vi>Her spectacular performance as Carmen <it>carried</it> the opera.</vi></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) continue <vi>They <it>carried</it> [=<it>took, extended</it>] the game into the 10th inning.</vi> <vi>The newspaper <it>carried</it> the story over to the following page.</vi> <vi>The design calls for the columns to be <it>carried</it> all the way up to the top of the building.</vi> <vi><it>carrying</it> the war to another continent</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to travel a long distance <vi>His deep voice <it>carries</it> well.</vi> <vi>Baseballs don't <it>carry</it> well in cold weather.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue (something) beyond a normal or acceptable limit <vi>He realized that he had <it>carried</it> the joke too far and hurt her feelings.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>carry (something) to extremes</tag> at <dxt>extreme</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to sing (a tune) correctly <vi>I've never been able to <it>carry</it> a tune.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to present (a story, sports event, TV show, etc.) to the public <vi>Channel 9 will <it>carry</it> the game.</vi> <vi>Every local newspaper <it>carried</it> [=<it>ran</it>] the photograph.</vi> <vi>The trial was <it>carried</it> live [=broadcast as it was happening] on television.</vi></dt> <sn>16 a</sn> <dt>:to cause (a bill or an official proposal) to be passed or adopted <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often used as <it>(be) carried</it> <vi>The bill <it>was carried</it> in the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He called for a motion to stop debate, but the motion did not <it>carry</it>.</vi> <vi>The motion <it>carried</it> unanimously. [=everyone voted to pass it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to win a majority of votes in (a state, legislature, etc.) <vi>The bill <it>carried</it> the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi> <vi>In the presidential election of 1936, Franklin D. Roosevelt <it>carried</it> [=<it>won, took</it>] all the states except Maine and Vermont.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (a number) from one column to another when you are adding numbers together <vi>When you added these two numbers, you forgot to <it>carry</it> the 1.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be/get carried away</dre> <def><dt>:to be so excited that you are no longer in control of your behavior <vi>I shouldn't have behaved like that. I just <it>got carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>Just relax! There's no need to <it>get carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>They allowed themselves to <it>be carried away</it> by fear.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry all/everything before you</dre> <def><sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to be completely successful <vi>This young boxer has the talent to <it>carry all before him</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry a torch for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry coals to Newcastle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coal</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry into effect</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry (something) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do (something difficult) successfully :to achieve or accomplish (something) <vi>He tried to look cool but couldn't <it>carry it off</it>. [=<it>pull it off</it>]</vi> <vi>She's the only actress I know with enough talent to <it>carry this off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>We <it>carried off</it> the prize.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to do what you have been doing <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you—please <it>carry on</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>carried on</it> as if nothing had happened.</vi> :to continue despite problems <vi>I know it's difficult, but you need to <it>carry on</it> as best you can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to behave or speak in an excited or foolish way <vi>They laughed and <it>carried on</it> like they were old friends.</vi> <vi>We were embarrassed by the way he was <it>carrying on</it>.</vi> <vi>She's always <it>carrying on</it> [=talking in an excited way] about her neighbors.</vi> <vi>screaming, crying, and <it>carrying on</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryings-on</dxt> <dxt>carry-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage or participate in (an activity) <vi>She <it>carried on</it> an affair with her boss.</vi> <vi>It's too noisy in here to <it>carry on</it> a conversation.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>carrying on</it> [=<it>conducting</it>] an investigation into his murder.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> a campaign against illegal drug use</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>The money allows us to <it>carry on</it> our research.</vi> <vi>Although the teacher spoke to them, they just <it>carried on</it> [=<it>went on</it>, <it>kept on</it>] talking.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a tradition) to continue <vi>We were the only ones left to <it>carry on</it> the tradition.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> the family name</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing or participating in (an activity) <vi>Please <it>carry on with</it> what you were doing.</vi> <vi>They <it>carried on with</it> their conversation.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have an often immoral sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>I found out that he had been <it>carrying on with</it> [=(more commonly) <it>fooling around with</it>] my sister.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do and complete (something) <vi>We <it>carried out</it> several experiments to test the theory.</vi> <vi>An investigation <it>carried out</it> several years ago revealed no new information.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to act on (a promise, plan, etc.) :to do something that you said you would do or that someone has asked you to do <vi>She failed to <it>carry out</it> [=<it>fulfill</it>] her promise.</vi> <vi>The town has plans to build a new school, but it currently lacks the money to <it>carry</it> them <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>You'll be paid when you've <it>carried out</it> [=<it>executed</it>] your instructions/orders/duties.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or be seen in another place or situation <vi>His unhappiness at home <it>carried over</it> into/to his work.</vi> <vi>Her abilities in singing didn't <it>carry over</it> to acting.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or allow (something) to continue in another place or situation <vi>People can <it>carry</it> bad eating habits learned in childhood <it>over</it> to/into adulthood.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the can</dre> <dx>see <dxt>can</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>day</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the torch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or happen <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>The yellow and blue theme in the kitchen <it>carries through to</it> the rest of the house.</vi> <vi>Our conversation <it>carried through to</it> dessert.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to do something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Though extremely tired, she managed to <it>carry through to</it> the finish.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry through with/on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to do (something that you said you would do) <vi>The mayor <it>carried through</it> [=<it>followed through</it>] <it>on</it> her promise to clean up the city.</vi> <vi>We're beginning to <it>carry through with</it> [=<it>carry out</it>] our plans.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to successfully finish or complete (something that you have begun or said you will do) <vi>Whatever project you begin, you must <it>carry it through</it> to completion.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> (until spring).</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue during (a period of time) <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> the winter.</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it> a difficult time in his life.</vi> <vi>I borrowed a few more books to <it>carry me through</it> the summer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fetch and carry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fetch</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="concentrated"> <hw>concentrated</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:nsənˌtreɪtəd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more concentrated; most concentrated</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:made stronger or more pure by removing water <vi><it>concentrated</it> orange juice</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:existing or happening together in one place :not spread out <vi>a highly <it>concentrated</it> beam of light</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:done in a way that involves a lot of effort and attention <vi>a <it>concentrated</it> [=<it>concerted</it>] effort</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be concentrated</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <it>is concentrated</it> in a specified place is mainly found in that place. <vi>The population <it>is concentrated</it> near the coast. [=most of the population is near the coast]</vi> <vi>Wealth <it>is concentrated</it> in the cities. [=most of the wealthy people live in the cities]</vi> <vi>Power <it>was concentrated</it> in the hands of a few rich men. [=a few rich men had most of the power]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
