<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="become"> <hw highlight="yes">be*come</hw> <sound><wav>become01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈkʌm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>be*comes</if></in> <in><if>be*came</if> <sound><wav>become02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>-ˈkeɪm</pr> <altpr>bɪˈkeɪm</altpr></in> <in><if>be*come</if></in> <in><if>be*com*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to begin to be or come to be something specified <vi>Although I've known him for years, we didn't <it>become</it> close friends until recently.</vi> <vi>She won the election, <it>becoming</it> the first woman to be President of the nation.</vi> <vi>They both <it>became</it> teachers.</vi> :to begin to have a specified quality <vi>The book has <it>become</it> quite popular.</vi> <vi>We <it>became</it> interested in the property last year.</vi> <vi>The crackers had <it>become</it> stale.</vi> <vi>It's <it>becoming</it> [=<it>getting</it>] quite cold in the evenings.</vi> <vi>It eventually <it>became</it> clear that he had lied.</vi> <vi>She's <it>become</it> [=<it>gotten</it>] somewhat cynical.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to look attractive on (someone) :to be flattering to (someone) <vi>That dress <it>becomes</it> you.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be suitable for (someone) :to be proper for (someone) <vi>Though poor, he carried himself with a dignity <it>becoming</it> [=<it>befitting</it>] a king.</vi> <vi>This kind of behavior hardly <it>becomes</it> a person of your age and position.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>become of</dre> <def><dt>:to happen to <vi>Whatever <it>became of</it> our old friend? I haven't heard from her in years.</vi> <vi>I don't know what <it>became of</it> my keys. I can't find them anywhere.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="man[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">man</hw> <sound><wav>man00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmæn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>men</if> <sound><wav>man00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmɛn</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an adult male human being <vi>He was a shy boy, but he grew to be a strong and confident <it>man</it>.</vi> <vi>He's a grown <it>man</it> now.</vi> <vi>The movie is popular with <it>men</it> and women.</vi> <vi>He's a <it>man</it> of great talent. = He's a very talented <it>man</it>.</vi> <vi>a good/bad <it>man</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a man or boy who shows the qualities (such as strength and courage) that men are traditionally supposed to have <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Don't cry, little boy: <phrase>be a man</phrase>!</vi> <vi>A few years in the army will <phrase>make a (real) man (out) of</phrase> you!</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Are you <it>man</it> enough to meet the challenge?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a woman's husband or boyfriend <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Who's the new <it>man</it> in her life? = Who's her new <it>man</it>?</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I now pronounce you <it>man</it> [=<it>husband</it>] and wife.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>old man</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an individual human being :<sx>person</sx> <vi>Time waits for no <it>man</it>. [=for no one]</vi> <vi>the differences between <it>men</it> [=<it>people</it>] and beasts/animals</vi> <vi>He believes that all <it>men</it> are created equal.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the human race <vi>prehistoric <it>man</it></vi> <vi>It's not a fit night out for <it>man</it> or/nor beast. [=for people or animals]</vi> <vi>the problems facing <phrase>modern man</phrase> [=the human race in modern times]</vi> <snote>Senses 4a and 4b are now sometimes avoided because they are considered sexist.</snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used when you are talking to a man <vi>(<it>chiefly US, informal</it>) Hey, <it>man</it>, how are you?</vi> <vi>(<it>old-fashioned</it>) Pull yourself together, <it>man</it>!</vi> <vi>Okay, <it>men</it>, let's go out there and win!</vi> <vi>(<it>US, informal</it>) Hey, <phrase>my man</phrase>! It's good to see you!</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit, old-fashioned</it>) <phrase>My good man</phrase>, can you tell me where the railroad station is?</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a male worker who goes to people's homes <vi>The furnace <it>man</it> came to repair the heater.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>men</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:a group of male workers, soldiers, etc. <vi>The <it>men</it> have threatened to go on strike.</vi> <vi>He led his <it>men</it> into battle against overwhelming odds.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a man who does a particular kind of work <vi>a medical/military <it>man</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a man who has a specified job or position or who belongs to a specified category of worker <un>used in combination <vi>a council<it>man</it></vi> <vi>Has the mail<it>man</it> come yet?</vi> <vi>He's a shrewd business<it>man</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a man who works for or represents a particular person or organization <vi>our <it>man</it> in Washington</vi> <vi>He spoke with the president's <it>man</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a male servant <un>usually singular <vi>My <it>man</it> will show you to your room.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a male student or former student at a college or university <vi>He's a Harvard <it>man</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a man who comes from or lives in a specified town, city, etc. <un>used chiefly by journalists <vi>One of the accident victims has been identified as a Boston <it>man</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a man who likes something very much or who is known for some activity or interest <vi>I'm strictly a vanilla ice cream <it>man</it>. [=I'm a man who likes vanilla ice cream]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who can do what is needed <vi>If you need someone to help organize the files, <phrase>I'm/he's/she's your man</phrase>! [=I'm/he's/she's the person you need for the job]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the person someone (such as a police officer) is looking for <vi>He matches the description, but I don't think he's our <it>man</it>.</vi> <vi>a detective who always <phrase>gets his man</phrase> [=catches the criminal]</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the pieces in a game like chess or checkers</dt></def> <dro><dre>a fine figure of a man</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as one man</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <sl>now usually used of a group of men</sl> <dt>:as a group :all together <vi>The audience rose <it>as one man</it> [=everyone in the audience stood up] and cheered.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be/become your own man</dre> <def><dt>:to be or become a man who is not controlled by other people or who is able to support himself without the help of other people <vi>He left home and moved to the city to <it>become his own man</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>every man for himself</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe a situation in which people do not help each other and each person has to take care of himself or herself <vi>As soon as there was a crisis, it was <it>every man for himself</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>iron man</dre> <dx>see <dxt>iron</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>man of action</dre> <dx>see <dxt>action</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>man of the hour</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hour</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>man's best friend</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to a dog or to dogs as a group <vi>She devotes her life to helping <it>man's best friend</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>poor man's</dre> <dx>see <dxt>poor</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>separate the men from the boys</dre> <dx>see <dxt>separate</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the man</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the Man</va></svr> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:the police <vi>He got in trouble with <it>the Man</it> and ended up in jail.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the Man</va> <vl>also</vl> <va>The Man</va></svr> <dt>:the white people who are seen as having power in the U.S. :the white establishment <vi>He got a job working for <it>the Man</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a man who is admired or respected as a leader or as the best man in a particular field, sport, etc. <vi>The other players on the team all know that he's <it>the man</it>.</vi> <vi>You're <it>the man</it>! = (<it>very informal</it>) You <it>the man</it>! = (<it>very informal + humorous</it>) <phrase>You da man</phrase>!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the man in the street</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>the man on the Clapham omnibus</va></vr> <def><dt>:the ordinary and average person <vi>What does <it>the man in the street</it> think about it?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the odd man out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>odd</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to a man</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that all the members in a group of men said, did, or thought the same thing <vi>He worried that some of his friends might object, but, <it>to a man</it>, they supported his decision. [=all of them supported his decision]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the last man</dre> <def><dt>:until all the men in a group are killed, defeated, etc. <vi>They vowed to fight <it>to the last man</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="unstuck"> <hw>un*stuck</hw> <sound><wav>unstuc01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌʌnˈstʌk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:able to move freely :no longer stuck <vi>We couldn't get the steering wheel <it>unstuck</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>become/come unstuck</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop being stuck to something <vi>The suction cup <it>came unstuck</it> from the wall.</vi> <vi>The photograph was <it>becoming unstuck</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to fail <vi>Their marriage <it>came unstuck</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>came unglued</it>] last summer.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
