<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bed[1]"> <art><artref id="bed_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>394,240</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bed</hw> <sound><wav>bed00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>beds</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a piece of furniture that people sleep on <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The room contains only a <it>bed</it> and a dresser.</vi> <vi>There are two <it>beds</it> in the hotel room.</vi> <vi>a hospital <it>bed</it></vi> <vi>a single <it>bed</it> [=a bed for one person]</vi> <vi>a double <it>bed</it> [=a bed for two people]</vi> <vi>He lay <phrase>on the bed</phrase> [=on top of the sheets, blankets, and bedspread] for a long time.</vi> <vi>Don't forget to <phrase>make the bed</phrase>. [=to neatly arrange the sheets, blankets, and bedspread on the bed so that the mattress is covered]</vi> <vi>He became ill and <phrase>took to his bed</phrase>. [=he went to lie in bed for a long time]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She usually <phrase>goes to bed</phrase> [=lies down in her bed to sleep] around 11:00.</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>get out of bed</phrase>. [=<it>get up</it>]</vi> <vi>He lay/stayed <phrase>in bed</phrase> all morning.</vi> <vi>The kids like to hear a story <phrase>before bed</phrase>. [=before they go to sleep]</vi> <vi>Have you <phrase>put the children to bed</phrase>? [=have you prepared the children to go to sleep and put them in their beds?]</vi> <vi>Come on, children. It's <phrase>time for bed</phrase>. [=<it>bedtime</it>, <it>time to sleep</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is used to sleep on <vi>The blanket by the fireplace is the dog's <it>bed</it>.</vi> <vi>Her <it>bed</it> was a mound of soft pine needles.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>deathbed</dxt> <dxt>sickbed</dxt> <dxt>sunbed</dxt> <dxt>water bed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases that describe having sexual relations</un> <snote>Someone who is <phrase>good in bed</phrase> is a skillful lover. When two people are <phrase>in bed</phrase>, they are in the act of having sex. <vi>She caught her husband and his secretary <it>in bed</it> together. = She caught her husband <it>in bed</it> with his secretary.</vi> To <phrase>go to bed with</phrase> someone is to have sex with someone. <vi>She likes him as a friend, but she's not interested in <it>going to bed with</it> him.</vi> To <phrase>get someone into bed</phrase> is to get someone to have sex with you. <vi>He has fantasies about <it>getting a fashion model into bed</it>.</vi> Phrases like these are also used figuratively. <vi>a politician who is accused of being <phrase>in bed with</phrase> the oil industry [=of having an improperly close relationship with the oil industry]</vi> <vi>The Communists and the Fascists <it>got into bed with</it> each other [=<it>joined forces</it>] to keep the liberals out of power.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small area of ground specially prepared for plants <vi>I'm planning on putting a <it>bed</it> of perennials in that corner of the yard.</vi> <vi>a <it>bed</it> of flowers</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bed of roses</dxt> <dxt>flower bed</dxt> <dxt>seedbed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a flat pile or layer of something <vi>a <it>bed</it> of coals</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a flat pile or layer of food that is placed on a dish with other food on top of it <vi>grilled fish served on a <it>bed</it> of greens</vi> <vi>a <it>bed</it> of rice</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the ground that is at the bottom of a sea, lake, etc. <vi>seaweed growing on the ocean <it>bed</it> [=<it>floor</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an area of shallow water where something grows <vi>an oyster <it>bed</it> [=an area where there are many oysters]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>riverbed</dxt> <dxt>seabed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a layer of rock or some other material from inside the earth <vi>fossil <it>beds</it></vi> <vi>a <it>bed</it> of shale</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the platform or box in the back of some kinds of trucks <vi>the <it>bed</it> of the truck</vi> <vi>We loaded the equipment and put a cover over the truck <it>bed</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>flatbed</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>die in (your) bed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>die</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get up on the wrong side of the bed</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get out of bed on the wrong side</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be in a bad mood throughout the day <vi>Be careful when you talk to the boss. He <it>got up on the wrong side of the bed</it> this morning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make your bed and lie in it</dre> <def><dt><snote>Expressions like <it>you've made your bed, and now you must lie in it</it> mean that you have done something that causes problems and now you must accept and deal with those problems. <vi>There's nothing we can do to help her. <it>She's made her bed and has to lie in it</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>marriage bed</dre> <def><dt>:a bed that married people share <un>sometimes used figuratively to refer to marriage in general or to the sexual relations that married people have <vi>the sorrows of their <it>marriage bed</it></vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bed[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bed</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛd</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>beds</if></in> <in><if>bed*ded</if></in> <in><if>bed*ding</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone) <vi>He has fantasies about <it>bedding</it> a fashion model.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to place (food) on a pile or layer of something else <un>usually used as <it>(be) bedded</it> <vi>a mixture of scallops and lobster <it>bedded</it> on rice</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bed down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to lie down somewhere for sleep <vi>There were so many people that some of us had to <it>bed down</it> in the living room.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bed (someone or something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bed down (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to provide (a person or animal) with a place to sleep <vi>They <it>bedded</it> us <it>down</it> in the living room.</vi> <vi>When the animals had been fed and <it>bedded down</it>, we went inside to eat dinner.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bed and board"> <hw>bed and board</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:food and a place to sleep <vi>They provide <it>bed and board</it> [=<it>room and board</it>] for travellers.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bed-and-breakfast"> <hw>bed–and–breakfast</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bed–and–breakfasts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a house or small hotel in which someone can rent a room to sleep in for a price that includes breakfast the next morning <vi>We stayed the night at a nice <it>bed-and-breakfast</it> near the beach.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>B and B</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:a service in which the price of a room also includes breakfast the next morning <vi>a small hotel that offers <it>bed-and-breakfast</it></vi> <ca>called also <cat>B and B</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bed linens"> <hw>bed linens</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:sheets and pillowcases for a bed <ca>called also (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>bed linen</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bed of roses"> <hw>bed of roses</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a place or situation that is pleasant or easy <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>Grandfather liked to remind people not to expect things to be easy. “Life's no <it>bed of roses</it>,” he'd say.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bed rest"> <hw>bed rest</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:rest while lying in a bed <vi>The doctor prescribed <it>bed rest</it> for a month.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bed-wetting"> <hw>bed–wet*ting</hw> <sound><wav>bedwe01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛdˌwɛtɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:urinating that occurs while someone (such as a child) is sleeping in bed</dt></def> <uro><ure>bed–wet*ter</ure> <sound><wav>bedwe01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛdˌwɛtɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bed–wet*ters</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="air bed"> <hw>air bed</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ beds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>air mattress</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bunk bed"> <hw>bunk bed</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ beds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a type of bed for two people that has two single beds placed so that one is above the other <dx>see picture at <dxt>bed</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
