<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="before[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">be*fore</hw> <sound><wav>before01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈfoɚ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at an earlier time <vi>Haven't we met <it>before</it>?</vi> <vi>the night/day <it>before</it></vi> <vi>I've never seen her so happy <it>before</it>. [=I've never seen her as happy as she is now]</vi> <vi>We haven't had these problems <it>before</it>.</vi> <vi>Everything is just as (it was) <it>before</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to or toward the place where someone is going :in advance <vi>marching on <it>before</it> [=<it>ahead</it>]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="before[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">before</hw> <altpr>bɪˈfoɚ</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:at a time preceding (something or someone) :earlier than (something or someone) <vi>We arrived shortly <it>before</it> six o'clock.</vi> <vi><it>before</it> dinner</vi> <vi>He left just <it>before</it> sunrise.</vi> <vi>I've never seen her so happy <it>before</it> now.</vi> <vi>Call me <it>before</it> your arrival.</vi> <vi>She arrived the day <it>before</it> yesterday.</vi> <vi>Why haven't you ever helped me <it>before</it> now/this?</vi> <vi>I finished the exam <it>before</it> him. [=before he finished the exam]</vi> <vi>You can go <it>before</it> me. [=before I go]</vi> <vi>He's an electrician, like his father <it>before</it> him. [=his father was also an electrician]</vi> <vi>They earned 50,000 dollars <it>before</it> (paying) taxes.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe a time earlier than a specified hour <vi>It's 20 (minutes) <it>before</it> 12. [=it's 20 of/to 12; it's 11:40]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:preceding (something or someone) in order or in a series <vi>Your name is listed <it>before</it> mine.</vi> <vi>You'll see my house just <it>before</it> the bank and after the school.</vi> <vi>The number 2 comes <it>before</it> 3 and after 1. [=2 comes between 1 and 3]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:in front of (someone or something) <vi>The Great Plains stretched endlessly <it>before</it> them.</vi> <vi>The championship fight took place <it>before</it> a crowd of thousands.</vi> :in the presence of (someone) <vi>The defendant stood up <it>before</it> the judge.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>(right) before/in front of your (very) eyes</tag> at <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:being considered by (someone or something) <vi>The case <it>before</it> the court involves a robbery.</vi> <vi>the candidates <it>before</it> the voters</vi> <vi>I have a proposal to put <it>before</it> [=<it>to</it>] the board.</vi> <vi>The question <it>before</it> us is this: did he fall or was he pushed?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:in the future for (someone) :ahead of (someone) <vi>They had no idea of the ordeal that lay <it>before</it> them.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:in a higher or more important position than (something) <vi>They put quantity <it>before</it> [=<it>above</it>] quality. [=they cared more about quantity than about quality]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:rather or sooner than <vi>He vowed that he would choose death <it>before</it> dishonor. [=he would rather die than be dishonored]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:under the force of (something) <vi>The tree fell <it>before</it> the force of the wind. [=the force of the wind caused the tree to fall]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="before[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">before</hw> <altpr>bɪˈfoɚ</altpr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:earlier than the time that :earlier than when <vi>He left long <it>before</it> morning came.</vi> <vi>The judge stood up <it>before</it> the defendant did. [=the defendant stood up after the judge did]</vi> <vi>Say goodbye <it>before</it> you go.</vi> <vi>Call me <it>before</it> you arrive.</vi> <vi><it>Before</it> [=<it>until</it>] she met him she had never been so happy.</vi> <vi>I finished the exam <it>before</it> he did.</vi> <vi>It was/happened not long <it>before</it> he arrived.</vi> <vi>He left <it>before</it> I could thank him. [=I wasn't able to thank him because he left too soon]</vi> <vi>I'll resign <it>before</it> I give in! [=I would rather resign than give in]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>before you know it</tag> at <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:until the time that <vi>It did not take long <it>before</it> he had earned their trust. [=he earned their trust quickly]</vi> <vi>“I have promises to keep and miles to go <it>before</it> I sleep…” <aq>Robert Frost, “Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening” (1923)</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt><un>used to refer to something that might happen <vi>Get out of there <it>before</it> you get dirty! [=get out of there because you will/might get dirty if you don't]</vi> <vi><it>Before</it> I forget, will you give me your telephone number? [=I'm asking for your telephone number now because I might forget to do it later]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that one thing must happen for another thing to happen or be possible <vi>He must be convicted <it>before</it> he can be removed from office.</vi> <vi>You must have completed an introductory class <it>before</it> you can take an advanced class.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blink[1]"> <hw hindex="1">blink</hw> <sound><wav>blink001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblɪŋk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>blinks</if></in> <in><if>blinked</if></in> <in><if>blink*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to close and then open your eyes very quickly <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>blinked</it> when the light flashed.</vi> <vi>Her eyes <it>blinked</it> when the light flashed.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>blinked</it> her eyes when the light flashed.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>wink</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to shine with a light that goes on and off <vi>The red light was <it>blinking</it>. [=<it>flashing</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to show that you are surprised or upset <vi>Laura <phrase>didn't (even) blink</phrase> [=did not seem surprised or upset at all] when I told her that the car was gone.</vi> <vi>She <it>didn't (even) blink</it> at the news.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to show weakness in an argument or disagreement :to show that you are willing to agree to or accept what someone else wants or says <vi>When threatened, the government <it>blinked</it> [=<it>gave in</it>] and agreed to move the missiles.</vi> <vi>Both sides in the dispute are determined not to <it>blink</it> first.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>before you can blink</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very quickly <vi>This may hurt a little, but it'll be over <it>before you can blink</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blink back tears</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>blink away tears</va></vr> <def><dt>:to prevent yourself from crying or to make your tears go away by blinking <vi>He <it>blinked back</it> (his) <it>tears</it> as he told us the bad news.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bring"> <hw highlight="yes">bring</hw> <sound><wav>bring001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɪŋ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>brings</if></in> <in><if>brought</if> <sound><wav>bring002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>bring*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to come with (something or someone) to a place <vi>I'll <it>bring</it> a bottle of wine (with me) when I come to your party.</vi> <vi>“Should I send you a check?” “Why not just <it>bring</it> me the money when you come?”</vi> <vi>Have you <it>brought</it> the money with you from the bank?</vi> <vi>She <it>brought</it> her boyfriend home to meet her parents.</vi> <vi>You stay where you are and I'll <it>bring</it> you another drink. = I'll <it>bring</it> another drink to you.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to come <vi>Her screams <it>brought</it> [=<it>attracted</it>] help.</vi> <vi>Her screams <it>brought</it> the neighbors running. [=the neighbors ran to help her when they heard her screams]</vi> <vi>Love of adventure <it>brought</it> her here before taking her to many other places.</vi> <vi>This radio station <it>brings</it> you all the news as it happens.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to exist, happen, or start <vi>Can anything <it>bring</it> peace to this troubled region?</vi> <vi>In this part of the country, winter <it>brings</it> snow (with it).</vi> <vi>The tablets may <it>bring</it> (you) some relief.</vi> <vi>Having a baby has <it>brought</it> great happiness into her life.</vi> <vi>The sad story <phrase>brought tears to our eyes</phrase> [=made us cry] but its happy ending <phrase>brought smiles to our lips</phrase>. [=made us smile]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to reach a specified state, place, condition, etc. <vi>The dancer <it>brought</it> his hands up to his face.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) <it>Bring</it> the water to a boil. = (<it>Brit</it>) <it>Bring</it> the water to the boil. [=heat the water so that it boils]</vi> <vi>The pilot <it>brought</it> them safely out of danger.</vi> <vi>Winter snow <it>brought</it> traffic to a stop.</vi> <vi>A few steps <it>brought</it> us to the front door.</vi> <vi>The thrilling climax <it>brought</it> the audience to its/their feet.</vi> <vi>This history book <it>brings</it> us up to the present day.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to have (a particular talent, quality, etc.) when you start to do something (such as a job) <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>brings</it> years of experience <it>to</it> the position. [=she comes to the position with years of experience]</vi> <vi>He <it>brings</it> a rare talent for solving problems <it>to</it> his new job as company president.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to start a case against someone in a court of law <vi>They threatened to <it>bring</it> [=<it>institute</it>] legal action against him.</vi> <vi>They are going to <phrase>bring charges against</phrase> him. [=they are going to charge him with a crime]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to reach a total <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>Last week's sales figures <it>brought</it> our pretax profits for the year <it>to</it> just over $35,000,000.</vi> <vi>The donation <it>brought</it> the fund <it>to</it> over a million dollars.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to get (an amount of money) as a price :to be sold for (a price) <vi>The painting ought to <it>bring</it> [=<it>fetch</it>] a high price.</vi></dt> <snotebox>In addition to the phrases shown below, <it>bring</it> occurs in many idioms that are shown at appropriate entries throughout the dictionary. For example, <it>bring to bear</it> can be found at <sc>bear</sc> and <it>bring to an end</it> can be found at <sc>end</sc>.</snotebox></def> <dro><dre>bring about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring about (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>bring (something) about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) <vi>“What <it>brought about</it> the crisis?” “It was <it>brought about</it> by many factors.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring around</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>bring round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to come around: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to accept and support something (such as an idea) after opposing it <vi>She still says she won't support us, but we'll <it>bring</it> her <it>around</it> eventually. [=we'll convince/persuade her to support us eventually]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'm sure we can <it>bring</it> her <it>around to</it> our way of thinking.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become awake again after being unconscious <vi>The boxer was knocked out and it took the doctor several minutes to <it>bring</it> him <it>around</it>. [=bring him to]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to come with (someone) for a social visit <vi>Why don't you <it>bring</it> your friend <it>around</it> (to my house) after work today?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a conversation) to go to a desired subject or area <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>We gradually <it>brought</it> the conversation <it>around to</it> the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something or someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring back (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to come back with (something or someone) <vi>What did you <it>bring back</it> (with you) from your vacation?</vi> <vi>You promised to <it>bring back</it> a present for me. = You promised to <it>bring</it> me <it>back</it> a present.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to return <vi>The death penalty was done away with in this area many years ago, but some people now want it to be <it>brought back</it>.</vi> <vi>The movie is a fantasy about a man who is <it>brought back</it> (to life) from the dead.</vi> <vi>The company is doing poorly, and its former president is being <it>brought back</it> to help solve its problems.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to return <it>to</it> a condition, subject, etc. <vi>That question <it>brings</it> us <it>back</it> (again) <it>to</it> the fundamental problem of world peace.</vi> <vi>We gradually <it>brought</it> the conversation <it>back to</it> the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to return to someone's memory <vi>Seeing her again <it>brought back</it> a lot of happy memories.</vi> <vi>I had almost forgotten about the time we spent together, but seeing her again <phrase>brought it all back</phrase> (to me).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (someone or something) before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to come to (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>He was <it>brought</it> (up) <it>before</it> the judge on a charge of obstructing justice.</vi> <vi>The case was finally <it>brought before</it> the Supreme Court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring down (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone or something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to fall down onto the ground <vi>The deer was <it>brought down</it> by a single shot.</vi> <vi>The plane was <it>brought down</it> by enemy fire.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The government was <it>brought down</it> by a vote of no confidence.</vi> <vi>a famous politician who was <it>brought down</it> by scandal</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to become lower <vi>Will anything ever <it>bring</it> house prices <it>down</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>All this rainy weather is really <it>bringing</it> me <it>down</it>. [=getting me down]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) forth</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring forth (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>The rosebushes <it>brought forth</it> an abundance of flowers.</vi> <vi>He was able to <it>bring forth</it> persuasive arguments in support of his position.</vi> :to cause (something) to occur or exist <vi>Her controversial comments <it>brought forth</it> [=<it>provoked</it>] strong reactions from the public.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to talk about or show (something) so that it can be seen or discussed by others <vi>The police have <it>brought</it> new evidence <it>forward</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make the time of (something) earlier or sooner <vi>We need to <it>bring</it> the meeting <it>forward</it> from Tuesday to Monday so that more people can attend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become involved in a process, activity, etc. <vi>The company has decided to <it>bring in</it> outside experts to help on the project.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) in</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce or earn (an amount of money) <vi>Each sale <it>brought in</it> $5.</vi> <vi>He works at a large company and <it>brings in</it> a good salary.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to report (an official decision) to a court <vi>The jury <it>brought in</it> [=<it>returned</it>] a verdict of not guilty. [=the jury said that the defendant was not guilty]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to introduce (a new law, rule, etc.) <vi>The government is going to <it>bring in</it> legislation to make such practices illegal.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone or something) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to come to a place <vi>The store is having a special sale in order to <it>bring in</it> [=<it>attract</it>] new customers/business.</vi> <vi>The police <it>brought</it> him <it>in</it> (to the police station) for questioning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) off</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>bring off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something difficult) :to achieve or accomplish (something) <vi>It's a challenging role. She's the only actress I know with enough talent to <it>bring</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring on (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) on</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to appear or occur <vi>The crisis was <it>brought on</it> by many factors.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something bad) to happen to (someone) <vi>You've <it>brought</it> nothing but shame <it>on</it> your family since the day you were born!</vi> <vi>I can't help thinking you've <it>brought</it> some of this trouble <it>on</it> yourself.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to show (something) :to cause (something) to appear or to be more easily seen <vi>The debate <it>brought out</it> [=<it>highlighted</it>] the differences between the two candidates.</vi> <vi>That blue sweater really <it>brings out</it> the color in your eyes.</vi> <vi>Our school aims to <it>bring out</it> [=<it>develop</it>] the talents in each of our students.</vi> <vi>A crisis <phrase>brings out the best in</phrase> some people and <phrase>brings out the worst in</phrase> others. [=a crisis causes some people to behave very well and other people to behave very badly]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as a book) :to cause (something) to become available or to come out <vi>a writer who's expected to <it>bring out</it> a new novel next year</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) out in (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to begin to have (something, such as a rash) on the skin <vi>Eating strawberries <it>brings</it> me <it>out in</it> spots. [=eating strawberries makes me break out in spots]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bring around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bring to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (someone) to</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become awake again after being unconscious <vi>The boxer was knocked out and it took the doctor several minutes to <it>bring</it> him <it>to</it>. [=bring him around]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (people) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring together (people)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to join or meet :to cause (people) to come together <vi>She and her husband were <it>brought together</it> by a shared love of the natural world.</vi> <vi>The conference has <it>brought together</it> some of the world's leading experts on laser technology.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take care of and teach (a child who is growing up) <vi>I was born and <it>brought up</it> [=<it>raised, reared</it>] in Chicago.</vi> <vi>My grandparents <it>brought</it> me <it>up</it> after my parents died.</vi> <vi>My parents <it>brought</it> me <it>up</it> to respect authority. [=my parents taught me to respect authority when I was a child]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to mention (something) when talking :to start to talk about (something) <vi>We were waiting for a suitable moment to <it>bring up</it> [=<it>introduce, raise</it>] the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi> <vi>I wasn't going to talk about money, but since you've <it>brought</it> it <it>up</it>, I guess it's something we should really discuss.</vi> <vi>I'm glad you mentioned money. That <it>brings up</it> the question of how much we can afford to spend.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a file or picture) to appear on a computer screen <vi>The system makes it easy to <it>bring up</it> (on the screen) information about any customer.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>vomit</sx> <vi>The patient tried to eat some breakfast but immediately <it>brought</it> it back <it>up</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stop suddenly <un>used in phrases like <phrase>bring up short</phrase> and <phrase>bring up suddenly</phrase> <vi>He was just starting to argue when her scream <it>brought him up short</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to force yourself <it>to do</it> something that you do not want to do <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>He knew that he should apologize, but he couldn't <it>bring himself to do</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bring*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bring*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bringer</it> of good news</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="calm[2]"> <hw hindex="2">calm</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:m</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a quiet and peaceful state or condition <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>After two days of violent protests, the mayor appealed/pleaded for <it>calm</it>.</vi> <vi>The <it>calm</it> was broken by another terrorist bombing.</vi> <vi>the <it>calm</it> of a church</vi> <vi>Police tried to <phrase>restore calm</phrase> after the riot.</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>A quiet <it>calm</it> settled over the city.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a peaceful mental or emotional state <un>usually singular <vi>The coach was able to keep his <it>calm</it> during the game.</vi> <vi>Everyone noticed her outward <it>calm</it> at the funeral.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>the calm before the storm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>storm</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="carry[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">car*ry</hw> <sound><wav>carry001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeri</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>car*ries</if></in> <in><if>car*ried</if></in> <in><if>car*ry*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (something) while holding and supporting it <vi>She helped me <it>carry</it> [=<it>transport</it>] the boxes out to my car.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>carry</it> your luggage to your room.</vi> <vi>He was <it>carrying</it> his baby daughter in his arms.</vi> <vi>For two months, I <it>carried</it> the book around with me everywhere I went.</vi> <vi>The waitress <it>carried</it> away our empty dinner plates.</vi> <vi>The wind <it>carried</it> the smoke away from the campsite.</vi> <vi>These planes can <it>carry</it> up to 300 passengers.</vi> <vi>a ship <it>carrying</it> thousands of gallons of oil</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Your talent will <it>carry</it> you far. [=it will make you very successful]</vi> <vi>She intended the play to <it>carry</it> audiences toward a sense of peace and understanding.</vi> <vi>She still <it>carries</it> the memories of an unhappy childhood.</vi> <vi>The song <phrase>carries me back to</phrase> [=it makes me remember] my first year of college.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to contain and direct the flow of (water, electricity, etc.) <vi>Oil is <it>carried</it> to the factory through these pipes.</vi> <vi>We installed gutters that will <it>carry</it> water away from the house.</vi> <vi>blood vessels that <it>carry</it> blood to the heart</vi> <vi>These cables <it>carry</it> electricity to hundreds of homes.</vi> <vi>The bridge <it>carries</it> traffic in two directions.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) with you or on your body <vi>Do police officers <it>carry</it> guns when they're off duty?</vi> <vi>This bus driver doesn't <it>carry</it> change, so please have the exact fare ready.</vi> <vi>I always <it>carry</it> $20 in case of an emergency.</vi> <vi>tourists <it>carrying</it> cameras</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be able to give (a disease or a gene) to others even though you may not be affected by it <vi>One percent of the population now <it>carries</it> the virus, and one in three will suffer symptoms of the disease.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be pregnant with (a baby) <vi>She's <it>carrying</it> her second child.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hold (your body or your head) in a particular way <vi>He's over 80 years old and still <it>carries</it> himself erect/upright like a soldier.</vi> <vi>Be proud of yourself. Walk tall and <it>carry</it> your head high!</vi> <vi>She always <it>carries</it> [=(more formally) <it>comports</it>] herself with dignity and grace.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) in a store and ready to be sold :to keep (something) in stock <vi>Our grocery store <it>carries</it> a good selection of wines.</vi> <vi>We no longer <it>carry</it> that brand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have (someone or something) on a list or record <vi>The company <it>carries</it> nearly 200 employees on its payroll.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) as a quality or characteristic <vi>All of our products <it>carry</it> a lifetime guarantee.</vi> <vi>Your promises would <phrase>carry more weight</phrase> [=they would be more meaningful] if you didn't break them so often.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be marked or labeled with (something) <vi>Cigarettes are required to <it>carry</it> a government health warning.</vi> <vi>men who <it>carry</it> the physical scars of war</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a result or consequence <vi>Such crimes <it>carry</it> [=<it>entail</it>, <it>involve</it>] a heavy penalty.</vi> <vi>The surgery does <it>carry</it> certain risks.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>You must understand that the job <it>carries with</it> it <it>g</it>reat responsibility.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a duty or responsibility <vi>I'm <it>carrying</it> a full course load this semester.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>carries the weight of the world on his shoulders</phrase>. [=he feels much pressure because he has great responsibilities]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be responsible for the success of (something or someone) <vi>He's a player that's capable of <it>carrying</it> a team on his own.</vi> <vi>Her spectacular performance as Carmen <it>carried</it> the opera.</vi></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) continue <vi>They <it>carried</it> [=<it>took, extended</it>] the game into the 10th inning.</vi> <vi>The newspaper <it>carried</it> the story over to the following page.</vi> <vi>The design calls for the columns to be <it>carried</it> all the way up to the top of the building.</vi> <vi><it>carrying</it> the war to another continent</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to travel a long distance <vi>His deep voice <it>carries</it> well.</vi> <vi>Baseballs don't <it>carry</it> well in cold weather.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue (something) beyond a normal or acceptable limit <vi>He realized that he had <it>carried</it> the joke too far and hurt her feelings.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>carry (something) to extremes</tag> at <dxt>extreme</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to sing (a tune) correctly <vi>I've never been able to <it>carry</it> a tune.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to present (a story, sports event, TV show, etc.) to the public <vi>Channel 9 will <it>carry</it> the game.</vi> <vi>Every local newspaper <it>carried</it> [=<it>ran</it>] the photograph.</vi> <vi>The trial was <it>carried</it> live [=broadcast as it was happening] on television.</vi></dt> <sn>16 a</sn> <dt>:to cause (a bill or an official proposal) to be passed or adopted <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often used as <it>(be) carried</it> <vi>The bill <it>was carried</it> in the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He called for a motion to stop debate, but the motion did not <it>carry</it>.</vi> <vi>The motion <it>carried</it> unanimously. [=everyone voted to pass it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to win a majority of votes in (a state, legislature, etc.) <vi>The bill <it>carried</it> the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi> <vi>In the presidential election of 1936, Franklin D. Roosevelt <it>carried</it> [=<it>won, took</it>] all the states except Maine and Vermont.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (a number) from one column to another when you are adding numbers together <vi>When you added these two numbers, you forgot to <it>carry</it> the 1.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be/get carried away</dre> <def><dt>:to be so excited that you are no longer in control of your behavior <vi>I shouldn't have behaved like that. I just <it>got carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>Just relax! There's no need to <it>get carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>They allowed themselves to <it>be carried away</it> by fear.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry all/everything before you</dre> <def><sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to be completely successful <vi>This young boxer has the talent to <it>carry all before him</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry a torch for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry coals to Newcastle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coal</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry into effect</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry (something) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do (something difficult) successfully :to achieve or accomplish (something) <vi>He tried to look cool but couldn't <it>carry it off</it>. [=<it>pull it off</it>]</vi> <vi>She's the only actress I know with enough talent to <it>carry this off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>We <it>carried off</it> the prize.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to do what you have been doing <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you—please <it>carry on</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>carried on</it> as if nothing had happened.</vi> :to continue despite problems <vi>I know it's difficult, but you need to <it>carry on</it> as best you can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to behave or speak in an excited or foolish way <vi>They laughed and <it>carried on</it> like they were old friends.</vi> <vi>We were embarrassed by the way he was <it>carrying on</it>.</vi> <vi>She's always <it>carrying on</it> [=talking in an excited way] about her neighbors.</vi> <vi>screaming, crying, and <it>carrying on</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryings-on</dxt> <dxt>carry-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage or participate in (an activity) <vi>She <it>carried on</it> an affair with her boss.</vi> <vi>It's too noisy in here to <it>carry on</it> a conversation.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>carrying on</it> [=<it>conducting</it>] an investigation into his murder.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> a campaign against illegal drug use</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>The money allows us to <it>carry on</it> our research.</vi> <vi>Although the teacher spoke to them, they just <it>carried on</it> [=<it>went on</it>, <it>kept on</it>] talking.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a tradition) to continue <vi>We were the only ones left to <it>carry on</it> the tradition.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> the family name</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing or participating in (an activity) <vi>Please <it>carry on with</it> what you were doing.</vi> <vi>They <it>carried on with</it> their conversation.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have an often immoral sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>I found out that he had been <it>carrying on with</it> [=(more commonly) <it>fooling around with</it>] my sister.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do and complete (something) <vi>We <it>carried out</it> several experiments to test the theory.</vi> <vi>An investigation <it>carried out</it> several years ago revealed no new information.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to act on (a promise, plan, etc.) :to do something that you said you would do or that someone has asked you to do <vi>She failed to <it>carry out</it> [=<it>fulfill</it>] her promise.</vi> <vi>The town has plans to build a new school, but it currently lacks the money to <it>carry</it> them <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>You'll be paid when you've <it>carried out</it> [=<it>executed</it>] your instructions/orders/duties.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or be seen in another place or situation <vi>His unhappiness at home <it>carried over</it> into/to his work.</vi> <vi>Her abilities in singing didn't <it>carry over</it> to acting.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or allow (something) to continue in another place or situation <vi>People can <it>carry</it> bad eating habits learned in childhood <it>over</it> to/into adulthood.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the can</dre> <dx>see <dxt>can</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>day</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the torch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or happen <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>The yellow and blue theme in the kitchen <it>carries through to</it> the rest of the house.</vi> <vi>Our conversation <it>carried through to</it> dessert.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to do something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Though extremely tired, she managed to <it>carry through to</it> the finish.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry through with/on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to do (something that you said you would do) <vi>The mayor <it>carried through</it> [=<it>followed through</it>] <it>on</it> her promise to clean up the city.</vi> <vi>We're beginning to <it>carry through with</it> [=<it>carry out</it>] our plans.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to successfully finish or complete (something that you have begun or said you will do) <vi>Whatever project you begin, you must <it>carry it through</it> to completion.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> (until spring).</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue during (a period of time) <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> the winter.</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it> a difficult time in his life.</vi> <vi>I borrowed a few more books to <it>carry me through</it> the summer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fetch and carry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fetch</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cart[1]"> <hw hindex="1">cart</hw> <sound><wav>cart0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>carts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a wagon with two wheels that is pulled by an animal (such as a horse or donkey)</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a small wheeled vehicle that is pushed: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a metal basket on wheels used to hold groceries while you are shopping <vi>a grocery <it>cart</it></vi> <ca>called also <cat>shopping cart</cat> (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>trolley</cat></ca></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a table with wheels used especially for serving food <vi>a dessert <it>cart</it></vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>trolley</cat></ca></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>golf cart</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>put the cart before the horse</dre> <def><dt>:to do things in the wrong order :to do something first instead of waiting until something else has been done <vi>People are <it>putting the cart before the horse</it> by making plans on how to spend the money before we are even certain that the money will be available.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>upset the apple cart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>upset</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cast[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cast</hw> <sound><wav>cast0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈkɑ:st</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>casts</if></in> <in><if>cast</if></in> <in><if>cast*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to throw or move (something) in a forceful way <vi><it>cast</it> [=<it>throw, toss</it>] a stone</vi> <vi>Seaweed was <it>cast</it> up by the waves.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to throw (a fishing line, hook, etc.) into the water by using a fishing pole</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to send or direct (something) in the direction of someone or something <vi>He <it>cast</it> a glance toward the door. [=he glanced at the door]</vi> <vi>The witch <it>cast</it> [=<it>put</it>] a spell on him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send (something) out or forward <vi>The fire <it>casts</it> [=<it>gives off</it>] a warm glow.</vi> <vi>The tree <it>cast</it> a long shadow on the lawn.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The trial <it>casts</it> a harsh light on [=reveals bad things about] the banking industry.</vi> <vi>Their argument <phrase>cast a pall</phrase> on the party. [=gave the party an unhappy mood]</vi> <vi>The incident <phrase>casts doubt</phrase> on her honesty.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (a vote) formally <vi>How many votes were <it>cast</it>?</vi> <vi><it>cast</it> a ballot</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to assign roles for (a play, movie, etc.) to actors <vi><it>cast</it> a play</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to assign (an actor or actress) a role in a film, play, etc. <vi>She was <it>cast</it> as a college professor who becomes a spy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>typecast</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to shape (a substance) by pouring it into a mold and letting it harden <vi>The metal was <it>cast</it> into candlesticks.</vi> <vi>molds used for <it>casting</it> steel</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form (something, such as a sculpture) by casting metal, plaster, etc. <vi>The statue will be <it>cast</it> in bronze.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to arrange (something) into parts or into a proper form <vi>He <it>cast</it> the story in the form of a diary.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think of (someone or something) in a particular way <vi>The war was <it>cast</it> as a battle against terrorism.</vi> <vi>Health care issues are often <it>cast</it> in economic terms.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cast about/around for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast about/around for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look in many places for (something) <vi>They <it>cast about for</it> new ways to make money on the farm.</vi> <vi>She is still <it>casting around for</it> [=<it>seeking</it>] someone to watch her son while she is at work.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast a (dark) cloud</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloud</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast adrift</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (a boat) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat) to float on the water without being tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>a small lifeboat <it>cast adrift</it> in the open sea</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (someone) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to float on the water in a boat that is not tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>They <it>were cast adrift</it> in a small, leaky boat.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>I <it>was cast adrift</it> in a sea of confusion.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast aside (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) aside</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop thinking about (something) <vi>She tried to <it>cast aside</it> her worries and enjoy the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aspersions</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aspersions</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast away (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone) away</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (someone) alone somewhere (such as on an island) as a result of a storm, shipwreck, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be) cast away</it> <vi>The crew <it>was cast away</it> on a desert island.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>castaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast caution to the wind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>caution</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast light on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast lots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get rid of (something) <vi>The snake <it>casts off</it> [=<it>sheds</it>] its skin.</vi> <vi>They wanted to <it>cast off</it> their fears.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>castoff</dxt> <dxt>cast-off</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to untie the rope that is holding a boat near the land <vi>We decided to <it>cast off</it> and head out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to remove stitches from a knitting needle in a way that does not cause them to become loose <vi>When I finish this row, can you show me how to <it>cast off</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to place stitches on a knitting needle <vi>I was having trouble <it>casting on</it>, but I think I have it now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone or something) to go away <vi>He was <it>cast out</it> of [=expelled from] the tribe.</vi> <vi>They tried to <it>cast out</it> the spirits from the haunted house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast pearls before swine</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pearl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your eye over</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your lot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your mind back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your net wide</dre> <dx>see <dxt>net</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the die is cast</dre> <dx>see <dxt>die</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="count[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">count</hw> <sound><wav>count001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkaʊnt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>counts</if></in> <in><if>count*ed</if></in> <in><if>count*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to add (people or things) together to find the total number <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Count</it> the plates on the table.</vi> <vi>She made sure to <it>count</it> her change.</vi> <vi><it>Count</it> how many fingers I am holding up.</vi> <vi>He <it>counted</it> seven deer in the field.</vi> <vi>When it comes to books, I have <phrase>too many to count</phrase>. [=I have a lot of books]</vi> <vi>She is <phrase>counting calories</phrase>. [=she counts the number of calories in the food she eats so that she won't eat too much]</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She was <it>counting up</it> the money in the envelope.</vi> <vi>All the votes were <it>counted up</it>, and he was the winner.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>There are 10 days left until the end of school, <it>counting</it> from today.</vi> <vi>Keep <it>counting</it> until there are no more left to count.</vi> <vi>Don't interrupt me. I'm <it>counting</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to say numbers in order <vi>Can your daughter <it>count</it> yet?</vi> <vi>The teacher taught the students to <it>count</it> by 10s. [=to say “10, 20, 30, etc.”]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> or <it>up to</it> <vi>My son can <it>count to</it> one hundred.</vi> <vi>He <it>counted up to</it> 10 and then stopped.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to include (someone or something) in a total <vi>She <it>counts</it> [=<it>numbers</it>] several musicians among her friends. [=her friends include musicians]</vi> <vi>There will be 150 people at the wedding, not <it>counting</it> children.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be accepted or allowed officially <vi>There was a penalty on the play, so the goal does not <it>count</it>. [=the goal is not allowed]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to consider or regard (someone or something) in a specified way <vi>I <it>count</it> myself lucky.</vi> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>I don't <it>count</it> him <it>as</it> my friend anymore.</vi> <vi>She was <it>counted as</it> absent from school that day.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be considered or regarded <it>as</it> something <vi>A laptop computer <it>counts as</it> a piece of luggage on the plane.</vi> <vi>The job is so easy that it hardly <it>counts as</it> work. [=it can hardly be considered to be work]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have value or importance <vi>Every vote <it>counts</it>.</vi> <vi>He played well in the play-offs, when it really <it>counted</it>. [=<it>mattered</it>]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>My effort in class has to <it>count for</it> something!</vi> <vi>Her promises don't <it>count for</it> much. [=his promises don't have much value]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to be considered in a specified way when a person or thing is being judged <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His experience <it>counts</it> in his favor. [=his experience is a good thing that is in his favor]</vi> <vi>His lack of experience <it>counts</it> against him.</vi> <vi>A wrong answer on the quiz will not <it>count</it> against [=will not hurt] your final grade.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>counted</it> his lack of job experience against him.</vi> <vi>A wrong answer on the quiz will not be <it>counted</it> against your final grade.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and counting</dre> <def><dt>:with more to come <vi>He is 47 years old <it>and counting</it>.</vi> <vi>They have been in business for 50 years <it>and counting</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to count numbers in a reverse order from higher numbers to lower ones <vi>He <it>counted down</it> from 10 to 1.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count down (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>count (something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay close attention to the number of (days, miles, etc.) that remain until a particular moment or event is reached <vi>He is <it>counting down</it> the days left in the school year. [=he is eagerly looking forward to the end of the school year]</vi> <vi>We were <it>counting down</it> the miles as we approached our destination.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <def><dt>:to count how many people are present at a place <vi>The coach <it>counted heads</it> before the bus left.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>count (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to plan to include (someone) in an activity :to consider (someone) as one of the people who will be doing something <vi>“Do you want to go to the beach with us?” “Yes! <it>Count</it> me <it>in</it>!”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to count numbers that are spaced a certain number apart <vi>The students <it>counted off</it> by twos. [=counted 2, 4, 6, 8, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to list (something) out loud <vi>She <it>counted off</it> all the things she wanted to do.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>count on/upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to trust (someone) :to rely or depend on (someone) to do something <vi>He isn't someone you can <it>count on</it> all the time.</vi> <vi>I am <it>counting on</it> you to help me through this difficult time.</vi> <vi>She is <it>counted on</it> [=<it>trusted</it>] as a leader.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to expect (someone) to do something <vi>I wouldn't <it>count on</it> him to win the match.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to expect (something) to happen <vi>My parents might loan me some money, but I can't <it>count on</it> it.</vi> <vi>She is <it>counting on</it> a big tax refund this year.</vi> <vi>The kids are <it>counting on</it> going to the movies. Don't disappoint them!</vi> <vi>They were not <it>counting on</it> getting a flat tire on the way to the restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>count (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not include (someone) in an activity <vi>If you are looking for people to help you clean the house today, <it>count</it> me <it>out</it>. [=don't include me; I won't be helping you]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count (someone or something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count out (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that (someone or something) cannot win or succeed <vi>Don't <it>count out</it> our team just yet. They could still win.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count the cost</dre> <def><dt>:to feel the bad effects of a mistake, accident, etc. <vi>He was careless and now he's <it>counting the cost</it>. = Now he's <it>counting the cost</it> of his carelessness.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count toward/towards</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>count toward/towards (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count (something) toward/towards (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have value as a credit or payment in relation to (something) <vi>The credits you earned for this class <it>count toward</it> your degree. [=they are added to the total number of credits you have earned for your degree]</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) counted toward/towards</it> <vi>Fifty dollars will <it>be counted towards</it> [=<it>credited to</it>] your next bill.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count your blessings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blessing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count your chickens before they hatch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chicken</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand up and be counted</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>who's counting?</dre> <def><sl>informal + humorous</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not care about how large a number is <vi>Tomorrow's my 80th birthday, but <it>who's counting</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
