<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="begin"> <hw highlight="yes">be*gin</hw> <sound><wav>begin001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈgɪn</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>be*gins</if></in> <in><if>be*gan</if> <sound><wav>begin002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>-ˈgæn</pr> <altpr>bɪˈgæn</altpr></in> <in><if>be*gun</if> <sound><wav>begin003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>-ˈgʌn</pr> <altpr>bɪˈgʌn</altpr></in> <in><if>be*gin*ning</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to do the first part of an action :to start doing something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They will <it>begin</it> construction on the new school soon.</vi> <vi>I got the job and I <it>begin</it> work on Monday!</vi> <vi>She'll <it>begin</it> the lecture at 10.</vi> <vi>He plans to <it>begin</it> the project later this week.</vi> <vi>They both <it>began</it> their careers at the local newspaper.</vi> <vi>The university <it>began</it> accepting applications in November.</vi> <vi>I had just <it>begun</it> eating when the phone rang.</vi> <vi>She interrupted as soon as I <it>began</it> to speak.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>began</it> by showing some photographs of his trip. = He <it>began</it> with some photographs of his trip.</vi> <vi>Now that I've <it>begun</it>, I'll go on till I finish.</vi> <vi>You'll have to <it>begin</it> again. [=start over]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to start to work on, produce, or give attention to (something) <vi>I <it>began</it> the quilt last month.</vi> <vi>I <it>began</it> (reading) the book last week.</vi> <vi>Schubert <it>began</it> more symphonies than he finished.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to start <vi>The chairman <it>began</it> the meeting at noon.</vi> <vi>They <it>began</it> [=<it>founded</it>] the state's first traveling theater troupe.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to start to have a feeling, thought, etc. <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She <it>began to feel</it> dizzy soon after the accident.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>beginning to think</it> the oversight was intentional.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>She <it>began feeling</it> dizzy soon after the accident.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start to happen, to exist, to be done, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The meeting <it>began</it> [=<it>started</it>] in the morning and finished/ended at noon.</vi> <vi>Construction on the new school will <it>begin</it> soon.</vi> <vi>Our problems were just <it>beginning</it>.</vi> <vi>When does the play <it>begin</it>?</vi> <vi>The rain <it>began</it> around noon.</vi> <vi>Let the games <it>begin</it>.</vi> <vi>The American Civil War <it>began</it> in 1861 and ended in 1865.</vi> <vi>His passion for music <it>began</it> at the age of six when he had his first piano lessons.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>It's <it>beginning</it> [=<it>starting</it>] <it>to rain</it>.</vi> <vi>The flowers on the trees are <it>beginning to bloom</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have a particular starting point :to start at a specified place or in a specified way <vi>“Where does the river <it>begin</it>?” “It <it>begins</it> in the mountains to the north.”</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>began</it> on a positive note.</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>began</it> with an announcement. [=an announcement was made at the start of the meeting]</vi> <vi>The English alphabet <it>begins</it> with A and ends with Z.</vi> <vi>Each sentence should <it>begin</it> with a capital.</vi> <vi>The season <it>began</it> with our team in last place but finished (up) with us in first place.</vi> <vi>Her long career in advertising <it>began</it> at a small firm in Chicago.</vi> <vi>Prices for the hotel rooms <it>begin</it> at 85 dollars. [=85 dollars is the lowest price for a hotel room; some rooms cost more than 85 dollars]</vi> <vi>The road <it>begins</it> at the bottom of the hill and ends at the top of the hill.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a specified quality, identity, job, etc., at the start <un><it>+ as</it> <vi>What <it>began</it> [=<it>started</it>] <it>as</it> a simple idea has become a complicated project.</vi> <vi>The town <it>began as</it> a small farming community.</vi> <vi>He <it>began as</it> a clerk [=he was a clerk when he started working] and eventually became president of the company.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to start speaking by saying (something) <vi>“Allow me to introduce myself,” he <it>began</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used in an exaggerated way to say that something is not possible <vi>I <phrase>can't even begin to describe</phrase> how good the food was. [=the food was very good]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>can't begin to tell you</phrase> how grateful I am for all your help. [=I am very grateful for all your help]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>can hardly begin to thank you</phrase> for all you've done.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>to begin with</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:as the first thing to be thought about or considered <vi>“I don't think we should buy the car.” “Why not?” “<it>To begin with</it>, I'm not sure we can afford it.”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:at the start :before the current time or situation <vi>She has lost a lot of weight, and she wasn't very heavy <it>to begin with</it>.</vi> <vi>She didn't like her job <it>to begin with</it>, [=<it>at first, initially</it>] but she got used to it eventually.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
