<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="belong"> <hw highlight="yes">be*long</hw> <sound><wav>belong01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈlɑ:ŋ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>be*longs</if></in> <in><if>be*longed</if></in> <in><if>be*long*ing</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something should be in a particular place or situation <vi>This book <it>belongs</it> [=<it>goes</it>] on the top shelf.</vi> <vi>Put the groceries away where they <it>belong</it>.</vi> <vi>Those kids really <it>belong</it> in school. [=they should be in school]</vi> <vi>Does that item really <it>belong</it> on the list?</vi> <vi>A dictionary <it>belongs</it> in every home. [=every home should have a dictionary]</vi> <vi>A sick person <it>belongs</it> in bed.</vi> <vi>A man with his abilities <it>belongs</it> in teaching. [=he should be a teacher]</vi> <vi>Whales <it>belong</it> among the mammals, not fish. [=whales are mammals, not fish; whales are classified as mammals]</vi> <vi>She and her husband are a perfect couple. They <it>belong</it> together.</vi> <vi>They <it>belong</it> with each other.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be accepted and liked by the other people in a group <vi>She was here for 15 years, but she never really <it>belonged</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>belong to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>belong to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be the property of (someone) :to be owned by (someone) <vi>The money <it>belongs to</it> him. [=the money is his]</vi> <vi>That watch <it>belongs to</it> me.</vi> <vi>The house <it>belongs</it> not just <it>to</it> her, but <it>to</it> her husband as well.</vi> <vi>His style <it>belongs</it> only <it>to</it> himself. [=no one else has his style]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>belong to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be a member of (a club, organization, etc.) <vi>The family <it>belongs to</it> a country club.</vi> <vi>Most of the company's employees <it>belong to</it> an HMO.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be included in (a category, group, etc.) <vi>What family does that bird <it>belong to</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be a part of (something) :to be connected with (something) <vi>the parts <it>belonging to</it> the clock</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>belonging</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>The kindness that they showed to her when she first arrived gave her a real sense/feeling of <it>belonging</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="long[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">long</hw> <altpr>ˈlɑ:ŋ</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>longer</if></in> <in><if>longest</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:for or during a long time :for many years, days, hours, etc. <vi>The extra food she brought did not last <it>long</it>.</vi> <vi>Will he be away (very) <it>long</it>?</vi> <vi>They'll have to wait a bit <it>longer</it>.</vi> <vi>The mall has <it>long</it> been a popular hangout for teenagers.</vi> <vi>They have <it>long</it> been devoted friends.</vi> <vi>It's been so <it>long</it> since we've seen each other.</vi> <vi>It's been much <phrase>too long</phrase> since we've seen each other.</vi> <vi>That meeting was way <it>too long</it>.</vi> <vi>She's been away <phrase>so long</phrase>. [=for such a long time]</vi> <vi>We had to leave <phrase>long before</phrase> we were ready to go.</vi> <vi><phrase>Long live</phrase> the King/Queen! [=may the King/Queen live for many years]</vi> <un>sometimes used in combination <vi>her <phrase>long-awaited</phrase> new novel</vi> <vi>a <phrase>long-anticipated</phrase> announcement</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for a specified period of time <vi>The children played all day <it>long</it>. [=throughout the day]</vi> <vi>We talked all night <it>long</it>.</vi> <vi>all summer/week <it>long</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:at a time far before or after a specified moment or event <vi>events that occurred <phrase>long before</phrase> the discovery of America</vi> <vi>He remembered that day <phrase>long after</phrase> it had faded from her memory.</vi> <vi>The book wasn't published until <it>long after</it> she had died.</vi> <vi>He went to bed at 10 o'clock. Not <it>long after/afterward</it>, the phone rang.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:for a great distance <vi>The quarterback threw the ball <it>long</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as long as</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>so long as</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>since</sx> <vi><it>As long as</it> I'm here, we may as well begin.</vi> <vi><it>As long as</it> you're up, would you mind getting me a drink?</vi> <vi><it>So long as</it> you feel that way I'll leave.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>if</sx> <vi>I'll go with you <it>as long as</it> you'll drive.</vi> <vi>They can do anything they want, <it>so long as</it> they follow the rules.</vi> <vi><it>As long as</it> she's allowed to go first, she's happy.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:during the time that :<sx>while</sx> <vi>The economy will remain strong <it>as long as</it> there are jobs to go around.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be long</dre> <def><dt><un>used to ask how much time will be required or to say that something will take only a short amount of time or will happen soon <vi>“Will you <it>be long</it>?” “No, I'll be ready soon.”</vi> <vi>I'm going out now, but I <phrase>won't be long</phrase>. [=I will return soon]</vi> <vi>“Have you finished yet?” “No, but I <it>won't be long</it>.” [=I will finish soon]</vi> <vi>“Will you <phrase>be much longer</phrase>?” “No, I'm almost ready.”</vi> <vi>We've been waiting since morning, but <phrase>it won't be long now</phrase>. [=what we have been waiting for will happen/come soon]</vi> <vi>It <phrase>can't be much longer</phrase> before they give up. [=they will probably give up soon]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>long ago</dre> <def><dt>:at a time in the distant past <vi>events that happened <it>long ago</it></vi> <vi>The announcement was made <phrase>not long ago</phrase>. [=the announcement was made recently]</vi> <vi>It wasn't so/very <it>long ago</it> that this place was empty field.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>long gone</dre> <def><dt>:having ended, died, disappeared, etc., at a distant time in the past <vi>Those buildings are <it>long gone</it> now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>long since</dre> <def><dt>:at a time in the distant past :long ago <vi>questions that have <it>long since</it> been answered [=questions that were answered long ago]</vi> <vi>an animal that has <it>long since</it> disappeared from this region</vi> <vi>I <it>long since</it> gave up trying to change her mind.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no longer</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>not any longer</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that something that was once true or possible is not now true or possible <vi>They could wait <it>no longer</it>. = They couldn't wait <it>any longer</it>. [=it was not possible for them to continue waiting]</vi> <vi>I can <it>no longer</it> afford the car. [=I could afford the car at some time in the past but I cannot afford it now]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>so long</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>goodbye</sx> <vi><it>So long</it> (for now)! Have a safe journey home!</vi> <vi>She said <it>so long</it> to her friends and family and headed off to college.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>the time of year when we say <it>so long</it> to winter coats [=when we stop wearing winter coats]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take long</dre> <def><dt>:to require a large amount of time <vi>It won't <it>take long</it> to make dinner.</vi> <vi>This is <it>taking longer</it> than I thought (it would).</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
