<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="benefit[1]"> <hw hindex="1">ben*e*fit</hw> <sound><wav>benefi11.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛnəˌfɪt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ben*e*fits</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a good or helpful result or effect <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>the <it>benefits</it> of fresh air and sunshine</vi> <vi>A <it>benefit</it> of museum membership is that purchases are discounted.</vi> <vi>There are many financial <it>benefits</it> to owning your own home.</vi> <vi>She is just now starting to reap/enjoy the <it>benefits</it> of all her hard work.</vi> <vi>The <it>benefits</it> of taking the drug outweigh its risks.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I see no <it>benefit</it> in changing the system now.</vi> <vi>We're lucky to be able to get the full <it>benefit</it> of/from her knowledge.</vi> <vi>These changes will be <phrase>of benefit to</phrase> all of you. [=will help/benefit all of you]</vi> <vi>These changes will be <phrase>to your benefit</phrase>. [=will help you]</vi> <vi>I'm not doing it for myself; I'm doing it <phrase>for your benefit</phrase>. [=to help you; for your sake]</vi> <vi>Since he owns the land, he thinks he should be free to use it <phrase>for his own benefit</phrase>. [=in a way that is helpful to him]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:money that is paid by a company (such as an insurance company) or by a government when someone dies, becomes sick, stops working, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He began collecting his retirement <it>benefits</it> when he was 65.</vi> <vi>a disability <it>benefit</it></vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a family <phrase>on benefits</phrase> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>on welfare</it>; receiving money from the government because of a low income or lack of income]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He began collecting his retirement <it>benefit</it> when he was 65.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) He is on housing/unemployment <it>benefit</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>child benefit</dxt> <dxt>death benefit</dxt> <dxt>sickness benefit</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something extra (such as vacation time or health insurance) that is given by an employer to workers in addition to their regular pay :<sx>fringe benefit</sx> <vi>The company provides health (insurance) <it>benefits</it>.</vi> <vi>The job doesn't pay much, but the <it>benefits</it> are good.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a company with a good <it>benefit</it> plan/package/program</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a social event to raise money for a person or cause <vi>The school is having/holding a <it>benefit</it> to raise money for a new gymnasium.</vi> <vi>a charity <it>benefit</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>benefit</it> concert/dinner/event/performance</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>have the benefit of</dre> <def><dt>:to be helped by (something) :to be able to use (something) <vi>Her judgment will be better when she <it>has the benefit of</it> more experience.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the benefit of the doubt</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people give you <it>the benefit of the doubt</it>, they treat you as someone who is honest or deserving of trust even though they are not sure that you really are. <vi>He might be lying, but we have to give him <it>the benefit of the doubt</it> and accept what he says for now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>without the benefit of</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>without benefit of</va></vr> <def><dt>:without the help of (something or someone) <vi>The band had to perform <it>without benefit of</it> a rehearsal.</vi> <vi>He was able to learn a great deal <it>without the benefit of</it> formal schooling.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't try to handle this problem <it>without benefit of</it> a lawyer.</vi> <vi>They lived together <phrase>without (the) benefit of marriage</phrase>. [=without being married]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with the benefit of</dre> <def><dt>:with the help of (something) :by using (something) <vi><it>With the benefit of</it> hindsight, he saw where he had made a mistake.</vi> <vi>She'll do better <it>with the benefit of</it> more experience.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="benefit[2]"> <hw hindex="2">benefit</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛnəˌfɪt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>benefits</if></in> <in><if>benefit*ed</if> <il>also</il> <if>benefit*ted</if></in> <in><if>benefit*ing</if> <il>also</il> <if>benefit*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be useful or helpful to (someone or something) <vi>The new plan may <it>benefit</it> many students.</vi> <vi>medicines that <it>benefit</it> thousands of people</vi> <vi>These changes will <it>benefit</it> all of you. = All of you will be <it>benefited</it> by these changes.</vi> <vi>The politician held a fund-raiser to <it>benefit</it> his campaign.</vi> <vi>Some critics say that the tax cuts only <it>benefit</it> wealthy people.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be helped <vi>He'll <it>benefit</it> by having experiences I never did.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>I <it>benefited from</it> the experience.</vi> <vi>Many patients will <it>benefit from</it> the new drug.</vi> <vi>All of you will <it>benefit from</it> these changes.</vi> <vi>Some critics say that only wealthy people will <it>benefit from</it> the tax cuts.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="child benefit"> <hw>child benefit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -fits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:money that the government pays to families with children</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cost-benefit"> <hw>cost–ben*e*fit</hw> <sound><wav>cost_b01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:stˈbɛnəˌfɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>business</sl> <dt>:of or relating to the study of how much money a company earns compared to how much money it spends <vi><it>cost-benefit</it> analysis</vi> <vi><it>cost-benefit</it> calculations</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="death benefit"> <hw>death benefit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -fits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:money that an insurance company pays to the family of someone who has died because that person had life insurance</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="fringe benefit"> <hw>fringe benefit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -fits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something extra (such as vacation time) that is given by an employer to workers in addition to their regular pay</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sickness benefit"> <hw>sickness benefit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:money that is paid by the government to someone who is too sick to work</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="doubt[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">doubt</hw> <altpr>ˈdaʊt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>doubts</if></in> <def><dt>:a feeling of being uncertain or unsure about something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I still have moments of <it>doubt</it>.</vi> <vi>There can be little <it>doubt</it> that smoking is bad for your health.</vi> <vi>There is no <it>doubt</it> [=<it>question</it>] in my mind that he is best candidate.</vi> <vi>These mistakes <phrase>cast/throw doubt on</phrase> her ability. = They <phrase>cast/throw into doubt</phrase> her ability. [=they make people question or lose confidence in her ability]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) The results of the study have been <phrase>called into doubt</phrase>. [=people are expressing doubts about the results]</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>She was filled with <it>doubt</it> [=<it>uncertainty</it>] <it>about</it> the future.</vi> <vi>The evidence against her leaves little room for <it>doubt about</it> her guilt. [=the evidence shows that she is guilty]</vi></un> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I had a nagging <it>doubt</it> in the back of my mind.</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>He still has <it>doubts about</it> his chances of success.</vi> <vi>I've always had my <it>doubts about</it> him.</vi> <vi>Two separate studies have <phrase>raised doubts about</phrase> the car's safety.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>beyond doubt</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>beyond doubt</it>, it is definitely true. <vi>The test results proved <it>beyond</it> (all/any) <it>doubt</it> that he was not the child's father.</vi> <vi>If she is to be found guilty, the charges against her must be proved <phrase>beyond a reasonable doubt</phrase>.</vi> <vi>I knew, <phrase>beyond a shadow of a doubt</phrase>, that everything was going to be okay.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in doubt</dre> <def><dt>:in a state of being uncertain or unsure <vi>The outcome was <it>in doubt</it> [=not known with certainty] until the final seconds of the game.</vi> <vi>The future of the company remains very much <it>in doubt</it>.</vi> <vi>When/if <it>in doubt</it>, please contact us with your questions.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no doubt</dre> <def><dt>:without doubt or with very little doubt <un>used when you are making a statement that you think is certainly or almost certainly true <vi>She was <it>no doubt</it> [=<it>certainly</it>, <it>doubtless</it>, <it>unquestionably</it>] the smartest person in her class.</vi> <vi><it>No doubt</it> many readers will find the book too long.</vi> <vi>By now, you have <it>no doubt</it> heard the news.</vi> <vi>“He'll probably blame someone else.” “<it>No doubt</it>.” [=I agree that he'll blame someone else]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no doubt about it</dre> <def><dt><un>used to stress that something is true <vi><it>No doubt about it</it>, the fans are disappointed in the team.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the benefit of the doubt</dre> <dx>see <dxt>benefit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>without (a) doubt</dre> <def><dt><un>used to stress that something is true <vi>They are, <it>without doubt</it>, the nicest people I've ever met.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
