<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bet[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bet</hw> <sound><wav>bet00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bets</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an agreement in which people try to guess what will happen and the person who guesses wrong has to give something (such as money) to the person who guesses right <vi>He has a <it>bet</it> on the game.</vi> <vi>“I'll bet five dollars that my team will beat your team.” “Okay. It's a <it>bet</it>!” [=I agree to the bet]</vi> <vi>He made a <it>bet</it> with his brother that he could finish his chores first.</vi> <vi>He and his brother have a <it>bet</it> about who can finish his chores first.</vi> <vi>He lost the <it>bet</it> and had to pay his brother five dollars.</vi> <vi>His brother won the <it>bet</it>.</vi> <vi>He paid his brother five dollars to <phrase>settle the bet</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the money or other valuable thing that you could win or lose in a bet <vi>What's your <it>bet</it>? [=how much money do you want to risk?]</vi> <vi>She placed/laid a $10 <it>bet</it> [=<it>wager</it>] on the number five horse.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a choice made by thinking about what will probably happen <vi>It's <phrase>a good/safe/sure bet</phrase> that they'll win. [=it is very likely that they will win]</vi> <vi>I don't know what their decision will be, but <phrase>my bet is</phrase> that they'll approve the project. [=I think they'll approve the project]</vi> <vi>If you want to get there early, your <phrase>best/surest/safest bet</phrase> is to take a different road. [=you are most likely to get there early if you take a different road]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all bets are off</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe a situation in which it is impossible to be sure about what will happen <vi><it>All bets are off</it> on the election: it's too close to call.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hedge your bets</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hedge</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bet[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bet</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bets</if></in> <in><if>bet</if> <il>also</il> <if>bet*ted</if></in> <in><if>bet*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a bet :to risk losing something (such as money) if your guess about what will happen is wrong <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bet</it> $5 on the game.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>bet</it> (you) a dollar that he makes the next shot.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>bet</it> that he makes the next shot.</vi> <vi>He always <it>bets</it> that the favorite will win.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He lost a lot of money by <phrase>betting on</phrase> college football and basketball.</vi> <vi>He always <it>bets on</it> the favorite (to win).</vi> <vi>I <phrase>bet against</phrase> the favorite and I lost.</vi> <vi>I wouldn't <it>bet against</it> her. She's very likely to win this race.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to risk losing (something) when you try to do or achieve something <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>She's willing to <it>bet</it> [=<it>gamble</it>, <it>risk</it>, <it>stake</it>] everything <it>on</it> winning this election.</vi> <vi>(<it>US, informal</it>) They want to start their own restaurant, but they're not willing to <phrase>bet the farm on it</phrase>. [=they're not willing to risk losing everything they have]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make decisions that are based on the belief that something will happen or is true <vi>Carmakers are <it>betting</it> that people will want to buy larger, more expensive cars this year.</vi> <vi>We're <it>betting</it> (that) the price of houses will drop.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to think that something will probably or certainly happen <vi>I <it>bet</it> (that) it'll rain tomorrow. [=I think it'll rain tomorrow]</vi> <vi>You can <it>bet</it> (that) he'll take the money. [=you can be sure that he'll take the money]</vi> <vi>She says she'll quit her job, but I <it>bet</it> (you) she doesn't do it. [=I don't believe that she'll do it]</vi> :to think that something is probably or certainly true <vi>I'd <it>bet</it> most people feel the same way.</vi> <vi>I <it>bet</it> you that no one knows we're here.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>bet</it> you've never seen one of these before. [=you've probably never seen one of these before]</vi> <vi>I <it>bet</it> you were tired by the end of the trip. [=you must have been tired]</vi> <vi>“He was so handsome in his new suit.” “<phrase>I bet</phrase> he was.” = “<phrase>I'll bet</phrase> he was.” [=I'm sure he was]</vi> <snote>If you would <phrase>bet your life</phrase> or <phrase>bet your bottom dollar</phrase> that something will happen or that something is true, you are very sure about it. <vi>“Are you sure he'll be there?” “Yes, I'd <it>bet my life</it> on it.” [=I am entirely sure]</vi> <vi>You can <it>bet your bottom dollar</it> he's going to be late! [=you can be sure he's going to be late]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>you bet</phrase>, <phrase>you can bet on it</phrase>, and <phrase>you bet your life</phrase> as an enthusiastic way of saying “yes” <vi>“Would you like some cake?” “<it>You bet</it>!”</vi> <vi>“Are you going to be there?” “<it>You bet</it> I'll be there!” [=I'll certainly be there]</vi> <vi>“Are you going to be there?” “<it>You can bet on it</it>!”</vi> <vi>“Will you be there?” “<it>You bet your life</it> I will!”</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>betcha</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases that express doubt about what will happen <vi>“The economy will improve next year.” “<phrase>I wouldn't bet on it</phrase> if I were you.” [=I'm doubtful that the economy will improve next year]</vi> <vi>“The weather will be better tomorrow.” “<phrase>Don't bet on it</phrase>!”</vi> <vi>“The weather will be better tomorrow.” “<phrase>Do you want to bet</phrase>?” = “<phrase>Wanna bet</phrase>?” [=I don't think that the weather will be better tomorrow]</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>betting</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>I'm not a <it>betting</it> man myself. [=I'm not a man who likes to bet]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>betting</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>No <it>betting</it> [=<it>gambling</it>] is allowed in this state.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) The <it>betting</it> is that she'll win the election. [=most people think that she'll win the election]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bottom[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bottom</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:təm</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the lowest position <vi>the <it>bottom</it> rung of the ladder</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> drawer/shelf</vi> <vi>her <it>bottom</it> lip</vi> <vi>Somebody's fingerprints are all along the <it>bottom</it> edge of the photograph.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottom line</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:living at the lowest level of an ocean or lake <vi><it>bottom</it> fish</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bet your bottom dollar</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bet</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="dollar"> <hw highlight="yes">dol*lar</hw> <sound><wav>dollar01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɑ:lɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>dol*lars</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a basic unit of money in the U.S., Canada, Australia, and other countries that is equal to 100 cents <vi>The shirt costs 20 <it>dollars</it>. [=$20]</vi> <vi>She had to pay hundreds of <it>dollars</it> in auto repairs.</vi> <vi>The property is worth a million <it>dollars</it>. = It's a million-<it>dollar</it> property.</vi> <vi>Do you have a 20-<it>dollar bill</it>? [=a twenty]</vi> <vi>It costs 500 pesos. How much is that <phrase>in dollars</phrase>? [=how many dollars equals 500 pesos?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a bill or coin that is worth one dollar <vi>I found a <it>dollar</it> on the sidewalk. = I found a <phrase>dollar bill</phrase> on the sidewalk.</vi> <vi>She put a wrinkled <it>dollar</it> down on the counter.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>half-dollar</dxt> <dxt>top dollar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the dollar</bnote> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:the value of a dollar when it is compared to another unit of money <vi><it>The dollar</it> dropped sharply against the pound.</vi> <vi>the strength/weakness of <it>the dollar</it></vi> <vi><it>The dollar</it> is worth more in Mexico.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:money that is from a specified source or used for a specified purpose <vi>You want to know how the state spends every federal <it>dollar</it> [=money from the federal government] it receives?</vi> <un>usually plural <vi>Should a program like this be paid for with tax/taxpayer <it>dollars</it>? [=with money the government collects through taxes]</vi> <vi>tourist/tourism <it>dollars</it> [=money that an economy gets because of the money tourists spend there]</vi> <vi>The company needs to invest its advertising <it>dollars</it> wisely.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bet your bottom dollar</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look/feel like a million dollars</dre> <dx>see <dxt>million</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>sand dollar</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="life[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">life</hw> <sound><wav>life0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪf</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>lives</if> <sound><wav>life0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪvz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to grow, change, etc., that separates plants and animals from things like water or rocks <vi>He believes that God gives <it>life</it> to all creatures.</vi> <vi>the miracle of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>eternal/everlasting <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the period of time when a person is alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She knew what she wanted to do <phrase>early in life</phrase>. [=when she was young]</vi> <vi>He became famous relatively <phrase>late in life</phrase>. [=at a relatively old age]</vi> <vi>He became famous <phrase>later in life</phrase>. = He became famous <phrase>in later life</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She was happy and healthy for most of her <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>The people in her family tend to have long/short <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her all my <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>He is nearing the end of his <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>They spent their whole/entire <it>lives</it> in one town. = They lived in one town all their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>People can expect to change jobs several times in their <it>life/lives</it>.</vi> <vi>They've been waiting their whole/entire <it>life/lives</it> for an opportunity like this.</vi> <vi>This is the financial opportunity <phrase>of his life</phrase>. [=<it>of his lifetime</it>; the best chance in his life to make money]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the experience of being alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want out of <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>He believes in living <it>life</it> to the fullest. [=in living a very full and rich life]</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>The details of everyday/ordinary <it>life</it> can be fascinating.</vi> <vi><it>life</it> in the city/country = city/country <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Sometimes <it>life</it> just isn't fair.</vi> <vi>We can laugh at things in movies that would scare us in <phrase>real life</phrase>. [=in a real situation; in actual existence]</vi> <vi>Oh well, <phrase>that's life</phrase>! [=bad things will happen, and you have to deal with them]</vi> <vi>Despite the political upheaval, for most people <phrase>life goes on</phrase> as usual. [=the activities of life continue in the usual way]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want to do with your <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>Her children say that she has ruined their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>She talked about the men in her <it>life</it>. [=the men she has had a romantic or close relationship with during her life]</vi> <vi>She has dedicated/devoted <it>her life</it> to helping other people.</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made my <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>They're trying to <phrase>get/put their lives back together</phrase>. [=to begin living in a normal way after suffering loss, hardship, etc.]</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>the love of my life</phrase>. [=the person I loved more than any other person at any time in my life]</vi> <vi>I've never heard such a silly idea <phrase>in all my life</phrase>! [=at any time] = Never <phrase>in my life</phrase> have I heard such a silly idea!</vi> <vi>They're old enough to <phrase>run/live their own lives</phrase>. [=to make their own decisions about how to live]</vi> <vi>After all the problems they've had recently, they just want to <phrase>get/move on with their lives</phrase>. [=to continue living their lives in the usual way]</vi> <vi>I'm not surprised that I didn't get the job. That's <phrase>the story of my life</phrase>. [=that's the way things usually or always happen in my life]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>She told us her <phrase>life story</phrase>. [=she told us about many of the things that had happened to her in her life]</vi> <vi>a lack of <phrase>life experience</phrase> [=experience and knowledge gained through living]</vi></un> <snote>If your <phrase>life flashes/passes before your eyes</phrase> or if your <phrase>life flashes/passes before you</phrase>, many memories from different parts of your life quickly appear in your mind one after the other. <vi>Her <it>life flashed before her eyes</it> when her car was about to crash.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a specified part of a person's life <vi>He talked about his <it>life</it> as an artist.</vi> <vi>the social <it>lives</it> of college students</vi> <vi>How's your love/sex <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>They had difficult home <it>lives</it> when they were children.</vi> <vi>They are trying to keep their personal/private <it>lives</it> separate from their public <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>the responsibilities of their family <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a specified way or manner of living <vi>He lived/led a <it>life</it> of crime. [=he was a criminal]</vi> <vi>They have lived/led sheltered <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>He is trying to make a better <it>life</it> for himself and his family.</vi> <snote>Your <phrase>way of life</phrase> is how you live your life. <vi>a fisherman's <it>way of life</it></vi> <vi>Most people don't approve of my <it>way of life</it>.</vi> <vi>a traditional <it>way of life</it></vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition of being alive <vi>They spared the horse's <it>life</it>. [=they did not kill the horse]</vi> <vi>She feels that her <it>life</it> is in danger. = She <phrase>fears for her life</phrase>. = She is <phrase>in fear for her life</phrase>. [=she feels that she is in danger of being killed]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>risked her life</phrase> [=she did something very dangerous that could have resulted in her death] to help him.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>gave/sacrificed her life</phrase> [=she did something that resulted in her death] for her country.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>running for his life</phrase>. [=he was running to escape from great danger]</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>fighting for his life</phrase>. [=he is very sick or injured and may die]</vi> <vi>A would-be assassin <phrase>made an attempt on the President's life</phrase>. [=tried to kill the President]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:living things of a specified kind or in a specified place <vi>There may be a great deal of animal/plant <it>life</it> still to be discovered in this region.</vi> <vi>forest <it>life</it></vi> <vi>ocean <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Will we ever find intelligent <it>life</it> on other planets?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the time when something can be used :the period when something exists or is useful or effective <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>battery <it>life</it></vi> <vi>the <it>life</it> of an insurance policy</vi> <vi>They claim that using their product will extend the <it>life</it> of the car.</vi> <vi>a warranty that is good for the <it>life</it> of the product</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a product that extends the <it>lives</it> of the rugs/cars</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>half-life</dxt> <dxt>shelf life</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:energy and spirit <vi>eyes full of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) suck the <it>life</it> out of a room [=take all the fun and energy out of a group of people in a room]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:activity and movement <vi>The streets were humming with <it>life</it>. [=the streets were filled with people and activity]</vi> <vi>There were no signs of <it>life</it> in the deserted village.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a book that tells about the life of a person :<sx>biography</sx> <vi>She wrote a <it>life</it> of Napoleon.</vi> <vi>Boswell's <it>Life of Johnson</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the punishment of being kept in a prison for the rest of your life :<sx>life imprisonment</sx> <vi>He was found guilty and sentenced to <it>life</it>. = (<it>informal</it>) He got <it>life</it>. = He was given <it>life</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a dog's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a life of its own</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <phrase>takes on a life of its own</phrase> becomes very large, important, or hard to control. <vi>The project soon <it>took on a life of its own</it> and prevented us from getting any other work done.</vi> <vi>The story <it>took on a life of its own</it> and began to appear on news broadcasts everywhere.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all walks of life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>every walk of life</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>walk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a matter of life and death</dre> <def><dt>:something that is extremely important and often involves decisions that will determine whether someone lives or dies <vi>Being prepared for severe weather can be <it>a matter of life and death</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>life-and-death</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a new lease on/of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lease</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(as) big as life</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) large as life</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in person <un>used to describe the surprise of seeing someone <vi>I never expected her to come to the party, but there she was, <it>as big as life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bet/stake your life on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you would <it>bet/stake your life on</it> something, you are very sure that it will happen. <vi>“Will she keep her promise?” “I'd <it>bet/stake my life on</it> it!”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe (new) life into</dre> <def><dt>:to give new energy and excitement to (something) <vi>She is credited with <it>breathing new life into</it> contemporary art.</vi> <vi>The singer managed to <it>breathe life into</it> some tired old songs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring someone or something back to life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone or something that has died to begin living again <vi>The story is about a mad scientist who tries to <it>bring</it> dead people <it>back to life</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>They're trying to <it>bring</it> the restaurant <it>back to life</it> by introducing a new menu.</vi> <vi>an old theory that is <it>being brought back to life</it></vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring something to life</dre> <def><dt>:to make something very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>She <it>brings</it> history <it>to life</it> with her books.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to life</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>The movie really <it>comes to life</it> when she appears on the screen.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a place</ssl> <dt>:to become filled with the energy and excitement of active people <vi>Downtown <it>comes to life</it> each night when the clubs open.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>sputter/roar (etc.) to life</va></svr> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to begin working <vi>The engine suddenly <it>roared to life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>depart this life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>depart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for dear life</dre> <def><dt>:very tightly or quickly because of fear or danger <vi>He was hanging/holding on to the rope <it>for dear life</it>.</vi> <vi>They were running <it>for dear life</it> to get away from the vicious dogs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for life</dre> <def><dt>:for the whole of your life :for the rest of your life <vi>They met in college and have remained friends <it>for life</it>.</vi> <vi>He was sentenced to prison <it>for life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for the life of me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in any way at all <un>used to say that you are unable to remember or understand something <vi>I couldn't <it>for the life of me</it> remember what her name was.</vi> <vi><it>For the life of me</it>, I can't think of any reasons why you wouldn't want a computer at home.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>frighten/scare the life out of</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to frighten (someone) very badly <vi>You (nearly) <it>scared the life out of</it> me when you startled me like that!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from life</dre> <def><sl>of a painting, drawing, etc.</sl> <dt>:from looking at an actual person, object, etc. <vi>drawings done <it>from life</it> rather than from photographs</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get a life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop spending time doing or thinking about things that are not important or interesting :to begin to have a more interesting or exciting life <vi>My girlfriend's parents are nice people, but all they do is watch TV all day. They need to <it>get a life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>larger than life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>large</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay down your life</dre> <dx>see <tag>lay down</tag> at <dxt>lay</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>life depends on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If your <it>life depends on</it> something, then you must do it. <vi>His <it>life depends on</it> how he answers this question.</vi> <vi>He was studying as if his <it>life depended on</it> it.</vi></snote> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>I wouldn't eat that food if my <it>life depended on</it> it. [=I would never eat it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose your life</dre> <def><dt>:to die <vi>She nearly <it>lost her life</it> in a car accident.</vi> <vi>Many <it>lives were lost</it>. [=many people died]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>new life</dre> <def><dt><snote>When something <phrase>takes on (a) new life</phrase> or when you <phrase>give something new life</phrase> or <phrase>give new life to something</phrase>, it becomes more active, interesting, etc. <vi>Plain old mashed potatoes <it>take on a new life</it> in this recipe.</vi> <vi>Falling interest rates <it>gave new life to</it> the housing market.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not on your life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a very forceful way of saying “no” or “never” <vi>Do the government's policies really help the average worker? <it>Not on your life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>risk life and limb</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that is very dangerous <vi>They <it>risked life and limb</it> to pull the child from the river.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>spring into/to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spring</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>staff of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>staff</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>such is life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>such</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take/claim someone's life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's death <vi>Two years ago he was diagnosed with the illness that eventually <it>took his life</it>.</vi> <vi>The flood <it>claimed many lives</it>. [=caused the deaths of many people]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your own life</dre> <def><dt>:to kill yourself <vi>He threatened to <it>take his own life</it> [=<it>commit suicide</it>], but no one believed him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the life of the party</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>the life and soul of the party</va></vr> <def><dt>:someone who is very lively and amusing at a party or other social gathering</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the light of your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the next life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the life to come</va></vr> <def><dt>:a life that is believed by some people to come after death <vi>He believed that he would see his family again in <it>the next life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the simple life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>simple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to save your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>true to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>true</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>fact of life</dxt> <dxt>good life</dxt> <dxt>slice-of-life</dxt> <dxt>still life</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
