<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="between[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">be*tween</hw> <sound><wav>betwee01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈtwi:n</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the space that separates (two things or people) <vi>The ball rolled <it>between</it> the desk and the wall.</vi> <vi>He stood <it>between</it> his mother and his father.</vi> <vi>The office has two desks with a table <it>between</it> them.</vi> <vi>They put up a fence <it>between</it> their house and their neighbor's house.</vi> <vi>There are fences <it>between</it> all the houses.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>a book that blurs the line/boundary <it>between</it> fact and fiction</vi></un> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>in between</phrase> <vi>There are fences <it>in between</it> all the houses.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in the time that separates (two actions, events, etc.) <vi>If you want to lose weight, you shouldn't eat <it>between</it> meals.</vi> <vi><it>Between</it> bites of food, they talked to their teacher.</vi> <vi>The two days <it>between</it> Monday and Thursday are Tuesday and Wednesday.</vi> <vi>We should arrive <it>between</it> 9 and 10 o'clock.</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>in between</phrase> <vi>You shouldn't eat <it>in between</it> meals.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the beginning and ending points of a group of numbers, a range of measurement, etc. <vi>a number <it>between</it> 1 and 20</vi> <vi>The package weighs somewhere <it>between</it> a pound and a pound and a half.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in the phrase <phrase>in between</phrase> <vi>a number <it>in between</it> 1 and 20</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:in shares to each of (two or more people) <vi>The property was divided equally <it>between</it> the son and the daughter. [=the son and the daughter received an equal share of the property]</vi> <vi>His estate was divided <it>between</it> [=<it>among</it>] his four grandchildren.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate two or more people or things that together produce a result or have an effect <vi>She ate two hot dogs, and he ate three hot dogs, so <it>between</it> them they ate five hot dogs.</vi> <vi><it>Between</it> work and family life, she has no time for hobbies. [=because of all the time she spends on her work and family life, she has no time for hobbies]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate two people or teams that are involved in a game, activity, etc. <vi>There's a game tonight <it>between</it> the Red Sox and the Yankees. [=the Red Sox are playing a game against the Yankees tonight]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate two or more people or things that are joined, related, or connected in some way <vi>There are many relations/connections <it>between</it> linguistics, philosophy, and psychology.</vi> <vi>There is a passageway <it>between</it> the two rooms.</vi> <vi>the bond <it>between</it> friends</vi> <vi>We used to love each other, but there's nothing <it>between</it> us now. [=we don't love each other now]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate two or more people or things that are being considered, compared, etc. <vi>They compared the cars but found few differences <it>between</it> them.</vi> <vi>We were allowed to choose <it>between</it> two/several options.</vi> <vi>There's not much to choose <it>between</it> the two cars. [=the two cars are very similar]</vi> <vi>There is very little difference <it>between</it> the two cars.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate movement from one place to another place <vi>He flies <it>between</it> Miami and Chicago twice a week.</vi> <vi>The airline provides service <it>between</it> New York and Paris.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:known only by (two people) <vi>They shared a secret <it>between</it> them.</vi> <vi>(Just) <phrase>Between you and me</phrase>, I think he's wrong. [=I'm telling you that I think he's wrong, but you should not tell anyone else what I've told you]</vi> <vi>What I'm going to tell you should remain a secret (just) <phrase>between us/ourselves</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="between[2]"> <hw hindex="2">between</hw> <altpr>bɪˈtwi:n</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:in the space separating two things or people <vi>The office has two desks with a table <it>between</it>.</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>in between</phrase> <vi>The office has two desks with a table <it>in between</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>betwixt and between</dre> <dx>see <dxt>betwixt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>few and far between</dre> <dx>see <dxt>few</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="devil"> <hw>dev*il</hw> <sound><wav>devil001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛvl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>dev*ils</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <bnote>the Devil</bnote> <dt>:the most powerful spirit of evil in Christianity, Judaism, and Islam who is often represented as the ruler of hell <vi>He went to the Halloween party dressed up as <it>the Devil</it>. [=<it>Satan</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an evil spirit <vi>an imaginary world haunted by ghosts and <it>devils</it> [=<it>demons</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who does bad things or causes trouble usually in a way that is not too serious <vi>She is a tricky <it>devil</it>, so be careful.</vi> <vi>Those kids can be little <it>devils</it> sometimes.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person (especially a man) who is lucky, unlucky, etc. <vi>The <phrase>poor devil</phrase> [=<it>poor guy</it>] broke his leg on the first day of his skiing vacation.</vi> <vi>He's such a <phrase>lucky devil</phrase> that he'll probably win the lottery someday.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the devil</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>What <it>the devil</it> are you talking about?</vi> <vi>Where <it>the devil</it> have you been?</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:something that is very difficult or that causes a lot of trouble <vi>The shoes look great, but they're <phrase>the devil</phrase> to walk in. [=they are very difficult to walk in]</vi> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>a devil of</phrase> <vi>The new regulations have created <it>a devil of</it> a problem [=a very difficult problem] for many small businesses.</vi> <vi>He had <phrase>a devil of a time</phrase> getting another job. [=he found it very difficult to get another job]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>the devil to pay</tag> at <dxt>pay</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>be a devil</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell someone who is not sure about doing something to go ahead and do it <vi>“I don't know if I should eat anything else.” “Oh, go on, <it>be a devil</it>, order dessert!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>better the devil you know than the devil you don't</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is better to deal with a difficult person or situation you know than with a new person or situation that could be worse</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>between the devil and the deep blue sea</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:in a situation that is difficult because you must choose between two unpleasant things <vi>She felt caught <it>between the devil and the deep blue sea</it>. [=in a very bad situation]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to the devil</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to forcefully and rudely tell someone to go away and leave you alone <vi>She angrily told him to <it>go to the devil</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>go to hell</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>like the devil</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:very much <vi>I'm sorry to hear about your injury. It must hurt <it>like the devil</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:with a lot of energy and speed <vi>He ran <it>like the devil</it>. [=he ran very fast]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>speak/talk of the devil</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used in speech to say that someone you have been talking about has unexpectedly appeared <vi>“Well, <it>speak of the devil</it>! We were just talking about you!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="hard[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">hard</hw> <sound><wav>hard0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>hard*er</if></in> <in><if>hard*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:very firm or solid :not easy to bend, cut, etc. :not soft <vi><it>hard</it> ground</vi> <vi>a <it>hard</it> bench/floor/shell</vi> <vi><it>hard</it> cheese/rubber</vi> <vi>This bread is (as) <phrase>hard as a rock</phrase>. [=very hard]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:physically or mentally difficult :not easy <vi>That test was <it>hard</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>hard</it> task</vi> <vi><it>hard</it> work</vi> <vi>She was asked a lot of <it>hard</it> questions.</vi> <vi>We're going to have to make some <it>hard</it> choices/decisions.</vi> <vi>It's <it>hard</it> to solve this problem. = This is a <it>hard</it> problem (to solve). = This problem is <it>hard</it> (to solve).</vi> <vi>He's a <it>hard</it> guy to figure out. = He's a guy who's <it>hard</it> to figure out. = It's <it>hard</it> to figure that guy out.</vi> <vi>It was very <it>hard</it> to find a replacement for her.</vi> <vi>Their story is <it>hard</it> to believe.</vi> <vi>It's <it>hard</it> not to worry about her.</vi> <vi>It's <it>hard</it> to tell/know what she's thinking.</vi> <vi>He was sentenced to five years of <phrase>hard labor</phrase>. [=time in prison spent in intense physical labor]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:difficult to experience :severe or harsh <vi>He has learned a <it>hard</it> lesson.</vi> <vi>It's been a <it>hard</it> winter. [=a very cold winter with harsh weather]</vi> :having a lot of pain, trouble, or worries <vi>She has had a very <it>hard</it> life. = Life has been very <it>hard</it> for her.</vi> <vi>I had a <it>hard</it> [=<it>tough</it>] day at the office.</vi> <vi>We've been having some <it>hard</it> [=<it>poor, bad</it>] luck.</vi> <snote><phrase>Hard times</phrase> are times when there is a lot of trouble, poverty, worry, or failure. <vi>She's stuck with them through all the <it>hard times</it>.</vi> <vi>The region has been experiencing some economic <it>hard times</it>.</vi> <vi>After years of success, their business has <phrase>fallen on hard times</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a harmful or destructive effect <vi>His health has suffered from years of <it>hard</it> living.</vi> <vi>This old bicycle has obviously gotten some <it>hard</it> use.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:working or doing something with a lot of energy <vi>She's a <it>hard</it> [=<it>diligent, energetic</it>] worker.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:very forceful <vi>The plane made a <it>hard</it> [=<it>jarring</it>] landing.</vi> <vi>He hit a <it>hard</it> line drive past the shortstop.</vi> <vi>A <it>hard</it> rain was falling.</vi> <vi>He was knocked out by a <it>hard</it> right to the jaw.</vi> :quick and forceful <vi><it>hard</it> acceleration</vi> <vi><it>hard</it> braking</vi> <vi>a <it>hard</it> left turn</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:done with a lot of careful thought and attention :thorough or intense <vi>The jeweler gave the gem a long <it>hard</it> look. [=the jeweler looked at the gem very closely and carefully]</vi> <vi>Investors are taking a very <it>hard</it> look at how the company does business.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:able to be clearly seen and measured :not able to be questioned or doubted <vi>Those are the (cold) <it>hard</it> facts of the case.</vi> <vi>She is still collecting <it>hard</it> data on the software's performance.</vi> <vi>It's an interesting theory, but there is no <it>hard</it> evidence that supports it.</vi></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:not seeming to care about other people or to feel kindness or affection <vi>He's a <it>hard</it> man.</vi> <vi>a <it>hard</it> taskmaster</vi> <vi>She has an extremely <it>hard</it> [=<it>unfeeling</it>] heart.</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>as hard as nails</phrase>. [=he's very hard or tough]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not gentle or friendly <vi><it>hard</it> [=<it>harsh</it>] words</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:holding extreme political views <vi>a member of the <it>hard</it> [=<it>far, extreme</it>] right/left</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:relating to serious matters <vi>They only report <it>hard</it> news.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt>:containing a large amount of alcohol <vi><it>hard</it> liquor</vi> <vi>the <it>hard</it> stuff</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:containing alcohol <vi><it>hard</it> cider/lemonade</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:powerful and extremely harmful to the health <vi>cocaine and other <it>hard</it> drugs</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>13</sn> <ssl>of water</ssl> <dt>:containing many minerals and therefore unable to make bubbles with soap <vi><it>hard</it> water</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:having clear, sharp lines <vi>trying to soften the <it>hard</it> edges of the image</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <dt>:very bright and unpleasant <vi><it>hard</it> lighting</vi> <vi>the cold, <it>hard</it> light of day</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <dt>:sounding like the “c” in “cold” or the “g” in “geese” <vi>The “g” in “gorilla” is <it>hard</it>, but the “g” in “giant” is soft.</vi> <vi>the <it>hard</it> “c” in “cat”</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>soft</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>17</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:physically strong <vi><it>hard</it> [=<it>muscular</it>] bodies</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a hard act to follow</dre> <dx>see <dxt>follow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a hard nut (to crack)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a hard row to hoe</dre> <dx>see <dxt>row</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>between a rock and a hard place</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>drive a hard bargain</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bargain</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) a hard time</dre> <def><dt>:to criticize or annoy someone <vi>They <it>gave him a hard time</it> about quitting the team.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hard feelings</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><snote>If you have <it>hard feelings</it>, you feel dislike or anger toward someone who you think has mistreated you. <vi>She felt/had no <it>hard feelings</it> towards him.</vi> <vi>The court's decision has caused a lot of <it>hard feelings</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>no hard feelings</phrase> is used in speech to say that you are not upset or to ask if someone else is upset. <vi>“I'm sorry I broke our date last night.” “That's OK; <it>no hard feelings</it>.”</vi> <vi>“So, we're still friends, right? <it>No hard feelings</it>?”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hard knocks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hard of hearing</dre> <def><dt>:not able to hear well <vi>He has become a little <it>hard of hearing</it> in his old age.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hard on</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:causing damage or strain to (something) <vi>Reading in dim light is <it>hard on</it> your eyes. [=it puts a strain on your eyes; it is not good for them]</vi> <vi>This kind of work can be <it>hard on</it> your back.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:causing stress or worry to (someone) <vi>These past few months have been <it>hard on</it> everyone, but things should get better soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:treating or judging (someone) in a harsh or critical way <vi>Don't be too <it>hard on</it> the boy. [=don't judge or treat the boy too harshly]</vi> <vi>She is sometimes too <it>hard on</it> herself.</vi> <vi>There's no need to be so <it>hard on</it> yourself—you did the best you could.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hard up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:lacking money <vi>We're pretty <it>hard up</it> these days.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having not enough of something <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>She always seems to be <it>hard up for</it> cash.</vi> <vi>He's <it>hard up for</it> friends. [=he has few friends]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a hard time</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have a hard time</it> doing something or with something, it is difficult for you. <vi>She's <it>having a hard time</it> adjusting to college life.</vi> <vi>The school has <it>had a hard time</it> recruiting substitute teachers.</vi> <vi>He's been <it>having a hard time</it> with his research paper.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play hard to get</dre> <dx>see <dxt>play</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the hard way</dre> <def><dt>:in a way that involves difficult or painful experiences <vi>He found out <it>the hard way</it> that crime doesn't pay. [=he found out by being punished for his crimes]</vi> <vi>She insisted on doing things <it>the hard way</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="place[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">place</hw> <sound><wav>place001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpleɪs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>plac*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a specific area or region of the world :a particular city, country, etc. <vi>Please state your <it>place</it> of birth and your current <it>place</it> of residence. [=where you were born and where you live now]</vi> <vi>New York City is a nice <it>place</it> to visit, but I wouldn't want to live there.</vi> <vi>I've heard it's a good <it>place</it> to raise children.</vi> <vi><it>places</it> like Africa and South America</vi> <vi>traveling to distant/exotic/faraway/remote <it>places</it></vi> <vi>the hottest <it>place</it> on earth</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a building or area that is used for a particular purpose <vi>churches and other <it>places</it> of worship</vi> <vi>a <it>place</it> of learning/business</vi> <vi>You should plan to meet him in a public <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>a local gathering/meeting <it>place</it></vi> <vi>Muslim holy <it>places</it></vi> <vi>ancient burial <it>places</it></vi> <vi>We had dinner at a great little Italian <it>place</it> [=<it>restaurant</it>] downtown.</vi> <vi>He tried several <it>places</it> [=<it>stores</it>], but no one sold the ingredients he needed.</vi> <vi>You've come to the right <it>place</it>. I have just what you need.</vi> <vi>This bar is <phrase>the place to be</phrase> [=it is where many people go and where exciting things happen] on Saturday nights.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a building, part of a building, or area that is used for shelter <vi>They gave him a <it>place</it> to stay for the night.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a house, apartment, etc., where a person lives :<sx>home</sx> <vi>We're going to need a bigger <it>place</it> once the baby is born.</vi> <vi>He's looking to buy a <it>place</it> in the country.</vi> <vi>Shall we go to my <it>place</it> or yours?</vi> <vi>our summer <it>place</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular space or area <vi>This looks like a good <it>place</it> [=<it>location</it>, <it>spot</it>] to stop and rest.</vi> <vi>It's nice to have the whole family together in one <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>Keep your jewelry and other valuables in a safe <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>The map is torn in (some) <it>places</it>. [=some parts of the map are torn]</vi> <vi>The bone in her leg broke in two <it>places</it>.</vi> <vi>Try looking for the phrase in another <it>place</it> in the dictionary.</vi> <vi>A person can only be in one <it>place</it> at one time.</vi> <vi>The guards/chairs were not in their proper <it>places</it>.</vi> <vi>Wires carry the information <phrase>from place to place</phrase>. = They carry it <phrase>from one place to another</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Success is sometimes just a matter of being in <phrase>the right place at the right time</phrase>.</vi> <vi>You were just unlucky; you happened to be at <phrase>the wrong place at the wrong time</phrase>.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She keeps a special <it>place</it> in her heart for mistreated animals.</vi> <vi>When I left the army, I was in a very strange <it>place</it> mentally. [=I was in a very strange mental state]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>hiding place</dxt> <dxt>resting place</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular point that you reach in a discussion, book, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>This seems like a good <it>place</it> to end our discussion for today.</vi> <vi>He used the receipt to keep/mark his <it>place</it> in the book he was reading.</vi> <vi>She dropped the magazine on the floor and <phrase>lost her place</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an available seat, space, or amount of room <vi>There's no <it>place</it> to sit down.</vi> <vi>I found a <it>place</it> to put my things.</vi> <vi>They didn't have a good <it>place</it> for the painting in their apartment.</vi> <vi>If you get to the theater before me, could you save me a <it>place</it>?</vi> <vi>“Excuse me, is this <it>place</it> taken?” “Yes, I'm saving it for my friend.”</vi> <vi>She said she couldn't see the stage and asked if he would change/trade/swap/switch <it>places</it> with her.</vi> <vi>During the ceremony, he was given a <phrase>place of honor</phrase> [=a seat for someone who is being honored] next to the president's wife.</vi> <vi>We'll have to <phrase>make a place</phrase> [=make a space available; make room] for our guests.</vi> <vi>We <it>made a place</it> for you at the dinner table.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular position in a line especially of people or vehicles <vi>I had to use the bathroom, but I didn't want to lose my <it>place</it> in line.</vi> <vi>Would you save/hold our <it>places</it> (in line), please?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular position during or at the end of a race or competition <un>usually singular <vi>The runner from the U.S. is currently in third <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>Their horse finished in last <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>The two teams are tied for second <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>“Who took first <it>place</it>?” “First <it>place</it> went to the red team.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a position in a group, course, organization, school, etc. <vi>They offered her a <it>place</it> [=<it>job</it>] on their staff.</vi> <vi>He started getting bad grades and lost his <it>place</it> on the basketball team. [=he was no longer allowed to be on the team]</vi> <vi>She was guaranteed a <it>place</it> in the college.</vi> <vi>There are two <it>places</it> still open in the course/class.</vi> <vi>He has friends <phrase>in high places</phrase>. [=friends who have power and influence]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Her courage during the war earned her a <it>place</it> in history. [=she is remembered as an important person in history because of her courage during the war]</vi> <vi>She has an important <it>place</it> in the community. [=she is an important part of the community]</vi> <vi>He occupies a prominent <it>place</it> among the great musicians of our time.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the proper position of someone in a group or society <vi>The queen's servants must know their <it>place</it> and act accordingly. [=they must act like servants]</vi> <vi>It's not my <it>place</it> [=it is not appropriate for me] to punish other people's children.</vi> <vi>It was not his <it>place</it> to make the final decision.</vi></dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:an appropriate situation or setting <vi>There's a time and a <it>place</it> for everything.</vi> <vi>This is neither the time nor the <it>place</it> to talk about money.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular situation or set of conditions <vi>Call me if you ever find yourself in a tight <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>Anyone in her <it>place</it> [=<it>position</it>] would have done the same thing.</vi> <vi>I love my life and wouldn't <phrase>change/trade/swap/switch places</phrase> with anyone in the world!</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt>:the position of a digit in a number <vi>In the number 316, the digit 1 is in the tens <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>Move the decimal point two <it>places</it> to the right.</vi> <vi>a number with three <phrase>decimal places</phrase> [=a number with three digits that follow the decimal point; a number like 2.345 or .678]</vi> <vi>In the number 2.468, the 4 is in the first <it>decimal place</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><un>used in the names of streets <vi>He lives at 313 Jackson <it>Place</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>all over the place</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:in many different areas or locations :<sx>everywhere</sx> <vi>New houses are springing up <it>all over the place</it> in that part of the country.</vi> <vi>The kids left their toys <it>all over the place</it>.</vi> <vi>Bullets were flying <it>all over the place</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not organized in a logical way <vi>Your essay lacks organization; your ideas are <it>all over the place</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>between a rock and a hard place</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fall into place</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fall</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give place to (something)</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to be replaced by (something) <vi>Confidence <it>gave place to</it> [=(more commonly) <it>gave way to</it>] fear.</vi> <vi>Further down the street, tall office buildings <it>give place to</it> rows of tidy houses.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go places</dre> <def><dt>:to become successful <vi>She has enough ambition to really <it>go places</it>.</vi> <vi>The band is clearly <it>going places</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep (someone) in his/her place</dre> <def><dt>:to prevent (someone) from achieving a higher social status <vi>Such social rules were used to <it>keep</it> women <it>in their place</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in place</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the proper position <vi>He makes sure that every hair on his head is <it>in place</it> before leaving the house.</vi> <vi>Tape held/kept the photo <it>in place</it>.</vi> <vi>The house's walls are <it>in place</it>, but nothing else has been done.</vi> <vi>With all the performers <it>in place</it>, we were ready to rehearse.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in the state of being used or active <vi>The new computer system should be <it>in place</it> by next Monday.</vi> <vi>These changes were already <it>in place</it> when the new president took office.</vi> <vi>Plans are <it>in place</it> for the upcoming hurricane season.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:in the same location without moving forward or backward. <vi>To warm up before swimming practice, we run <it>in place</it> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>on the spot</it>] for five minutes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in place of (someone or something)</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>in someone's or something's place</va></vr> <def><dt>:as a substitute or replacement for someone or something <vi>Use milk <it>in place of</it> [=<it>instead of</it>] water for creamier hot chocolate.</vi> <vi><it>In place of</it> butter, olive oil was served with the bread.</vi> <vi>The prince ruled the kingdom <it>in place of</it> his father. = The prince ruled the kingdom <it>in</it> his father's <it>place</it>.</vi> <vi>She couldn't attend the meeting, so she sent her secretary <it>in</it> her <it>place</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the first place</dre> <def><dt><un>used at the end of a sentence to indicate what was true or what should have been done at the beginning of a situation <vi>We should never have gone there <it>in the first place</it>. [=<it>to begin with</it>]</vi> <vi>I didn't care much for the job <it>in the first place</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the first/second place</dre> <def><dt><un>used when listing the most important parts of something or the most important reasons for something <vi>I'm not going to tell you because, <it>in the first place</it>, it's none of your business, and <it>in the second place</it>, you would tell everyone else.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into place</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:into the proper position <vi>She lowered her glasses then pushed them back <it>into place</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:into the state of being used or active <vi>The curfew was <phrase>put into place</phrase> [=was established] by the town's mayor.</vi> <vi>The plan will be <it>put into place</it> over the course of several months.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no place for</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone or something does not belong in a particular place, situation, etc. <vi>This party is <it>no place for</it> children. [=children should not be allowed at this party]</vi> <vi>There is <it>no place for</it> racism in our society.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of all places</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is unusual or surprising that something happened in or is true about a particular place <vi>She met her future husband in a grocery store, <it>of all places</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of place</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not in the correct location or position <vi>Nothing in the room was <it>out of place</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not in a typical or appropriate situation or setting <vi>Their modern style home seems oddly <it>out of place</it> among the town's old farmhouses.</vi> <vi>She wouldn't look <it>out of place</it> on the cover of a fashion magazine.</vi> <vi>I feel a bit <it>out of place</it> [=I feel like I don't belong] with my wife's family.</vi> <vi>The law seems particularly <it>out of place</it> in today's society.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>place in the sun</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pride of place</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pride</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put someone in his/her place</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who <it>puts you in your place</it> shows you that you are not better than other people and should not be acting in such a confident and proud way. <vi>He told her to stop talking, but she quickly <it>put him in his place</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take place</dre> <def><dt>:to happen <vi>The wedding is set to <it>take place</it> this July.</vi> <vi>Negotiations are now <it>taking place</it> between the two governments.</vi> <vi>He didn't understand what had just <it>taken place</it>.</vi> <vi>Where does the story <phrase>take place</phrase>? [=where is the story set?]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take someone's or something's place</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take the place of (someone or something)</va></vr> <def><dt>:to replace someone or something <vi>Who will <it>take the king's place</it> when he dies?</vi> <vi>We solved the original problem, but now a new one has <it>taken its place</it>.</vi> <vi>I was too busy to attend the meeting, so I had my secretary <it>take my place</it>.</vi> <vi>Who will <it>take the place of</it> the current pope?</vi> <vi>Televisions began to <it>take the place of</it> radios in most families' homes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your place</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go to the location where you are supposed to sit, stand, etc. <vi>The goalie <it>took her place</it> on the field.</vi> <vi>The actors <it>take their places</it> on the stage and the curtain rises.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) Ladies and gentlemen, please <it>take your places</it>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>take your seats</it>] The play is about to begin.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be thought of or considered as sharing a particular rank or status with others <vi>He has <it>taken his place</it> among/alongside/beside/with history's most brutal dictators.</vi> <vi>The film will surely <it>take its place</it> among the greatest films of all time. [=will be recognized as one of the greatest films of all time]</vi> <vi>The hurricane will <it>take its place</it> in history as one of this country's worst natural disasters.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="rock[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">rock</hw> <altpr>ˈrɑ:k</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>rocks</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the hard, solid material that the surface of the Earth is made of <vi>They drilled through several layers of solid <it>rock</it>.</vi> <vi>Moss can grow on bare <it>rock</it>.</vi> <vi>The miners made a tunnel through the <it>rock</it>.</vi> <vi>volcanic <it>rock</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>The mountain had many amazing <it>rock</it> formations.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bedrock</dxt> <dxt>sheetrock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of rock <vi>a flat <it>rock</it></vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) We threw <it>rocks</it> [=<it>stones</it>] into the water.</vi> <vi>a pile of <it>rocks</it></vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large piece of rock that sticks up from the surface of the Earth <vi>She climbed the <it>rock</it>.</vi> <vi>The ship crashed into the <it>rocks</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases to say that something is very hard, steady, etc. <vi>This bread is (as) <phrase>hard as a rock</phrase>. = The bread is <phrase>rock-hard</phrase>. [=the bread is very hard]</vi> <vi>Her hand was <phrase>steady as a rock</phrase>. [=her hand was very steady]</vi> <vi>His muscles are <phrase>solid as a rock</phrase>. [=very strong/solid]</vi> <vi>The frozen chicken is <phrase>rock-solid</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The beat of the drum was <phrase>rock-steady</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a strong person who can be relied on <vi>We could always count on him—he was our <it>rock</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:someone whose ideas, values, ways of doing things, etc., do not change <vi>Once she makes up her mind, she's (like) a <it>rock</it>. [=nobody can change her mind once she decides something]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a diamond or other jewel <vi>Look at the size of that <it>rock</it> on her finger.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:hard candy that is made in a stick <vi>a stick of <it>rock</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>rock candy</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a small hard piece of a drug <vi>a <it>rock</it> of crack cocaine</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>between a rock and a hard place</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a very difficult or bad position or situation with no good way of getting out of it <vi>He is caught/stuck <it>between a rock and a hard place</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your rocks off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a man</ssl> <dt>:to have an orgasm</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to feel great pleasure or satisfaction <vi>He <it>gets his rocks off</it> bossing everyone around.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live under a rock</dre> <def><dt>:to be unaware of things that most people know about <vi>How could you have not heard about it? Do you <it>live under a rock</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the rocks</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a lot of problems and likely to fail <vi>Their marriage is <it>on the rocks</it>. [=<it>in trouble</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of an alcoholic drink</ssl> <dt>:with ice cubes <vi>He ordered a whiskey/Scotch <it>on the rocks</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>rock</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="sea"> <hw highlight="yes">sea</hw> <sound><wav>sea00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>seas</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the salt water that covers much of the Earth's surface <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>We traveled <phrase>by sea</phrase>. [=on a ship]</vi> <un>often used with <it>the</it> <vi>The ship sank to the bottom of <it>the sea</it>. [=<it>the ocean</it>]</vi> <vi>creatures of <it>the sea</it></vi> <vi>He was sailing <phrase>the open sea</phrase>. [=sailing far away from land]</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>sea</it> voyage</vi> <vi>a <it>sea</it> animal/creature</vi> <vi>the <it>sea</it> floor</vi></un> <wsgram>plural</wsgram> (<it>literary</it>) <vi>the uncharted <it>seas</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>high seas</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>Sea</va></svr> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large body of water that is part of the sea or that has land around part or all of it <vi>the Mediterranean <it>Sea</it></vi> <vi>the <it>seas</it> of the Southern Hemisphere</vi> <dx>see color picture on page C7</dx> <dx>see also <dxt>seven seas</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area of the sea <un>used to describe the movement of the water in the sea <vi>a calm/rough <it>sea</it></vi></un> <un>often plural <vi>We sailed in heavy <it>seas</it>. [=in very large waves]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large amount or number <it>of</it> people or things spread over a large area <un>usually singular <vi>a <it>sea of</it> screaming fans</vi> <vi>a golden <it>sea of</it> wheat</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a <it>sea of</it> sadness</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>Sea</va></svr> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:one of the large, flat areas on the moon or on Mars <vi>lunar <it>seas</it></vi> <vi>the <it>Sea</it> of Tranquility</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at sea</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:sailing or traveling on the sea <vi>The navy spent as much time in port as they did <it>at sea</it>.</vi> <vi>The crew was <phrase>lost at sea</phrase>. [=the crew disappeared while traveling on the sea]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:confused and not confident <vi>She felt completely <it>at sea</it> when she started her new job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>between the devil and the deep blue sea</dre> <dx>see <dxt>devil</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fish in the sea</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fish</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go to sea</dre> <def><sl>somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to become a sailor <vi>He <it>went to sea</it> at a young age.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out to sea</dre> <def><dt>:toward or into a part of the ocean that is far away from land <vi>The boat headed <it>out to sea</it>.</vi> <vi>He fell overboard and was <phrase>swept out to sea</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put (out) to sea</dre> <def><dt>:to leave a port, harbor, etc., and begin traveling on the sea <vi>The ship <it>put to sea</it>.</vi> <vi>We will dock tonight and <it>put out to sea</it> tomorrow.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="go-between"> <hw>go–be*tween</hw> <sound><wav>gobetw01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊbəˌtwi:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>go–be*tweens</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person who talks to people or groups who disagree in order to help deal with or end the disagreement <vi>He'll act/serve as a <it>go-between</it> during the negotiations.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="in-between"> <hw>in–be*tween</hw> <sound><wav>inbetw01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɪnbɪˈtwi:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>in–be*tweens</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a state or position that is in the middle between two other things :a middle position <vi>The switch is either on or off; there's no <it>in-between</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>in–between</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>available in small, large, and <it>in-between</it> sizes</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="betwixt"> <hw>be*twixt</hw> <sound><wav>betwix01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈtwɪkst</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sl>old-fashioned + literary</sl> <dt>:<sx>between</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>betwixt and between</dre> <def><dt>:in the middle :not completely one thing and not completely the other thing <vi>Politically, my parents are <it>betwixt and between</it>. They're neither liberal nor conservative in their views.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
