<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="birth"> <hw highlight="yes">birth</hw> <sound><wav>birth001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>births</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the time when a baby comes out from the body of its mother <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He was present at/for the <it>birth</it> of his daughter.</vi> <vi>The hospital reported an increase in premature <it>births</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Please indicate your date of <it>birth</it>.</vi> <vi>the period from <it>birth</it> to adolescence</vi> <vi>a disease that is present at <it>birth</it></vi> <vi>She's Canadian by <it>birth</it>. [=she was born in Canada]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>What was the baby's <it>birth</it> weight?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the beginning or origin of something <vi>the <it>birth</it> of the solar system</vi> <vi>the <it>birth</it> of the blues</vi> <vi>We are witnessing the <it>birth</it> of a new era.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the kind of family a person comes from <vi>a person of noble/low/humble <it>birth</it> [=<it>ancestry</it>]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>give birth</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a mother</ssl> <dt>:produce a baby from the body <vi>Did she <it>give birth</it> in a hospital or at home?</vi> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He was present when his wife <it>gave birth to</it> his daughter.</vi> <vi>Our cat <it>gave birth to</it> four kittens.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause the beginning of something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>a revolution that <it>gave birth to</it> a new nation</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="birth canal"> <hw>birth canal</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -nals</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the part of a mother's body that a baby passes through when it is born</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="birth certificate"> <hw>birth certificate</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -cates</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an official document that gives information about a person's birth (such as the person's name, the names of the parents, and the time and place where the birth occurred)</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="birth control"> <hw>birth control</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:things that are done to keep a woman from becoming pregnant <vi>modern methods of <it>birth control</it> [=<it>contraception</it>]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>birth control</it> pill</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="birth father"> <hw>birth father</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the father of a child when the child is born :the natural father of a child who has been adopted</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="birth mother"> <hw>birth mother</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the mother of a child when the child is born :a woman who gave birth to a child who has been adopted</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="birth parent"> <hw>birth parent</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ents</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the natural father or mother of a child who has been adopted</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="breech birth"> <hw>breech birth</hw> <sound><wav>breec01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbri:tʃ-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ births</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a birth in which a baby is born with the feet or buttocks coming out of the mother first instead of the head <ca>called also <cat>breech delivery</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="give[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">give</hw> <sound><wav>give0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɪv</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gives</if></in> <in><if>gave</if> <sound><wav>give0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgeɪv</pr></in> <in><if>giv*en</if> <sound><wav>give0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɪvən</pr></in> <in><if>giv*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause or allow someone to have (something) as a present :to make a present of (something) <vi>She <it>gave</it> him a camera for Christmas.</vi> <vi>Someone <it>gave</it> me a present. = Someone <it>gave</it> a present to me. = I was <it>given</it> a present. = A present was <it>given</it> (to) me.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>giving</it> this to me or only lending it?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause or allow (something valued or needed) to go to another person, group, etc. :<sx>donate</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She has <it>given</it> money to many worthy/good causes.</vi> <vi>They're asking people to <it>give</it> money for a new hospital.</vi> <vi><it>give</it> blood</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>give</it> to our charity.</vi> <vi>We already <it>gave</it> at the office.</vi> <vi>It is better to <it>give</it> than to receive.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put (something) into someone's hand <vi>He picked up the letter and <it>gave</it> [=<it>handed</it>] it to me.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> me the letter.</vi> :to cause someone to hold or possess (something) for a specified reason <vi>He <it>gave</it> me a letter to mail for him. = He <it>gave</it> a letter to me to mail for him.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her his coat to hold.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to provide someone with (something wanted or needed) <vi>She has <it>given</it> me a lot of help/support/encouragement. [=she has helped/supported/encouraged me a lot]</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> me a job. [=they hired me]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> me a head start.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>give</it> you a lift/ride to the station. [=I'll drive you to the station in my car]</vi> :to allow someone to have (something wanted or needed) <vi>I know I can do it if you'll just <it>give</it> me a chance.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> her another opportunity.</vi> <vi>Her boss has <it>given</it> her a lot of responsibility/authority.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> him the best room available.</vi> <vi>The law <it>gives</it> all citizens the right to vote. = The law <it>gives</it> the right to vote to all citizens.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to allow someone to have or take (an amount of time) <vi>Just <it>give</it> me a few more minutes and I'll be ready.</vi> <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him two weeks to pay his bill.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to treat or regard someone or something with (a particular attitude, feeling, etc.) <vi>She <it>gave</it> her friend her complete confidence. = She <it>gave</it> her complete confidence to her friend. [=she trusted her friend completely]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> the company his loyalty. [=he was loyal to the company]</vi> <vi>They've worked hard. You should <it>give</it> them some respect. [=you should respect them]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to direct (something) toward someone <vi>She <it>gave</it> him an angry look. [=she looked at him angrily]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her a smile. [=he smiled at her]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to tell (information) to someone <vi>Just <it>give</it> me the facts.</vi> <vi>They weren't able to <it>give</it> us the information we needed.</vi> <vi>The witness was reluctant to <it>give</it> evidence.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> his name as “John Smith.” [=he said his name was “John Smith”]</vi> <vi>The drawing <it>gives</it> [=<it>shows</it>] the dimensions of the room.</vi> <vi>The book <it>gives</it> [=<it>provides</it>] a brief history of the industry.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to express or say (something) to someone <vi>You have no right to <it>give</it> me orders.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> him careful instructions on how to proceed.</vi> <vi><it>Give</it> them my regards. = <it>Give</it> my regards to them.</vi> <vi>His parents <it>gave</it> him a lecture about the importance of studying.</vi> <vi>The coach <it>gave</it> the team a pep talk.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>give you my word</phrase> [=I swear; I promise], I knew nothing about their plans.</vi> <vi>Just <phrase>give it to me straight</phrase>. [=just say what you are going to say to me in a direct way]</vi> <snote>The informal phrase <phrase>don't give me that</phrase> is used in speech to show annoyance when someone tells you something that you do not believe or accept. <vi>“It's not my fault that we're late.” “<it>Don't give me that</it>! You were the one who said we didn't have to leave early!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to show (something) <vi>a young artist who has <it>given</it> evidence/signs of real talent</vi> <vi>She <it>gave</it> (us) no hint/indication that she was upset or worried.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) for consideration or acceptance <vi>He declined to <it>give</it> an opinion.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>give</it> an example?</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> no reason for his absence.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say that someone has or deserves (something) <vi>He <it>gives</it> the credit for his success to his wife. [=he credits his wife for his success]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to have or experience (something, such as an emotion, a problem, etc.) <vi>My car has been <it>giving</it> [=<it>causing</it>] me a lot of trouble lately.</vi> <vi>I like Mexican food, but it <it>gives</it> me indigestion.</vi> <vi>a book that <it>gives</it> pleasure to the reader</vi> <vi>All that noise is <it>giving</it> me a headache. [=I'm getting a headache from all that noise]</vi> <vi>It <it>gave</it> me a shock to see how sick he is.</vi> <vi>Her encouragement <it>gave</it> me a lot of self-confidence. [=made me feel very self-confident]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to become affected by (something, such as an illness) <vi>His sister <it>gave</it> him the measles. [=he got/caught the measles from his sister]</vi> <vi>Hearing the joke <it>gave</it> him the giggles. [=hearing the joke made him giggle]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause someone or something to have (a quality) <vi>His quiet manner <it>gives</it> him a mysterious air.</vi> <vi>The large windows <it>give</it> the room an open feeling.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause something to be affected by (something) <vi>He argues that the tax cuts would <it>give</it> a considerable stimulus/boost to the economy.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause someone to get or take (a medicine) <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> the patient a pill.</vi> <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him an injection.</vi> <vi>The drug is usually <it>given</it> intravenously.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to present (a show, speech, etc.) in public <vi><it>give</it> a concert/lecture/talk/speech/reading/performance</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to provide (something) as entertainment or as a social gathering <vi><it>give</it> [=<it>throw</it>] a party</vi> <vi><it>give</it> a formal dinner</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to do (an action) <vi>She <it>gave</it> the door a push. [=she pushed the door]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her a hug. [=he hugged her]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> a cynical smile. [=he smiled cynically]</vi> <vi>She picked up the package and <it>gave</it> it a shake. [=she shook the package]</vi> <vi>The referee <it>gave</it> [=<it>made</it>] the signal to start the game.</vi> <vi>The ship <it>gave</it> a sudden lurch. [=the ship lurched suddenly]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to experience or suffer (a form of punishment) <vi>His father <it>gave</it> the boy a whipping.</vi> <vi>The judge <it>gave</it> him life (imprisonment) for murder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to undergo or do (something) <vi>The teacher <it>gave</it> the class a test.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>give something thought/consideration (etc.)</phrase> is to think about it. <vi>We've <it>given</it> your proposal a lot of thought and careful consideration. [=we've thought about your proposal a lot and considered it carefully]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>give someone a call/ring/buzz/bell</phrase> is to make a telephone call to someone. <vi>I'll <it>give you a call</it> later.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt><snote>If you try to do something, you <phrase>give it a try</phrase> or (informally) <phrase>give it a go/shot/stab</phrase>. <vi>I've never gone skiing before, but I'm willing to <it>give it a try</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>15</sn> <dt><snote>If you would <phrase>give anything</phrase> or <phrase>give your right hand/arm</phrase> to do or to have something, you want to do or have it very much. <vi>I'd <it>give anything</it> to be able to sing like that!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as your hand) available for someone <vi>She <it>gave</it> [=<it>offered</it>] her hand to him to shake/kiss. = She <it>gave</it> him her hand to shake/kiss. [=she held out her hand toward him so that he could shake/kiss it]</vi> <vi>She <it>gave</it> him her arm [=she linked her arm in his arm] and they walked together into the room.</vi> <snote>When a woman <phrase>gives her hand in marriage to</phrase> a man, she marries him. This is a formal and somewhat old-fashioned expression.</snote></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:<sx>pay</sx> <vi>I wouldn't <it>give</it> a penny for that old bike!</vi> <vi>If you have an extra ticket, I'll <it>give</it> you $20 for it.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>sell</sx> <vi>I'm willing to <it>give</it> you the ticket for $20.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or judge that someone or something will last for (an amount of time) <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him only a few weeks to live. [=the doctor said that he would live for only a few weeks]</vi> <vi>Their marriage will never work. I <it>give</it> it/them six months—tops!</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to admit (something) to or about someone <vi>He made an effort, I'll <it>give</it> him that (much). [=I'll admit that he made an effort]</vi> <vi>I don't really like his movies, but he's a talented actor, <phrase>I'll give you that</phrase>. [=I admit that he is a talented actor]</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or produce (something) as a product, result, or effect <vi>medical procedures that <it>give</it> better results</vi> <vi>Cows <it>give</it> milk.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to cause someone to believe or think (something) <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>They <it>gave</it> [=<it>led</it>] me <it>to understand</it> that they'd be arriving later.</vi></un> <snote>To <phrase>give someone an idea/impression (etc.)</phrase> is to cause someone to believe or think something. <vi>Whatever <it>gave you the idea</it> (that) he loved you?! [=whatever made you think that he loved you?]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry if I <it>gave you the wrong impression</it>. [=I'm sorry if I misled you; I'm sorry if you got the wrong impression from me]</vi> <vi>I don't know what <it>gave her the notion</it> that she could treat people that way.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bend because of force, pressure, or strain <vi>The branch <it>gave</it> [=<it>sagged</it>] under his weight, but it didn't break.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to break because of force, pressure, or strain <vi>The branch suddenly <it>gave</it> [=<it>gave way</it>] under his weight, and he fell to the ground.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop trying to resist or oppose something :to give in or submit to pressure <vi>Both sides refuse to <it>give</it> [=refuse to accept or agree to the demands of the other side] in this dispute.</vi> <vi>For the strike to be settled, <phrase>something has (got) to give</phrase>! [=one side or the other has to give in]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a possible or assumed state or condition <vi><it>Give</it> him his books and his music and he's happy. [=he is happy if he has his books and his music]</vi> <vi>(If) <it>Given</it> better conditions, she'd do the work even better. = She'd do the work even better (if) <it>given</it> better conditions. = If she were <it>given</it> better conditions, she'd do the work even better.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what you want to have or would prefer to have <vi>“…<it>give</it> me liberty, or <it>give</it> me death!” [=I would rather die than live without liberty] <aq>Patrick Henry, Speech (1775)</aq></vi> <vi>The country's OK—but <it>give</it> me the city any day! [=I prefer the city]</vi></un></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>give a damn</phrase> to say that you do not care at all about something <vi>He angrily told her that he didn't <it>give a damn</it> what she did.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>give as good as you get</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be as forceful in fighting or arguing against others as they are in fighting or arguing against you <vi>She can <it>give as good as she gets</it> in an argument with just about anybody.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give away (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make a present of (something) <vi>For a limited time only our store is <it>giving away</it> [=<it>giving</it>] a free can of soda to each and every one of our customers!</vi> <vi>Our prices are so cheap we're practically <it>giving away</it> everything in our store!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to lose (something) in a careless way <vi>He virtually <it>gave</it> the election <it>away</it> when he made a racist remark.</vi> <vi>The pitcher <it>gave</it> the game <it>away</it> by walking four batters in a row.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to allow (something hidden or secret) to become known <vi>The way she looked at him <it>gave away</it> her real feelings for him.</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>give away</it> [=<it>reveal</it>] how the trick is done.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>giveaway</dxt> <dxt>giveaway price</dxt> <tag>give the game away</tag> at <dxt>game</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (someone) away</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>give away (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bring (the bride) to the groom at a wedding <vi>Traditionally, it's the father of the bride who <it>gives</it> his daughter <it>away</it> at the wedding.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reveal the truth about (someone) <vi>His fellow conspirators <it>gave</it> him <it>away</it> to the police. [=they betrayed him to the police]</vi> <vi>His accent <it>gave</it> him <it>away</it> as a northerner. [=his accent showed that he was a northerner]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause someone to have (something) again :to return or restore (something) to someone <vi>He <it>gave back</it> the money he found to the person who'd lost it.</vi> <vi>Her encouragement helped to <it>give</it> me <it>back</it> my self-confidence. [=her encouragement helped me to get my self-confidence back]</vi> <vi>They agreed to <it>give</it> him his old job <it>back</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>giveback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give birth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>birth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give chase</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chase</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to fight or resist something :to agree to do or accept something that you have been resisting or opposing <vi>The strike has been going on for weeks, and neither side seems willing to <it>give in</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He refused to <it>give in to</it> their demands. [=he refused to do what they demanded that he do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give in (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to give (something) to a person who has authority to review or accept it <vi><it>give in</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>hand in</it>] an assignment</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give it a rest, give (something) a rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give me a break, give (someone) a break</dre> <dx>see <dxt>break</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give of yourself</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give of your time</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to use your time and effort to help others <vi>They freely <it>gave of their time</it> when their help was needed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to send (light, energy, etc.) out from a source <vi>The telescope can detect light <it>given off</it> [=<it>emitted</it>] by distant galaxies.</vi> <vi>The garbage <it>gave off</it> an unpleasant smell.</vi> <vi>The chimneys <it>gave off</it> thick, black smoke.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give on to</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>give onto</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give on to (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>give onto (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to provide a view of or a passage to (something) <vi>The door <it>gives</it> directly <it>on to</it> the garden.</vi> <vi>The rooms <it>give onto</it> a hall.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give or take</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that the stated amount is approximate and might be increased or decreased by a specified amount <vi>He ran a mile, <it>give or take</it> a few yards.</vi> <vi>The movie lasted three hours, <it>give or take</it> a few minutes either way.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal)</it> He ran a mile, <it>give or take</it>. [=he ran about a mile]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The plane's engine sputtered and <it>gave out</it>, forcing an emergency landing.</vi> <vi>His voice <it>gave out</it>. [=he was unable to talk]</vi> <vi>His courage finally <it>gave out</it>. [=he lost his courage]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become used up <vi>Our supply of fuel had almost <it>given out</it> [=<it>run out</it>] entirely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>give out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to produce (noise, light, etc.) <vi>The brakes <it>gave out</it> a loud squeal.</vi> <vi>The woodstove <it>gives out</it> a lot of heat.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (something) to many people :to hand out (something) <vi>They <it>gave out</it> copies of the newsletter.</vi> <vi>He's always <it>giving out</it> unwanted advice.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop doing something that is annoying or unpleasant <vi>Oh, <it>give over</it>! I'm tired of your complaints!</vi> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>They eventually <it>gave over bothering</it> me [=stopped bothering me] and let me alone.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give over to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give (something) over to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to give (something) to (someone) to have, use, do, etc. <vi>She has <it>given</it> most of her work <it>over</it> to her assistant.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) over to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (yourself) to be fully affected by, controlled by, or involved in (something) <vi>He <it>gave himself over to</it> despair. [=he was overcome by despair]</vi> <vi>She <it>gave herself over</it> completely <it>to</it> her work. [=she devoted all of her attention and energy to her work]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>given over to</phrase> a specified purpose is used for that purpose. <vi>One of the upstairs rooms is <it>given over to</it> storage.</vi> <vi>Much of her time recently has been <it>given over to</it> researching her family history.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give place to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>place</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give rise to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rise</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop an activity or effort :to admit that you cannot do something and stop trying :<sx>quit</sx> <vi>He vowed that he would never <it>give up</it>.</vi> <vi>I <it>give up</it>! I don't know what more I can do to please my girlfriend!</vi> <vi>“How many prime numbers are there between 1 and 100? Well, do you <it>give up</it>?” “OK, I <it>give up</it>!”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop having, doing, or using (something) <vi>He was forced to <it>give up</it> his job.</vi> <vi>She refused to <it>give up</it> trying.</vi> <vi>My doctor urged me to <it>give up</it> smoking/cigarettes.</vi> <vi>Rescuers have not yet <it>given up</it> hope that more survivors will be found.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave up</it> his seat to an elderly woman. [=he got out of his seat so that an elderly woman could sit there]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to do (something) <vi>We did our best to repair the engine, but in the end we had to <it>give</it> it <it>up</it> as impossible.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to allow (a score, a hit, etc.) by an opposing team or player <vi>The defense <it>gave up</it> two touchdowns in the first quarter.</vi> <vi>The pitcher didn't <it>give up</it> a hit till the ninth inning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to surrender (yourself) as a prisoner <vi>The fugitive eventually <it>gave himself up</it> (to the police/authorities).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to improve the condition of (someone) because it seems hopeless <vi>The teacher <it>gave</it> him <it>up</it> as a hopeless case.</vi> <vi>The doctors <phrase>gave him up for dead</phrase>. [=the doctors said that he was certain to die]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having hope of seeing (someone) <vi>We'd <it>given</it> you <it>up</it> (for lost) hours ago!</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (yourself) to be fully affected by, controlled by, or involved in (something) <vi>He <it>gave himself up to</it> despair.</vi> <vi>She <it>gave herself up</it> completely <it>to</it> her work.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>give up on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to improve the condition of (someone) <vi>He has gotten in trouble many times, but his parents have never <it>given up on</it> him.</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>give up on</it> me. I promise I'll do better.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having hope of seeing (someone) <vi>We'd <it>given up on</it> you hours ago!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>give up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop trying to do or achieve (something) <vi>They have <it>given up on</it> their plan to build a new factory.</vi> <vi>She hasn't <it>given up on</it> trying to convince her husband to buy a new car.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give up the ghost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ghost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>What gives?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to ask the reason for something <vi>You've been acting weird all week. <it>What gives</it>? [=why are you acting weird?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
