<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bit[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bit</hw> <sound><wav>bit00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bits</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small piece of something <vi>Put all the broken <it>bits</it> back together.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>He ate every last/single <it>bit of</it> the food. [=he ate all of the food]</vi> <vi>He ate only a couple of tiny little <it>bits of</it> bread and cheese and drank a drop or two of wine.</vi> <vi>We need to get all the <it>bits of</it> dirt out of the carpet.</vi> <vi>There were broken <it>bits of</it> glass all over the floor.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bits and pieces <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:a part of something (such as a book, play, etc.) <vi>There are some good <it>bits</it> [=<it>parts</it>] near the end of the story: one is the <it>bit</it> where the hero and the heroine are nearly separated.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a brief comic performance or joke <vi>The comedian did a funny <it>bit</it> about taking his daughter to the dentist.</vi> <vi>a corny comedy <it>bit</it></vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a very short performance in a movie, play, etc. <un>usually used before another noun <vi>a <it>bit</it> part/role</vi> <vi><it>bit</it> players</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:all the things that are connected to an activity, a process, etc. <vi>He says he's tired of his job, tired of driving to work every day, <phrase>the whole bit</phrase>. [=<it>everything</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:an old coin with a specified small value <vi>a threepenny <it>bit</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>two bits</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a bit</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a little :somewhat or rather <vi>I let it bother me <it>a bit</it>. [=<it>slightly</it>]</vi> <vi>His house is down the street <it>a bit</it> further.</vi> <vi>There's <it>a bit</it> too much sugar in the dessert, which makes it <it>a bit</it> too sweet.</vi> <vi>I'm feeling <it>a bit</it> better today.</vi> <vi>It's <it>a bit</it> like driving a car.</vi> <vi>This one is <it>a bit</it> bigger than that one.</vi> <vi>At first, I was <it>a bit</it> confused.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a small amount or quantity :a little of something <vi>They don't understand much—but they do understand <it>a bit</it>.</vi> <vi>They saved money <it>a bit</it> at a time.</vi> <vi>“How much cake is left?” “Only <it>a</it> (very little) <it>bit</it>.”</vi> <vi>“How old is your daughter?” “She's two and <it>a bit</it>.” [=she's slightly older than two]</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>They understand only <it>a bit of</it> [=<it>a little of</it>] what is going on.</vi> <vi>There's <it>a bit of</it> both brown sugar and molasses in these cookies.</vi> <vi>The job may cause you <it>a bit of</it> trouble.</vi> <vi>His mind's already made up. It won't do you <it>a bit of</it> good to argue. [=it won't do you any good to argue]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a short period of time :a while <vi>Let's wait <it>a</it> (little/wee) <it>bit</it> longer.</vi> <vi>Repairs will begin in <it>a bit</it> more than a month.</vi> <vi>He left but came back after <it>a bit</it>. [=he came back soon]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:for a short period of time <vi>Please stay here with me <it>a bit</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a bit much</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe a person or thing that is regarded as annoying, excessive, or unfair <vi>My mother thinks he's funny, but I find him <it>a bit much</it>.</vi> <vi>I find his constant joking <it>a bit much</it>.</vi> <vi>It was <it>a bit much</it> to expect us to wait that long.</vi> <vi>The hot weather is getting to be <it>a bit much</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a bit of a/an</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt><un>used to make a statement or description less forceful or definite <vi>I had <it>a bit of a</it> shock when I saw him. [=I was somewhat shocked when I saw him]</vi> <vi>He's <it>a bit of a</it> rascal. [=he's something of a rascal]</vi> <vi>We had <it>a bit of a</it> laugh about it afterwards.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a bit of all right</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:someone or something very pleasing</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a sexually attractive person <vi>His girlfriend's <it>a bit of all right</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a little bit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>little</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bit by bit</dre> <def><dt>:by small steps or amounts :<sx>gradually</sx> <vi>The situation improved <it>bit by bit</it>. [=<it>little by little</it>]</vi> <vi>I got to know them <it>bit by bit</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bits and pieces</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:small pieces <vi>There were broken <it>bits and pieces</it> of glass all over the floor.</vi> <vi>I finished the project <phrase>in bits and pieces</phrase> [=a little at a time] during my spare time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bits and bobs</va></svr> <dt>:things or objects of different kinds <vi>There are just a few <it>bits and pieces</it> of furniture in the office.</vi> <vi>No one knows exactly what happened. All we have is a few <it>bits and pieces</it> [=<it>odds and ends</it>] of information so far.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do your bit</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to do your share of a job or task <vi>We all have to <it>do our bit</it> [=<it>do our part</it>] to help out.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>every bit</dre> <def><dt>:in every way <vi>The end of the movie was <it>every bit</it> [=<it>just</it>] as good as the beginning.</vi> <vi>This new project seems <it>every bit</it> as ambitious as the first one.</vi> <vi>He is <it>every bit</it> the high-powered businessman.</vi> <vi>You are <it>every bit</it> as deserving as she is.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not a/one bit</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>not (in) the least/smallest/slightest/tiniest bit</va></vr> <def><dt>:not at all <vi>It <it>didn't</it> interest me <it>a bit</it>. = It <it>didn't</it> interest me <it>one</it> (single/little) <it>bit</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>not a bit</it> interested in this movie. = I'm <it>not the least bit</it> interested in this movie.</vi> <vi>That joke was <it>not a/one bit</it> funny. [=was not funny at all]</vi> <vi>We <it>weren't a bit</it> tired. [=we weren't tired at all]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not a bit of it</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something expected or possible did not happen or is not true <vi>Am I tired? <it>Not a bit of it</it>. [=I am not tired at all]</vi> <vi>I thought she'd be angry, but <it>not a bit of it</it>. [=she wasn't angry at all]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>quite a bit</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>a good/fair bit</va></vr> <def><dt>:a fairly large amount :a lot <vi>He knows <it>quite a bit</it> [=<it>quite a lot</it>] more about it than I do.</vi> <vi>The wait was <it>quite a bit</it> [=<it>considerably</it>] longer than I thought it would be.</vi> <vi>She lost the race by <it>quite a bit</it>.</vi> <vi>We've been seeing <it>quite a bit</it> of each other lately. [=we've been spending a lot of time together lately]</vi> <vi>She'd already finished <it>a good bit</it> of the work before I returned.</vi> <vi>There's still <it>a fair bit</it> (of the cake) left.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take a bit of doing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>doing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to bits</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to pieces :<sx>apart</sx> <vi>The ball hit the window and smashed it <it>to bits</it>.</vi> <vi>The bridge was blown <it>to bits</it> by the explosion.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) The pie was <phrase>falling to bits</phrase> [=<it>falling apart</it>] as I tried to serve it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to a very great degree <vi>She was thrilled <it>to bits</it>. [=she was very thrilled]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bit</dxt> <dxt>bit</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bit[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bit</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the part of a tool (such as a drill) that is used for cutting, drilling, etc. <dx>see picture at <dxt>carpentry</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a piece of metal that is put in the mouth of a horse and that is part of the device (called a bridle) that is used to control the horse <dx>see picture at <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>champing/chomping at the bit</dre> <def><dt>:waiting in an impatient way to do something <vi>We've all been <it>champing at the bit</it> to get started on the project.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get/take the bit between your teeth</dre> <def><dt>:to start doing something in a very enthusiastic and determined way <vi>He can be lazy about doing his work, but when he <it>gets the bit between his teeth</it> there's no stopping him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bit</dxt> <dxt>bit</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bit[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bit</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>computers</sl> <dt>:a single unit of computer information that is represented as either 1 or 0 <dx>compare <dxt>byte</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>megabit</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bit</dxt> <dxt>bit</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bit[4]"> <hw hindex="4">bit</hw> <cx><cl>past tense of</cl> <ct>bite</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="bite[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bite</hw> <sound><wav>bite0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bites</if></in> <in><if>bit</if> <sound><wav>bite0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪt</pr></in> <in><if>bit*ten</if> <sound><wav>bite0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪtn̩</pr></in> <in><if>bit*ing</if> <sound><wav>biting01.wav</wav><wav>bite0004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪtɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a person or animal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to press down on or cut into (someone or something) with the teeth <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bit</it> the apple.</vi> <vi>The hamster <it>bit</it> the child.</vi> <vi>She <it>bit</it> the cookie in half.</vi> <vi>Some people <it>bite</it> their nails when they feel nervous.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>The child <it>bit off</it> a corner of the cracker.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>A wild animal may <it>bite</it> if it is frightened.</vi> <un>often + <it>down, into</it>, or <it>through</it> <vi>He accidentally <it>bit down</it> on his tongue.</vi> <vi>She had just <it>bitten into</it> her sandwich when the phone rang.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>bit through</it> its leash and ran off.</vi> <vi>Go talk to him. He <phrase>won't bite</phrase>. [=you should not be afraid to go talk to him]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of an insect or snake</ssl> <dt>:to wound (someone) by pushing a stinger, fang, etc., into the skin <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The patient had been <it>bitten</it> by a poisonous snake.</vi> <vi>A mosquito <it>bit</it> me.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The mosquitoes are <it>biting</it> tonight.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was <phrase>bitten by the travel bug</phrase>. [=he became very interested in or excited about traveling]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to grab and hold something without slipping <un>usually + <it>into</it> <vi>The anchor <it>bit into</it> the ocean floor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a fish</ssl> <dt>:to take a fishhook and bait into the mouth and usually to get caught <vi>Are the fish <it>biting</it> today?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to respond to or accept something that is being offered <snote>Someone gets you to <it>bite</it> by offering something you want so that you will do something desired. <vi>We offered them a great deal, but they wouldn't <it>bite</it>. [=they wouldn't accept the deal]</vi> <vi>“I just heard the juiciest piece of gossip!” “OK, I'll <it>bite</it>. [=I'll ask the question you want me to ask] What is it?”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to have a bad effect <vi>With the recession starting to <it>bite</it>, many government-funded programs have had to be eliminated.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <ssl>impolite</ssl> <dt>:to be extremely bad <vi>This movie really <it>bites</it>. [=<it>sucks, stinks</it>]</vi> <vi>“They canceled the concert.” “Man, <phrase>that bites</phrase>!” [=(politely) that's awful]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite back</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to attack or criticize someone who has attacked or criticized you <vi>Weary of her rival's accusations, the candidate <it>bit back</it> [=<it>hit back, fought back</it>] with an aggressive ad campaign.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>She <it>bit back at</it> her rival with an aggressive ad campaign.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bite back (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bite (something) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop yourself from saying (something) <vi>I attempted to smile sweetly while <it>biting back</it> angry comments.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite off more than you can chew</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to try to do too much :to take on more responsibility than you can handle <vi>I really <it>bit off more than I could chew</it> when I took on this project.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to yell at someone or to be very critical of someone especially very suddenly and without a good reason <vi>I asked him one simple question and he <it>bit my head off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the bullet</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to do something unpleasant or painful because it is necessary even though you would like to avoid it <vi>We need to <it>bite the bullet</it> and make some budget cuts.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the dust</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to die or stop functioning <vi>My old car finally <it>bit the dust</it> and I had to buy a new one.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the hand that feeds you</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to harm someone who has helped or supported you <vi>He was reluctant to criticize his mentor for fear of <it>biting the hand that fed him</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite your tongue</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bite your lip</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to not speak :to stop yourself from saying something that you are tempted to say <vi>I thought she was acting foolishly, but I <it>bit my tongue</it> [=<it>held my tongue</it>] and didn't say anything.</vi> <un>often used as a command <vi>“I hope he gets hurt.” “<it>Bite your tongue</it>! [=don't say that] That's a terrible thing to say!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come back to bite you</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something that you do <it>comes back to bite you</it>, it causes problems for you at a later time. <vi>Their decision not to invest more money in new equipment may <it>come back to bite them</it> eventually.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hair of the dog that bit you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>once bitten, twice shy</dre> <def><dt><snote>The expression <it>once bitten, twice shy</it> means that a person who has failed or been hurt when trying to do something is careful or fearful about doing it again.</snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bit*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bit*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="two-bit"> <hw>two–bit</hw> <sound><wav>twobit01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtu:ˈbɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not very important or valuable <vi>a <it>two-bit</it> thief/town/opinion</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all right[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">all right</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun except in sense 4</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:fairly good :<sx>satisfactory</sx> <vi>The quality of his work is <it>all right</it> but not outstanding.</vi> <vi>Her first movie was pretty bad but her second one was <it>all right</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:acceptable or agreeable <vi>Whatever you decide to do is <it>all right</it> (with/by me). [=I will accept whatever you want to do]</vi> <vi>Is it <it>all right</it> to leave early?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:suitable or appropriate <vi>Is this movie <it>all right</it> for children?</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:not ill, hurt, unhappy, etc. <vi>He was very sick but now he's <it>all right</it> again.</vi> <vi>“Are you hurt?” “No, I'm <it>all right</it>.”</vi> <vi>She was upset when her boyfriend left, but she's <it>all right</it> now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not marked by problems, danger, etc. <un>used to tell someone not to be worried or concerned <vi>Don't worry. Everything will be <it>all right</it>.</vi> <vi>“I'm so sorry that I'm late.” “It's/That's <it>all right</it>. We still have plenty of time.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:likable, good, or honest <vi>He's an <it>all right</it> guy.</vi> <vi>I had my doubts about him at first, but I trust him now. He's <it>all right</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a bit of all right</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bit</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blind[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">blind</hw> <sound><wav>blind001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblaɪnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>blind*er</if></in> <in><if>blind*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:unable to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> person</vi> <vi>He was born <it>blind</it>.</vi> <vi>She is <it>blind</it> in one eye. [=she can see with one of her eyes but not with the other]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went blind</phrase> [=she became unable to see] at age 67.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>color-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:unable to notice or judge something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He is <it>blind to</it> his son's faults.</vi> <vi>Each party was <it>blind to</it> the other's concerns.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>usually disapproving</ssl> <dt>:accepting the actions or decisions of someone or something without any questions or criticism <vi><it>blind</it> loyalty/allegiance/obedience</vi> <vi>I'm not sure <it>blind</it> faith [=unquestioning belief] in our leaders is wise.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe strong emotions that make someone unable to think clearly or to act reasonably <vi>a <it>blind</it> fury/rage</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:done in a way that prevents participants, judges, etc., from seeing or knowing certain things that might influence them <vi>a <it>blind</it> taste test [=a test in which people taste something without knowing what it is, who made it, etc.]</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> clinical trial for the new medicine</vi> <vi><it>blind</it> auditions</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind date</dxt> <dxt>double-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:difficult for a driver to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> driveway/drive</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> curve</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind spot</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) blind as a bat</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to see well at all :having very poor vision <vi>Without glasses I'm <it>blind as a bat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>love is blind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not a blind bit</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not even a very small amount :not the slightest bit <vi>I told them what I wanted, but they <it>didn't</it> take <it>a blind bit</it> of notice. [=they didn't notice at all; they did not listen to me]</vi> <vi>It does <it>not</it> make <it>a blind bit</it> of difference what you do. [=it does not matter at all what you do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the blind</dre> <def><dt>:blind people :people who are not able to see <vi>The agency provides assistance to <it>the blind</it>.</vi> <snote>The expression <phrase>the blind leading the blind</phrase> is used informally to describe a situation in which someone who is not sure about how to do something is helping another person who also is not sure about how to do it. <vi>I'll try to help, but it's <it>the blind leading the blind</it> because I've never done this before either.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <def><dt>:to ignore a problem instead of dealing with it <vi>Corruption in the police force is rampant, but authorities are <it>turning a blind eye</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Colleges can't afford to <it>turn a blind eye to</it> alcohol abuse.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>blind*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>a leading cause of <it>blindness</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="champ[2]"> <hw hindex="2">champ</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃæmp</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>champs</if></in> <in><if>champed</if></in> <in><if>champ*ing</if></in> <def><dt>:to bite and chew on (something) in a noisy way :<sx>chomp</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>champed</it> his pipe angrily.</vi> <vi>The horse was <it>champing</it> its bit.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>champed</it> on his pipe angrily.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>champing at the bit</dre> <def><dt>:waiting in an impatient way to do something <vi>We've all been <it>champing at the bit</it> to get started on the project.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chomp"> <hw>chomp</hw> <sound><wav>chomp001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃɑ:mp</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chomps</if></in> <in><if>chomped</if></in> <in><if>chomp*ing</if></in> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to chew or bite on something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He was <it>chomping on</it> a bagel.</vi> <vi>The dog <phrase>chomped down on</phrase> its bone.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>away</it> <vi>The children were sitting at the table, happily <it>chomping away</it>.</vi> <vi>The bug <phrase>chomped away at</phrase> the leaf.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Lawmakers have been <it>chomping away at</it> the state budget.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They were <it>chomping</it> burgers at a picnic.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>chomping at the bit</dre> <def><dt>:waiting in an impatient way to do something <vi>We've all been <it>chomping</it> [=<it>champing</it>] <it>at the bit</it> to get started on the project.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
