<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bite[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bite</hw> <sound><wav>bite0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bites</if></in> <in><if>bit</if> <sound><wav>bite0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪt</pr></in> <in><if>bit*ten</if> <sound><wav>bite0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪtn̩</pr></in> <in><if>bit*ing</if> <sound><wav>biting01.wav</wav><wav>bite0004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪtɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a person or animal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to press down on or cut into (someone or something) with the teeth <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bit</it> the apple.</vi> <vi>The hamster <it>bit</it> the child.</vi> <vi>She <it>bit</it> the cookie in half.</vi> <vi>Some people <it>bite</it> their nails when they feel nervous.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>The child <it>bit off</it> a corner of the cracker.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>A wild animal may <it>bite</it> if it is frightened.</vi> <un>often + <it>down, into</it>, or <it>through</it> <vi>He accidentally <it>bit down</it> on his tongue.</vi> <vi>She had just <it>bitten into</it> her sandwich when the phone rang.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>bit through</it> its leash and ran off.</vi> <vi>Go talk to him. He <phrase>won't bite</phrase>. [=you should not be afraid to go talk to him]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of an insect or snake</ssl> <dt>:to wound (someone) by pushing a stinger, fang, etc., into the skin <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The patient had been <it>bitten</it> by a poisonous snake.</vi> <vi>A mosquito <it>bit</it> me.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The mosquitoes are <it>biting</it> tonight.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was <phrase>bitten by the travel bug</phrase>. [=he became very interested in or excited about traveling]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to grab and hold something without slipping <un>usually + <it>into</it> <vi>The anchor <it>bit into</it> the ocean floor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a fish</ssl> <dt>:to take a fishhook and bait into the mouth and usually to get caught <vi>Are the fish <it>biting</it> today?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to respond to or accept something that is being offered <snote>Someone gets you to <it>bite</it> by offering something you want so that you will do something desired. <vi>We offered them a great deal, but they wouldn't <it>bite</it>. [=they wouldn't accept the deal]</vi> <vi>“I just heard the juiciest piece of gossip!” “OK, I'll <it>bite</it>. [=I'll ask the question you want me to ask] What is it?”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to have a bad effect <vi>With the recession starting to <it>bite</it>, many government-funded programs have had to be eliminated.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <ssl>impolite</ssl> <dt>:to be extremely bad <vi>This movie really <it>bites</it>. [=<it>sucks, stinks</it>]</vi> <vi>“They canceled the concert.” “Man, <phrase>that bites</phrase>!” [=(politely) that's awful]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite back</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to attack or criticize someone who has attacked or criticized you <vi>Weary of her rival's accusations, the candidate <it>bit back</it> [=<it>hit back, fought back</it>] with an aggressive ad campaign.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>She <it>bit back at</it> her rival with an aggressive ad campaign.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bite back (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bite (something) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop yourself from saying (something) <vi>I attempted to smile sweetly while <it>biting back</it> angry comments.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite off more than you can chew</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to try to do too much :to take on more responsibility than you can handle <vi>I really <it>bit off more than I could chew</it> when I took on this project.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to yell at someone or to be very critical of someone especially very suddenly and without a good reason <vi>I asked him one simple question and he <it>bit my head off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the bullet</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to do something unpleasant or painful because it is necessary even though you would like to avoid it <vi>We need to <it>bite the bullet</it> and make some budget cuts.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the dust</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to die or stop functioning <vi>My old car finally <it>bit the dust</it> and I had to buy a new one.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite the hand that feeds you</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to harm someone who has helped or supported you <vi>He was reluctant to criticize his mentor for fear of <it>biting the hand that fed him</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bite your tongue</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bite your lip</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to not speak :to stop yourself from saying something that you are tempted to say <vi>I thought she was acting foolishly, but I <it>bit my tongue</it> [=<it>held my tongue</it>] and didn't say anything.</vi> <un>often used as a command <vi>“I hope he gets hurt.” “<it>Bite your tongue</it>! [=don't say that] That's a terrible thing to say!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come back to bite you</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something that you do <it>comes back to bite you</it>, it causes problems for you at a later time. <vi>Their decision not to invest more money in new equipment may <it>come back to bite them</it> eventually.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hair of the dog that bit you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>once bitten, twice shy</dre> <def><dt><snote>The expression <it>once bitten, twice shy</it> means that a person who has failed or been hurt when trying to do something is careful or fearful about doing it again.</snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bit*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bit*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bite[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bite</hw> <altpr>ˈbaɪt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bites</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an act of biting <vi>He ate the candy bar in three quick <it>bites</it>.</vi> <vi>She gave her lip a gentle <it>bite</it>.</vi> <vi>The fisherman felt a <it>bite</it> at the end of his line and reeled in a fish.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the way the upper and lower teeth come together <vi>My teenage daughter wears a special device at night to correct her <it>bite</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>overbite</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the amount of food eaten with a bite <vi>He took several <it>bites</it> (out) of the apple.</vi> <vi>She didn't touch/eat a <it>bite</it>. [=she didn't eat anything]</vi> <vi>I can't eat another <it>bite</it>. [=I'm completely full; I no longer feel any hunger]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a small amount of food :a snack or a small informal meal <vi>We grabbed a quick <it>bite</it> (to eat) before the show.</vi> <vi>They've gone out for a <it>bite</it> (to eat).</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a wound made by biting <vi>Don't scratch that mosquito <it>bite</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>snakebite</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a bad effect :a negative impact <vi>Many agencies have been feeling the <it>bite</it> of budget cuts.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a sharp feeling or taste <vi>We felt the <it>bite</it> of the cold wind on our cheeks.</vi> <vi>The soup has a peppery <it>bite</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a sharp quality in something written, spoken, or performed <snote>Something that has <it>bite</it> usually expresses criticism in a strong and often clever way. <vi>satirical <it>bite</it></vi> <vi>the <it>bite</it> of his humor</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>your bark is worse than your bite</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bark</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>sound bite</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bite-size"> <hw>bite–size</hw> <sound><wav>bites01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪtˌsaɪz</pr> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bite–sized</va> <sound><wav>bites02v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪtˌsaɪzd</pr></vr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:small enough to be eaten in one bite <vi><it>bite-size</it> pieces</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sound bite"> <hw>sound bite</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bites</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a short recorded statement that is broadcast on a television or radio news program <vi>His campaign relies on catchy <it>sound bites</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bullet"> <hw highlight="yes">bul*let</hw> <sound><wav>bullet01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊlət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bul*lets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small piece of metal or another material that is shot out of a gun <vi>He was hit by a stray <it>bullet</it>. [=the bullet missed its target and hit him instead]</vi> <vi>He was killed by an assassin's <it>bullet</it>.</vi> <vi>He took a <it>bullet</it> to the head. [=he was shot in the head]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>There are <it>bullet</it> holes in the walls.</vi> <vi>a <it>bullet</it> wound</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>magic bullet</dxt> <dxt>rubber bullet</dxt> <dxt>silver bullet</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a large dot in a document, book, etc., that brings attention to separate pieces of information in a list <vi><it>Bullets</it> were used to separate each item.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bullet point</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a hit or thrown ball or puck that is moving very fast <vi>The quarterback threw a <it>bullet</it> to the receiver.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite the bullet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dodge a/the bullet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dodge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sweat bullets</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sweat</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bul*let*ed</ure> <sound><wav>bullet02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊlətəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>bulleted</it> list</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="chew[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chew</hw> <sound><wav>chew0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃu:</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chews</if></in> <in><if>chewed</if></in> <in><if>chew*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use your teeth to cut food into small pieces before you swallow it <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We were taught to <it>chew</it> our food thoroughly before swallowing.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>chews</it> with his mouth open.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bite on (something) repeatedly with the teeth <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You're not allowed to <it>chew</it> gum in class.</vi> <vi><it>chew</it> tobacco</vi> <vi>Stop <it>chewing</it> [=<it>biting</it>] your nails.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>A mouse <it>chewed</it> through the cord.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The dog was <it>chewing on</it> a bone.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as a hole) by chewing <vi>The dog <it>chewed</it> a hole in the rug.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite off more than you can chew</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>chew off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chew off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chew (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) by chewing <vi>The dog <it>chewed</it> the doll's eyes <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chew on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chew on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to think about (something) <vi><it>Chew on</it> it for a while before you decide.</vi> <vi>That should give you <it>something to chew on</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>chew <dxn>1b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chew out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chew (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chew out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to speak in an angry and critical way to (someone) <vi>I got <it>chewed out</it> [=<it>reprimanded</it>] for leaving early.</vi> <vi>The coach <it>chewed</it> him <it>out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chew over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chew (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chew over (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to think about (something) <vi>He <it>chewed</it> the problem <it>over</it> in his mind.</vi> <vi><it>Chew it over</it> for a while before you decide.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chew the fat</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>chew the rag</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to talk together in a friendly and casual way <vi>They would sit for hours and <it>chew the fat</it>. [=<it>chat, shoot the breeze</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chew up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chew (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chew up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to destroy (something) by chewing it <vi>My new puppy <it>chewed up</it> my shoes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to destroy or defeat (someone or something) <vi>The truck <it>chewed up</it> the grass.</vi> <vi>The gears got all <it>chewed up</it>.</vi> <vi>They <it>chewed up</it> the competition.</vi> <vi>Don't mess with her—she'll <phrase>chew you up and spit you out</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>chew*able</ure> <sound><wav>chew0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃu:wəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>chewable</it> vitamins</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>chew*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chew*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>gum <it>chewers</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="dust[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dust</hw> <sound><wav>dust0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdʌst</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:fine dry powder that builds up inside buildings on surfaces that have not recently been cleaned <vi>The floor was covered with <it>dust</it>.</vi> <vi>You can see the <phrase>dust particles</phrase> floating through the air.</vi> <vi>There is not a <phrase>speck of dust</phrase> in that house.</vi> <snote>Something that is <phrase>collecting/gathering dust</phrase> is not being used. <vi>The book just sat on the shelf <it>gathering dust</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:fine powder made up of very small pieces of earth or sand <vi>As the car sped down the dirt road, it left a cloud of <it>dust</it> behind.</vi> <vi>The wind <phrase>kicked up dust</phrase>. [=blew dust into the air]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:fine powder made from a particular substance <vi>coal/gold <it>dust</it></vi> <vi>He wiped the chalk <it>dust</it> off his hands.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sawdust</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite the dust</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat dust</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to breathe the dust that has been raised into the air by the vehicle that is moving in front of you <vi>He said, “<phrase>Eat my dust!</phrase>” as he jumped in his car and drove away.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>They've left other companies <it>eating their dust</it>. [=they have gone far ahead of other companies]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave (someone) in the dust</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go far ahead of (someone) :to be much more advanced than (someone) <vi>The company has <it>left</it> its competitors <it>in the dust</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the dust settles</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about what happens when things become clear or calm after a period of change or confusion <vi>I'll call you <phrase>as soon as the dust settles</phrase> from the move. [=as soon as I am not busy with moving]</vi> <vi><phrase>When the dust settled</phrase> [=when the situation became less confusing] and the votes were recounted, she had won the election.</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>let the dust settle</phrase> before you make any big decisions.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="feed[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">feed</hw> <sound><wav>feed0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfi:d</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>feeds</if></in> <in><if>fed</if> <sound><wav>fed00001.wav</wav><wav>feed0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɛd</pr></in> <in><if>feed*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give food to (someone or something) <vi>Don't <it>feed</it> the animals.</vi> <vi>He was too weak to <it>feed</it> himself.</vi> <vi>We <it>feed</it> the plants with a special fertilizer twice a week.</vi> <vi>We <it>fed</it> the horses with/on apples, oats, and hay.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give (something) as food to someone or something <vi>They <it>fed</it> [=<it>gave, served</it>] us breakfast before we left. = They <it>fed</it> breakfast to us before we left.</vi> <vi>The children <it>fed</it> apples to the horses.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was <it>feeding</it> information to the enemy. [=he was secretly giving information to the enemy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce or provide food for (someone or something) <vi>These supplies could <it>feed</it> a small army for a week.</vi> <vi>He doesn't earn enough to <it>feed</it> a family of four.</vi> <vi>helping to <it>feed</it> and clothe poor children</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:<sx>eat</sx> <un>usually used of animals <vi>We spotted some ducks <it>feeding</it> in a nearby pond.</vi> <vi>They are studying the <it>feeding</it> habits of sharks.</vi> <vi>a favorite <phrase>feeding ground</phrase> [=an area where animals feed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to provide what is needed for the continued growth, operation, or existence of (something) <vi>They used the wood to <it>feed</it> the fire.</vi> <vi>The streams <it>feed</it> the creek.</vi> <vi>The motor is <it>fed</it> by an electrical current.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to supply (material to be used) to a machine <vi>The logs are <it>fed</it> into the mill for processing.</vi> <vi>She <it>fed</it> the data into the computer.</vi> <vi>The camera <it>feeds</it> the images to a monitor.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give support or strength to (something, such as a feeling) <vi>He <it>fed</it> their hopes with false promises.</vi> <vi>fears <it>fed</it> by ignorance</vi> <vi>Her early success only served to <it>feed</it> her ambition.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) move through an opening <vi>The procedure involves <it>feeding</it> a tube down the patient's throat.</vi> <vi>She <it>fed</it> more coins into the slot.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to pass a ball or puck to (a team member) especially for a shot at the goal <vi>He <it>fed</it> the ball to a teammate for an easy basket.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bite the hand that feeds you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>feed back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>feed back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>feed back (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>feed (something) back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to give helpful information or criticism to someone about a performance, product, etc. :to provide feedback <un>usually + <it>to</it> or <it>into</it> <vi>My music <it>feeds back into</it> my work.</vi> <vi>Decide how your staff should <it>feed back to</it> you.</vi> <vi>Computer users can <it>feed</it> their views <it>back to</it> the software companies.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feed off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>feed off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to gain strength, energy, or support from (something) <vi>She <it>fed off</it> the crowd's enthusiasm.</vi> <vi>His anger <it>fed off</it> his jealousy.</vi> <vi>We are able to <it>feed off</it> each other's ideas.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feed on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>feed on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to eat (something) as food <un>usually used of animals <vi>Owls <it>feed on</it> insects, birds, and small mammals.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feed (someone) a line</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to tell (someone) a story or an explanation that is not true <vi>He <it>fed me a line</it> about how he was late because his car broke down.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feed up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>feed (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make (someone) stronger or less thin by giving them large meals <vi>His mother <it>fed him up</it> after his illness.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fed up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feed your face</dre> <def><sl>slang</sl> <dt>:to eat a lot of food <vi>He sat there for an hour, just <it>feeding his face</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="head[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">head</hw> <sound><wav>head0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>heads</if> <il>or in sense 7</il> <if>head</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body containing the brain, eyes, ears, nose, and mouth <vi>She patted the dog on the <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>He nodded his <it>head</it> in agreement.</vi> <vi>The ceiling's low—watch your <it>head</it>!</vi> <vi><it>head</it> injuries</vi> <vi>They were covered <phrase>from head to foot/toe</phrase> in mud. [=they were completely covered in mud]</vi> <vi>He has a <phrase>full head of hair</phrase>. [=he has a full amount of hair on his head]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>talking head</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person's mental ability :mind or intellect <vi>You shouldn't let your heart rule your <it>head</it>. [=you should be guided by reason and not by your emotions]</vi> <vi>She did some quick calculations <phrase>in her head</phrase>. [=without writing anything; mentally]</vi> <vi>I keep hearing that song <it>in my head</it>. = That song keeps running through my <it>head</it>. = I can't get that song <phrase>out of my head</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It never even <phrase>entered my head</phrase> to run for office. [=I never thought of running for office]</vi> <vi>The problem is <phrase>all in his head</phrase>. [=the problem is not real; he's just imagining it]</vi> <vi>Don't go <phrase>putting ideas in/into his head</phrase>. [=don't cause him to have ideas or suspicions that he would not have himself]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>put that idea out of your head</phrase>. [=you should stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>She always says the first thing that <phrase>comes/pops into her head</phrase>. [=the first thing that she thinks of]</vi> <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <phrase>use our heads</phrase>. [=think carefully]</vi> <vi>That guy should <phrase>have his head examined</phrase>. = That guy is <phrase>not right in the head</phrase>. [=that guy is crazy]</vi> <vi>You need a <phrase>cool/calm head</phrase> [=an ability to remain calm] to deal with someone like him.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>clear head</phrase> [=an ability to think clearly]</vi> <snote>If you have <phrase>a good head on your shoulders</phrase>, you are intelligent and have good judgment. <vi>You don't have to worry about her—she's got <it>a good head on her shoulders</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>When you <phrase>get/take it into your head</phrase> to do something, you suddenly decide to do it in a way that seems foolish or surprising. <vi>He's <it>taken it into his head</it> to try skydiving.</vi> <vi>I somehow <it>got it into my head</it> to run for public office.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get it into your head</phrase> that something is true, you begin to believe something even though there is no good reason for believing it. <vi>She's somehow <it>gotten it into her head</it> that I don't like her. [=she believes that I don't like her although I do like her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who has a specified mental or emotional quality <vi>A fight was avoided when <phrase>cooler heads prevailed</phrase>. [=when calmer or less angry people were able to convince others not to fight]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hothead</dxt> <dxt>sorehead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a distance equal to the length of a head <vi>The horse won the race by a <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a <it>head</it> taller than you.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the front side of a coin :the side of a coin that shows a picture of a person's head <vi>the <it>head</it> of a penny</vi> <un>usually used in the plural to refer to one of the two choices you can make when a coin is thrown in the air to decide something <vi>I call <it>heads</it>.</vi> <vi>Is it <it>heads</it> or tails? [=did the coin land with heads or tails facing up?]</vi> <vi>It landed <it>heads</it> up.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>tail <dxn>3</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>head</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:individual animals <vi>100 <it>head</it> of cattle</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an end of something that is like a head in shape or position <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She placed the pillows at the <it>head of</it> the bed.</vi> <vi>We arrived early so that we'd be at the <it>head</it> [=<it>front</it>] <it>of</it> the line.</vi> <vi>The chairman sat at the <it>head of</it> the table.</vi> <vi>the <it>head</it> [=<it>top</it>] <it>of</it> a nail/pin/screw</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an object that hits or touches something else <vi>a grinding <it>head</it></vi> <vi>the hammer's <it>head</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a spear</vi> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a golf club</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>arrowhead</dxt> <dxt>spearhead</dxt> <dxt>warhead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the position of being a leader <vi>She's <phrase>at the head of</phrase> her class. [=she is the best student in her class]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who leads or directs a group or organization <vi>Have you met the new department <it>head</it>?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She is the <it>head of</it> our sales division.</vi> <vi><it>heads of</it> families/households</vi> <vi><phrase>heads of state</phrase> [=leaders of countries]</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the restaurant's <it>head</it> cook</vi> <vi>the team's <it>head</it> coach</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>head teacher</sx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a tight mass of leaves or flowers on a plant <vi>The flower <it>heads</it> on the plant are very large.</vi> <vi>a <it>head</it> of cabbage/lettuce</vi> <vi>a <it>head of</it> garlic</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where a stream or river begins <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>head</it> of the Nile</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:pressure caused by the water or steam in a machine <snote>When an engine has a <phrase>full head of steam</phrase>, it has built up a full amount of power. This phrase is often used figuratively to describe something that is moving forward in a fast and powerful way. <vi>The project started slowly, but now we have a <it>full head of steam</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the bubbles that form on the top of some liquids (such as beer) <un>usually singular <vi>the foamy <it>head</it> on a beer</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the point at which a situation becomes very serious or when action is required <vi>Things <phrase>came to a head</phrase> when the workers threatened to go on strike.</vi> <vi>These new revelations <phrase>brought</phrase> the scandal <phrase>to a head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small, inflamed area on the skin with a spot in the middle <dx>see also <dxt>blackhead</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a big/swelled head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an overly high opinion of yourself <vi>All those compliments have given him a <it>big head</it>. [=have made him very conceited]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>a head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a price on someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>price</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bang heads together</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>butt heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>butt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get it through someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to learn and remember something <vi>She's finally <it>gotten it through their heads</it> that she doesn't eat meat.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get it through your head</dre> <def><dt>:to accept or understand (something) <vi>He can't seem to <it>get it through his head</it> that I'm not interested in working with him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your head round</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to understand (something) <vi>She couldn't <it>get her head round</it> why he had to leave.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to discuss something with a person who is higher in rank than someone else <vi>He <it>went over his supervisor's head</it> to complain about the policy to the company's president. [=he complained about the policy to the company's president rather than his supervisor]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of an alcoholic drink</ssl> <dt>:to make you feel drunk <vi>I just had one glass of wine, but it <phrase>went straight to my head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make you believe that you are better than other people <vi>He has never let his fame <it>go to his head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a head for</dre> <def><dt>:to have an ability to understand or deal with (something) <vi>She's always <it>had a</it> (good) <it>head for</it> business.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) He <phrase>has a head for heights</phrase>. [=he is not afraid of heights; being up high does not bother him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/get your head (screwed) on right/straight</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to think or act in a smart and sensible way <vi>She's young, but it's clear that she <it>has her head screwed on right</it>.</vi> <vi>You think that's a good idea? You need to <it>get your head screwed on straight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head and shoulders above</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone or something is much better than others <vi>They <phrase>are/stand head and shoulders above</phrase> the competition.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head in the sand</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>bury/have/hide (etc.) your head in the sand</phrase>, you ignore something unpleasant that you should be dealing with. <vi>He can't just <it>bury his head in the sand</it> every time there's a problem.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head over heels</dre> <def><dt>:very deeply in love <vi>We were <it>head over heels</it> (in love).</vi> <vi>He <phrase>fell head over heels for</phrase> some girl he met at school.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>went head over heels for</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heads roll</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that <phrase>heads will roll</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>heads are going to roll</phrase>, you mean that people will be severely punished or will lose their jobs because of something that has happened. <vi>When the boss finds out about the mistake, <it>heads will roll</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the nail on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold up your head</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold your head (up) high</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be proud :to not feel ashamed <vi>Even though they lost the game, they can still <it>hold up their heads</it> because they tried their best.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head</dre> <def><dt>:to remain calm <vi>She has shown that she can <it>keep her head</it> in a crisis.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head above water</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid financial failure while having money problems <vi>We have so much debt that we're barely able to <it>keep our heads above water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head down</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in a quiet way that does not attract attention <vi>a politician who is <it>keeping his head down</it> and trying to avoid controversy</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock some sense into someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock (something) on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your head</dre> <def><dt>:to become very upset or angry <vi>He <it>lost his head</it> and said some things he regrets.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not make head or/nor tail of</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>not make heads or/nor tails (out) of</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be unable to understand (something) <vi>I <it>couldn't make heads or tails of</it> her reaction.</vi> <vi>His handwriting was so bad that we <it>couldn't make heads or tails out of</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the top of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>off your head</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:crazy or foolish <vi>He's not just eccentric—he's completely <it>off his head</it>!</vi> <vi>He's gone <it>off his head</it> over some girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with the upper and lower parts of your body reversed in position <vi>Can you <phrase>stand on your head</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or into great disorder <vi>News of the discovery <phrase>turned</phrase> the scientific world <phrase>on its head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you will be blamed for something <vi>If we miss our deadline, it will be <it>on your head</it>. [=it will be your fault]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to act or think in a reasonable and controlled way because of drunkenness or strong emotion <vi>He was (drunk) <it>out of his head</it>. [=he was extremely drunk]</vi> <vi>Her parents were <it>out of their heads</it> with worry [=were extremely worried and upset] when she didn't come home on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over your head</dre> <def><dt>:beyond your understanding or ability <vi>The technical details were <it>over my head</it>. [=too complicated for me to understand]</vi> <vi>That joke went right <it>over my head</it>. [=I did not get that joke]</vi> <vi>We realized after we started the business that we were (in) <it>over our heads</it>. [=we were trying to do something that was too difficult]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>per head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>per head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick/raise your head above the parapet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>parapet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your heads together</dre> <def><dt>:to think of a solution to a problem with another person <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <it>put our heads together</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rear/raise its ugly head</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something bad <it>rears/raises its ugly head</it>, it suddenly becomes obvious or causes trouble. <vi>Inflation threatened to <it>rear its ugly head</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be confused about something and unable to understand the reason for it <vi>His odd behavior left us all <it>scratching our heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) your head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) very loudly or for a long time <vi>She was <it>screaming her head off</it>.</vi> <vi>You can <it>shout your head off</it> at him, but he still won't listen.</vi> <vi>If they saw me dressed like this, they'd <it>laugh their heads off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>shake your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two heads are better than one</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is easier for two people who help each other to solve a problem than it is for one person to solve a problem alone</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn heads</dre> <def><dt>:to attract attention or notice <vi>The car's sleek design is bound to <it>turn heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="put[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">put</hw> <sound><wav>put00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpʊt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>puts</if></in> <in><if>put</if></in> <in><if>put*ting</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular place or position <vi>She <it>put</it> [=<it>placed, set</it>] the plant near the window.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the car in the garage.</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> the keys on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his arms around her and held her tight.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to go into or through something in a forceful way <vi>He fell and accidentally <it>put</it> his hand through a window.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be in a particular place or send (someone) to a particular place <vi>The illness <it>put</it> her in the hospital for three days.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her in prison for forgery.</vi> <vi>Her parents decided to <it>put</it> her in a special school for deaf children.</vi> <vi>If she drove 55 mph for 20 minutes, that would <it>put</it> her about halfway there by now.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to show that (someone or something) is in a particular place <vi>The evidence/report <it>puts</it> the defendant at the scene of the crime. [=it shows that the defendant was at the scene of the crime]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to write (something) with a pen or pencil in or on something <vi>Don't forget to <it>put</it> your signature on the check.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his phone number on a napkin.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> a circle around the correct answer.</vi> <vi>I wrote that the answer was option B. What did you <it>put</it>?</vi> <vi>She had always dreamed of writing a novel, but she never actually <phrase>put pen to paper</phrase>. [=started writing]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular state or condition <vi>Not exercising <it>puts</it> you at greater risk of developing heart disease.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the TV on channel 5, please.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you in charge/command/control?</vi> <vi>I told her some jokes to <it>put</it> her in/into a good mood.</vi> <vi>His careless spending <it>put</it> him in/into debt.</vi> <vi>Their actions have <it>put</it> them in serious danger.</vi> <vi>Her reassuring words <phrase>put us at ease</phrase>. [=made us feel calm and relaxed]</vi> <vi><phrase>Put</phrase> that idea <phrase>out of your mind</phrase>. [=stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>They said they shot the injured horse to <phrase>put</phrase> it <phrase>out of its misery</phrase>. [=so that it would not continue to suffer]</vi> <vi>They have <phrase>put</phrase> their competitors <phrase>out of business</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The new technology could <phrase>put him out of a job</phrase>. = It could <phrase>put him out of work</phrase>. [=it could make him lose his job]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>putting</phrase> the children <phrase>to bed</phrase>. [=helping them get into their beds]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do work or perform a task <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>put</it> the kids <it>to</it> work cleaning the basement.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) <vi>They are ready to <it>put</it> the plan in action/motion.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> an idea into action/effect/practice</vi> <vi>The new weapon was immediately <phrase>put to use</phrase> by the military.</vi> <vi>I don't need this camera, but maybe you can <phrase>put it to good use</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (something) to have an effect on someone or something <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>puts</it> [=<it>places</it>] great emphasis <it>on</it> the need for new leadership. [=he strongly emphasizes the need for new leadership]</vi> <vi>She has been <it>putting</it> pressure <it>on</it> us to finish the project early.</vi> <vi>Another child would <it>put</it> a heavy strain <it>on</it> their finances. [=would strain their finances very much]</vi> <vi>A special tax/duty/surcharge was <it>put on</it> luxury items.</vi> <vi>They want to <it>put</it> a limit <it>on</it> government spending.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to say or express (something) <vi>As she <it>put</it> it, “You can't please everyone.”</vi> <vi>How should I <it>put</it> this? I don't think you're cut out for this job.</vi> <vi>Well <it>put</it>!</vi> <vi>Let me <it>put</it> it another way.</vi> <vi>I think you're incompetent, <phrase>to put it bluntly</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It was a difficult experience, <phrase>to put it mildly</phrase>. [=it was a very difficult experience]</vi> <vi>She finds it hard to <phrase>put her feelings into words</phrase>. [=to say what her feelings are]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to ask (a question) or make (a suggestion) to someone <vi>Let me <it>put</it> this question to you [=let me ask you this question]: what do we do now?</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> my plan/proposal before the board of directors for consideration.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to ask a group of people to formally vote on (something) <vi>They plan on <it>putting</it> the motion/resolution to a/the vote this afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to add music to (words) <vi>She writes the lyrics and he <it>puts</it> [=<it>sets</it>] them to music.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to throw (a shot put)</dt></def> <dro><dre>I wouldn't put it past (someone)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>past</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put about (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to tell many people about (something) <vi>They <it>put about</it> the news that he was resigning. = They <it>put</it> it <it>about</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to change direction <vi>The ship <it>put about</it> and sailed back out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat or ship) to change direction <vi>a boat that can be <it>put about</it> quickly</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to get (something) across <vi>She has had trouble <it>putting</it> her message <it>across</it> to voters.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) across as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>He tries to <it>put himself across as</it> [=to make other people believe that he is] a nice guy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put a foot wrong</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>She's been <it>putting aside</it> some money for a vacation.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>put</it> a few minutes <it>aside</it> for a short meeting?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop worrying or thinking about (something) <vi>We need to <it>put</it> these problems <it>aside</it> for now and get the work done.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>put aside</it> our differences and start working together.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to guess or estimate (something) to be (something) <vi>The coroner <it>put</it> his time of death <it>at</it> 7:00. [=the coroner estimated that the time of his death was 7:00]</vi> <vi>Recent estimates <it>put</it> the number of unreported cases <it>at</it> 2,000 each year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put away</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> the pictures <it>away</it> for safekeeping.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> your notes <it>away</it>. It's time for the test.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>Her parents started <it>putting away</it> money for her education the year she was born.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to eat (a large amount of food) <vi>I used to <it>put away</it> huge meals before I went on a diet.</vi> <vi>That guy can really <phrase>put it away</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be kept in a prison or mental hospital <vi>He's a vicious criminal. I hope they <it>put</it> him <it>away</it> for the rest of his life.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>Remember to <it>put</it> the vacuum cleaner <it>back</it> in the closet after you've used it.</vi> <vi>The books had been <it>put back</it> neatly on the shelf.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to change (a planned event) to start at a later date or time <vi>They <it>put back</it> [=<it>pushed back</it>, <it>postponed</it>] the game until next week.</vi> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put back</it> from 1 p.m. to 3 p.m.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask (a person or group) to make a decision about (something) <vi>The problem of downtown parking was <it>put before</it> the mayor/council.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put</it> this question <it>before</it> the voters.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) behind you</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop worrying about or being upset by (something that happened in the past) <vi>It was a disappointing loss, but we need to <it>put it behind us</it> and focus on winning the next game.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the past <it>behind you</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put by (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to save (money) for a later time <vi>She has <it>put</it> some money <it>by</it> [=<it>put aside</it>] for emergencies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) down</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>put down (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (someone or something that you have been holding or carrying) on a table, on the floor, etc. <vi>She carefully <it>put</it> the vase <it>down</it> on the table.</vi> <vi>The police ordered him to <it>put down</it> the gun.</vi> <vi>I don't need you to carry me. <it>Put</it> me <it>down</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to a list <vi>Don't forget to <it>put down</it> milk and bread on the shopping list.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say critical or insulting things about (someone or something) <vi>He frequently <it>puts down</it> her work.</vi> <vi>Her parents are always <it>putting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>puts himself down</phrase> a lot, but he's really quite an attractive man.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-down</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write (something) :to record (something) in writing <vi>She says that the reporter <it>put</it> her quote <it>down</it> incorrectly.</vi> <vi>Every night, he <it>puts</it> his thoughts <it>down</it> in a journal.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put down</it> my thoughts on paper before I forget them.</vi> <vi>What answer did you <it>put down</it> on the test?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (an amount of money) as a first payment when you are buying something that costs a lot of money <vi>We <it>put</it> 10 percent <it>down</it> on the house. = We <it>put down</it> a 10 percent deposit on the house.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> no money <it>down</it> and pay no interest on the car until next year.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to put (something) in place on the floor or ground <vi><it>Putting down</it> [=<it>installing</it>] a new hardwood floor would greatly increase the value of your home.</vi> <vi>We <it>put down</it> a layer of mulch in the rose garden.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop (a violent or dangerous activity) by using force <vi>Federal troops were brought in to help <it>put down</it> the riot.</vi> <vi><it>put down</it> a rebellion/revolt/uprising</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to kill (an animal) in a way that causes it little pain usually because it is injured or sick <vi>They had to have their dog <it>put down</it> [=<it>put to sleep</it>] by the vet.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to end a telephone connection <vi>She said goodbye and <phrase>put down the phone</phrase>. [=<it>hung up the phone</it>]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put the phone down on him</phrase>. [=she hung up the phone while he was still talking to her]</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to formally suggest (something) as an idea to be discussed and voted on by a group of people :to propose or introduce (something) <vi><it>putting down</it> an amendment in Parliament</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to land or to cause (an airplane) to land <vi>Our plane <it>put down</it> [=<it>landed</it>] in New York around 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The pilot was forced to <it>put</it> [=<it>set</it>] the plane <it>down</it> in a field.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to place (a baby or child) in a bed to sleep <vi>He <it>put</it> the baby <it>down</it> (in her crib) for a nap.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think of (someone) as (a specified kind of person or thing) <vi>Most people <it>put</it> him <it>down as</it> [=believe that he is] a fanatic.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to write the name of (someone) on a list of people who will do or give (something) <vi>Can I <it>put you down for</it> a donation? [=can I write that you will give a donation?]</vi> <vi>Sure, <it>put me down for</it> $20.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or think that (something) happened because of (something) <vi>Let's <it>put</it> the mistake <it>down to</it> your inexperience and forget about it.</vi> <vi>The mistake was <it>put down to</it> [=<it>attributed to</it>] his inexperience.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suggest (an idea, plan, etc.) for people to think about or consider <vi>The same argument has been <it>put forth</it> by many people in the opposition.</vi> <vi>I would like to <it>put forth</it> some alternatives.</vi> <vi><it>putting forth</it> a plan/proposal/theory</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (something, such as energy) for a particular purpose <vi>She <it>put forth</it> all her energy to win the race.</vi> <vi>They <it>put forth</it> a good effort.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to produce or send out (something) by growing <vi>The trees are starting to <it>put forth</it> new leaves.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to suggest (something) for consideration :<sx>propose</sx> <vi>He <it>put forward</it> [=<it>put forth</it>] a theory about how the accident may have occurred.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) ready to be used in a certain place :<sx>install</sx> <vi>We <it>put in</it> new cabinets just last year.</vi> <vi>In order to fix the car they have to <it>put in</it> a new engine.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (a comment) to a conversation or argument <vi>She <it>put</it> a quick comment <it>in</it> about her busy schedule.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> a few words on his behalf. [=to say something that supports him]</vi> <vi>Would you mind <phrase>putting in a good word for</phrase> me? [=would you say something good about me?]</vi> <vi>You will each have a chance to <phrase>put in your two cents</phrase>. [=to express your opinion]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make an official statement, offer, or request <vi>She <it>put in</it> a plea of not guilty. [=she pleaded not guilty]</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put in</it> [=<it>make, submit</it>] a report about this.</vi> <vi>You have two weeks to <it>put in</it> [=<it>submit</it>] a claim with the insurance company.</vi> <vi>They are <it>putting in</it> [=<it>making</it>] a $300,000 offer for the house.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> [=<it>place</it>] an order for a dozen roses.</vi> <vi>Contractors have begun <it>putting in</it> bids for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to perform (a particular action) <vi>They <it>put in</it> an amazing performance last night.</vi> <vi>The prime minister <phrase>put in a call to</phrase> [=<it>called</it>] the White House.</vi> <vi>I won't be able to stay at the party long, but I'll at least try to <phrase>put in an appearance</phrase>. [=to go to the party for a short time]</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to work or do something for (an amount of time) <vi>She <it>put in</it> 10 hours at the office yesterday.</vi> <vi>She <it>put in</it> a long day at work.</vi> <vi>He has <it>put in</it> his time (in jail), and now he is a free man.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing something <vi>If we <it>put in</it> a little more effort, we could finish by this afternoon.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>in</it> his performances.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to invest (money) into (something) <vi>She <it>put</it> her money <it>in</it> stocks and bonds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what causes you to have faith, confidence, etc. <vi>He <it>puts</it> his faith <it>in</it> reason/science.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> her trust <it>in</it> God</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for (something) in an official way :to formally request (something) <vi>He <it>put in for</it> a leave of absence.</vi> <vi><it>putting in for</it> a promotion</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to enter a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put in</it> at Sydney.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing (something) <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>into</it> his performances.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put her heart into</phrase> (writing) the letter. [=she expressed her feelings in a very open and honest way]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to invest (time, money, etc.) in (something) <vi>They <it>put</it> their entire life savings <it>into</it> the company.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> a lot of money <it>into</it> (fixing up) that house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put it there</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>put her there</va></vr> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to invite someone to shake hands with you <vi><it>Put her there</it>, pal!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that (something) will happen at a later time :<sx>postpone</sx> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put off</it> until next week. = We <it>put off</it> (holding) the meeting until next week.</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call him, but I keep <it>putting</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>putting off</it> calling him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to wait <vi>I need to come up with an excuse to <it>put off</it> the bill collector.</vi> <vi>She finally called him after <it>putting</it> him <it>off</it> all week.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to dislike someone or something <vi>Don't let the restaurant's dingy appearance <it>put</it> you <it>off</it>—their food is great.</vi> <vi>I was <it>put off</it> by his rudeness.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) His rudeness <phrase>put me off him</phrase> [=made me dislike him] at once.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>off-putting</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to allow (someone) to get off a bus or other vehicle <vi>Could you <it>put</it> [=<it>let</it>] me <it>off</it> (the bus) at the next stop, please?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to dress yourself in (clothing) <vi>She <it>put on</it> her new dress.</vi> <vi><it>Put on</it> a hat and gloves.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>put</it> some clothes <it>on</it> and be right there.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to apply (something) to your face or body <vi><it>putting on</it> lipstick/mascara/lotion</vi> <vi>She <it>puts on</it> far too much makeup.</vi> <vi>We tried to <phrase>put on a happy/brave face</phrase> [=we tried to appear happy/brave] despite our concern.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to add to or increase the amount of (something) <vi>The fire was getting low and we needed to <it>put on</it> more wood.</vi> <vi>She <it>put on</it> [=<it>gained</it>] 40 pounds during her pregnancy.</vi> <vi>He's <it>put on</it> some weight recently.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause (a machine, a light, etc.) to begin to work <vi>Would you mind if I <it>put</it> [=<it>turned</it>] the TV <it>on</it>?</vi> <vi>Somebody <it>put on</it> the lights.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to be heard, seen, produced, etc. <vi><it>put on</it> a record/CD/album</vi> <vi><it>putting on</it> some music</vi> <vi>We <it>put on</it> the air-conditioning/heat in the car.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to start cooking or making (something) <vi>Let me know when to <it>put on</it> the rice.</vi> <vi>He <it>put on</it> a pot of coffee for his guests.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to produce (something that entertains people, such as a play, a party, etc.) <vi>They're <it>putting on</it> a concert.</vi> <vi>He always <it>puts on</it> a great show/performance.</vi> <vi>The town <it>puts on</it> a fireworks display every Independence Day.</vi> <vi>We are <it>putting on</it> a barbecue for everyone in the neighborhood.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say that (someone or something) is responsible for or guilty of (something) <vi>Responsibility for the accident was <it>put on</it> the other driver.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> much of the blame for his problems <it>on</it> the government.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bet (an amount of money) on (someone or something) <vi>We <it>put</it> $2 <it>on</it> the favorite to win.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> money <it>on</it> horse races</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to (a list or group of related things) <vi>She asked to have her name <it>put on</it> the list of candidates.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> the list.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> several new dishes <it>on</it> the menu.</vi> <vi>“Bartender, I'll have another beer.” “Okay, I'll <it>put</it> it <it>on</it> your bill.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say things that are not true to (someone) in a joking way :to trick or fool (someone) for amusement <vi>He said he knew the President, but I think he was just <it>putting me on</it>. [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>having me on</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you would like to speak to someone on the phone <vi>Hi Dad. Could you <it>put</it> Mom <it>on</it>? [=could you give Mom the phone so that I can speak to her?]</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> Dave <it>on</it> the phone, please.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to tell (someone) to use or do (something) <vi>Her doctor <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> medication. [=her doctor prescribed medication for her]</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>put</it> himself <it>on</it> a diet. [=to go on a diet]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (someone) information about (something) :to tell (someone) about (something that he or she did not know about before) <vi>A friend of mine <it>put</it> me <it>on to</it> this book in high school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to stop burning :<sx>extinguish</sx> <vi>She <it>put</it> the fire <it>out</it> by pouring water on it.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her cigarette in an ashtray.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from working <vi>Who <it>put out</it> [=<it>turned off</it>] the lights?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to take (something) outside and leave it there <vi>I <it>put</it> the dog <it>out</it> in the backyard before leaving the house.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> horses <it>out</it> to graze</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the trash/garbage. = (<it>Brit</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the rubbish.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to extend (something) outward <vi>I <it>put out</it> my hand and he shook it eagerly.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her arm for them to stop.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to place (something) where people may use it <vi>He always <it>put out</it> a bowl of candy for the grandchildren.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put out</it> a few extra chairs in case more people arrive.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>This small radiator <it>puts out</it> a surprising amount of heat.</vi> <vi>They will have to <it>put out</it> considerable effort to meet the deadline.</vi> <vi>It was early spring, and the trees were just starting to <it>put out</it> their leaves.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available to be bought, used, etc. <vi>She plans to <it>put out</it> a new album in March.</vi> <vi>They need to be <it>putting out</it> cars that get better gas mileage.</vi> <vi>The information was given in a pamphlet <it>put out</it> by the university's health department.</vi> <vi>Researchers recently <it>put out</it> a report/study on the issue.</vi> <vi>The police have <it>put out</it> [=<it>issued</it>] a warrant for his arrest.</vi> <vi>Someone <phrase>put the word out</phrase> [=started telling people] that the police were looking for her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to annoy or bother (someone) <vi>All the attention didn't seem to <it>put</it> her <it>out</it> at all.</vi> <vi>I'm a little <it>put out</it> that no one called to tell me they would be late.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to do extra work :to cause trouble for (someone) <vi>I hope my visit didn't <it>put</it> you <it>out</it>. [=didn't inconvenience you]</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>put</it> yourself <it>out</it> just for us.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) unconscious <vi>The anesthesia <it>put</it> him <it>out</it> for a little over three hours.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be out in baseball or cricket <vi>The runner was <it>put out</it> at second base.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>putout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with someone <vi>Did she <it>put out</it> last night?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to leave a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put out</it> to sea.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to put (something) across <vi>He <it>puts over</it> very complicated concepts in a way that his students can understand.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) over as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>She <it>puts herself over as</it> [=makes other people believe that she is] a modern, independent woman.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to lie about (something) to (someone) :to trick or deceive someone <vi>Don't try to <it>put</it> anything <it>over on</it> her. She'll see right through you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put paid to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>paid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put (someone) in mind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be accepted or done successfully <vi>They <it>put through</it> a number of reforms.</vi> <vi>tax cuts that were <it>put through</it> by former administrations</vi> <vi>I asked Human Resources to help me <it>put through</it> [=to help me get] a transfer to a different department.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay for (someone) to attend (school) <vi>She has a full-time job and is <it>putting</it> herself <it>through</it> college.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to experience (something) <vi>His doctor <it>put</it> him <it>through</it> a series of tests.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> her parents <it>through</it> a lot when she was a teenager.</vi> <vi>You've been <it>put through</it> quite an ordeal.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>put through</it> hell!</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> that truck <it>through</it> a lot when we owned it.</vi> <vi>The new software still needs to be <phrase>put through its paces</phrase> [=it still needs to be tested] before it can be made available to the public.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause a phone call from (someone) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> you <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (a phone call) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> your call <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put to death</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put together (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to create (something) by joining or gathering parts together <vi>You'll need a screwdriver to <it>put</it> the toy <it>together</it>.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> their first band <it>together</it> when they were in high school.</vi> <vi>Help me <it>put together</it> a list of what we need at the store.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> a proposal <it>together</it> to give to the committee for consideration.</vi> <vi>Her outfit was very well <it>put together</it>. [=the parts looked good together]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something is greater than the total of all the other people or things mentioned <vi>You're smarter than all of those other guys <it>put together</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add or combine (something) with (something) <vi>I never would have thought of <it>putting</it> this wine together <it>with</it> fish.</vi> <vi>The lack of rain <it>put together with</it> [=along with, combined with] the heat ruined many of the region's crops.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) in a higher position <vi>They <it>put up</it> the flag in the morning and take it down at night.</vi> <vi>Sit down. <it>Put</it> your feet <it>up</it> and relax.</vi> <vi>If you have a question, please <it>put up</it> [=<it>raise</it>] your hand.</vi> <vi>Stop! <it>Put</it> your hands <it>up</it> (over your head)!</vi> <vi>When she goes to work, she usually <it>puts</it> her hair <it>up</it> (in a ponytail).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to be on a wall, to hang from a ceiling, etc. <vi>She went around town <it>putting up</it> posters for the concert.</vi> <vi>I just <it>put up</it> new curtains.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to set or place (something) so that it stands up <vi><it>putting up</it> a tent</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a display of new products.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a “for sale” sign in front of their house.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to build (something) <vi>They're <it>putting up</it> a new office building on Main Street.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a fence</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available for people to buy or have <vi>The lamps were <it>put up</it> at auction.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>They <it>put</it> all of their possessions <it>up for</it> sale.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> the puppies <it>up for</it> adoption.</vi></un></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to provide (money, property, etc.) in order to pay for something <vi>They decided not to <it>put up</it> the money for her bail.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> the company's assets as collateral on the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as a prize <vi>The police have <it>put up</it> a $1,000 reward for information leading to his capture.</vi></dt> <sn>h</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to increase (something) :<sx>raise</sx> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> interest rates again this year.</vi></dt> <sn>i</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>It's time to <it>put up</it> [=<it>put away</it>] your toys and get ready for bed.</vi> <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put up</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>j</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to preserve (fruits, vegetables, etc.) to be used later :<sx>can</sx> <vi>Their grandmother spent the afternoon <it>putting up</it> peaches.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do (something) as a way of resisting or struggling against someone or something <vi>We're not leaving without <it>putting up</it> a fight. [=without fighting]</vi> <vi>As expected, the kids <it>put up</it> a fuss when we said it was time for bed.</vi> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> stiff resistance to any new proposals.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as an argument, a suggestion, etc. <vi>She <it>put up</it> a good/solid argument in his defense.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a proposal</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to score (points) <vi>They <it>put up</it> 20 points in the first half.</vi> <vi>She needs to <it>put up</it> big numbers [=to score a lot of points] in today's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give food and shelter to (someone) :to allow or pay for (someone) to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>Could you <it>put</it> me <it>up</it> for the night?</vi> <vi>His employers <it>put</it> him <it>up</it> at a hotel.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> our guests <it>up</it> in the spare bedroom.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>He <it>put up</it> with a friend while he was in town.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> at a hotel</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or suggest (someone) to be a candidate or competitor <vi>The party <it>put</it> her <it>up</it> (as its candidate) for governor.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> their best man to compete against the champion.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to convince (someone) to do (something stupid or foolish) <vi>His friends <it>put</it> him <it>up to</it> (playing) the prank.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you <it>up</it> to this?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up with (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (someone or something unpleasant or annoying) to exist or happen :<sx>tolerate</sx> <vi>At this school, we will not <it>put up with</it> bad behavior.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>put up with</it> much more of this.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up or shut up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to tell someone in a somewhat rude way to start doing something or to stop talking about it <vi>You've complained long enough. It's time to <it>put up or shut up</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
