<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="black[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">black</hw> <sound><wav>black001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblæk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>black*er</if></in> <in><if>black*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:having the very dark color of coal or the night sky <vi><it>black</it> ink</vi> <vi>a <it>black</it> dress</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very dark because there is no light <vi>a <it>black</it> night</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>Black</va></svr> <dt>:of or relating to a race of people who have dark skin and who come originally from Africa <vi><it>black</it> people</vi> <vi><it>black</it> culture</vi> <snote>In the U.S., the term <it>African-American</it> is often preferred over <it>black</it> when referring to Americans of African descent.</snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:very dirty <vi>His hand were <it>black</it> with grime.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:served without cream or milk <vi><it>black</it> coffee</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:evil or wicked <vi>a <it>black</it> deed</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>black art</dxt> <dxt>black magic</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:very sad or hopeless :<sx>bleak</sx> <vi>The outlook was <it>black</it>.</vi> <vi>When they heard the terrible news, they were filled with <it>black</it> despair.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very tragic or unhappy <vi>That was a <it>black</it> day in our country's history.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:marked by anger or hatred <vi>A <it>black</it> [=very angry] look darkened his face.</vi> <vi><it>black</it> resentment</vi> <vi>a <it>black</it> mood</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe humor that deals with subjects which are usually regarded as very serious or unpleasant <vi>The film is a <it>black</it> comedy set in a funeral home.</vi> <vi><it>black</it> humor</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>black*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>blackly</it> funny/comic/humorous movie</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>black*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>blackness</it> of the night</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="black[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">black</hw> <altpr>ˈblæk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>blacks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the dark color of coal or the night sky <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The wall was painted in <it>black</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>black</it> of night</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a mixture of grays and <it>blacks</it></vi> <dx>see color picture on page C1</dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:black clothing <vi>She was dressed in <it>black</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person belonging to a race of people who have dark skin :a black person <snote>The singular form <it>black</it> in this sense is rarely used and is often considered offensive. It should be avoided. The plural form <it>blacks</it> is commonly used to refer to black people as a group or community. <vi>His policies are supported by both <it>blacks</it> and whites.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>in the black</dre> <def><dt>:making a profit <vi>The company is finally <it>in the black</it>. [=the company is profitable]</vi> <dx>compare <tag>in the red</tag> at <dxt>red</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="black[3]"> <hw hindex="3">black</hw> <altpr>ˈblæk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>blacks</if></in> <in><if>blacked</if></in> <in><if>black*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned + literary</ssl> <dt>:to make (something) black <vi>He <it>blacked</it> his boots with polish.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to refuse to work for or with (a business, employer, etc.) or to buy (goods, services, etc.) <vi>Labor union members have <it>blacked</it> the company.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>black out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suddenly become unconscious <vi>What's the last thing you remember before you <it>blacked out</it>? [=<it>passed out, fainted</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>black (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>black out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cover (something written) with a black or dark mark so that it cannot be read <vi>Someone had <it>blacked out</it> certain sections of the newspaper.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (a place) to become dark <vi>They <it>blacked out</it> the stage by turning off all the lights.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to prevent the broadcast of (a televised sports event) <un>usually used as <it>(be) blacked out</it> <vi>Last night's game <it>was blacked out</it> in this area, so I couldn't watch it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>blackout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="black-and-blue"> <hw>black–and–blue</hw> <sound><wav>black01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌblækənˈblu:</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:having dark marks (called bruises) on your skin because of being hit or injured <vi>He beat me <it>black-and-blue</it>. [=he beat me until I was covered with bruises]</vi> <vi>She had <it>black-and-blue</it> marks [=dark bruises] all over her legs.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="black and white"> <hw>black and white</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>in black and white</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in written or printed form <vi>I want to see it <it>in black and white</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a way that involves a simple choice between two opposite things (such as good and bad or right and wrong) <vi>She sees everything <it>in black and white</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:using equipment that produces only black-and-white pictures <vi>a movie filmed <it>in black and white</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="black-and-white"> <hw>black–and–white</hw> <sound><wav>black03w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌblækənˈwaɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:partly black and partly white in color <vi>a <it>black-and-white</it> dog</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having, showing, or producing pictures that do not have colors except for black, white, and shades of gray <vi>She loves to watch old <it>black-and-white</it> movies.</vi> <vi><it>black-and-white</it> wedding photos</vi> <vi>a <it>black-and-white</it> television set</vi> <vi>Did you put color or <it>black-and-white</it> film in the camera?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:involving a simple choice between things that are clearly opposite and especially between good and bad or right and wrong <vi>You are oversimplifying things if you only look at the situation in <it>black-and-white</it> terms.</vi> <vi>The truth is not always <it>black-and-white</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="black art"> <hw>black art</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ arts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a skill or ability that seems mysterious or magical <un>often used humorously <vi>She's trying to master the <it>black art</it> of setting up a computer network.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>the black arts</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>black magic</sx> <vi>She practices <it>the black arts</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="black bear"> <hw>black bear</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bears</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a North American bear that usually has black fur <dx>see picture at <dxt>bear</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="black belt"> <hw>black belt</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ belts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an expert in a martial art such as karate or tae kwon do <vi>She is a karate <it>black belt</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the rank of such an expert <vi>He has a <it>black belt</it> in judo.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="black box"> <hw>black box</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boxes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a device used in an airplane to record flight information (such as altitude or airspeed) or the voices of the pilots and crew <vi>The <it>black boxes</it> were recovered from the crash site and provided useful information about the cause of the crash.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
