<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="blame[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">blame</hw> <sound><wav>blame001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbleɪm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>blames</if></in> <in><if>blamed</if></in> <in><if>blam*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to say or think that a person or thing is responsible for something bad that has happened <vi>Don't <it>blame</it> me. You are responsible for your own problems.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>blame</it> me for your problems. = Don't <it>blame</it> your problems on me.</vi> <vi>The company <it>blames</it> the poor economy for its financial losses. = The company <it>blames</it> its financial losses on the poor economy.</vi> <vi>My father always <it>blames</it> everything on me.</vi> <vi>I <it>blame</it> the poor harvest on the weather.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blame the messenger</dre> <dx>see <dxt>messenger</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have yourself to blame</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>have only yourself to blame</phrase> or <phrase>have no one to blame but yourself</phrase>, then something is your fault and nobody else's. <vi>She <it>has only herself to blame</it> for her money problems.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not blame</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you say that you <phrase>wouldn't/don't/can't blame someone</phrase> or <phrase>can hardly blame someone</phrase>, you think that person has a good reason for doing something. <vi>After the way he treated you, I <it>wouldn't blame you</it> [=I would completely understand] if you never spoke to him again.</vi> <vi>You <it>can hardly blame her</it> for being angry.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to blame</dre> <def><dt>:responsible for something bad :deserving to be blamed for something. <vi>Who's <it>to blame</it> for these problems?</vi> <vi>He says he's not <it>to blame</it> for the delays. [=he did not cause the delays]</vi> <vi>Poor communication is at least partly <it>to blame</it>. [=<it>at fault</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blame[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">blame</hw> <altpr>ˈbleɪm</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:responsibility for something that fails or is wrong <vi>It's not entirely his fault, but he's not completely free of <it>blame</it>, either.</vi> <vi>He deserves <it>blame</it> [=deserves to be blamed] for his careless behavior.</vi> <un>usually used with <it>the</it> <vi><it>The blame</it> lies with me. [=I am at fault; I am to blame]</vi> <vi>It's not fair—she gets the credit when things go well, and I get <it>the blame</it> when they fail.</vi> <vi>Don't try to put/lay/pin <it>the blame</it> for your problems on me.</vi> <vi>The coach <phrase>took the blame</phrase> for the defeat. [=the coach said he was responsible for the defeat]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>the finger of blame</tag> at <dxt>finger</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="door"> <art><artref id="door_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,195.8</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes">door</hw> <sound><wav>door0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdoɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>doors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a movable piece of wood, glass, or metal that swings or slides open and shut so that people can enter or leave a room, building, vehicle, etc. <vi>open/shut/slam/lock/bolt the <it>door</it></vi> <vi>I heard a knock on/at the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>the bedroom/bathroom/cellar <it>door</it></vi> <vi>The car has four <it>doors</it>. = It's a four-<it>door</it> car.</vi> <vi>Leave the package at the front/back/side <it>door</it>. [=the door at the front/back/side of the house, building, etc.]</vi> <vi>Can you <phrase>answer the door</phrase>? [=open the door to see who is knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Is somebody <phrase>at the door</phrase>? [=knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Let me open the <it>door</it> for you. = (<it>US</it>) Let me <phrase>get the door</phrase> for you.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Can you <it>get the door</it>? [=can you open or close the door for me?] My hands are full.</vi> <vi>an <phrase>exterior/outside door</phrase> [=a door that can be used to enter or leave a building]</vi> <vi>an <phrase>interior door</phrase> [=a door inside a building; a door that connects rooms]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>garage door</phrase> [=a large door that covers the opening through which a car enters and leaves a garage]</vi> <vi>turn/pull the <phrase>door handle</phrase></vi> <vi>a large brass <phrase>door knocker</phrase> [=<it>knocker</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back door</dxt> <dxt>dutch door</dxt> <dxt>french door</dxt> <dxt>revolving door</dxt> <dxt>storm door</dxt> <dxt>trapdoor</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a part of an object (such as piece of furniture or an appliance) that swings or slides open and shut <vi>the cupboard/closet/refrigerator/oven <it>door</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the opening for a door :the entrance to a room or building :<sx>doorway</sx> <vi>Please don't block the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>I peeked through the open <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He stood at/before the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He greeted his guests as they <phrase>came in/through the door</phrase>. = He greeted his guests <phrase>at the door</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>walked out the door</phrase> [=<it>left</it>] without saying goodbye.</vi> <vi>standing (just/right) <phrase>inside/outside the door</phrase> [=inside/outside the room, building, etc., near the door]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a house, building, apartment, office, etc. <un>used with an adverb to indicate where something is in relation to something else <vi>She lives in a house two <phrase>doors down/up</phrase> from me. [=there is one house between our houses]</vi> <vi>The library is a <phrase>few doors down</phrase> from the bank. [=there are several buildings between the library and the bank]</vi> <vi>We grew up <phrase>two doors apart</phrase>. [=with one house/apartment between our houses/apartments]</vi></un> <snote>If you do something <phrase>(from) door to door</phrase>, you do it at each of the houses, apartments, or buildings in an area. <vi>Girl Scouts are selling cookies <it>door to door</it>. = Girl Scouts are <phrase>going door to door</phrase> selling cookies.</vi> <vi>She <it>went (from) door to door</it> looking for her cat.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>door-to-door</dxt> <dxt>next door</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used especially with <it>open</it> or <it>unlock</it> to describe an opportunity or possibility <vi>The grant will <it>open</it> new <it>doors</it> for our town. [=will give our town new opportunities]</vi> <vi>The discovery may <it>unlock</it> the <it>door</it> to a cure for the disease.</vi> <vi>The <it>door</it> is <it>open</it> (to you) if you want a better job.</vi> <vi>A good education can <it>open/unlock</it> the <it>door</it> of success. [=can make success possible]</vi> <vi>The patent on the product has expired, which <phrase>leaves the door open for</phrase> [=makes it possible for] other companies to make it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>out of doors</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>at death's door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>behind closed doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>closed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close the door on</dre> <def><dt>:to no longer think about, consider, or accept (something) <vi>I'd like to <it>close the door on</it> that chapter in my life.</vi> <vi>The former senator says she hasn't <it>closed the door on</it> politics.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>close the door on</it> your options.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>closed its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to close permanently :to stop operating <vi>The museum may be forced to <it>close its doors</it>.</vi> <vi>The store <it>closed its doors</it> (for the last time) last fall.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>darken someone's door/doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>darken</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your foot in the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep the wolf from the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wolf</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay the blame for (something) at someone's door</dre> <def><dt>:to blame someone for (something) <vi>They <it>laid the blame for</it> the book's failure <it>at my door</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open doors for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>opened its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi> <vi>local churches that <it>open their doors</it> to the homeless in the winter months [=that let homeless people stay there]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to open for business :to begin operating <vi>The new store will be <it>opening its doors</it> next month.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show (someone) the door</dre> <def><dt>:to tell or force (someone) to leave <vi>We don't tolerate bad behavior. If you cause trouble, we'll <it>show you the door</it>.</vi> <vi>If the coach doesn't win this year, they'll <it>show him the door</it>. [=they'll fire him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show/see (someone) to the door</dre> <def><dt>:to go to the door with (someone who is leaving) <vi>My secretary will <it>show you to the door</it>. [=<it>show you out</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>doorless</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>doorless</it> cubicle</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="finger[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fin*ger</hw> <sound><wav>finger01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɪŋgɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>fin*gers</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the five long parts of the hand that are used for holding things</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:one of the four that are not the thumb <vi>Don't stick your <it>fingers</it> in the cookie batter!</vi> <vi>He slipped the ring onto her <it>finger</it>.</vi> <vi>The baby held onto my thumb with her tiny <it>fingers</it>.</vi> <vi>She ran her <it>fingers</it> through his hair.</vi> <vi>He drummed his <it>fingers</it> on the table impatiently.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>forefinger</dxt> <dxt>index finger</dxt> <dxt>little finger</dxt> <dxt>middle finger</dxt> <dxt>ring finger</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something that is long and thin and looks like a finger <vi>a <it>finger</it> of land extending into the sea</vi> <vi>a <it>finger</it> of flame</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a glove into which a finger is placed</dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the finger</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an obscene gesture made by pointing the middle finger up, keeping the other fingers down, and turning the palm towards you <vi>She was so mad, she <phrase>gave him the finger</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Some angry driver <phrase>flipped me the finger</phrase> on the highway this morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all fingers and thumbs</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very clumsy <vi>Sorry I dropped the vase; I'm <it>all fingers and thumbs</it> today.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross your fingers</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>finger on the pulse</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>have/keep your finger on the pulse of</phrase> something, you know about the latest things that are happening. <vi>He claims that he <it>has/keeps his finger on the pulse of</it> the computer industry. [=that he is very aware what is happening in the computer industry]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a finger in a/the pie</dre> <def><dt>:to have an interest or share in something <vi>a sharp talent agent who <it>has a finger in</it> nearly every <it>pie</it> in show business</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>itchy finger</dre> <dx>see <dxt>itchy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your fingers crossed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay a finger on</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to touch or hit (someone) <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I don't know what he's complaining about. I never <it>laid a finger on him</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lift a finger</dre> <def><dt>:to make an effort to do something <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I have so many chores to do, and my sister won't <it>lift a finger</it> to help me.</vi> <vi>He never <it>lifted a finger</it> to try to improve his failing grades.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>point an accusing finger at</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>point a/the finger at</va></vr> <def><dt>:to accuse or blame (someone) <vi>He was quick to <it>point an accusing finger at</it> his coworkers.</vi> <vi>Let's stop <it>pointing fingers at</it> each other and just solve the problem!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick two fingers up at someone</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to make an obscene gesture by holding up the index finger and the middle finger of one hand in the shape of a V while keeping the palm turned inward</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your finger on</dre> <def><dt>:to find out the exact nature of (something) :<sx>identify</sx> <vi>I feel that something is wrong but I can't quite <it>put my finger on</it> the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the finger of blame/suspicion</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone is being blamed or suspected <vi>He was shocked to realize that the <it>finger of suspicion</it> was now pointed at him. [=that he was now suspected]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>work your fingers to the bone</dre> <def><dt>:to work very hard <vi>She had to <it>work her fingers to the bone</it> to make enough money to raise her kids.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wrap (someone) around your (little) finger</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wrap</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>fin*gered</ure> <pr>ˈfɪŋgɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><un>used in combination <vi>three<it>-fingered</it></vi></un></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>fin*ger*like</ure> <sound><wav>finger03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɪŋgɚˌlaɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="messenger"> <hw>mes*sen*ger</hw> <sound><wav>messen01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmɛsn̩ʤɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>mes*sen*gers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:someone who delivers a message or does other small jobs that involve going somewhere <vi>Their company's <it>messenger</it> brought us the plans. = The company's plans were brought to us by <it>messenger</it>.</vi> <vi>They sent a <it>messenger</it> to pick up the package.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blame/shoot the messenger</dre> <def><dt>:to become angry at someone who has told you bad news</dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
