<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="boiling[1]"> <hw hindex="1">boil*ing</hw> <sound><wav>boilin01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɪlɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:very hot <vi>a <it>boiling</it> sun</vi> <vi>a <it>boiling</it> summer day</vi> <vi>I'm <it>boiling</it> in this suit.</vi> <vi>It is <it>boiling</it> in here.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="boiling[2]"> <hw hindex="2">boiling</hw> <altpr>ˈboɪlɪŋ</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:very or extremely <vi>The sun was <phrase>boiling hot</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>boiling mad</phrase> at how he was treated.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="boil[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">boil</hw> <sound><wav>boil0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbojəl</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>boils</if></in> <in><if>boiled</if></in> <in><if>boil*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to become so hot that bubbles are formed in a liquid and rise to the top <vi>Let the water <it>boil</it>.</vi> <vi>Keep the temperature low enough so the mixture will not <it>boil</it>.</vi> <vi>a pot of <it>boiling</it> water</vi> <vi>The kettle (of water) is <it>boiling</it>. = The water in the kettle is <it>boiling</it>.</vi> <vi>french fries cooked in <it>boiling</it> oil</vi> <vi>Cook the mixture until the liquid has <phrase>boiled away</phrase>. [=until the liquid has gone; until all of the liquid has turned into steam]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to heat (a liquid or a container with liquid in it) so that bubbles are formed and rise to the top <vi><it>Boil</it> (up) some water.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>boil</it> a kettle (of water) for tea?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cook (something) in water that is boiling <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Boil</it> the eggs/vegetables.</vi> <vi>Make sure you <it>boil</it> (up) a lot of potatoes.</vi> <vi><it>boiled</it> eggs/potatoes</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He put some potatoes on to <it>boil</it>. [=he put a pot with potatoes and water in it on the stove and turned the burner on]</vi> <vi>The pasta is <it>boiling</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to feel a strong emotion (such as anger) <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>The crowd <it>boiled</it> [=<it>seethed</it>] <it>with</it> anger.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a watched pot never boils</dre> <def><dt><snote>The expression <it>a watched pot never boils</it> means that time passes very slowly when you are waiting for something to happen if that is the only thing you are thinking about.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>boil down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to become reduced in amount by boiling <vi>Let the sauce <it>boil down</it> and thicken.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>boil (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>boil down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reduce the amount of (a liquid) by boiling it <vi><it>Boil down</it> the sauce so that it thickens.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>boil (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>boil down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (something) short or simple by removing the parts that are not important or necessary <vi>He was able to <it>boil down</it> [=<it>condense</it>] the report to a brief summary.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>boil down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (something) as the main or basic part <vi>His speech <it>boiled down to</it> [=was basically] a plea for more money.</vi> <vi>Their objections all <it>boil down to</it> one thing: cost.</vi> <vi>You can get advice from many sources, but it all <it>boils down to</it> common sense. [=you should be guided by common sense]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>boil over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to flow over the side of a container while boiling <vi>The water in the pot is <it>boiling over</it>. = The pot (of water) is <it>boiling over</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become violent or to lose control because of anger <vi>He's so mad that he's ready to <it>boil over</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change <it>into</it> something more violent <vi>Their disagreement finally <it>boiled over into</it> a fight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>boil up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to grow toward a dangerous level <vi>He could feel the anger <it>boiling up</it> inside him. [=he could feel himself becoming very angry]</vi> <vi>Problems have been <it>boiling up</it> in the cities during the hot summer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood boil</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="boiling point"> <hw>boiling point</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ points</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the temperature at which a liquid begins to boil <vi>The <it>boiling point</it> of water is 212° Fahrenheit or 100° Celsius.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the point at which people might do or say something violent or might take some definite or extreme action because of anger, disagreement, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>The incident brought tensions to a <it>boiling point</it>.</vi> <vi>He sensed he had reached his <it>boiling point</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) Tempers are reaching the <it>boiling point</it>.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Tempers are reaching <it>boiling point</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
