<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="book[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">book</hw> <sound><wav>book0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>books</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a set of printed sheets of paper that are held together inside a cover :a long written work <vi>The shelves in his office are filled with <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>That's one of the best <it>books</it> I've read in a long time.</vi> <vi>a novelist who has written some wonderful <it>books</it></vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> about plumbing</vi> <vi>The library has many dictionaries and other reference <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>a hardcover/paperback <it>book</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can learn many things by studying the great <it>book</it> of nature. [=by studying nature]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long written work that can be read on a computer :<sx>e-book</sx> <vi>an electronic <it>book</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of sheets of paper that are inside a cover and that you can write information on <vi>an appointment <it>book</it></vi> <vi>an address <it>book</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>notebook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a major section of a long written work (such as the Bible) <vi>the <it>books</it> of the Bible</vi> <vi>a story that is told in the <it>Book</it> of Job</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good book</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of things held together inside a cover like the pages of a book <vi>a <it>book</it> of stamps</vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> of matches [=a matchbook]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkbook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>books</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the financial records of a business <vi>The company's <it>books</it> [=<it>accounts</it>] show a profit.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the official records of a business or organization <vi>I'm sorry, but your name does not appear in/on our <it>books</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the knowledge or information that relates to a particular subject, person, etc. <vi><it>The book</it> on him is that he can't hit a curveball. [=people have seen and reported that he can't hit a curveball]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>phone book</sx> <vi>Give me a call if you need to. I'm in <it>the book</it>. [=my telephone number is listed in the telephone book]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a closed book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is difficult to understand <vi>Even to his closest friends, he was always something of <it>a closed book</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>an open book <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an open book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is easy to learn about and understand <vi>My life is <it>an open book</it>. I have nothing to hide.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (someone) to book</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>The people responsible for these crimes must be <it>brought to book</it>. [=<it>brought to account</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by the book</dre> <def><dt>:by following the official rules very strictly <vi>My boss insists on doing everything <it>by the book</it>.</vi> <vi>They ran all the investigations <it>by the book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cook the books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cook</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every trick in the book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the books</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to study or begin studying very intensely <vi>I've got to <it>hit the books</it> all weekend if I'm going to pass this test.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in my book</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She deserves credit, <it>in my book</it>, for much of the company's recent success.</vi> <vi>He isn't even a good boss, at least not <it>in my book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's bad books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are not liked or treated nicely by someone <vi>He remains <it>in her bad books</it>. [=she is still displeased with him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's good books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are liked or are treated nicely by someone <vi>He's trying to get back <it>in his boss's good books</it> by offering to work overtime.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one for the books</dre> <def><dt>:a very unusual, important, or surprising situation, statement, event, etc. <vi>There have been a lot of scandals in local politics over the years, but this is <it>one for the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the books</dre> <def><dt>:part of the set of official laws <vi>It's an outdated law that's still <it>on the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>read someone like a book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>read</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>suit someone's book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>suit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>throw the book at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to punish (someone) as severely as possible <vi>The judge threatened to <it>throw the book at</it> him if he committed another offense.</vi> <vi>I thought I would get off with just a warning, but they <it>threw the book at</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>write the book on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>write</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="book[2]"> <hw hindex="2">book</hw> <altpr>ˈbʊk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>books</if></in> <in><if>booked</if></in> <in><if>book*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make arrangements so that you will be able to use or have (something, such as a room, table, or seat) at a later time <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We <it>booked</it> [=<it>reserved</it>] a hotel room.</vi> <vi>They <it>booked</it> two seats at the theater.</vi> <vi>They <it>booked</it> tickets for a direct flight from London to New York.</vi> <vi>I <it>booked</it> a table at our favorite restaurant.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>booked</it> through her travel agent.</vi> <vi>We will need to <it>book</it> early.</vi> <snote>This sense is used in U.S. English, but it is more common in British English. In U.S. English, <it>reserve</it> or <it>make a reservation for</it> is more commonly used.</snote> <snote>When a hotel, restaurant, etc., is <phrase>booked (up)</phrase>, <phrase>booked solid</phrase>, or <phrase>fully booked</phrase>, there are no more rooms, tables, etc., available. These forms are commonly used in both U.S. and British English. <vi>The hotels in the city were <it>booked solid</it> for the conference.</vi> <vi>The flight was <it>fully booked</it>.</vi> <vi>The hotel was all <it>booked up</it> for the week.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make arrangements for (someone) to do, use, or have something at a later time <vi>She <it>booked</it> me on a flight from Oslo to Paris.</vi> <vi>He was <it>booked</it> to sail on Monday.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to schedule a performance or appearance by (someone, such as a musician) <vi>The band was <it>booked</it> to play at the reception.</vi> <vi><it>book</it> a singer</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to write down in an official police record the name of (a person who is being charged with a crime) <un>usually used as <it>(be) booked</it> <vi>She <it>was booked</it> on suspicion of murder.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>of a soccer referee</ssl> <dt>:to write down in an official book the name of (a player who has broken the rules in a game) <un>usually used as <it>(be) booked</it> <vi>He <it>was booked</it> for a late tackle.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>book in/into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>book in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>book into (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to arrive at and be given a room in a hotel, an inn, etc. <vi>We <it>booked in</it> [=<it>checked in</it>] shortly after noon.</vi> <vi>We <it>booked into</it> [=<it>checked into</it>] our hotel shortly after noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>book*able</ure> <sound><wav>book0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊkəbə</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <utxt><vi><it>bookable</it> flights/seats</vi> <vi><it>bookable</it> hotel rooms</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="book[3]"> <hw hindex="3">book</hw> <altpr>ˈbʊk</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:learned from reading books and not from experience <vi>His schooling provided him with extensive <it>book</it> knowledge/learning.</vi> <vi>She had plenty of <it>book</it> learning but no hands-on experience.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="book club"> <hw>book club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an organization that sells books to its members at low prices</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a group of people who meet to talk about the books that they are reading</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="book token"> <hw>book token</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -kens</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a card that can be used instead of money to pay for books :a gift certificate for buying books</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="book value"> <hw>book value</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>finance</sl> <dt>:the amount of money that something (such as a car) is officially worth based on its age, style, condition, etc. <vi>I paid $4,100 for the car four years ago, but its <it>book value</it> is now under $500.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="address book"> <hw>address book</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ books</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small book in which you write the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of people you know</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a place on a computer or other device for storing e-mail addresses, phone numbers, etc.</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="audio book"> <hw>audio book</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ books</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a recording of a book or magazine being read <vi>I listen to <it>audio books</it> when I drive to work.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blue book"> <hw>blue book</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ books</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a report that is published by the government <vi>The information is listed in the <it>blue book</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a thin booklet with a blue cover and empty pages that is often used for writing the answers to test questions in college</dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a book that lists the current value of items (such as used cars)</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="coffee-table book"> <hw>coffee–table book</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ books</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a large expensive book with many pictures that is typically placed on a table for people to look at in a casual way</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
