<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="boot[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">boot</hw> <sound><wav>boot0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbu:t</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>boots</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a covering usually of leather or rubber for the entire foot and the lower part of the leg <vi>You'll need a pair of warm <it>boots</it> for winter.</vi> <vi>It's been snowing, so you'd better wear your <it>boots</it>.</vi> <vi>hiking <it>boots</it> [=boots worn for hiking]</vi> <vi>riding <it>boots</it> [=boots worn for horseback riding]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>shoe</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>booted</dxt> <dxt>cowboy boot</dxt> <dxt>hobnail boot</dxt> <dxt>ski boot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a forceful kick with the foot <vi>She gave the ball a <it>boot</it>, and it landed on the other side of the field.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the boot</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a sudden dismissal from a job <vi>He <phrase>got the boot</phrase> [=<it>got fired</it>] for talking to the press about company secrets.</vi> <vi>I heard they <phrase>gave her the boot</phrase>. [=they fired her; they told her she could no longer work for them]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the trunk of a car</dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:<sx>denver boot</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>as tough as old boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tough</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lick someone's boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the boot is on the other foot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to boot</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>besides</sx> <sx>also</sx> <vi>He's smart, funny, and handsome <it>to boot</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too big for your boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>big</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to put the boot in</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to treat someone in a cruel or critical way</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to kick someone again and again</dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>bossy-boots</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="boot[2]"> <hw hindex="2">boot</hw> <altpr>ˈbu:t</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>boots</if></in> <in><if>boot*ed</if></in> <in><if>boot*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to kick (something) forcefully <vi>She <it>booted</it> the ball across the field.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to force (someone) to leave a place or situation <vi>He left public service after voters <it>booted</it> him from the mayor's office. [=he chose not to work for the government after he was not reelected as mayor]</vi> <vi>Any players who start a fight will get <it>booted</it> from the game.</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> <vi>His wife <it>booted</it> him <it>out</it>. [=his wife made him leave their home]</vi> <vi>He got <it>booted out</it> of office in the last election.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to dismiss (someone) suddenly from a job <vi>She got <it>booted</it> [=<it>fired</it>] in May and has been looking for work ever since.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to start a computer <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The new computer <it>boots</it> much more quickly than the old one did.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>Did you <it>boot up</it> yet?</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You don't need all these applications to open every time you <it>boot</it> your computer.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She <it>booted up</it> the computer.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>reboot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to lock a special device (called a Denver boot) onto one of the wheels of (a car) so that the car cannot be moved <vi>His car was <it>booted</it> (by the police).</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="boot camp"> <hw>boot camp</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ camps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a camp where people who have recently joined the U.S. Army, Navy, or Marine Corps receive their basic training</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a short but very difficult training program :a program or situation that helps people become much better at doing something in a short period of time <vi>business <it>boot camp</it></vi> <vi><it>boot camp</it> for artists</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="car boot sale"> <hw>car boot sale</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sales</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a sale in which people gather to sell items that they bring to the sale in their cars</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cowboy boot"> <hw>cowboy boot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a type of boot that has a thick heel and often a decorative design on the upper part and that is worn especially by cowboys and cowgirls <dx>see picture at <dxt>shoe</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Denver boot"> <hw>Den*ver boot</hw> <sound><wav>denver01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛnvɚ-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:an object that the police lock onto one of the wheels of a car so that the car cannot be moved <snote>A Denver boot is usually placed on a car in order to force the car's owner to pay money that is owed for parking illegally.</snote> <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>boot</cat> (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>clamp</cat> (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>wheel clamp</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hobnail boot"> <hw>hob*nail boot</hw> <sound><wav>hobna01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑ:bˌneɪl-</pr> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hob*nailed boot</va> <sound><wav>hobna02ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑ:bˌneɪld-</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a heavy boot with short nails driven into the bottom to protect against wear</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="rubber boot"> <hw>rubber boot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a tall boot that is made out of rubber and that keeps your feet and lower legs dry <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>Wellington</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ski boot"> <hw>ski boot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a boot or shoe made to be fastened to skis <dx>see picture at <dxt>ski</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="foot[1]"> <art><artref id="foot_rev2.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,96</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">foot</hw> <sound><wav>foot0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfʊt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>feet</if> <sound><wav>foot0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfi:t</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the leg on which an animal or person stands and moves :the part of the leg below the ankle <vi>He was wearing boots on his <it>feet</it>.</vi> <vi>tracks made by the <it>feet</it> of a bird</vi> <vi>standing on one <it>foot</it></vi> <vi>The people in the crowd began to stamp their <it>feet</it>.</vi> <vi>She was walking around the house in (her) bare <it>feet</it>. [=she was not wearing any shoes or socks]</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>in her stockinged/stocking feet</phrase>. [=she was wearing socks but no shoes]</vi> <vi>It's a long hike, but we'll get there if we just keep <phrase>putting one foot in front of the other</phrase>. [=if we just keep walking]</vi> <vi><phrase>Wipe your feet</phrase> [=rub the bottoms of your shoes on the doormat] when you come in.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>foot</it> pump [=a pump that is operated by being pressed with the foot]</vi> <vi>a <it>foot</it> brake</vi> <vi>an area that gets a lot of <phrase>foot traffic</phrase> [=an area where many people walk]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>athlete's foot</dxt> <dxt>clubfoot</dxt> <dxt>cold feet</dxt> <dxt>flat foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sin><il>plural also</il> <if>foot</if></sin> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a unit of measurement equal to <frac>1/3</frac> yard (0.3048 meter) or 12 inches <vi>a 10-<it>foot</it> pole = a pole 10 <it>feet</it> long</vi> <vi>He's six <it>feet</it> tall.</vi> <vi>He's six <it>feet</it>, three inches tall. = He's six <it>foot</it> three.</vi> <vi>a plant that grows three <it>feet</it> tall = a three-<it>foot</it>-tall plant</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the lowest part of something :<sx>bottom</sx> <vi>They camped at the <it>foot</it> of the mountain.</vi> <vi>at the <it>foot</it> of the stairs</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the end of something that is opposite to the end that is called the head <vi>the <it>foot</it> of the bed [=the end where your feet are when you are lying on the bed]</vi> <vi>the <it>foot</it> of the table</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a basic unit of rhythm in a line of poetry made up of a group of syllables that are accented in a certain way <vi>Each line of the poem has five <it>feet</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at someone's feet</dre> <def><dt>:close to someone's feet <vi>His dog was lying <it>at his feet</it>.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was young and fearless, and he felt the world was <it>at his feet</it>. [=felt that he could do great things in the world]</vi> <vi>She claimed that men fell <it>at her feet</it>. [=that men often fell in love with her]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be run/rushed off your feet</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be very busy <vi>We <it>are run off our feet</it> trying to fill orders.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drag your feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>drag</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>feet of clay</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person who was admired in the past but who has serious faults or flaws can be described as having <it>feet of clay</it>. <vi>a former political leader who turned out to have <it>feet of clay</it></vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find your feet</dre> <def><dt>:to start to be comfortable in a new situation :to begin to be confident or successful <vi>They quickly <it>found their feet</it> in their adopted country.</vi> <vi>I was away for a long time, so it will take me a while to <it>find my feet</it> again.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get/start off on the right foot</dre> <def><dt>:to begin a relationship well <vi>I want to <it>get off on the right foot</it> with your parents.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get/start off on the wrong foot</dre> <def><dt>:to begin a relationship badly <vi>They <it>got off on the wrong foot</it> when they first met and they've disliked each other ever since.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your feet wet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your foot in the door</dre> <def><dt>:to make the first step toward a goal by gaining entry into an organization, a career, etc. <vi>He took a job as a secretary to <it>get his foot in the door</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hand and foot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have one foot in the grave</dre> <def><dt>:to be close to dying because of old age or illness</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep your feet on the ground</dre> <def><dt>:to be a sensible and practical person <vi>Even after she became famous, she always <it>kept her feet on the ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let the grass grow under your feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grass</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>light on your feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>my foot</dre> <def><sl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise or disagreement <vi>Fair, <it>my foot</it>! That contest wasn't fair!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off your feet</dre> <def><dt>:not in a standing position :in or into a sitting or lying position <vi>The blow knocked me <it>off my feet</it>.</vi> <vi>The doctor suggested that he stay <it>off his feet</it> [=that he avoid standing and walking] as much as possible.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on foot</dre> <def><dt>:by walking <vi>The refugees traveled <it>on foot</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your feet</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a standing position <vi>I've been <it>on my feet</it> all day.</vi> <vi>He jumped over the wall and landed <it>on his feet</it>.</vi> <vi>They say that no matter how a cat falls, it always manages to land <it>on its feet</it>.</vi> <vi>By the end of the day the workers were <phrase>dead on their feet</phrase>. [=very tired but still standing, working, etc.]</vi> <snote>In figurative use, to <phrase>land on your feet</phrase> or <it>Brit</it> <phrase>fall on your feet</phrase> is to be lucky and be in good condition or in a good situation after having a bad or difficult experience. <vi>He lost his job but <it>landed on his feet</it> when he was hired by another company just a few days later.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a good position or condition <vi>The business is finally/back <it>on its feet</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in a healthy condition after an illness or injury <vi>She should be out of the hospital and (back) <it>on her feet</it> again in a couple of weeks.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:quickly and while actively doing something <vi>Good debaters can think <it>on their feet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put a foot wrong</dre> <def><dt>:to make a mistake <vi>He never <it>put a foot wrong</it> during the campaign.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your best foot forward</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to behave very well so that someone will like you and approve of you <vi>When I visited my girlfriend's parents I tried to be very polite and <it>put my best foot forward</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to try as hard as possible to do something difficult <vi>I've got to <it>put my best foot forward</it> [=do my best] to meet this deadline.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your feet up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to sit and relax :to not work or be active <vi>I'm going to go home and <it>put my feet up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your foot down</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to deal with someone in a harsh or strict way <vi>When my son broke his curfew for the third time, I knew it was time to <it>put my foot down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to make a car go faster</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your foot in your mouth</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>put your foot in it</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to say something that causes someone to be embarrassed, upset, or hurt especially when you did not expect that reaction <vi>I really <it>put my foot in it</it> when I asked her about her job. I didn't know she'd just been fired.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set foot in</dre> <def><dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>That was the last time she ever <it>set foot in</it> this house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set foot on</dre> <def><dt>:to walk on (something) <vi>Neil Armstrong was the first man to <it>set foot on</it> the surface of the moon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>shoot yourself in the foot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shoot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand on your own two feet</dre> <def><dt>:to support yourself without help from other people <vi>You can't live with your parents forever. It's time to get a place of your own and learn to <it>stand on your own two feet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep (someone) off his/her feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sweep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the shoe is on the other foot</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>the boot is on the other foot</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that a situation has changed to the opposite of what it was before <vi>I used to boss my little sister around. Now <it>the shoe is on the other foot</it>. [=now she bosses me around]</vi> <vi><it>The shoe is on the other foot</it> and he is the one asking for help this time.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to your feet</dre> <def><dt>:to a standing position <vi>I got/rose <it>to my feet</it> [=I stood up] and left.</vi> <vi>His inspirational speech brought the crowd <it>to its feet</it>.</vi> <vi>Everyone in the courtroom came <it>to their feet</it> when the judge entered.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two left feet</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person who dances badly can be described as having <it>two left feet</it>. <vi>My wife is a good dancer, but I've got <it>two left feet</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>under your feet</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:in the way :<sx>underfoot</sx> <vi>I can't get any work done with those kids <it>under my feet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>vote with your feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>vote</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
