<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="borrow"> <hw highlight="yes">bor*row</hw> <sound><wav>borrow01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑroʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bor*rows</if></in> <in><if>bor*rowed</if></in> <in><if>bor*row*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take and use (something that belongs to someone else) for a period of time before returning it <vi>Can I <it>borrow</it> your camera? [=will you lend me your camera]</vi> <vi>The twins often <it>borrow</it> each other's clothes.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>borrowing</it> a friend's car for the weekend.</vi> <vi>He <it>borrowed</it> the book from the library.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take and use up (something) with the promise to give back something of equal value <vi>Will you see if we can <it>borrow</it> a cup of sugar from the neighbors?</vi> <vi>She <it>borrowed</it> $20 from me.</vi> <snote>When people borrow money from a bank they pay back the same amount over a number of months or years plus an added amount that is called <it>interest</it>. <vi>He <it>borrowed</it> money from the bank to buy the car.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (an idea, saying, etc.) that was thought up by someone else <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The speech was peppered with phrases <it>borrowed</it> from Winston Churchill.</vi> <vi>She <it>borrowed</it> the technique from local artisans.</vi> <vi>The company is <phrase>borrowing a page from</phrase> [=using a technique or idea first used by] its largest competitor.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>borrows</it> heavily [=includes many ideas] from other philosophers in the book.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use (a word or phrase from another language) in a language <vi>The English word “entrepreneur” was <it>borrowed</it> from (the) French.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>in subtracting from a number with two or more digits</ssl> <dt>:to take 1 from a digit and add it as 10 to the digit in the next lower place</dt></def> <dro><dre>beg, borrow, or/and steal</dre> <dx>see <dxt>beg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be living on borrowed time</dre> <def><dt>:to continue to be alive after you were expected to die <vi>After his heart attack, my grandfather always felt that he was <it>living on borrowed time</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bor*row*er</ure> <sound><wav>borrow02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑrəwɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bor*row*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>Each <it>borrower's</it> payments will vary according to the terms of the loan.</vi> <vi>the library's <it>borrowers</it> [=people who borrow books from the library]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="beg"> <hw highlight="yes">beg</hw> <sound><wav>beg00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛg</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>begs</if></in> <in><if>begged</if></in> <in><if>beg*ging</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to ask people for money or food <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>A homeless man <it>begs</it> on that corner every day.</vi> <vi>children <it>begging</it> for food</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>children <it>begging</it> strangers for food</vi> <vi>children <it>begging</it> food from strangers</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to ask (someone) in a very serious and emotional way for something needed or wanted very much <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>begged</it> the doctor for medicine.</vi> <vi>He <it>begged</it> her for forgiveness. = He <it>begged</it> her to forgive him.</vi> <vi>She <it>begged</it> him to read the story again.</vi> <vi>I <it>beg</it> you to help them! = Help them, I <it>beg</it> you!</vi> <vi>“Help them!” I <it>begged</it>.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un><it>+ of</it> <vi>(<it>formal</it>) I <it>beg of</it> you to help them!</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to ask for (something needed or wanted very much) in a very serious and emotional way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He got down on his knees and <it>begged</it> forgiveness. = He got down on his knees and <it>begged</it> to be forgiven.</vi> <vi>He <it>begged</it> that she would forgive him.</vi> <vi><it>begging</it> a favor of someone</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He's too proud to <it>beg</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>begged</it> for forgiveness.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a dog</ssl> <dt>:to sit up on the back legs with the front legs raised <vi>“Does your dog know any tricks?” “She knows how to <it>beg</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>of a thing</ssl> <dt>:to seem perfect for some purpose :to be very well suited for something <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I couldn't resist cutting some of the flowers. They were just <it>begging to be made</it> into a bouquet.</vi> <vi>a scene <it>begging to be photographed</it> [=a scene that should be photographed]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>beg, borrow, or/and steal</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to do whatever is necessary to get something that is wanted or needed <vi>We'll have to <it>beg, borrow, or steal</it> the extra chairs we need for the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beg leave</dre> <def><sl>formal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to ask for permission <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>We <it>beg leave to offer</it> our humble thanks.</vi> <vi>I <it>beg leave to differ</it> with you, sir.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beg off</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to say that you cannot do something that you have been asked to do or have agreed to do <vi>He originally said he'd go to the party, but he later <it>begged off</it> (going), claiming he had to work that night.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beg the question</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to ask a specified question as a reaction or response <vi>The quarterback's injury <it>begs the question</it> of who will start in his place.</vi> <vi>The tragic drowning <it>begs the question</it>: why are there no safe places in the area for children to swim?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to ignore a question or issue by assuming it has been answered or settled <vi>Their proposed solution <it>begs the question</it> of whether the changes in the town are actually a problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beg to differ</dre> <def><dt>:to politely disagree with someone <vi>You say that the candidates are essentially the same, but I <it>beg to differ</it>. [=I do not agree]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beg your pardon</dre> <def><dt><snote>The phrase <it>I beg your pardon</it> is used in polite speech to apologize when you have done something impolite or when you have made a mistake. <vi><it>I beg your pardon</it>. [=<it>sorry, excuse me</it>] I didn't mean to bump into you like that.</vi> <vi><it>I beg your pardon</it>. You're correct; the amount is 12 dollars.</vi> It can be used to show that you are annoyed or offended by something that another person has said. <vi>“That boy isn't very bright.” “<it>I beg your pardon</it>! That's my son!”</vi> It can also be used as a question when you have not heard or understood something clearly. <vi><it>I beg your pardon</it> [=<it>excuse me, sorry</it>]? What did you say?</vi> The shorter form <phrase>beg pardon</phrase> is also used informally this way. <vi>“He's been in Haiti for the past two months.” “<it>Beg pardon</it>? He's been in Hawaii?” “No, Haiti.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go begging</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to be something that few or no people want <vi>With the poor economy, many expensive restaurants now have tables that <it>go begging</it>. [=tables that are empty because there are no customers]</vi> <vi>If that last biscuit's (still) <it>going begging</it>, can I have it, please?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="page[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">page</hw> <sound><wav>page0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpeɪʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>pag*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:one side of a sheet of paper especially in a book, magazine, etc. <vi>The book is 237 <it>pages</it> long.</vi> <vi>The article continues on <it>page</it> 12.</vi> <vi>a three-<it>page</it> article</vi> <vi>See the chart on the following/facing/opposite/next <it>page</it>.</vi> <vi>They ran the story on the front <it>page</it> of the newspaper.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>blank page</phrase> [=a sheet of paper that does not have anything written on it]</vi> <vi>It was thrilling to finally see her poetry <phrase>on the printed page</phrase>. [=in a book, magazine, etc.]</vi> <vi>The computer will automatically put a <phrase>page number</phrase> at the bottom of each <it>page</it>.</vi> <un>abbr. <it>p</it></un> <dx>see also <dxt>front-page</dxt> <dxt>title page</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the material printed or written on a page <vi>Read the second <it>page</it> out loud.</vi> <vi>The event described in these <it>pages</it> is nothing like what I remember.</vi> <vi>the <phrase>sports/financial/business pages</phrase> [=the part of the newspaper that has sports, financial information, business news, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a sheet of paper in a book, magazine, etc. <vi>He ripped a <it>page</it> out of the phone book.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>white pages</dxt> <dxt>yellow pages</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:one section of a Web site that is found at a single address <vi>You'll find that information on the “Contact Us” <it>page</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>home page</dxt> <dxt>web page</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:an important event or period in history <vi>His accomplishments hold a special place in the <phrase>pages of history</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>borrow/take a page from someone</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>borrow/take a page from someone's book</va></vr> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to do the same thing that someone else has done <vi>You may want to <it>borrow/take a page from his book</it> and study harder for your finals.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>jump/leap off the page</dre> <def><sl>of writing, a picture, etc.</sl> <dt>:to be very noticeable, interesting, exciting, etc. <vi>The characters are so real that they <it>leap off the page</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the same page</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:agreeing about something (such as how things should be done) <vi>Try to get employees and clients <it>on the same page</it>.</vi> <vi>Make sure everyone is <it>on the same page</it> before you give your final answer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>page</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="steal[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">steal</hw> <sound><wav>steal001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsti:l</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>steals</if></in> <in><if>stole</if> <sound><wav>steal002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstoʊl</pr></in> <in><if>sto*len</if> <sound><wav>steal003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstoʊlən</pr></in> <in><if>steal*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to take (something that does not belong to you) in a way that is wrong or illegal <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>stole</it> thousands of dollars' worth of jewelry from the store.</vi> <vi>Someone <it>stole</it> my bicycle.</vi> <vi>He discovered that his car had been <it>stolen</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>stolen</it> watch</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The store manager accused the boy of <it>stealing</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (something that you are not supposed to have) without asking for permission <vi>I <it>stole</it> a cookie from the cookie jar.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to wrongly take and use (another person's idea, words, etc.) <vi>He <it>stole</it> my idea.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to persuade (someone who has been with someone else) to be with you especially by doing things that are unfair or dishonest <vi>He <it>stole</it> my girlfriend.</vi> <vi>They <it>stole</it> our best pitcher away from our team.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get (something that is difficult to get) in usually a quick and often secret way <vi>I <it>stole</it> a nap this afternoon. [=I managed to take a brief nap this afternoon]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>stole a peek/look</phrase> [=took a quick peek/look] at the birthday cake.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>stole a glance</phrase> at her [=glanced at her quickly] before riding away.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>stole a kiss</phrase> from him [=kissed him in a quick and sudden way] and ran away.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get more attention than others during (a performance, scene, etc.) <vi>Her impassioned acting <it>stole</it> the scene. [=everyone in the audience watched her during the scene because of her impassioned acting]</vi> <vi>His outstanding performance <phrase>stole the show</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to reach (a base) safely by running to it from the previous base when the ball has not been hit by a batter <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He reached first base on a single and then <it>stole</it> second (base).</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She tried to <it>steal</it> but got thrown out.</vi> <vi>He leads the league in <it>stealing</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to take (the ball, puck, etc.) from another player <vi>(<it>basketball</it>) He <it>stole</it> the ball and took it down the court for two points.</vi> <vi>He <it>stole</it> the pass.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to come or go quietly or secretly <vi>They <it>stole</it> out of the room.</vi> <vi>She <it>stole</it> away silently.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beg, borrow, or/and steal</dre> <dx>see <dxt>beg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>steal a march on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>march</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>steal someone's thunder</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thunder</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
