<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bother[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">both*er</hw> <sound><wav>bother01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:ðɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>both*ers</if></in> <in><if>both*ered</if></in> <in><if>both*er*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to feel troubled, worried, or concerned <vi>He's so easygoing. Nothing seems to <it>bother</it> him.</vi> <vi>It didn't <it>bother</it> [=<it>trouble</it>] her in the least that she wasn't offered the job.</vi> <vi>It <it>bothers</it> [=<it>worries</it>] them that there's no hospital nearby.</vi> <vi>Something he said at the meeting has been <it>bothering</it> me.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>not bother yourself about/with something</phrase> or <phrase>not bother your head about/with something</phrase> is to not worry or be concerned about something. <vi>He decided he <it>wasn't</it> going to <it>bother himself about</it> the opinions of others.</vi> <vi><it>Don't bother your head with</it> those questions right now.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to annoy (someone) :to cause (someone) to feel annoyed <vi>It <it>bothers</it> [=<it>irks</it>] her when people throw trash on the ground.</vi> <vi>He's <it>bothered</it> [=<it>annoyed</it>] by drivers who don't use their turn signals.</vi> <vi>The entire car trip was filled with complaints like, “Mom, David keeps <it>bothering</it> me!” and “Will you tell him to quit <it>bothering</it> me?”</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take the time to do something :to make an effort to do something <vi>Mother used to cook elaborate dinners, but with only herself to cook for, she doesn't <it>bother</it> anymore.</vi> <vi>“Should I call later?” “No, don't <it>bother</it>.”</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> or by <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>Nobody <it>bothered</it> [=<it>took the trouble</it>] <it>to tell</it> me the school would be closed today.</vi> <vi>He never <it>bothered to explain</it> what happened.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>bother asking</it> him about it. He won't tell you anything.</vi> <vi>Why <it>bother talking</it> if no one is listening?</vi></un> <snote>If you <phrase>can't be bothered</phrase> to do something, you do not want to make an effort to do it or are not interested in doing it. <vi>The trick is somewhat dangerous, so if you <it>can't be bothered</it> to do it right, then don't even attempt it.</vi> <vi>I asked her to send a picture, but apparently she just <it>couldn't be bothered</it> (to send one).</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be concerned <it>with</it> or <it>about</it> something <vi>I'm not going to <it>bother with</it> the details.</vi> <vi>We were told not to <it>bother about</it> the early data [=not to consider or use early data] when writing the report.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to interrupt or talk to (someone who is working or who wants to be alone) <vi>Don't <it>bother</it> your mother right now. She's very tired.</vi> <vi>I hate to <it>bother</it> [=<it>trouble</it>] you, but I was wondering if you could help me with something.</vi> <vi>Sorry to <it>bother</it> [=<it>inconvenience</it>] you. I just had a quick question.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel sick or uncomfortable <vi>He said his stomach was <it>bothering</it> him.</vi> <vi>Her arthritis has been <it>bothering</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause a painful or unpleasant feeling in (part of someone's body) <vi>The camera strap <it>bothers</it> my shoulder.</vi> <vi>The bright light <it>bothered</it> her eyes.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt><un>used as an interjection to express annoyance or frustration <vi><it>Bother</it> this car! It won't start!</vi> <vi>Oh, <it>bother</it> (it). I forgot my keys.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bother[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bother</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:ðɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:someone or something that is annoying or that causes trouble <vi>Replacing the windows could be more of a <it>bother</it> than it's worth.</vi> <vi>Sorry to be such a <it>bother</it> [=<it>nuisance</it>], but I was wondering if you could help me with something.</vi> <vi>I know what a <it>bother</it> driving into the city can be this time of day.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:trouble or difficulty :<sx>inconvenience</sx> <vi>“Sorry to bother you.” “That's okay, it's no <it>bother</it> at all.”</vi> <vi>I considered replacing that part of the floor but decided it wasn't worth the <it>bother</it>.</vi> <vi>He doesn't want the <it>bother</it> of filling out all those forms again.</vi> <vi>Will you mail this for me? It will save me the <it>bother</it> of going to the post office.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
