<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bounce[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bounce</hw> <sound><wav>bounce01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaʊns</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bounc*es</if></in> <in><if>bounced</if></in> <in><if>bounc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a ball, rock, etc.) to hit against a surface and quickly move in a different and usually opposite direction <vi>He was <it>bouncing</it> a tennis ball against/off the garage door.</vi> <vi><it>bouncing</it> the ball back and forth</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in one direction, hit a surface (such as a wall or the floor), and then quickly move in a different and usually opposite direction <un>usually + <it>off</it> <vi>The ball <it>bounced off</it> the wall.</vi> <vi>A rock <it>bounced off</it> the road and hit our car's windshield.</vi> <vi>The light will <it>bounce off</it> the mirror and shine into the next room.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move with a lot of energy and excitement <vi>He <it>bounced</it> [=<it>bounded</it>] into the room to welcome his guests.</vi> <vi>The kids are <phrase>bouncing off the walls</phrase>. [=the kids are very/too excited and have a lot of energy]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move or jump up and down <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The children love to <it>bounce</it> on the bed/trampoline.</vi> <vi>The winner <it>bounced</it> up and down with delight.</vi> <vi>Her curls <it>bounced</it> as she jumped.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bounced</it> the baby on his knee.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a check</ssl> <dt>:to be returned by a bank because there is not enough money in the bank account to pay the amount that is on the check <vi>She gave me a check for 20 dollars, but the check <it>bounced</it>, and I never got the money.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to write (a check) that is returned without payment by the bank <vi>He <it>bounced</it> a 100-dollar check at the grocery store.</vi> <vi>The store charges a $15 fee for a <it>bounced</it> check.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go quickly and repeatedly from one job, place, etc., to another <vi>He <it>bounces</it> back and forth between Miami and Houston.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi><it>bouncing from</it> place to place</vi> <vi>She <it>bounces from</it> one job to another.</vi> <vi>Our teacher's always <it>bouncing from</it> one subject to another.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to return (an e-mail) to the sender instead of delivering it <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I tried to send you an e-mail, but it got <it>bounced</it> back to me. [=the e-mail or computer system was not able to deliver it]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I tried to send you an e-mail but it <it>bounced</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bounce around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bounce (something) around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bounce around (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk about (something, such as an idea) in an informal way in order to get different opinions about it <vi>We were <it>bouncing</it> some ideas <it>around</it> for the design of the book's cover.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bounce back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to return quickly to a normal condition after a difficult situation or event <vi>She <it>bounced back</it> [=<it>recovered</it>] easily from her surgery.</vi> <vi>After losing the first three games of the series, they <it>bounced back</it> to win their next eight games.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bounce into</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <phrasev><pva>bounce (someone) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to decide to do (something) especially without having time to think about it <vi>The voters were <it>bounced into</it> agreeing to the proposal.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bounce off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bounce (something) off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk about (something, such as an idea) with (someone) in an informal way in order to get an opinion <vi>I wanted to <it>bounce</it> some ideas <it>off</it> you before the meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bounce[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bounce</hw> <altpr>ˈbaʊns</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bounces</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act or action of bouncing off the ground or another surface <vi>The ball took a high <it>bounce</it> over the shortstop's head.</vi> <vi>He caught the ball on the first <it>bounce</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the ability to move quickly in a different direction after hitting a surface :the ability to bounce <vi>a basketball that has lost all its <it>bounce</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a quality that makes a person's hair look healthy, full, and attractive :a bouncy quality <vi>The shampoo promises to give limp hair lots of <it>bounce</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a sudden increase <vi>Several companies showed a <it>bounce</it> [=<it>upswing, upsurge</it>] in earnings.</vi> <vi>After the debates, she enjoyed a big <it>bounce</it> in the election polls.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:energy and liveliness <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He may be 90 years old, but he still has plenty of <it>bounce</it> [=<it>spring</it>] in his step.</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>There's still a <it>bounce</it> in his step.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bounce pass"> <hw>bounce pass</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ passes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>basketball</sl> <dt>:a pass to a teammate that is made by bouncing the ball once</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
