<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="box[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">box</hw> <sound><wav>box00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:ks</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>box*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a container that is made of a hard material (such as wood, metal, or cardboard) and that usually has four straight sides <vi>a cardboard <it>box</it></vi> <vi>She kept the letters in an old <it>box</it>.</vi> <vi>empty pizza <it>boxes</it></vi> <vi>the cat's litter <it>box</it></vi> <vi>a <it>box</it> of tissues/matches/cigars/tools</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount of something inside a box <vi>I ate an entire <it>box</it> of chocolates.</vi> <vi>two <it>boxes</it> of cereal</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a container used for holding mail or papers especially in an office <vi>I'll put the messages in your <it>box</it>.</vi> <vi>The letter was sent to a post office <it>box</it> in New York.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>in-box</dxt> <dxt>mailbox</dxt> <dxt>out-box</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of electronic equipment that is contained inside a box <vi>Where's the system's control <it>box</it>?</vi> <vi>The cable <it>box</it> is on top of the TV.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>black box</dxt> <dxt>gearbox</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the box</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a television <vi>Let's turn on <it>the box</it> and watch the game.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small area or section of seats that is separated from other seats inside a theater, stadium, or courtroom <vi>She's sitting in the jury <it>box</it>.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>theater</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>box seat</dxt> <dxt>luxury box</dxt> <dxt>press box</dxt> <dxt>skybox</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a closed shape with four sides on a piece of paper, a Web page, etc.: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a square in which you make a mark (such as an X) to show that you choose something <vi>If you are over 18 years old, check this <it>box</it>.</vi> <vi>Put an X in the correct/appropriate <it>box</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a square or rectangle around special information in a document, book, etc. <vi>For more information, see <it>box</it> A17.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area on a sports field that is used for a special purpose</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:one of six areas on a baseball field that are marked by lines and that show where the batter, pitcher, catcher, and coaches stand <vi>He stepped out of the batter's <it>box</it> to take a practice swing.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>penalty box</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>cup <sxn>5</sxn></sx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:an area where two streets cross that is marked by painted lines to show where cars are not allowed to stop but can only pass through <vi>The sign at the intersection said “Don't Block the <it>Box</it>.”</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>box junction</cat></ca></dt></def> <dro><dre>think outside the box</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>think outside the box</it>, your thoughts are not limited or controlled by rules or tradition, and you have ideas that are creative and unusual. <vi>To solve this puzzle, you'll have to <it>think outside the box</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>box</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="box[2]"> <hw hindex="2">box</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:ks</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>boxes</if></in> <in><if>boxed</if></in> <in><if>box*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to put (something) in a box <vi>Can you <it>box</it> this for me? It's a gift.</vi> <vi>The CDs are sold as a <phrase>boxed set</phrase>. [=a set of things that are sold together in a box]</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She was told to <it>box up</it> her things and go home.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>box in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>box (someone or something) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to surround (someone or something) and make movement difficult <vi>The other bicyclists <it>boxed her in</it> and she couldn't move ahead.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) boxed in</it> <vi>We got <it>boxed in</it> and couldn't get out of our parking space. [=other cars were parked so close to our car that we could not move out of our parking space]</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>I feel <it>boxed in</it> by all these rules.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>box</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="box[3]"> <hw hindex="3">box</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑks</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>boxes</if></in> <in><if>boxed</if></in> <in><if>boxing</if></in> <def><dt>:to participate in the sport of boxing :to fight with the hands often while wearing very thick gloves <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His father taught him how to <it>box</it> when he was 12.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Who did he <it>box</it> in his first fight?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>kickboxing</dxt> <dxt>shadowbox</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>box someone's ears</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to hit someone on the sides of the head or on the ears <vi>His mother threatened to <it>box his ears</it> if he misbehaved again.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>box</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="box[4]"> <hw hindex="4">box</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑks</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>box*es</if></in> <def><gram>count, noncount</gram> <dt>:<sx>boxwood <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>box</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="box cutter"> <hw>box cutter</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small tool that is made for opening cardboard boxes and that has a very sharp blade that can be pushed in and out of its case</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="box junction"> <hw>box junction</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>box <sxn>8</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="box lunch"> <hw>box lunch</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ lunches</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>bag lunch</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="box office"> <hw>box office</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -fices</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area in a theater where tickets are sold for a movie, play, etc. <vi>The <it>box office</it> will open at 10:00 a.m.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe how many tickets have been sold for a movie, play, etc. <vi>The movie did very well at the <it>box office</it>. [=many people bought tickets to see the movie]</vi> <vi>It made over 100 million dollars at the <it>box office</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>The movie is a <it>box office</it> hit/success.</vi> <vi>a <it>box office</it> failure/flop</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="box room"> <hw>box room</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ rooms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a room in a house where things are stored</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="box score"> <hw>box score</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ scores</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a small chart that shows the players, score, and other details of a baseball game <vi>reading the <it>box scores</it> in the newspaper</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
