<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="brain[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">brain</hw> <sound><wav>brain001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>brains</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the organ of the body in the head that controls functions, movements, sensations, and thoughts <vi>Scientists are learning more about how the human <it>brain</it> works.</vi> <vi>The left and right sides of the <it>brain</it> have different functions.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>brain</it> injury/tumor</vi> <vi><it>brain</it> damage/surgery</vi> <vi><it>brain</it> cells/tissue</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the ability to think and reason :<sx>intelligence</sx> <vi>Don't be such an idiot—use your <it>brain</it>. [=<it>head</it>]</vi> <vi>She has a good <it>brain</it>. [=she is smart]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry—I don't know where my <it>brain</it> is today. [=I'm not thinking clearly today]</vi> <vi>If he had <phrase>half a brain</phrase> [=if he was at all smart], he would have left a long time ago.</vi> <un>often plural <vi>If he had any <it>brains</it>, he would have left a long time ago.</vi> <vi>She has both <it>brains</it> and beauty.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a very intelligent person <vi>The other children always teased him about being such a <it>brain</it>.</vi> <vi>She is one of the best <it>brains</it> [=<it>intellects, minds</it>] in the field.</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>the brains of/behind</phrase> something, you are the person who thinks of plans or makes important decisions for a group. <vi>She's <it>the brains of</it> this organization.</vi> <vi>He was <it>the brains behind</it> the scheme.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>beat/bash someone's brains out</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>beat/bash someone's brains in</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to hit someone on the head in a way that causes serious injury or death :to beat someone very badly <vi>They threatened to <it>beat my brains in</it> if I ever came here again.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blow someone's brains out</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to kill someone with a shot to the head :to shoot someone fatally in the head <vi>When he refused to hand over the money, the robbers threatened to <it>blow his brains out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cudgel your brain/brains</dre> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to think very hard :to rack your brain <vi>I <it>cudgeled my brains</it> for a solution to the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the brain</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:always in your thoughts <vi>I've had pizza <it>on the brain</it> all day. [=I've been thinking about pizza all day]</vi> <vi>He's got sex <it>on the brain</it>. [=he's always thinking about sex]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick someone's brain/brains</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to talk to someone in order to get helpful information or advice <vi>Do you have a moment? I need to <it>pick your brain</it> about a little situation that has come up.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rack your brain/brains</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rack</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brain[2]"> <hw hindex="2">brain</hw> <altpr>ˈbreɪn</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>brains</if></in> <in><if>brained</if></in> <in><if>brain*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to hit (someone) on the head very hard <vi>The tree limb fell and nearly <it>brained</it> me.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brain-dead"> <hw>brain–dead</hw> <sound><wav>brain01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪnˌdɛd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>medical</ssl> <dt>:showing no sign of activity in the brain :having no brain function <vi>Doctors determined that she was <it>brain-dead</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:very stupid <vi>You would have to be <it>brain-dead</it> not to see the problem.</vi> :not able to function normally <vi>I'll be <it>brain-dead</it> in the morning if I don't get some sleep.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brain death"> <hw>brain death</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>medical</sl> <dt>:the condition of having no brain function :the end of activity in the brain</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brain drain"> <hw>brain drain</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a situation in which many educated or professional people leave a particular place or profession and move to another one that gives them better pay or living conditions <vi>Nothing has been done to stop the <it>brain drain</it> as more and more doctors move away from the area.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brain trust"> <hw>brain trust</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ trusts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a group of people who give advice to a leader about what should be done <vi>The president's <it>brain trust</it> recommended the action.</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>brains trust</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brain wave"> <hw>brain wave</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ waves</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a pattern or cycle of electrical activity in the brain <un>usually plural <vi>Do your <it>brain waves</it> change when you are sleeping?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>brainstorm <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cudgel[2]"> <hw hindex="2">cudgel</hw> <altpr>ˈkʌʤəl</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cudgels</if></in> <in><il>US</il> <if>cudgeled</if> <il>or British</il> <if>cudgelled</if></in> <in><il>US</il> <if>cudgel*ing</if> <il>or British</il> <if>cudgel*ling</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to hit (someone or something) with a club <un>usually used figuratively <vi>a politician who is being <it>cudgeled</it> in the press for his failure to support tax cuts</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>cudgel your brain/brains</dre> <dx>see <dxt>brain</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="pick[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">pick</hw> <sound><wav>pick0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>picks</if></in> <in><if>picked</if></in> <in><if>pick*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to choose or select (someone or something) from a group <vi><it>Pick</it> a card—any card.</vi> <vi>They <it>picked</it> a name out of a hat.</vi> <vi>The winners will be <it>picked</it> by lottery.</vi> <vi>She was <it>picked</it> to replace the retiring CEO.</vi> <vi>Who do you think he will <it>pick</it> as/for his running mate?</vi> <vi>He <it>picked</it> the blue tie to wear to the interview.</vi> <vi>He <it>picked</it> the right/wrong answer.</vi> <vi>They both <it>picked</it> New York to win the World Series. [=they both said that they thought the New York team would win the World Series]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cherry-pick</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to remove (a fruit, flower, etc.) from a plant especially by using your hand <vi>She <it>picked</it> a flower for her mother.</vi> <vi>I <it>picked</it> some carrots and a few tomatoes.</vi> <vi>They sell freshly <it>picked</it> fruits and vegetables.</vi> <vi>Our grapes are <it>picked</it> by hand.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>handpick</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to remove unwanted material from (something) by using your finger, a small tool, etc. <vi>It's considered impolite to <phrase>pick your nose</phrase> in public.</vi> <vi>He was sitting at the table, <phrase>picking his teeth</phrase> with a toothpick.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to remove (something) from something by using your fingers <vi><it>Pick</it> the meat from/off the bones.</vi> <vi>She <it>picked</it> all the pepperoni off (of) the pizza.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to play (a guitar, banjo, etc.) by pulling the strings with your fingers or with a pick :<sx>pluck</sx> <vi>She was strumming and <it>picking</it> her guitar.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bone to pick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pick a fight/quarrel</dre> <def><dt>:to deliberately start a fight with someone <vi>Never <it>pick a fight</it> you can't win.</vi> <vi>She sometimes <it>picked fights</it> with other girls at school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick a lock</dre> <def><dt>:to open a lock by using something that is not the key <vi>He used a knife to <it>pick the lock</it> on the front door.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick and choose</dre> <def><dt>:to choose only the best or most appropriate things or people <vi>As one of Hollywood's most successful actors, he's now in a position to carefully <it>pick and choose</it> his roles.</vi> <vi>The newspaper <it>picks and chooses</it> which stories to report.</vi> <vi>With so many candidates, we can afford to <it>pick and choose</it>. [=we can afford to take our time and only choose the best candidate]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick apart</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pick (someone or something) apart</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick apart (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to say all of the things that are bad or wrong about (someone or something) :to criticize (a person or thing) in a very detailed and usually unkind way <vi>You can expect political analysts to <it>pick apart</it> the governor's speech.</vi> <vi>The film's critics <it>picked</it> his performance <it>apart</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick at (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to eat small amounts of (food) very slowly usually because you do not want to eat <vi>She <it>picked at</it> a salad while I ate my steak.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to pull on (something) with your fingertips or your fingernails often because you are nervous <vi>She <it>picked at</it> the buttons on her jacket while waiting for her interview.</vi> <vi>He was <it>picking at</it> his shoelaces.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick at (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to criticize (someone or something) especially for small mistakes <vi>They're constantly arguing and <it>picking at</it> each other.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick off (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick (someone or something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to aim at and shoot (someone or something) <vi>The hunters hid by the stream and waited to <it>pick off</it> deer as they passed.</vi> <vi>A sniper was <it>picking off</it> soldiers from the top of the building.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick off (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to cause (a player who is standing close to a base) to be tagged out by making a quick throw <vi>The runner on second base was <it>picked off</it> by the catcher.</vi> <vi>The pitcher almost <it>picked</it> her <it>off</it> with a quick throw to first base.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pickoff</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pick on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to laugh at or make fun of (someone) in an unkind way <vi>Kids used to <it>pick on</it> me for wearing old worn-out clothes.</vi> <vi>He used to get <it>picked on</it> by the other kids at the bus stop.</vi> <vi>Why is she always <it>picking on</it> me?</vi> <vi>Hey, why don't you <it>pick on</it> someone your own size?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to unfairly criticize (one person or group) when others also deserve to be criticized <vi>It's unfair to <it>pick on</it> teachers for the problems in our schools when politicians are equally to blame.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to choose or select (the best or most appropriate person or thing) from a group <vi>It took him an hour to <it>pick out</it> [=<it>pick</it>] what to wear.</vi> <vi>They let their two-year-old daughter <it>pick out</it> her own clothes.</vi> <vi>I've <it>picked out</it> the perfect spot for our picnic.</vi> <vi><it>picking out</it> a gift for a friend</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to play (a song, melody, etc.) by playing each note separately <vi>She sat <it>picking out</it> a tune on the piano.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (someone or something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick out (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to see and identify (someone or something) <vi>His red hair makes it easy to <it>pick</it> him <it>out</it> of/in a crowd.</vi> <vi>The police had a witness <it>pick</it> the suspect <it>out</it> of a lineup.</vi> <vi>I could <it>pick out</it> the pattern against the background.</vi> <vi>No one was able to <it>pick out</it> the originals from the copies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pick over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick (something) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look at (a group of objects or an amount of material) in order to choose the best ones or to remove pieces you do not want <vi>They <it>picked over</it> the strawberries and threw away the green ones.</vi> <vi><it>Pick over</it> the fish to remove any bones.</vi> <vi>The applications were thoroughly <it>picked over</it> and only the best applicants were given interviews.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick pockets</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>pick someone's pocket</va></vr> <def><dt>:to steal money or objects from someone's pockets or purse <vi>One of the boys distracted her while the other <it>picked her pocket</it>.</vi> <vi>She survived on the streets by shoplifting and <it>picking pockets</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pickpocket</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick (someone or something) to pieces/shreds</dre> <def><dt>:to study and criticize all of the parts of (someone or something) <vi>The media <it>picked</it> his personal life <it>to pieces</it>.</vi> <vi>Her ideas were <it>picked to shreds</it> by her coworkers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick someone's brain/brains</dre> <dx>see <dxt>brain</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pick (something) clean</dre> <def><dt>:to remove all the material that covers something <vi>The birds <it>picked</it> the bones <it>clean</it>. = The bones were <it>picked clean</it> by the birds.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (someone or something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick up (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to lift (someone or something) from the ground or a low surface <vi>Would you <it>pick</it> that pencil <it>up</it> for me, please?</vi> <vi>She <it>picked</it> the book <it>up</it> off/from the ground by its cover.</vi> <vi>He bent to <it>pick up</it> his hat.</vi> <vi><it>Pick up</it> the ball!</vi> <vi>They <it>picked up</it> their guitars and started to play.</vi> <vi>She always <it>picks up</it> her baby when he cries.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go somewhere in order to get and bring back (someone or something) <vi>I have to <it>pick up</it> my kids at school. = I have to <it>pick</it> them <it>up</it> from school.</vi> <vi>Have you <it>picked up</it> the car from the repair shop yet?</vi> <vi>He <it>picked up</it> his dry cleaning.</vi> <vi>They'll hold our tickets but we have to <it>pick</it> them <it>up</it> an hour before the show.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to let or put (people or things) into or onto a car, bus, ship, etc. <vi>She had a taxi <it>pick</it> her <it>up</it> at the airport and take her to the hotel.</vi> <vi>Have you ever <it>picked up</it> a hitchhiker?</vi> <vi>The ship will be <it>picking up</it> more cargo at the next port.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick up (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to make an area clean and organized by removing trash and putting things in the proper places <vi>We have just enough time to <it>pick up</it> [=<it>clean up</it>] and wash our hands before dinner.</vi> <vi>The children worked together to <it>pick up</it> the toys.</vi> <vi><it>Pick up</it> that mess!</vi> <vi>You may go outside after you <it>pick</it> your room <it>up</it>.</vi> <vi>Everyone needs to help <it>pick up</it> the kitchen after dinner.</vi> <vi>We spent the morning <it>picking up</it> the yard after the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to clean the mess created by (someone) <vi>You have to <it>pick up after</it> yourself if you make a mess.</vi> <vi>His mother still <it>picks up after</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to answer a telephone <vi>I called your house, but no one <it>picked up</it>.</vi> <vi>She got to the phone just before the answering machine <it>picked up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become busy usually after a period of little activity :to improve or increase in activity <vi>Sales slowed down after the winter holidays, but we're expecting things to <it>pick up</it> again this summer.</vi> <vi>Business really <it>picked up</it> last month.</vi> <vi>The economy/market seems to be <it>picking up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to increase in speed or strength <vi>The wind will <it>pick up</it> later this afternoon.</vi> <vi>The movie starts out slowly, but the pace <it>picks up</it> when the two main characters meet for the first time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up speed/momentum (etc.)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to have more speed/momentum (etc.) <vi>The cyclists quickly <it>picked up speed</it> [=gained speed; began to go faster] as they headed down the mountain.</vi> <vi>His campaign has begun to <it>pick up momentum</it>.</vi> <vi>The idea began to <phrase>pick up steam</phrase> [=become more popular] around the turn of the century.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up the pace</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go faster <vi>If we want to finish on time, we're going to have to <it>pick up the pace</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:to begin again after a temporary stop <vi>The discussion <it>picked up</it> this morning at the point where we had stopped yesterday.</vi> <vi>After being separated for three years, they <phrase>picked up (right) where they left off</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start (something) again after a temporary stop <vi>We'll <it>pick up</it> this discussion tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to buy or get (something) <vi>Have you <it>picked up</it> a copy of her new CD yet?</vi> <vi>On Tuesdays, he <it>picks up</it> dinner at our favorite restaurant and brings it home.</vi> <vi>She stopped to <it>pick up</it> a few groceries at the supermarket.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to earn or gain (something) <vi>She'll likely <it>pick up</it> an award for her performance in the film.</vi> <vi>The team <it>picked up</it> [=<it>gained</it>] a few yards on the last play.</vi> <vi>They've finally <it>picked up</it> their first victory of the season.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to become aware of (something, such as a story) and begin to write about it, work on it, etc. <vi>Few people had heard about this problem until the press <it>picked up</it> [=<it>took up</it>] the story.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to learn (something) usually in an informal way <vi>I <it>picked up</it> a few French phrases on my trip to Paris.</vi> <vi>He seems to <it>pick</it> foreign languages <it>up</it> very easily.</vi> <vi>She uses a style of singing she <it>picked up</it> from listening to jazz music.</vi> <vi>He's been <it>picking up</it> some bad habits from his friends.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to become sick with (an illness) from someone or something <vi>I think I <it>picked up</it> [=<it>caught</it>] a cold from someone at work.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to be able to see, hear, or smell (something) <vi>This radio lets me <it>pick up</it> stations from other countries.</vi> <vi>The planes were <it>picked up</it> [=<it>detected</it>] by radar.</vi> <vi>telescopes <it>picking up</it> the faint glow of distant stars</vi> <vi>The dogs <it>picked up</it> the scent and started to bark.</vi> :to become aware of (something) <vi>He learned that he could <it>pick up</it> cues from his partner if he paid close attention.</vi> <vi>They studied the evidence and managed to <it>pick up</it> some clues.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to meet and begin a usually brief sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She used to go to bars to <it>pick up</it> men.</vi> <vi>He <it>picked</it> her <it>up</it> at a club.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of the police</ssl> <dt>:to use the power of the law to take and keep (someone, such as a criminal) <vi>The cops <it>picked up</it> the suspect at a local bar.</vi> <vi>The police <it>picked</it> him <it>up</it> [=arrested him] for trespassing/robbery/murder.</vi> <vi>The police <it>picked</it> him <it>up</it> for questioning. [=they brought him to the police station in order to ask him questions]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel more energetic and lively <vi>I drank some coffee hoping that it would <it>pick</it> me <it>up</it> a little.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pick-me-up</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to get (a player) from another team or from some other source <vi>The team <it>picked up</it> three new players in the draft.</vi> <vi>They <it>picked</it> him <it>up</it> from a rival team.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to begin to guard (a player from the opposite team) during a game <vi>Your job is to <it>pick up</it> an opposing player and block him.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick yourself up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stand up again after falling <vi>I fell to the ground but <it>picked myself up</it> and continued running.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to recover from a difficult situation <vi>After his divorce, he <it>picked himself up</it> and started looking for love again.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up and leave/go</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave suddenly with your possessions <vi>I couldn't just <it>pick up and leave/go</it> without saying goodbye.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up the tab/bill/check</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay the money that is owed for something <vi>When she stays at expensive hotels during business trips, her company <it>picks up the tab</it>.</vi> <vi>They always offer to <it>pick up the check</it> when we go out to dinner with them.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up the pieces</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to make a situation better after something bad has happened <vi>After her business went bankrupt, she <it>picked up the pieces</it> and started again.</vi> <vi>They created the problem, and now they expect us to <it>pick up the pieces</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>pick up the cudgels for</tag> at <dxt>cudgel</dxt> <tag>pick up the gauntlet</tag> at <dxt>gauntlet</dxt> <tag>pick up the slack</tag> at <dxt>slack</dxt> <tag>pick up the threads</tag> at <dxt>thread</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick up on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to notice or become aware of (something) <vi>He didn't <it>pick up on</it> the hint.</vi> <vi>I seemed to be the only one who <it>picked up on</it> the mistake.</vi> <vi>The reader soon <it>picks up on</it> the fact that the story's main character is crazy.</vi> <vi>She was nervous, but no one <it>picked up on</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take (something, such as an idea) from another person or group and use it or continue to develop it yourself <vi>The media has recently begun to <it>pick up on</it> this issue.</vi> <vi>The fashion world <it>picked up on</it> this trend after she wore that dress to the award show.</vi> <vi>The other students quickly <it>picked up on</it> [=<it>adopted</it>] the expression.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to continue talking about (a statement, subject, etc.) <vi>I'd like to <it>pick up on</it> your last comment.</vi> <vi>She began the class by <it>picking up on</it> a point she made earlier.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pick up (someone) on (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pick (someone) up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to question (someone) about (something said or done) <vi>I'd like to <it>pick up</it> the last speaker <it>on</it> one of the points she made.</vi> <vi>When he said that whales were fish, I felt I had to <it>pick</it> him <it>up on</it> it. [=to challenge him on it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick your way</dre> <def><slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to walk very slowly while carefully choosing where to put your feet <vi>The horses slowly <it>pick their way</it> across the rocky ground.</vi> <vi>We <it>picked our way</it> down the muddy path.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="rack[2]"> <hw hindex="2">rack</hw> <altpr>ˈræk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>racks</if></in> <in><if>racked</if></in> <in><if>rack*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to suffer pain or damage <un>usually used as <it>(be) racked</it> <vi>He <it>was racked</it> with/by jealousy [=he was very jealous] when he saw his ex-wife with another man.</vi> <vi>a body <it>racked</it> by disease</vi> <vi>The team has <it>been racked</it> by dissension. [=the team has experienced a lot of dissension]</vi> <vi>The country <it>was racked</it> by civil war.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to put (balls) in a rack for a game of billiards <vi><it>Rack</it> the balls (up) and we'll play some pool.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>rack up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>rack up (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to achieve or get (something) as time passes :<sx>accumulate</sx> <vi>I wanted to <it>rack up</it> as many points as possible.</vi> <vi>The company has <it>racked up</it> huge losses/sales.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rack your brain/brains</dre> <def><dt>:to think very hard in order to try to remember something, solve a problem, etc. <vi>I've been <it>racking my brain</it>, but I can't remember his name.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
