<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="break[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">break</hw> <sound><wav>break001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>breaks</if></in> <in><if>broke</if> <sound><wav>broke001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbroʊk</pr></in> <in><if>bro*ken</if> <sound><wav>broken01.wav</wav><wav>break003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbroʊkən</pr></in> <in><if>break*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to separate (something) into parts or pieces often in a sudden and forceful or violent way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>broke</it> the cup when she dropped it on the floor.</vi> <vi>I <it>broke</it> the stick in two/half. = I <it>broke</it> the stick into two pieces.</vi> <vi><it>Break</it> the chocolate bar into pieces so that everyone can have some.</vi> <vi>It is easiest to <it>break</it> a chain at its weakest link.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The cup <it>broke</it> (into bits/pieces) when it fell on the floor.</vi> <vi>A chain will <it>break</it> at its weakest link.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (a bone) to separate into two or more pieces <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He fell and <it>broke</it> [=<it>fractured</it>] his collarbone.</vi> <vi>He <it>broke</it> his arm in the accident. [=one of the bones in his arm was broken in the accident]</vi> <vi>The fall <it>broke</it> his arm.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His arm <it>broke</it> in three places when he fell.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to open suddenly especially because of pressure from inside <vi>The blister <it>broke</it>.</vi> <vi>A bruise forms when a blood vessel <it>breaks</it> under the skin.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break open <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a machine) to stop working by damaging it <vi>He <it>broke</it> his watch when he dropped it on the floor.</vi> <vi>I'm afraid I've <it>broken</it> your phone.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop working because of being damaged <vi>His watch <it>broke</it> when he dropped it on the floor.</vi> <vi>The pump recently <it>broke</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to split or divide (something) <it>into</it> smaller units or parts <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The word “singing” can be <it>broken</it> (up) <it>into</it> the two syllables “sing-” and “-ing.”</vi> <vi>They <it>broke</it> the corporation (up) <it>into</it> several smaller companies.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The corporation <it>broke</it> (up) <it>into</it> several smaller companies.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break into <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to go through or make a hole in (a surface, someone's skin, etc.) <vi>There is no risk of infection if the dog's bite did not <it>break</it> [=<it>puncture</it>] the skin.</vi> <vi>A large fish <it>broke</it> the surface of the water.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go through (something) by using force <vi>Use a knife to <it>break</it> the seal.</vi> <un>usually used figuratively <vi>The ceremony is to celebrate people who <it>broke</it> racial barriers in the music industry.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>break down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>break through <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cut into and turn over the surface of (the ground, soil, etc.) <vi>The farmer uses a plow to <it>break</it> the soil.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>break ground</tag> at <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail to do what is required by (a law, a promise, etc.) <vi>She may not have <it>broken</it> the law, but she acted wrongly.</vi> <vi>You <it>broke</it> your promise.</vi> <vi>Students who <it>break</it> the rules will be punished.</vi> <vi>He <it>broke</it> the contract by failing to make the payments on time.</vi> <vi>You can get fined for <it>breaking</it> the speed limit. [=for driving faster than you are legally allowed to drive]</vi></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:to destroy or defeat (something) by using force or pressure <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They kept putting pressure on him, but they couldn't <it>break</it> his spirit/determination/resistance.</vi> <vi>They finally <it>broke</it> his will to resist.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His spirit/determination will never <it>break</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to defeat or ruin (someone) :to cause (someone) to fail or to stop trying or fighting <vi>He swore that he would <it>break</it> his rivals/competitors.</vi> <vi>They kept putting pressure on him, but they couldn't <it>break</it> him.</vi> <vi>These huge losses are going to <it>break</it> [=<it>ruin</it>] me financially!</vi> <vi>This film could <phrase>make or break</phrase> her career. [=the success or failure of her career could depend on the success or failure of this film]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>make-or-break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to lose your health, mental or physical strength, or control <un>usually + <it>under</it> <vi>The witness <it>broke under</it> questioning.</vi> <vi>I was afraid I would <it>break under</it> the strain of constant uncertainty.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>break down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to train (a wild animal) to behave in a way that is useful to people <vi>special equipment used to <it>break</it> horses</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause the end of (something that is strong or that has continued for a long time) <vi>A group of moderates from both parties are negotiating to <it>break</it> the deadlock in Congress.</vi> <vi>Many people in the industry were very upset when the government <it>broke</it> the strike.</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>break</it> all ties/links with them. [=to end all connections with them]</vi> <vi>She scored a goal in the last minute of the game, <it>breaking</it> a 2–2 tie.</vi> <vi>It's never easy to <it>break</it> [=<it>kick, give up</it>] a bad habit.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to give up a habit <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi>His friends have tried everything to <it>break</it> him <it>of</it> his smoking habit. [=have tried everything to make him stop smoking]</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to interrupt (something) <vi>The peaceful silence of the evening was <it>broken</it> by a sudden shout.</vi> <vi>The commotion <it>broke</it> my train of thought.</vi> <vi>The sudden noise <it>broke</it> my concentration. [=made it impossible for me to concentrate]</vi> <vi>Sometimes I sing while I'm driving, just to <it>break</it> (up) the monotony of my commute.</vi> <vi>The horizon line was <it>broken</it> only by a few stands of trees in the distance.</vi> <vi>The planes <phrase>broke formation</phrase> [=stopped flying together in an organized group] and took off in different directions.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break up <dxn>4 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a curse or spell) to no longer be effective <vi>a mystic who claimed to be able to <it>break</it> curses</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop an activity (such as working) for a brief period of time <vi>Let's <it>break</it> for lunch. [=let's take a break for lunch; let's temporarily stop working and eat lunch]</vi></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to tell (bad news) to someone in a kind or gentle way <vi>I know she'll be very upset when she finds out she didn't get the job, so please try to <it>break</it> it to her gently.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as news) publicly known for the first time <vi>The local TV station was the first to <it>break</it> the news about the President's visit.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of news</ssl> <dt>:to become publicly known <vi>The story <it>broke</it> yesterday. [=the story was reported for the first time yesterday]</vi> <vi>People were shocked when (news of) the scandal first <it>broke</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to reduce the speed or force of (something) <vi>The bushes beneath the window helped to <phrase>break his fall</phrase>. [=helped make his fall less forceful]</vi> <vi>She walked straight across the room without <phrase>breaking (her) stride</phrase>. [=without pausing or slowing down]</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be higher or more than (a specified number, measurement, etc.) <vi>The temperature is expected to <it>break</it> 90 (degrees Fahrenheit) today.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do better than (a record) <vi>She ran a great race and almost <it>broke</it> the world record. [=she almost ran the race faster than anyone in the world has ever run it]</vi> <vi>He set a record that may never be <it>broken</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to have a score that is lower than or higher than (a specified total) <vi>golfers trying to <it>break</it> 90 [=to have a score below 90]</vi> <vi>bowlers trying to <it>break</it> 200 [=to have a score above 200]</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to find or provide an explanation or solution for (something, such as a criminal case) <vi>The detective finally <it>broke</it> [=<it>solved</it>] the case.</vi> <vi>The detective found the evidence that <it>broke</it> the case.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find the meaning of (a secret code) <vi>A team of experts was finally able to <it>break</it> the code and decipher the meaning of the message.</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of the weather</ssl> <dt>:to change by becoming rainy, clear, cool, etc., after a long time <vi>waiting for the weather to <it>break</it></vi> <vi>The heat wave should finally <it>break</it> [=<it>end</it>] tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of clouds</ssl> <dt>:to separate so that the sky or sun can be seen <vi>The clouds <it>broke</it> and the fog dissipated, revealing blue sky above.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of a storm</ssl> <dt>:to start suddenly <vi>Everyone ran to get indoors when the storm <it>broke</it>. [=when it began to rain]</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to begin when the sun rises <vi>They left just as <phrase>day was breaking</phrase>. [=just as the sun was rising]</vi> <vi>The <phrase>dawn was breaking</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>daybreak</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to begin running quickly <vi>Everyone <it>broke</it> [=<it>dashed, ran</it>] for cover.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop fighting and run away <vi>When the enemy charged, our troops <it>broke</it> and ran.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give smaller bills or coins for (a large bill) <vi>Can you <it>break</it> [=<it>change</it>] a $20 bill for me?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (a large bill) to pay for something that costs much less than the value of the bill <vi>I didn't want to <it>break</it> a $20 bill just to buy something for a dollar.</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a wave</ssl> <dt>:to curl over and fall onto or near land <vi>the sound of waves <it>breaking</it> against/over/on the rocks</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of someone's voice</ssl> <dt>:to change sharply in tone or pitch because of strong emotion <vi>Her voice was <it>breaking</it> with emotion as she said goodbye.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a boy's voice</ssl> <dt>:to change from the high voice of a boy to the lower voice of a man <vi>an adolescent boy whose voice is <it>breaking</it></vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <ssl>of a thrown or struck ball</ssl> <dt>:to turn or curve <vi>The putt <it>broke</it> to the left as it neared the hole.</vi> <vi>a pitch that <it>breaks</it> away from the batter</vi> <vi>The pitcher threw a <phrase>breaking ball</phrase>. [=a pitch that curves]</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <ssl>tennis</ssl> <dt>:to win against (an opponent who is serving) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The challenger <it>broke</it> the champion in the final set. = The challenger <it>broke</it> the champion's serve in the final set.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The challenger <it>broke</it> in the final set but the champion <it>broke</it> back to even the score.</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to happen or develop <vi>For the team to succeed, everything has to <it>break</it> right for them. [=for the team to succeed, they have to be lucky]</vi> <vi>Things have been <it>breaking</it> [=<it>going</it>] well for the company in the past six months.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>break a leg</dre> <dx>see <dxt>leg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break a sweat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sweat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to get away from someone or something especially by using force or effort <vi>Large pieces of the rock ledge have <it>broken away</it>. [=<it>broken free</it>]</vi> <un>usually + <it>from</it> <vi>He <it>broke away</it> [=<it>broke free/loose</it>] <it>from</it> his captors and escaped.</vi> <vi>She <it>broke away</it> [=<it>pulled away</it>] <it>from</it> the other runners to win the race.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company has <it>broken away from</it> the competition.</vi> <vi>young people <it>breaking away from</it> traditional values</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to separate or become separate from a larger group, country, etc. <vi>Three members of the band <it>broke away</it> and formed their own group.</vi> <un>usually + <it>from</it> <vi>a faction that has <it>broken away from</it> the main political party</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>breakaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break bread</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bread</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break camp</dre> <dx>see <dxt>camp</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break cover</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cover</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to stop working properly <vi>Our car <it>broke down</it> on the highway.</vi> <vi>This old motorcycle is constantly <it>breaking down</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>4 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to fail or stop usually in a complete and sudden way <vi>Negotiations have <it>broken down</it>. [=<it>collapsed</it>]</vi> <vi>The government's argument <it>broke down</it> completely when new evidence came to light.</vi> <vi>Their marriage had <it>broken down</it> [=<it>failed</it>], and there was nothing to do about it.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become overwhelmed by strong emotions <vi>She <it>broke down</it> and started to cry. = She <phrase>broke down in tears</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>8c (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>break down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to lose or cause (someone) to lose strength or the ability to resist or fight <vi>The prisoner finally <it>broke down</it> under intensive questioning.</vi> <vi>She finally <it>broke down</it> and got a cell phone. [=she bought a cell phone after resisting the desire to buy one for a long time]</vi> <vi>Intensive questioning finally <it>broke</it> the prisoner <it>down</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>8b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>break down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become separated or to separate (something) into simpler substances <vi>The foods you eat <it>break down</it> in the body's digestive system.</vi> <vi>The body's digestive system <it>breaks</it> food <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Water can be <it>broken down</it> into hydrogen and oxygen through electrolysis. = Water can <it>break down</it> into hydrogen and oxygen through electrolysis.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be able to be divided or to divide (something) <it>into</it> parts or groups <vi>The report <it>breaks down into</it> three sections. = The report is <it>broken down into</it> three sections. [=the report has three sections]</vi> <vi>The author has <it>broken down</it> the nation's history <it>into</it> three distinct periods.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>break (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use force to push (something) to the ground <vi><it>break</it> a door <it>down</it></vi> <vi><it>break down</it> a barrier</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>They are working to <it>break down</it> legal barriers to integration.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>breakdown</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break even</dre> <def><dt>:to take in as much money as you spend :to operate without either a loss or a profit <vi>After years of losing money the company is starting to <it>break even</it> and hopes to make a profit soon.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break-even</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break faith with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>faith</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break free</dre> <def><dt>:to become able to move or escape by using force or effort <vi>The prisoner struggled to <it>break free</it>.</vi> :to get away from someone or something that holds or limits you <un>often + <it>from</it> or <it>of</it> <vi>She wanted to <it>break free from</it> the constraints of her middle-class life.</vi> <vi>an animal struggling to <it>break free of</it> a trap</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>break from (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to end a relationship, connection, or agreement with (someone or something) <vi>She recently <it>broke from</it> [=<it>broke with</it>] the organization she helped found.</vi> <vi><it>breaking from</it> [=<it>breaking with</it>] tradition/stereotypes</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to enter a house, building, etc., illegally <vi>Someone tried to <it>break in</it> while we were away.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break into <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>break-in</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to interrupt or disturb someone or something <vi>I was listening to my favorite radio program when a reporter <it>broke in</it> with news about a storm.</vi> <vi>We were having a chat when he rudely <it>broke in</it> (on it).</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break into <dxn>4 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>break in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (someone) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break in (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start or help (someone) to start a new activity, job, etc. <vi>Baseball was very different when he first <it>broke in</it> [=started playing] as a catcher in 1962.</vi> <vi>The job involves a wide variety of tasks, so we try to <it>break</it> new employees <it>in</it> gradually.</vi> <vi>The band is <it>breaking in</it> a new backup singer.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>break (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to use (something, such as a new pair of shoes) for a period of time so that it becomes comfortable <vi>The shoes were tight when she first got them, so she <it>broke</it> them <it>in</it> by wearing them around the house for a few days.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to operate (a new machine) carefully for a period of time until it is ready for regular use <vi>You shouldn't drive a new car too fast while you're <it>breaking</it> it <it>in</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>break into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to enter (a house, building, etc.) illegally and especially by using force <vi>Someone tried to <it>break into</it> our house while we were away.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break in <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to begin to do or have (something) suddenly <vi>She <it>broke into</it> tears. [=she suddenly began to cry]</vi> <vi>The audience <it>broke into</it> applause. [=the audience suddenly began applauding]</vi> <vi>His face <it>broke into</it> a smile. [=he suddenly smiled]</vi> <vi>The horse <it>broke into</it> a gallop. [=the horse suddenly began to gallop]</vi> <vi>She <it>broke into</it> song. [=she suddenly began to sing]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to enter or get started in (something, such as a profession) <vi>I knew her when she was a young actress trying to <it>break into</it> show business.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to interrupt (something) <vi>The network <it>broke into</it> the program with a special news report.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break in <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break loose</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suddenly become loose :to suddenly stop being attached to something <vi>One of the shutters <it>broke loose</it> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to get away from someone or something by using force or effort <vi>The prisoner <it>broke loose</it> [=<it>broke free</it>] and ran away.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The prisoner <it>broke loose from</it> the guards.</vi> <vi>She wants to <it>break loose from</it> the constraints of her middle-class life.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>all hell breaks loose</tag> at <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break new ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>break off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (something) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become separated or cause (something) to become separated because of force or violence <vi>The piece of plaster <it>broke off</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The handle <it>broke off</it> when I accidentally dropped the cup.</vi> <vi>I accidentally <it>broke</it> the cup's handle <it>off</it>. = I accidentally <it>broke</it> the handle <it>off</it> the cup.</vi> <vi>I <it>broke</it> [=<it>tore</it>] a piece of bread <it>off</it> (the loaf) and ate it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>break off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop or end suddenly or cause (something) to stop or end suddenly <vi>The speaker <it>broke off</it> (speaking) in the middle of a sentence.</vi> <vi>At that point the recording suddenly <it>breaks off</it>. [=<it>ends</it>]</vi> <vi>The two countries have <it>broken off</it> diplomatic relations.</vi> <vi>The negotiations resumed soon after they were <it>broken off</it>.</vi> <vi>They had a fight and <it>broke off</it> [=<it>called off</it>] their engagement.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break open</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>break open</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break open (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (something) open</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to open or to cause (something) to open suddenly <vi>The pods <it>broke open</it> and the seeds scattered on the wind.</vi> <vi>The police <it>broke open</it> the door.</vi> <vi>The burglars <it>broke open</it> the locked safe.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>3 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin happening suddenly <vi>A fire <it>broke out</it> in the kitchen.</vi> <vi>A riot <it>broke out</it> in the prison.</vi> <vi>There is a danger that war could <it>break out</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to suddenly begin to have sweat, a rash, etc., on your skin <vi>He <phrase>broke out in a sweat</phrase>. [=he began to sweat]</vi> <vi>Eating strawberries makes her <phrase>break out in hives</phrase>. = Eating strawberries makes her <it>break out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to appear on the skin suddenly <vi>Sweat <it>broke out</it> on his forehead.</vi> <vi>A rash <it>broke out</it> on her skin.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to escape from a prison, jail, etc. <vi>Six prisoners were caught attempting to <it>break out</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>Six prisoners attempted to <it>break out of</it> the jail.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The team is trying to <it>break out of</it> its slump. [=is trying to end its slump]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>break out of</it> the financial rut we're in.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>break (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something) from the place where it is stored so that it can be used <vi>We <it>broke out</it> the champagne to celebrate our victory.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>breakout</dxt> <dxt>outbreak</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break rank</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break someone's heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break step</dre> <dx>see <dxt>step</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break the back of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>back</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break the bank</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break the ice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break the mold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>break through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break through (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use force to get through (something, such as a barrier) <vi>The enemy attacked our defenses but they weren't able to <it>break through</it>.</vi> <vi>The enemy finally <it>broke through</it> our defenses and defeated us.</vi> <vi>The prisoners <it>broke through</it> the wall and escaped.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The organization is committed to <it>breaking through</it> the barriers of poverty.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>6b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of the sun</ssl> <dt>:to shine through (clouds) <vi>The sun finally began to <it>break through</it>. = The sun finally began to <it>break through</it> the clouds.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>break up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to separate into parts or pieces or cause (something) to separate into parts or pieces <vi>The asteroid <it>broke up</it> [=<it>disintegrated</it>] when it hit the Earth's atmosphere.</vi> <vi>Enzymes help <it>break up</it> protein molecules.</vi> <vi><it>break up</it> a large estate</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to end or cause (something) to end <vi>The demonstration <it>broke up</it> when the police arrived.</vi> <vi>The party began to <it>break up</it> shortly after midnight.</vi> <vi>The police <it>broke up</it> the demonstration.</vi> <vi>He got hurt while trying to <it>break up</it> a fight.</vi> <vi><it>break up</it> a terrorist organization</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>break up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to end a romantic relationship, marriage, etc. <vi>They dated for years but recently <it>broke up</it>.</vi> <vi>I hear that he and his wife have <it>broken up</it>. = I hear that their marriage has <it>broken up</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>He <it>broke up with</it> his girlfriend.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>break up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin laughing or cause (someone) to begin laughing suddenly and in a way that is difficult to control <vi>I always <it>break up</it> [=<it>crack up</it>] when I hear that joke.</vi> <vi>Everyone <it>broke up</it> [=<it>burst into laughter, busted out laughing</it>] when they saw what he was wearing.</vi> <vi>That joke always <it>breaks me up</it>. [=<it>cracks me up</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>break (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>break up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to change the regular quality or appearance of (something) <vi><it>break up</it> a dull routine</vi> <vi>A chimney <it>breaks up</it> the line of the level roof.</vi> <vi><it>break up</it> a text with pictures</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>break <dxn>10 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to separate the parts of (something) so that it is not complete <vi>The seller was unwilling to <it>break up</it> the dining room set by selling one of the chairs.</vi> <vi>The owner <it>broke up</it> the team by trading many of the best players.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>break up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>of a school</ssl> <dt>:to come to the end of a period of instruction (such as a term) <vi>School <it>broke up</it> for the summer last Friday.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>breakup</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break wind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>break with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>break with (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to end a relationship, connection, or agreement with (someone or something) <vi>He <it>broke with</it> his former friends and colleagues when he decided to support the conservative candidate.</vi> <vi>a strong desire to <it>break with</it> tradition/the past</vi> <vi>A number of people have <it>broken with</it> the church over this issue.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="break[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">break</hw> <altpr>ˈbreɪk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>breaks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a crack, hole, etc., that is caused by damage, injury, or pressure <vi>The tank is reinforced to prevent <it>breaks</it> and leaks.</vi> <vi>The <it>break</it> [=<it>fracture</it>] in her arm will take months to heal.</vi> <vi>Watch out for <it>breaks</it> [=(more commonly) <it>cracks</it>] in the ice.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an opening or space <it>in</it> something <vi>There was a <it>break</it> [=<it>gap</it>] <it>in</it> the clouds.</vi> :an opening that makes it possible for someone or something to enter or pass through something <vi>There was a <it>break in</it> the hedge/fence.</vi> <vi>We waited for a <it>break in</it> the traffic.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that causes a change or interruption <vi>She gets upset over any little <it>break</it> in her routine. [=anything that changes/interrupts her routine]</vi> <vi>The fields extend for miles without a <it>break</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a time when something stops <vi>It has rained for five days without a <it>break</it>. [=it has been raining constantly for five days]</vi> <vi>We chatted during a <it>break</it> in the game.</vi> <vi>It rained all day. We waited for <phrase>a break in the weather</phrase> [=we waited for a time when the rain stopped], but it never came.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a brief period of time during which someone stops an activity <vi>I'm tired. Let's <phrase>take a break</phrase>. [=let's stop doing whatever we are doing for a short period of time]</vi> <vi>It was a long drive, but we <it>took</it> lots of <it>breaks</it>. [=we briefly stopped driving many times]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>bathroom break</phrase> [=a brief period of time when you stop doing something in order to use a bathroom]</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a brief period of time during which a worker is allowed to rest, eat, etc., instead of working <vi>All employees are entitled to two <it>breaks</it> during the workday.</vi> <vi>We've been working all day without a <it>break</it>.</vi> <vi>It's only five minutes until <phrase>break time</phrase>. [=the time when workers are supposed to stop working for a brief period of time]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>coffee break</dxt> <dxt>lunch break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a longer period of time when someone is not working or doing some other activity <vi>The long weekend provided her with a much-needed <it>break</it> (from her job).</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:a time when many people are not working or going to school because of a holiday, vacation, etc. <vi>She went home to visit her parents during (the) winter <it>break</it>.</vi> <vi>What are your plans for (the) Thanksgiving <it>break</it>?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>spring break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a planned interruption in a radio or television program <vi>a <it>break</it> for a commercial = a commercial <it>break</it></vi> <vi>We'll be back with more after the <it>break</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>station break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a sudden fast run :<sx>dash</sx> <vi>The runner <phrase>made a break for</phrase> second base. [=the runner suddenly ran toward second base]</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a fast run by someone who is trying to escape <vi>The prisoner <it>made a</it> (sudden) <it>break for</it> the door.</vi> <vi>The prisoner <phrase>made a break for it/freedom</phrase> and got away.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>jailbreak</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a situation or event that is lucky or unlucky <vi>a series of unlucky/bad <it>breaks</it></vi> <vi>Finding a hotel with a vacancy and low prices was a lucky/good <it>break</it> for us.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a lucky situation or event that makes success possible <vi>She's still hoping to get her big/lucky <it>break</it> in show business.</vi> <vi>She got the <it>breaks</it> she needed to succeed.</vi> <vi>She gets all the <it>breaks</it>. [=she is very lucky]</vi> <vi>For the team to succeed, all the <it>breaks</it> will have to go their way. [=they will have to be lucky]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) I just can't seem to <phrase>catch a break</phrase>. [=I am unlucky; I never have good luck]</vi> <snote>Informal expressions like <phrase>those are the breaks</phrase> and <phrase>that's the breaks</phrase> mean that something bad or unlucky should be thought of or accepted as the kind of thing that often happens to people. <vi>I'm disappointed that I didn't get the job, but <it>those are the breaks</it>. I'll keep trying.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that helps a particular person or group <vi>Can you give me a <it>break</it> on the price? = Can I get a <it>break</it> on the price? [=can you lower the price for me?]</vi> <vi>People with small children are being given a <phrase>tax break</phrase>. [=are being required to pay less in taxes than other people]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a sudden ending of a relationship <vi>The crisis has caused a <it>break</it> (in diplomatic relations) between the two countries.</vi> <vi>If you don't want to keep dating him, you should just <phrase>make a clean break</phrase> [=you should end your relationship quickly] instead of dragging it out.</vi> <vi>She talked about leaving her husband for years, but she never found the courage to <phrase>make the break</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a change from what was done before <un>usually + <it>with</it> or <it>from</it> <vi>We need to <it>make a clean break with</it> the past. [=we need to stop doing things as they were done in the past and start doing them in a completely new way]</vi> <vi>The company has made a sharp <it>break with</it> tradition.</vi> <vi>Her latest novel marks a complete <it>break with/from</it> her earlier fiction. [=her latest novel is completely different from her earlier fiction]</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt><un>used in the phrase <phrase>break of day</phrase> to refer to the time of morning when the sun can first be seen <vi>We left at (the) <it>break of day</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>dawn, sunrise, daybreak</it>]</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sharp change in the tone or pitch of someone's voice <vi>There was a <it>break</it> [=(more commonly) <it>crack</it>] in her voice as she said goodbye.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a curve in the path of a thrown or hit ball <vi>The batter was fooled completely by the <it>break</it> on the pitch.</vi> <vi>The putt had a lot of <it>break</it>. [=the putt curved a lot]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>tennis</ssl> <dt>:the act defeating an opponent who is serving <vi>a service <it>break</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>give me a break</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to tell someone to stop bothering you or treating you unfairly <vi>“Aren't you finished yet?” “<it>Give me a break</it>! I only started 10 minutes ago!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you do not believe or are disgusted about what someone has said or done <vi>“He says he went Harvard.” “<it>Give me a break</it>! I doubt he even graduated from high school!”</vi> <vi>He wants more money? <it>Give me a break</it>! [=it's ridiculous/outrageous that he wants more money]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) a break</dre> <def><dt>:to stop treating (someone) in a strict or harsh way <vi>Don't criticize him so much. He's doing the best he can. Why don't you <it>give him a break</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brake[1]"> <hw hindex="1">brake</hw> <sound><wav>brake001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>brakes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a device for slowing or stopping something (such as a wheel or vehicle) <vi>She released the <it>brake</it> slowly.</vi> <vi>Take your foot off the <it>brake</it>.</vi> <un>often plural <vi>The car will need new <it>brakes</it> soon.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>slammed/jammed on the brakes</phrase> [=he applied the brakes very quickly] to avoid hitting the other car.</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>brake</it> shoes/fluid</vi> <vi>Take your foot off the <it>brake</it> pedal.</vi> <vi>I didn't notice that the car in front of me had its <it>brake</it> lights on.</vi></un> <dx>see picture at <dxt>bicycle</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>disc brake</dxt> <dxt>emergency brake</dxt> <dxt>hand brake</dxt> <dxt>parking brake</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something used to slow or stop movement or activity <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>They plan to use interest rates as a <it>brake on</it> spending. [=as a way to slow down spending]</vi> <vi>trying to <phrase>put the brakes on</phrase> crime</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="broke[1]"> <hw hindex="1">broke</hw> <cx><cl>past tense of</cl> <ct>break</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="break dancing"> <hw>break dancing</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a type of dancing in which a dancer performs very athletic movements that involve touching the ground with various parts of the body (such as the head or back)</dt></def> <uro><ure>break dancer</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="break-even"> <hw>break–even</hw> <sound><wav>breake02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪkˈi:vən</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:having equal costs and income <vi>After years of losing money the company has finally reached the <phrase>break-even point</phrase> [=the point at which the company earns as much as it spends] and we hope to make a profit soon.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>break even</tag> at <dxt>break</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="break-in"> <hw>break–in</hw> <sound><wav>break_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪkˌɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>break–ins</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the act or crime of illegally entering a house, building, etc., especially by using force <vi>There was an attempted <it>break-in</it> at our house while we were away.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>break in</tag> at <dxt>break</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="coffee break"> <hw>coffee break</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ breaks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a short period of time in which you stop working to rest and have coffee or some other refreshment</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="fast break"> <hw>fast break</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ breaks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>basketball</sl> <dt>:a quick movement toward the net in an attempt to score before the opposing players can reach their defensive positions</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="lunch break"> <hw>lunch break</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ breaks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the time when people stop working or studying to have lunch :<sx>lunch hour</sx> <vi>Let's go out during our <it>lunch break</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
