<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="breathe"> <hw highlight="yes">breathe</hw> <sound><wav>breath05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbri:ð</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>breathes</if></in> <in><if>breathed</if></in> <in><if>breath*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move air into and out of your lungs :to inhale and exhale <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Relax and <it>breathe</it> deeply.</vi> <vi>He was <it>breathing</it> hard from running.</vi> <vi>The patient suddenly stopped <it>breathing</it>.</vi> <vi>I can hardly <it>breathe</it> with all this smoke.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He wants to live where he can <it>breathe</it> clean/fresh air.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to send (something) out from your lungs through your mouth or nose <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>a dragon that <it>breathes</it> fire</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> <vi><it>breathing out</it> [=<it>exhaling</it>] carbon dioxide</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>breathed</it> [=<it>blew</it>] on the glass and wiped it clean.</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> <vi><it>Breathe out</it> through your nose.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take (something) into your lungs through your mouth or nose <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You shouldn't be <it>breathing</it> [=<it>inhaling</it>] those fumes.</vi> <vi>People usually contract the virus by <it>breathing</it> contaminated air.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>You shouldn't be <it>breathing in</it> those fumes.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Breathe</it> deeply and then exhale.</vi> <un>usually + <it>in</it> <vi><it>Breathe in</it> through your nose.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be alive <vi>I'll never give up as long as I'm still <it>breathing</it>.</vi> <vi>a living, <it>breathing</it> human being</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to pause and rest before continuing <vi>We had barely stopped to <it>breathe</it> before we were on the go again.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to bring (something) <it>into</it> a thing <vi>City leaders hope the project will <it>breathe</it> vitality/energy <it>into</it> the downtown.</vi> <vi>Their leadership <phrase>breathed new life into</phrase> the movement. [=gave new energy to the movement]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to feel able to think or act freely <vi>I need some room to <it>breathe</it>. = I need some <it>breathing</it> room/space.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to allow air to pass through <vi>a fabric that <it>breathes</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be cooled or refreshed by air that passes through clothing <vi>Cotton clothing lets your skin <it>breathe</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say (something) very quietly <vi>“It's beautiful,” she <it>breathed</it>.</vi> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>breathe a word</phrase> <vi>Don't <it>breathe a word</it> of/about this to anyone! [=do not say anything about this to anyone]</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of wine</ssl> <dt>:to develop a better flavor because of contact with air <vi>Open the bottle a few minutes before you want to drink it so that the wine can <it>breathe</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>breathe a sigh of relief</dre> <def><dt>:to relax because something you have been worrying about is not a problem or danger anymore :to feel relieved <vi>We all <it>breathed a sigh of relief</it> when we heard that they were safe.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe down someone's neck</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to chase after someone closely <vi>The cops were <it>breathing down our necks</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to watch someone carefully and constantly <vi>His parents are always <it>breathing down his neck</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe easy</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>breathe easier</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>breathe easily</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>breathe freely</va></vr> <def><dt>:to feel relief from pressure, danger, etc. <vi>I'll <it>breathe easier</it> once this whole ordeal is over.</vi> <vi>You can <it>breathe easy</it> knowing that your children are safe.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe your last</dre> <dx>see <dxt>last</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>live and breathe</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>live and breathe</it> something, you spend a great deal of time, thought, or effort on that thing. <vi>She <it>lives and breathes</it> music.</vi> <vi>They <it>live and breathe</it> their work.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>breath*able</ure> <sound><wav>breath02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbri:ðəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more breath*able; most breath*able</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>breathable</it> fabric [=a fabric that allows air to pass through]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>breathing</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>Her <it>breathing</it> is heavy/shallow/labored.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>We'll begin with some <it>breathing</it> exercises.</vi> <vi>He has <it>breathing</it> problems.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>heavy breathing</tag> at <dxt>heavy</dxt></dx></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="easily"> <hw>eas*i*ly</hw> <sound><wav>easily01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈi:zəli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>more eas*i*ly; most eas*i*ly</sgram> <dt>:in an easy manner :without difficulty <vi>We won the game <it>easily</it>. [=<it>with ease</it>]</vi> <vi>These ingredients are <it>easily</it> obtained.</vi> <vi>I'm too heavy to be carried <it>easily</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:by a great extent or degree :by far <vi>She's <it>easily</it> the best player on the team. [=she is much better than the other players]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>breathe easily</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breathe</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="easy[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">easy</hw> <altpr>ˈi:zi</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>easier</if></in> <in><if>easiest</if></in> <def><dt>:without difficulty or stress <vi>He just wants to take life <it>easy</it> now.</vi> <vi>The repairs will cost $100, <it>easy</it>. [=the repairs will cost at least $100]</vi> <vi>“We just need to raise the money.” “That's <phrase>easier said than done</phrase>.” [=that will not be easy to do]</vi> <vi>Success hasn't <phrase>come easy</phrase> for her. [=success has not been easy to achieve]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>breathe easy</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breathe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you are not bothered about losing something <vi>His attitude toward money has always been, <it>easy come, easy go</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>easy does it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell someone to move slowly and carefully <vi><it>Easy does it</it>! We don't want anyone to get hurt.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go easy</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go easy on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to treat (someone) in a way that is not harsh or demanding <vi>The students might respond better if the teacher <it>went</it> (a little) <it>easy on</it> them.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go easy on/with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use less of (something) <vi>My doctor said to <it>go easy on</it> fatty foods.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>nice and easy</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>rest easy</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take it easy</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to relax and avoid hard work or strain <vi>The doctor told her she should <it>take it easy</it> for a while.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stay or become calm and unexcited <un>usually used as a command <vi><it>Take it easy</it>, Joe. Everything is going to be just fine.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="last[4]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="4">last</hw> <altpr>ˈlæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈlɑ:st</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the last</bnote> <dt>:the last person or thing in a group or series <vi>He was <it>the last</it> in line.</vi> <vi>It was <it>the last</it> of many delays.</vi> <vi>She was <it>the last</it> to leave.</vi> <vi><it>The last</it> of the tests was given today.</vi> <vi>This is the first time we've been here, but it definitely won't be <it>the last</it>! [=we will definitely come here again]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <bnote>the last</bnote> <dt>:the last time someone is seen, something is mentioned, etc. <vi>I guess that is <it>the last</it> we will see of her. [=the last time we will see her]</vi> <vi>I hope that we have finally <phrase>seen the last</phrase> of them. [=I hope that we will not see them again]</vi> <vi>He knew he had not <phrase>heard the last</phrase> of his mistake. [=he knew that he would hear again about his mistake]</vi> <vi>Don't tell them about your mistake or you'll never <phrase>hear the last of it</phrase>. [=they'll keep reminding you of it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a final action <vi>I've spoken my <it>last</it> on this subject. [=I've spoken for the last time on this subject; I will not be saying anything more on this subject]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe the most recent information you have about someone or something <vi>“Where's Hank these days?” “<phrase>(The) Last I heard</phrase>, he was living in New York.” [=the most recent information I have heard is that he was living in New York]</vi> <vi>“Do you know where my keys are?” “<phrase>(The) Last I saw</phrase> [=the last time I saw them], they were in the kitchen.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the last</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the end of something <vi>We stayed at the game till/until <it>the last</it>. [=until it ended]</vi> <vi>They fought hard to <it>the last</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the end of someone's life <vi>He was cheerful to <it>the last</it>. [=until he died]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the final thing or things that have been mentioned previously <vi>They had cats, dogs, and a horse. This <it>last</it> [=the horse] was kept in an old barn.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the most recent one of something <vi>The week before <it>last</it> [=the week before last week] I saw him at a restaurant.</vi> <vi>the night before <it>last</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>breathe your last</dre> <def><sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to die <vi>This is the room where he <it>breathed his last</it>. [=where he breathed his last breath; where he died]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="life[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">life</hw> <sound><wav>life0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪf</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>lives</if> <sound><wav>life0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪvz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to grow, change, etc., that separates plants and animals from things like water or rocks <vi>He believes that God gives <it>life</it> to all creatures.</vi> <vi>the miracle of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>eternal/everlasting <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the period of time when a person is alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She knew what she wanted to do <phrase>early in life</phrase>. [=when she was young]</vi> <vi>He became famous relatively <phrase>late in life</phrase>. [=at a relatively old age]</vi> <vi>He became famous <phrase>later in life</phrase>. = He became famous <phrase>in later life</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She was happy and healthy for most of her <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>The people in her family tend to have long/short <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her all my <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>He is nearing the end of his <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>They spent their whole/entire <it>lives</it> in one town. = They lived in one town all their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>People can expect to change jobs several times in their <it>life/lives</it>.</vi> <vi>They've been waiting their whole/entire <it>life/lives</it> for an opportunity like this.</vi> <vi>This is the financial opportunity <phrase>of his life</phrase>. [=<it>of his lifetime</it>; the best chance in his life to make money]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the experience of being alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want out of <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>He believes in living <it>life</it> to the fullest. [=in living a very full and rich life]</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>The details of everyday/ordinary <it>life</it> can be fascinating.</vi> <vi><it>life</it> in the city/country = city/country <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Sometimes <it>life</it> just isn't fair.</vi> <vi>We can laugh at things in movies that would scare us in <phrase>real life</phrase>. [=in a real situation; in actual existence]</vi> <vi>Oh well, <phrase>that's life</phrase>! [=bad things will happen, and you have to deal with them]</vi> <vi>Despite the political upheaval, for most people <phrase>life goes on</phrase> as usual. [=the activities of life continue in the usual way]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want to do with your <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>Her children say that she has ruined their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>She talked about the men in her <it>life</it>. [=the men she has had a romantic or close relationship with during her life]</vi> <vi>She has dedicated/devoted <it>her life</it> to helping other people.</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made my <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>They're trying to <phrase>get/put their lives back together</phrase>. [=to begin living in a normal way after suffering loss, hardship, etc.]</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>the love of my life</phrase>. [=the person I loved more than any other person at any time in my life]</vi> <vi>I've never heard such a silly idea <phrase>in all my life</phrase>! [=at any time] = Never <phrase>in my life</phrase> have I heard such a silly idea!</vi> <vi>They're old enough to <phrase>run/live their own lives</phrase>. [=to make their own decisions about how to live]</vi> <vi>After all the problems they've had recently, they just want to <phrase>get/move on with their lives</phrase>. [=to continue living their lives in the usual way]</vi> <vi>I'm not surprised that I didn't get the job. That's <phrase>the story of my life</phrase>. [=that's the way things usually or always happen in my life]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>She told us her <phrase>life story</phrase>. [=she told us about many of the things that had happened to her in her life]</vi> <vi>a lack of <phrase>life experience</phrase> [=experience and knowledge gained through living]</vi></un> <snote>If your <phrase>life flashes/passes before your eyes</phrase> or if your <phrase>life flashes/passes before you</phrase>, many memories from different parts of your life quickly appear in your mind one after the other. <vi>Her <it>life flashed before her eyes</it> when her car was about to crash.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a specified part of a person's life <vi>He talked about his <it>life</it> as an artist.</vi> <vi>the social <it>lives</it> of college students</vi> <vi>How's your love/sex <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>They had difficult home <it>lives</it> when they were children.</vi> <vi>They are trying to keep their personal/private <it>lives</it> separate from their public <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>the responsibilities of their family <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a specified way or manner of living <vi>He lived/led a <it>life</it> of crime. [=he was a criminal]</vi> <vi>They have lived/led sheltered <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>He is trying to make a better <it>life</it> for himself and his family.</vi> <snote>Your <phrase>way of life</phrase> is how you live your life. <vi>a fisherman's <it>way of life</it></vi> <vi>Most people don't approve of my <it>way of life</it>.</vi> <vi>a traditional <it>way of life</it></vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition of being alive <vi>They spared the horse's <it>life</it>. [=they did not kill the horse]</vi> <vi>She feels that her <it>life</it> is in danger. = She <phrase>fears for her life</phrase>. = She is <phrase>in fear for her life</phrase>. [=she feels that she is in danger of being killed]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>risked her life</phrase> [=she did something very dangerous that could have resulted in her death] to help him.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>gave/sacrificed her life</phrase> [=she did something that resulted in her death] for her country.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>running for his life</phrase>. [=he was running to escape from great danger]</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>fighting for his life</phrase>. [=he is very sick or injured and may die]</vi> <vi>A would-be assassin <phrase>made an attempt on the President's life</phrase>. [=tried to kill the President]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:living things of a specified kind or in a specified place <vi>There may be a great deal of animal/plant <it>life</it> still to be discovered in this region.</vi> <vi>forest <it>life</it></vi> <vi>ocean <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Will we ever find intelligent <it>life</it> on other planets?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the time when something can be used :the period when something exists or is useful or effective <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>battery <it>life</it></vi> <vi>the <it>life</it> of an insurance policy</vi> <vi>They claim that using their product will extend the <it>life</it> of the car.</vi> <vi>a warranty that is good for the <it>life</it> of the product</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a product that extends the <it>lives</it> of the rugs/cars</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>half-life</dxt> <dxt>shelf life</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:energy and spirit <vi>eyes full of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) suck the <it>life</it> out of a room [=take all the fun and energy out of a group of people in a room]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:activity and movement <vi>The streets were humming with <it>life</it>. [=the streets were filled with people and activity]</vi> <vi>There were no signs of <it>life</it> in the deserted village.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a book that tells about the life of a person :<sx>biography</sx> <vi>She wrote a <it>life</it> of Napoleon.</vi> <vi>Boswell's <it>Life of Johnson</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the punishment of being kept in a prison for the rest of your life :<sx>life imprisonment</sx> <vi>He was found guilty and sentenced to <it>life</it>. = (<it>informal</it>) He got <it>life</it>. = He was given <it>life</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a dog's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a life of its own</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <phrase>takes on a life of its own</phrase> becomes very large, important, or hard to control. <vi>The project soon <it>took on a life of its own</it> and prevented us from getting any other work done.</vi> <vi>The story <it>took on a life of its own</it> and began to appear on news broadcasts everywhere.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all walks of life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>every walk of life</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>walk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a matter of life and death</dre> <def><dt>:something that is extremely important and often involves decisions that will determine whether someone lives or dies <vi>Being prepared for severe weather can be <it>a matter of life and death</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>life-and-death</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a new lease on/of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lease</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(as) big as life</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) large as life</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in person <un>used to describe the surprise of seeing someone <vi>I never expected her to come to the party, but there she was, <it>as big as life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bet/stake your life on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you would <it>bet/stake your life on</it> something, you are very sure that it will happen. <vi>“Will she keep her promise?” “I'd <it>bet/stake my life on</it> it!”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe (new) life into</dre> <def><dt>:to give new energy and excitement to (something) <vi>She is credited with <it>breathing new life into</it> contemporary art.</vi> <vi>The singer managed to <it>breathe life into</it> some tired old songs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring someone or something back to life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone or something that has died to begin living again <vi>The story is about a mad scientist who tries to <it>bring</it> dead people <it>back to life</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>They're trying to <it>bring</it> the restaurant <it>back to life</it> by introducing a new menu.</vi> <vi>an old theory that is <it>being brought back to life</it></vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring something to life</dre> <def><dt>:to make something very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>She <it>brings</it> history <it>to life</it> with her books.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to life</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>The movie really <it>comes to life</it> when she appears on the screen.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a place</ssl> <dt>:to become filled with the energy and excitement of active people <vi>Downtown <it>comes to life</it> each night when the clubs open.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>sputter/roar (etc.) to life</va></svr> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to begin working <vi>The engine suddenly <it>roared to life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>depart this life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>depart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for dear life</dre> <def><dt>:very tightly or quickly because of fear or danger <vi>He was hanging/holding on to the rope <it>for dear life</it>.</vi> <vi>They were running <it>for dear life</it> to get away from the vicious dogs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for life</dre> <def><dt>:for the whole of your life :for the rest of your life <vi>They met in college and have remained friends <it>for life</it>.</vi> <vi>He was sentenced to prison <it>for life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for the life of me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in any way at all <un>used to say that you are unable to remember or understand something <vi>I couldn't <it>for the life of me</it> remember what her name was.</vi> <vi><it>For the life of me</it>, I can't think of any reasons why you wouldn't want a computer at home.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>frighten/scare the life out of</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to frighten (someone) very badly <vi>You (nearly) <it>scared the life out of</it> me when you startled me like that!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from life</dre> <def><sl>of a painting, drawing, etc.</sl> <dt>:from looking at an actual person, object, etc. <vi>drawings done <it>from life</it> rather than from photographs</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get a life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop spending time doing or thinking about things that are not important or interesting :to begin to have a more interesting or exciting life <vi>My girlfriend's parents are nice people, but all they do is watch TV all day. They need to <it>get a life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>larger than life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>large</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay down your life</dre> <dx>see <tag>lay down</tag> at <dxt>lay</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>life depends on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If your <it>life depends on</it> something, then you must do it. <vi>His <it>life depends on</it> how he answers this question.</vi> <vi>He was studying as if his <it>life depended on</it> it.</vi></snote> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>I wouldn't eat that food if my <it>life depended on</it> it. [=I would never eat it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose your life</dre> <def><dt>:to die <vi>She nearly <it>lost her life</it> in a car accident.</vi> <vi>Many <it>lives were lost</it>. [=many people died]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>new life</dre> <def><dt><snote>When something <phrase>takes on (a) new life</phrase> or when you <phrase>give something new life</phrase> or <phrase>give new life to something</phrase>, it becomes more active, interesting, etc. <vi>Plain old mashed potatoes <it>take on a new life</it> in this recipe.</vi> <vi>Falling interest rates <it>gave new life to</it> the housing market.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not on your life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a very forceful way of saying “no” or “never” <vi>Do the government's policies really help the average worker? <it>Not on your life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>risk life and limb</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that is very dangerous <vi>They <it>risked life and limb</it> to pull the child from the river.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>spring into/to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spring</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>staff of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>staff</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>such is life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>such</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take/claim someone's life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's death <vi>Two years ago he was diagnosed with the illness that eventually <it>took his life</it>.</vi> <vi>The flood <it>claimed many lives</it>. [=caused the deaths of many people]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your own life</dre> <def><dt>:to kill yourself <vi>He threatened to <it>take his own life</it> [=<it>commit suicide</it>], but no one believed him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the life of the party</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>the life and soul of the party</va></vr> <def><dt>:someone who is very lively and amusing at a party or other social gathering</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the light of your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the next life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the life to come</va></vr> <def><dt>:a life that is believed by some people to come after death <vi>He believed that he would see his family again in <it>the next life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the simple life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>simple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to save your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>true to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>true</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>fact of life</dxt> <dxt>good life</dxt> <dxt>slice-of-life</dxt> <dxt>still life</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="live[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">live</hw> <sound><wav>live0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlɪv</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>lives</if></in> <in><if>lived</if></in> <in><if>liv*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be alive <vi>We learned about the people who <it>lived</it> during colonial times.</vi> <vi>I wonder what it was like to <it>live</it> then.</vi> <vi>She's one of the greatest writers who ever <it>lived</it>.</vi> <vi>It was one of the largest animals that has ever <it>lived</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to be alive <vi>He <it>lived</it> to the age of 92.</vi> <vi>He's very sick and he may not <it>live</it> much longer.</vi> <vi>I hope to <it>live</it> (long enough) to see my grandchildren grow up.</vi> <vi>I hope I <it>live</it> to see the day when you admit you've been wrong about me!</vi> <vi>I'll remember that day <phrase>for as long as I live</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She's <phrase>living on borrowed time</phrase>. [=she is continuing to live after she was expected to die, but she will probably die soon]</vi> <vi><phrase>Long live</phrase> the Queen/King! [=may the Queen/King live for many years]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have a home in a specified place <vi>He <it>lives</it> next door to his parents.</vi> <vi>We <it>lived in</it> the city/suburbs/country.</vi> <vi>I <it>live</it> on Main St. [=my house is on Main St.]</vi> <vi>It's a nice place to visit, but I wouldn't want to <it>live</it> there.</vi> <vi>He's still <it>living</it> at home (with his parents).</vi> <vi>animals <it>living</it> in zoos</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a plant or animal</ssl> <dt>:to grow naturally in a specified place or area <vi>Tigers don't <it>live</it> in Africa. [=there are no tigers in the wild in Africa]</vi> <vi>We've been studying the plants and animals that <it>live</it> in this area.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to spend your life in a certain way or condition <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>live</it> well/simply.</vi> <vi>He likes to <it>live</it> dangerously.</vi> <vi>They <it>lived</it> peacefully for many years.</vi> <vi>animals <it>living</it> in captivity</vi> <vi>We know very little about how people in these ancient cultures <it>lived</it>.</vi> <vi>They all <phrase>lived happily ever after</phrase>. [=they all lived happily for the rest of their lives]</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>living within/beyond his means</phrase>. [=he can/cannot afford the things that he buys or the way he lives]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>If she believes that, she's <it>living</it> a fantasy. [=she is not seeing or accepting reality]</vi> <vi>They are <it>living</it> the American Dream. [=they are experiencing success in America]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have an enjoyable and exciting life <vi>Now that he's retired he just wants to <phrase>live a little</phrase>. [=to spend time doing enjoyable things]</vi> <vi><phrase>You haven't lived</phrase> until you've had a piece of my mom's apple pie! [=you would greatly enjoy my mom's apple pie]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to spend (your life or part of your life) in a specified way <vi>They <it>lived</it> (the rest of) their lives in quiet retirement.</vi> <vi>He had <it>lived</it> a childhood free from worry.</vi> <vi>She <it>lived</it> her final years in seclusion.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>lived life to the full/fullest</phrase>. [=he fully enjoyed his life]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have (a particular kind of life) <vi>She wants to <it>live</it> [=<it>lead</it>] a more productive life.</vi> <vi>They <it>live</it> a normal life.</vi> <vi>They are <it>living</it> a life of luxury.</vi> <vi>He made a lot of money in the stock market and he's been <phrase>living the good life</phrase> [=living the life of a wealthy person] ever since.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to exist <vi>The good that people do <it>lives</it> long after they are gone.</vi> <vi>That day will always <it>live</it> in my memory. [=I will always remember that day]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to belong in a specified place :to be located or stored <vi>“Where does this book <it>live</it>?” “It goes/belongs on the top shelf.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>live a lie</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lie</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>live and breathe</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breathe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>live and learn</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>you live and (you) learn</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you have learned something from an experience that is surprising and usually unpleasant <vi>I thought I could trust him, but I couldn't. Oh well, <it>you live and learn</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live and let live</dre> <def><dt>:to let others live the way they want to <vi>His philosophy was to <it>live and let live</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>live by (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to agree with and follow (something, such as a set of beliefs) <vi>He tried to <it>live by</it> his faith.</vi> <vi>a principle I try to <it>live by</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>live by (doing something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to survive by (doing something) <vi>They were an ancient people who <it>lived by</it> hunting and gathering.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>live by your wits</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to survive by doing clever and sometimes dishonest things <vi>Out in the jungle, with no food or shelter, he had to <it>live by his wits</it>.</vi> <vi>a young thief who <it>lives by her wits</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>live down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>live (something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop being blamed or laughed at for (something, such as a foolish or embarrassing error) <vi>He has a very bad reputation to <it>live down</it>.</vi> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>I can't believe I forgot my wife's birthday! I'll never <it>live</it> this <it>down</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>live for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to wait or hope for (something) very eagerly <vi>I <it>live for</it> the day when we'll be together!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to think of (something) as the most important or enjoyable part of your life <vi>She <it>lives for</it> her work.</vi> :to think of (something) as a reason for being alive <vi>He's depressed and feels as if he has nothing left to <it>live for</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to live in the place where you work :to live in another person's home <vi>a maid who <it>lives in</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live in hope</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hope</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>live in sin</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to live together and have sex without being married <vi>His mother did not want him <it>living in sin</it> with his girlfriend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live in the past</dre> <def><dt>:to think too much about something that happened in the past <vi>You have to accept that he's gone and stop <it>living in the past</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live it up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to do exciting and enjoyable things <vi>He's been <it>living it up</it> out in California with his friends.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live large</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt>:to live like a very wealthy and successful person <vi>a star who is <it>living large</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>live off (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (someone or something) as a source of the money or other things you need to live <vi>He has been <it>living off</it> his inheritance.</vi> <vi>He has been <it>living off</it> his girlfriend. [=his girlfriend has been supporting him financially]</vi> <vi>farmers who <it>live off</it> the land</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist <vi>His legend <it>lives on</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>live on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have or use (an amount of money) to pay for the things that you need to live <vi>You can't <it>live on</it> this salary. [=this salary does not provide enough money for food, shelter, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have (a particular food) as the only or main food that you eat <vi>They <it>lived</it> mainly/mostly <it>on</it> fruits and berries.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to live away from the place where you work <vi>a servant who <it>lives out</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>live out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>live (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to spend the rest of (your life) in a specified way <vi>He <it>lived out</it> (the final years of) his life in quiet retirement.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do (the things you have dreamed of doing) <vi>He has finally had the chance to <it>live out</it> his dreams/fantasies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>live through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to survive (an experience, a troubling time, etc.) :<sx>endure</sx> <vi>If I can <it>live through</it> this, I can <it>live through</it> anything.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>live through (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sometimes disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy the experiences and achievements of (another person) instead of your own experiences and achievements <vi>She can't <it>live through</it> her daughter.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to live with another person and have sex without being married <vi>They <it>lived together</it> for several months before getting married.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live up to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>live up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do what is required by (something) <vi>She <it>lived up to</it> her promises. [=she kept her promises]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be good enough for (something) <vi>He has found it difficult to <it>live up to</it> his name/reputation. [=to be as good/successful as people think he is or should be]</vi> <vi>Their vacation didn't <it>live up to</it> their expectations. [=their vacation wasn't as good as they expected it to be]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>live with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>live with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to accept and deal with (something unpleasant) <vi>You have to learn to <it>live with</it> [=<it>put up with</it>] other people's mistakes.</vi> <vi>I don't agree with his decision, but I'll have to <it>live with</it> it.</vi> <vi>Until we get a better answer, we will have to <it>live with</it> not knowing for sure.</vi> <vi>Because there was no cure, he had to learn to <it>live with</it> the disease.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>live with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to live together and usually have sex with (someone) <vi>She's been <it>living with</it> him since college.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="neck[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">neck</hw> <sound><wav>neck0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnɛk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>necks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the part of the body between the head and the shoulders <vi>She craned/stretched her <it>neck</it> to see what was going on.</vi> <vi>A giraffe is an animal with a very long <it>neck</it>.</vi> <vi>He broke his <it>neck</it> in the accident.</vi> <vi>Stop jumping on the bed. You're going to <phrase>break your neck</phrase>. [=you're going to hurt yourself]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the part of a piece of clothing that fits around your neck <vi>He likes T-shirts with round <it>necks</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>crew neck</dxt> <dxt>polo neck</dxt> <dxt>scoop neck</dxt> <dxt>turtleneck</dxt> <dxt>v-neck</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a long and narrow part of something :a part that is shaped like a neck <vi>He grabbed the <it>neck</it> of the bottle.</vi> <vi>a <it>neck</it> of land [=a narrow stretch of land]</vi> <vi>a guitar's <it>neck</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>breathe down someone's neck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breathe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead from the neck up</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get it in the neck</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be severely punished or criticized <vi>He really <it>got it in the neck</it> for not finishing the job on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>neck and neck</dre> <def><dt>:extremely close together in a race or contest <vi>The two candidates for president were <it>neck and neck</it> in the election.</vi> <vi>The two horses were running <it>neck and neck</it> to the finish line.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>neck of the woods</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the place or area where someone lives <vi>He's from my <it>neck of the woods</it>. [=he's from the area where I live]</vi> <vi>How is the weather in your <it>neck of the woods</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>risk your neck</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that puts you in danger of serious injury or death <vi>I would never <it>risk my neck</it> on a sport like skydiving.</vi> <vi>News reporters often <it>risk their necks</it> by working in war zones.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's neck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stick your neck out</dre> <def><dt>:to do or say something you think is important even though it may have bad results <vi>He's not afraid to <it>stick his neck out</it> to help people he thinks are being mistreated.</vi> <vi>I respect my boss because she will <it>stick her neck out</it> against unfair policies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your neck in</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in or affected by (something) <vi>She's <it>up to her neck in</it> work. [=she's very busy]</vi> <vi>He's <it>up to his neck in</it> debt.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wring someone's neck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wring</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
