<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="brief[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">brief</hw> <sound><wav>brief001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbri:f</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>brief*er</if></in> <in><if>brief*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:lasting only a short period of time <vi>The meeting will be <it>brief</it>.</vi> <vi>She worked there for only a <it>brief</it> period (of time) in the late 1980s.</vi> <vi>They stopped by for a <it>brief</it> [=<it>quick</it>] visit.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:using only a few words <vi>I promise to be <it>brief</it>. [=I promise to say what I need to say quickly]</vi> <vi>She gave a <it>brief</it> [=<it>concise</it>] description/summary/history of the problem.</vi> <vi>The essay is <it>brief</it> but thorough enough.</vi> <vi>I'd like to say <phrase>a brief word</phrase> [=a few words] about the people who made this event possible.</vi> <vi>a few <it>brief words</it> of caution/praise</vi> <vi>I'd like to <phrase>have a brief word</phrase> with you. [=I would like to have a short conversation with you]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>in brief</tag> at <dxt>brief</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of clothing</ssl> <dt>:covering less of the body than is usual <vi><it>brief</it> skirts/shorts</vi> <vi>a <it>brief</it> bikini</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brief[2]"> <hw hindex="2">brief</hw> <altpr>ˈbri:f</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>briefs</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a brief statement or report <vi>a news <it>brief</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:a document that states the facts a lawyer plans to use in a court case <vi>a legal <it>brief</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:instructions that explain what a person is supposed to do <vi>Her <it>brief</it> is to manage the company's sales department.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>briefs</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:short underpants for men, women, or children that fit close to the body <vi>a pair of <it>briefs</it></vi> <dx>see color picture on page C13</dx> <dx>compare <dxt>boxer shorts</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>lawyer</sx> <vi>the defendant's <it>brief</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in brief</dre> <def><dt>:in a few words <vi>Here is today's news <it>in brief</it>. [=here is a brief report of today's news]</vi> <vi>Their conclusion, <it>in brief</it>, is that we need more funding.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brief[3]"> <hw hindex="3">brief</hw> <altpr>ˈbri:f</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>briefs</if></in> <in><if>briefed</if></in> <in><if>brief*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to give information or instructions to (someone) <vi>The captain <it>briefed</it> the crew on the new safety procedures.</vi> <vi>The President has been <it>briefed</it> by his advisers.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>debrief</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>briefing</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>briefings</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a military <it>briefing</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="watching brief"> <hw>watching brief</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:an act of watching the actions of a person or organization to make sure nothing illegal or wrong is being done <vi>They have been <phrase>keeping a watching brief</phrase> on the company's financial dealings.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hold[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">hold</hw> <sound><wav>hold0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhoʊld</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>holds</if></in> <in><if>held</if> <sound><wav>hold0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛld</pr></in> <in><if>hold*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (something) in your hand, arms, etc. <vi><it>Hold</it> the rail so you won't fall.</vi> <vi>He was <it>holding</it> his hat (in his hand).</vi> <vi>He was <it>holding</it> a large package in his arms.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>hold</it> this for me?</vi> <vi>She showed him the correct way to <it>hold</it> the racket.</vi> <vi>She <it>held</it> his hand. = She <it>held</it> him by the hand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put your arms around (someone) :to embrace or hug (someone) <vi>Some people just don't like to be <it>held</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>held</it> her close/tight and kissed her.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put or keep (something or someone) in a specified place or position <vi>He <it>held</it> the pen in his mouth while he dialed the number.</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> the pen upright when you write.</vi> <vi>She picked up the trophy and <it>held</it> it over her head.</vi> <vi>You have to <it>hold</it> the button down for several seconds.</vi> <vi>I <it>held</it> the door open for her.</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> your arms at your sides.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to keep (something or someone) in the same place or position <vi>I need someone to <it>hold</it> this string while I finish tying the knot.</vi> <vi>She <it>held</it> the ladder steady while he climbed up it.</vi> <vi>It took six guards to <it>hold</it> him (down).</vi> <vi>The board was <it>held</it> in place/position by a couple of nails.</vi> <vi>The Federal Reserve has been <it>holding</it> interest rates down/up.</vi> <vi>The cover was <phrase>held on</phrase> by a piece of tape.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to remain in the same place or position <vi>The anchor <it>held</it>.</vi> <vi>The line of soldiers <it>held</it> under constant attack.</vi> <vi>Please <phrase>hold still</phrase> for a moment.</vi> <vi>His weight has <phrase>held steady</phrase> for several months now.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to be good <vi>We arrived late but our luck <it>held</it> and we were able to get tickets.</vi> <vi>We hope the weather <it>holds</it> through the weekend.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to own or possess (something) <vi>The bank <it>holds</it> (the) title to the car.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>hold</it> any shares/stock in the company?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (a job, a position, etc.) <vi>She has never before <it>held</it> public office.</vi> <vi>It's been a struggle for him to <it>hold</it> a job.</vi> <vi>In the last election the Democratic party managed to <it>hold</it> several seats but lost others.</vi> <vi>President Franklin Roosevelt <phrase>held office</phrase> for 12 years. = Franklin Roosevelt <it>held</it> the office of president for 12 years.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to succeed in keeping (something that is being attacked) <vi>The troops were able to <it>hold</it> the bridge.</vi> <vi>The line of soldiers <phrase>held their position/ground</phrase> and fought off the attack.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to have (something that you have achieved or earned) <vi>She <it>holds</it> a master's degree in chemistry.</vi> <vi>a swimmer who <it>holds</it> several world records</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to support the pressure or weight of (something or someone) <vi>The floor will <it>hold</it> 10 tons.</vi> <vi>I don't know if the roof can <it>hold</it> all that snow.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (a belief, a feeling, etc.) in your mind <vi>There's no need for him to <it>hold</it> [=<it>bear</it>] a grudge against me.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>hold</it> any resentment toward/against him.</vi> <vi>a belief <it>held</it> by many = a widely <it>held</it> belief</vi> <vi>I will always <it>hold</it> that memory in my heart.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to consider or judge (someone or something) in a specified way <vi>They <it>hold</it> me responsible.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>He should be <it>held</it> accountable <it>for</it> his actions.</vi> <vi>The store can't be <it>held</it> liable <it>for</it> damage to your vehicle.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>The court <it>held</it> his actions <it>to be</it> grounds for a lawsuit. [=the court said/ruled that his actions were grounds for a lawsuit]</vi> <vi>His latest book is generally/widely <it>held</it> [=<it>considered</it>] <it>to be</it> the best one.</vi> <vi>“We <it>hold</it> these truths <it>to be</it> self-evident…” <aq>U.S. Declaration of Independence (1776)</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to have or express (an opinion, belief, etc.) <un>+ <it>that</it> <vi>I <it>hold</it> [=<it>believe</it>] <it>that</it> such problems should be dealt with at the federal level.</vi> <vi>The Supreme Court <it>held</it> [=<it>ruled</it>] <it>that</it> the trial court had acted properly.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Tradition <it>holds that</it> [=it is traditional that] the oldest member of the family be seated first.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a meeting, class, sale, etc.) to take place <vi>A sale will be <it>held</it> next weekend.</vi> <vi>Free elections will be <it>held</it> next month.</vi> <vi>We will <it>hold</it> [=<it>have</it>] the meeting at 2 o'clock.</vi> <vi>The President has decided to <it>hold</it> [=<it>give</it>] a press conference.</vi> <vi>They're <it>holding</it> an art show at the gallery.</vi> <vi>The two sides will <it>hold</it> [=<it>have</it>] talks/discussions to resolve the dispute.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to contain (something) <vi>The box <it>holds</it> his collection of old photographs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to have enough room for (an amount) <vi>The disk can <it>hold</it> 1.44 megabytes of data.</vi> <vi>How much water can that bucket <it>hold</it>?</vi> <vi>The bottle <it>holds</it> two liters.</vi> <vi>The dining room <it>holds</it> 500 people.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to have (someone's interest or attention) <vi>The speaker wasn't able to <it>hold</it> [=<it>keep</it>] our interest/attention for long.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (a specified quality, feature, etc.) <vi>His eyes <it>held</it> [=<it>had</it>] a quizzical look.</vi> <vi>She has always <it>held</it> a special place in my heart. [=I have always had special feelings for her]</vi> <vi>This hotel has long <it>held</it> [=<it>claimed</it>] a place among the world's finest. [=has long been considered one of the world's finest]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Music <it>holds</it> great appeal <it>for</it> many people. [=music appeals greatly to many people]</vi> <vi>His job <it>holds</it> no surprises <it>for</it> him. [=nothing about his job surprises him]</vi> <vi>Her paintings <it>hold</it> a real fascination <it>for</it> me. [=her paintings fascinate me]</vi> <vi>No one can know what the future <it>holds</it> (<it>for</it> us). [=no one can know what will happen (to us) in the future]</vi> <vi>These experiments <it>hold</it> great promise <it>for</it> future cancer research.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop doing (something) or wait to do (something) <vi>Tell the men to <phrase>hold their fire</phrase> [=not shoot] until I give the order.</vi> <vi><phrase>Hold everything</phrase>. [=wait; stop] We're not doing this right.</vi> <vi><phrase>Hold it</phrase> right there. [=stop right there] Where do you think you're going?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) available for later use <vi>A room at the hotel will be <it>held</it> for us for 24 hours.</vi> <vi>We will <it>hold</it> these flight reservations for you until tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to delay the handling of (something, such as a telephone call) for a time <vi>Please <it>hold</it> all my calls while I'm in the meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to prevent (something, such as a vehicle) from leaving <vi>The train was <it>held</it> until the track was cleared.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>hold</it> the elevator for me?</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> that taxi!</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to not use or include (something) in preparing food <vi>I'd like a roast beef sandwich on rye, and <it>hold</it> the mustard please. [=do not put any mustard on the sandwich]</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to force (someone) to stay in a place (such as a prison) <vi>The police are <it>holding</it> him for questioning.</vi> <vi>Terrorists are <it>holding</it> the passengers hostage.</vi> <vi>They're being <it>held</it> hostage/captive/prisoner.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was <it>held</it> captive by his own fears.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue moving on (a course) without change <vi>The ship continued to <it>hold</it> its course.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>of a vehicle</ssl> <dt>:to stay on (a road) in a safe and secure way when being driven at high speeds <vi>The car <it>holds</it> the road well when turning quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be true :to remain valid <vi>Her advice still <it>holds</it> [=<it>applies</it>] today.</vi> <vi>The general rule <it>holds</it> in most cases.</vi> <un>often used in the phrases <phrase>hold true</phrase> and (less commonly) <phrase>hold good</phrase> <vi>The general rule <it>holds true</it> in most cases.</vi> <vi>Their son needs support and understanding. The same <it>holds true</it> for all children.</vi> <vi>The advice she gave us 10 years ago still <it>holds good</it> today.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <dt>:to wait to speak to someone on the telephone <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>All operators are currently busy. Please <it>hold</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>All operators are busy. Please <phrase>hold the line</phrase> for a minute.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>hold a candle to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>candle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold (something) against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something) as a reason to have a bad opinion of (someone) <vi>He lied to her once, and she still <it>holds it against him</it>.</vi> <vi>Nobody is going to <it>hold it against you</it> if you don't come. [=no one is going to be angry or upset with you if you don't come]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold a gun to someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold all the aces</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold (all/all of) the cards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>card</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to stop yourself from doing something <vi>She wanted to introduce herself to him but she <it>held back</it> out of shyness.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a less than complete effort <vi>She could have beaten him in the race, but she <it>held back</it> and let him win. [=she did not run as fast as she could have so that he would win]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from doing something <vi>Once he starts talking, <phrase>there's no holding him back</phrase>. [=it's very hard to get him to stop talking]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not allow (something) to be seen or known by someone <vi>He was unable to <it>hold back</it> his tears. [=to keep from crying]</vi> <vi>The government <it>held back</it> [=<it>withheld</it>] some crucial information from the media.</vi> <vi>I know you're angry, so don't <it>hold</it> anything <it>back</it> (from me). [=tell me everything]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) <vi>He <it>held</it> several thousand dollars <it>back</it> in case of an emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to delay (something) <vi>The company <it>held back</it> the first shipment of the new product until it was completely ready.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone or something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold back (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone or something) from moving forward :to stop (someone or something) from advancing to the next level, grade, or stage <vi>She might have been more successful, but bad health <it>held</it> her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held back</it> [=<it>kept back</it>] in first grade.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold court</dre> <dx>see <dxt>court</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from being or becoming too high <vi>Could you please <it>hold</it> the noise <it>down</it>? I'm trying to read.</vi> <vi>The company is trying to <it>hold down</it> costs/expenses/prices.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to have (a job) <vi>It's been a struggle for him to <it>hold down</it> [=<it>keep</it>] a job.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from doing something or advancing to a higher level, position, etc. <vi>We need to free ourselves of the unfair restrictions that are <it>holding</it> us <it>down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold firm</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to change what you have been doing or believing <vi>They are <it>holding firm</it> on their refusal to proceed.</vi> <vi>Despite opposition, she has <it>held firm</it> to her decision.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold forth</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to speak about something for a long time <vi>He <it>held forth</it> about/on the need for reform in his country.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold hands</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold someone's hand</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (an emotion) from being expressed <vi>Don't <it>hold</it> your feelings <it>in</it>. Let them out.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to wait to do something <vi>You need to decide now. You can't <it>hold off</it> any longer.</vi> <vi>He <it>held off</it> as long as he could.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>She decided to <it>hold off on</it> her vacation for a while longer.</vi></un> <snote>If you <phrase>hold off doing</phrase> something or <phrase>hold off on doing</phrase> something, you wait to do it at a later time. <vi>He <it>held off on</it> announcing his decision.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to not happen until later <vi>The rain <it>held off</it> until we got home. [=it didn't rain until we got home]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from coming near someone or something <vi>Her bodyguard <it>held off</it> the crowd. [=kept the crowd away from her]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to defend against (something) successfully :<sx>withstand</sx> <vi>The soldiers <it>held off</it> the attack.</vi> <vi>Our team <it>held off</it> a late rally by the other team.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have or keep your hand, arms, etc., tightly around something <vi>He was <it>holding on</it> [=<it>hanging on</it>] for dear life.</vi> <vi><it>Hold on</it> (tight). It's going to get bumpy.</vi> <vi>The steps are slippery; you'd better <it>hold on</it> to the railing.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to succeed in keeping a position, condition, etc. <vi>I hope we can <it>hold on</it> until help arrives.</vi> <vi>They were able to <it>hold on</it> for a 10–9 victory.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to wait or stop briefly <vi>“Can we go now?” “<it>Hold on</it>, I'll be ready in just a minute.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep possession of (something) <vi>She's trying very hard to <it>hold on to</it> her money.</vi> <vi>He has managed to <it>hold on to</it> his lead in the polls.</vi> :to not lose or give up (something) <vi>Despite all his troubles, he has somehow <it>held on to</it> his faith in himself.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or be available <vi>I don't know how much longer our supply of food will <it>hold out</it>. [=<it>last</it>]</vi> <vi>You should do it while your courage is still <it>holding out</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm going to keep writing as long as my money <it>holds out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to work <vi>My old car is still <it>holding out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to continue to oppose someone or defend against something :to refuse to surrender or give in <vi>The troops were able to <it>hold out</it> until help arrived.</vi> <vi>Many of the strikers are still <it>holding out</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to reach outward with (something, such as your hand) <vi>He <it>held out</it> [=<it>extended</it>] his hand in greeting.</vi> <vi>She <it>held out</it> the car keys and asked him to drive.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>I <it>held out</it> the hand of friendship to my enemies. [=I offered friendship to my enemies]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to say that there is a good reason to have (something, such as hope) <vi>The doctor didn't <it>hold out</it> [=<it>offer</it>] much hope for her recovery. [=the doctor didn't say that there was much hope for her recovery]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to say that (a possibility) exists <vi>The mayor has <it>held out</it> the possibility that the library will be expanded in the future. [=has said that it is possible that the library will be expanded]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to refuse to accept or agree to something in order to get (something) <vi>The workers are <it>holding out for</it> higher pay.</vi> <vi>The wide receiver is <it>holding out for</it> a new contract.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to keep something (such as information) from (someone) <vi>She didn't tell me she was rich; she's been <it>holding out on</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen later <vi>A vote on the proposal has been <it>held over</it> [=<it>delayed, postponed</it>] until tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something) to continue beyond a normal or planned time <vi>The movie is being <it>held over</it> for two more weeks. [=the movie will continue to be shown for two more weeks]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something or someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold over (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (something or someone) from an earlier time <vi>He is the only player to have been <it>held over</it> from their previous team.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use your knowledge of (something) to influence or control the behavior of (someone) <vi>She knows about his criminal past and has been <it>holding</it> it <it>over</it> him [=she has been threatening to tell other people about his criminal past] to force him to cooperate.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold the bag</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>hold the baby</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be given all of the blame or responsibility that should be shared with others <vi>His friends ran away and he was stuck/left <it>holding the bag</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold the fort</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fort</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold the line</dre> <dx>see <dxt>line</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to have or follow (a plan, purpose, etc.) <vi>He has <it>held to</it> his plan of exercising regularly.</vi> :to not change (a decision, belief, etc.) <vi>Despite opposition, she has <phrase>held to</phrase> her decision.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>You made a promise and I'm going to <it>hold</it> you <it>to</it> it.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held to</it> an impossible standard. [=he was required to meet very high expectations]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prevent (an opponent) from having or getting more than (a specified number of scores or shots) <vi>Our team <it>held</it> the other team <it>to</it> just three runs.</vi> <vi>The defense <it>held</it> him <it>to</it> only one shot attempt in the first half.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stay joined together or in one piece <vi>The empire <it>held together</it> for many decades.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold together (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to stay joined together or in one piece <vi>The coach hopes to <it>hold</it> the team <it>together</it> for at least one more season.</vi> <vi>The box was <it>held together</it> by a strong glue.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue in the same condition without failing or losing effectiveness or force <vi>The sales team was <it>holding up</it> well under the stress.</vi> <vi>The nurse came in to see how I was <it>holding up</it>.</vi> <vi>Their music still <it>holds up</it> 20 years later.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to raise (something) <vi>He <it>held up</it> his hand.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold up (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something or someone) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to delay, stop, or slow the movement, progress, or action of (something or someone) :<sx>delay</sx> <vi>Their decision was <it>held up</it> for months.</vi> <vi>A major accident <it>held</it> traffic <it>up</it> for hours.</vi> <vi>She was late for the meeting because she got <it>held up</it> in traffic.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use a gun to rob (a person, store, etc.) <vi>Someone <it>held up</it> the gas station.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held up</it> by a masked robber.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be noticed for a particular reason <vi>His work has been <it>held up</it> to ridicule. [=his work has been ridiculed]</vi> <vi>Experts have been <it>holding</it> these programs <it>up</it> as examples of government waste.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to agree with or approve of (something) <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I don't <it>hold with</it> all these newfangled notions!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your horses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your liquor</dre> <dx>see <dxt>liquor</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your nose</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your own</dre> <def><dt>:to do well in a difficult situation <vi>It was a tough interview, but she managed to <it>hold her own</it>.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>holding her own</it> against cancer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold your tongue</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>hold your peace</va></vr> <def><dt>:to keep silent :to not say anything about something <vi>It was difficult, but he somehow managed to <it>hold his tongue</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
