<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bright"> <hw highlight="yes">bright</hw> <sound><wav>bright01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbraɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bright*er</if></in> <in><if>bright*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:producing a lot of light <vi>a <it>bright</it> light</vi> <vi>The lighting was too <it>bright</it>.</vi> :filled with light <vi>a <it>bright</it> room with lots of windows</vi> <vi>It was a <it>bright</it>, sunny day.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a very light and strong color <vi>The room was decorated in <it>bright</it> colors.</vi> <vi>a <it>bright</it> red</vi> <vi><it>bright</it> blue eyes</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:able to learn things quickly :<sx>intelligent</sx> <un>used especially to describe a young person <vi>a <it>bright</it> child</vi> <vi>a <it>bright</it> young journalist</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:showing intelligence :<sx>clever</sx> <vi>a <it>bright</it> idea</vi> <un>often used in a joking or ironic way to describe a foolish idea, action, etc. <vi>Walking on the railroad bridge wasn't too <it>bright</it>.</vi> <vi>Who's <it>bright</it> idea was it to leave the refrigerator open?</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:happy and lively <vi>a <it>bright</it> smile</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:providing a reason for hope <vi>a young actress with a <it>bright</it> [=<it>promising</it>] future</vi> <vi><it>Brighter</it> days are ahead. [=things will improve in the future]</vi> <vi>The prospects for the team are <it>bright</it>. [=<it>good</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bright and early</dre> <def><dt>:very early <vi>We will be getting up <it>bright and early</it> in the morning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bright-eyed and bushy-tailed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:happy and full of energy <vi>He arrived all <it>bright-eyed and bushy-tailed</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bright spot</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a good thing that occurs during a bad or difficult time <vi>Car sales were one of the few <it>bright spots</it> for the economy last year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the bright side</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to the good part of something that is mostly bad <vi>(<it>US</it>) He lost the race, but <it>on the bright side</it>, he didn't get hurt.</vi> <vi>Your cat is very sick right now, but try to <phrase>look on the bright side</phrase>. She can be treated with medicine.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bright*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a candle glowing <it>brightly</it></vi> <vi>a <it>brightly</it> lit room</vi> <vi><it>brightly</it> colored toys</vi> <vi>She smiled <it>brightly</it> [=<it>cheerfully</it>] at her daughter.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>bright*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>You can adjust the light's <it>brightness</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bushy"> <hw>bushy</hw> <sound><wav>bushy001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊʃi</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bush*i*er</if></in> <in><if>bush*i*est</if></in> <def><gram>also more bushy; most bushy</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:very thick and full <vi>a <it>bushy</it> beard</vi> <vi><it>bushy</it> hair/eyebrows</vi> <vi>an animal with a <it>bushy</it> tail</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:having a lot of branches and leaves <vi>a <it>bushy</it> tree</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bright-eyed and bushy-tailed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bright</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bush*i*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>bushiness</it> of his eyebrows</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="side[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">side</hw> <sound><wav>side0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsaɪd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>sides</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place, space, or direction that is away from or beyond the center of something <vi>The army was attacked from all <it>sides</it>.</vi> <vi>the right-hand <it>side</it> of the street</vi> <vi>the opposite <it>side</it> of the room</vi> <vi>Move over. This is my <it>side</it> of the bed.</vi> <un>often used with <it>on</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>You have some dirt <it>on</it> the <it>side</it> of your face.</vi> <vi>The car was hit <it>on</it> the driver's <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>They live <it>on</it> the other <it>side</it> of town.</vi> <vi>The cabins are <it>on</it> the east <it>side</it> of the lake.</vi> <vi>Guards stood <it>on</it> either <it>side</it> of the gate.</vi> <vi>The army was surrounded <it>on</it> every <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>He sat <it>on</it> the <it>side</it> [=<it>edge</it>] of the bed.</vi> <vi>The statue is leaning <it>to</it> the <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>The dog tilted its head <it>to</it> one <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Pull over <it>to</it> the <it>side</it> of the road.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an outer surface or part of something <vi>The box says, “THIS <it>SIDE</it> UP.”</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the dark <it>side of</it> the moon</vi> <vi>You should season both <it>sides of</it> the steak before you grill it.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:one of the surfaces of an object that is not the front, back, top, or bottom <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>Nutritional information can be found on the <it>side of</it> the box.</vi> <vi>Red cloth decorated the front and <it>sides of</it> the platform.</vi> <vi>The <it>side of</it> the car was badly dented.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:one of the two surfaces of a thin object <vi>Flip the record over and play the other <it>side</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She wrote on both <it>sides of</it> the paper.</vi> <vi>Look on the back <it>side of</it> the note.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a line that forms part of a geometric shape <vi>A square has four <it>sides</it>.</vi> :a surface that forms part of a geometric object <vi>A cube has six <it>sides</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the slopes of a hill or mountain <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the steep <it>side of</it> the hill</vi> <vi>They built a house on the <it>side of</it> a mountain.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>hillside</dxt> <dxt>mountainside</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the right or left part of your body <vi>She likes to sleep on her right <it>side</it>.</vi> :the right or left part of your body from your shoulder to your hip <vi>I have a pain in my left <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>We laughed so much that our <it>sides</it> hurt.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the place directly to the right or left of someone <un>usually singular <vi>I stood <phrase>at/by her side</phrase> as she spoke to reporters.</vi> <vi>I was standing <phrase>on her left side</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She set/put the book <phrase>to the/one side</phrase> and looked out the window.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His wife <phrase>stood at/by his side</phrase> [=remained loyal to him] throughout the scandal.</vi> <vi>Promise me that you will not <phrase>leave my side</phrase>. [=abandon me]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>blind side</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of two or more opinions, positions, etc., that disagree with each other <vi>He listened to both <it>sides</it> of the argument.</vi> <vi>My <it>side</it> [=<it>version</it>] of the story is different from his.</vi> <vi>She has since changed <it>sides</it> on that issue.</vi> <vi>You are both my friends, so I don't want to <phrase>choose/pick/take sides</phrase>. [=support one person and not the other]</vi> <vi>Are you <phrase>on my side</phrase> or his? [=do you support me or him?]</vi> <vi><phrase>Whose side are you on</phrase>, anyway?</vi> <vi>People <phrase>on both sides</phrase> of the dispute [=people who support one position and people who support the other position] agree that changes are necessary.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>on your side <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the two or more people or groups that are involved in an argument, war, etc. <vi>All <it>sides</it> agreed on the treaty.</vi> <vi>Each <it>side</it> accuses the other of delaying progress.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a sports team <vi>There are 11 players on each <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Our <it>side</it> won the game.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a football <it>side</it></vi> <vi>We need to <phrase>choose/pick sides</phrase> [=to decide which players will be on each team] before we start playing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:the players on a team who bat in an inning <un>usually singular <vi>The pitcher struck out the <it>side</it> [=struck out three batters] in the first inning.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular part or feature of something that is opposite to or different from another part or feature <vi>There are good/positive and bad/negative <it>sides</it> to owning your own business.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>He's learning about the sales <it>side of</it> the business.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>kept her side of the bargain/deal</phrase>. [=she did what she agreed to do]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>downside</dxt> <dxt>flip side</dxt> <dxt>upside</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>on the large side</phrase>, <phrase>on the heavy side</phrase>, etc., to describe someone or something as somewhat heavy, large, etc. <vi>She has always been a little <it>on the heavy side</it>. [=has always been somewhat heavy]</vi> <vi>These pants are <it>on the tight side</it>. [=are a little tight]</vi> <vi>The sauce is a bit <it>on the spicy side</it>. [=is a bit spicy]</vi> <vi>Your boyfriend is <it>on the young side</it> for you, isn't he?</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a part of someone's personality that is opposite or different from another part <vi>I have never seen this <it>side</it> of you before.</vi> <vi>He is in touch with his feminine <it>side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>be/get on someone's good/bad side</phrase> and <phrase>be/get on the right/wrong side of someone</phrase> to talk about doing things that cause someone to like you or dislike you <vi>Trust me. You don't want to <it>get on his bad side</it>. [=you don't want to make him annoyed or angry]</vi> <vi>She tries to <it>keep/stay on her boss's good side</it> by finishing all of her work on time.</vi> <vi>If you <it>get on the wrong side of</it> him [=if you make him annoyed or angry] he can be very mean.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the ancestors or relatives of your mother or your father <vi>She gets her red hair from her mother's <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Both <it>sides</it> of his family are Irish.</vi> <vi>my grandfather on my father's <it>side</it> [=my father's father]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a small amount of food that is ordered in addition to the main meal <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>I ordered a <it>side of</it> fries with my hamburger.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the two halves of an animal that is eaten as food <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>side of</it> bacon/pork/beef</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:a page of writing on one side of a piece of paper <vi>I wrote two <it>sides</it> in response to the question.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a television channel <un>usually singular <vi>What's on the other <it>side</it>?</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a thorn in the/your side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thorn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>err on the side of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>err</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(from) side to side</dre> <def><dt>:moving to the left and then to the right <vi>She shook her head <it>from side to side</it> in disagreement.</vi> <vi>waving the flags <it>from side to side</it></vi> <vi>He moved <it>side to side</it> on the tennis court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let the side down</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to disappoint your family, friends, etc., by failing to do what is needed or expected <vi>I feel like I really <it>let the side down</it>. [=let everyone down]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on side</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:included among the group of people who support a particular goal, project, etc. <vi>We need to keep everyone <it>on side</it>. [=<it>on board</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the bright side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bright</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the credit side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>credit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the debit side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>debit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the right/wrong side of 30, 40, 50 (etc.)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:younger/older than 30, 40, 50 (etc.) <vi>She's still <it>on the right side of 40</it>. [=younger than 40]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the side</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in addition to the main item in a meal <vi>We were served salmon with rice and grilled vegetables <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:served next to something rather than on top of it <vi>For my salad, I'd like Italian dressing <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in addition to your main job <vi>She sells insurance <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:as part of a secret romantic relationship that is outside of your marriage or main romantic relationship <vi>a married man with a girlfriend <it>on the side</it></vi> <vi>She had a fiancé but was seeing another man <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the wrong/right side of the law</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone is or is not living the life of a criminal <vi>He has been <it>on the wrong side of</it> the law since he stole a car at the age of 17.</vi> <vi>Now that she's out of prison she's trying to stay <it>on the right side of the law</it>. [=trying not to get into trouble with the police]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your side</dre> <def><dt>:as an advantage <vi>He is not a very tall basketball player, but he does have quickness <it>on his side</it>.</vi> :helping you to succeed <vi>Luck seems to be <it>on your side</it> tonight.</vi> <vi>Time is <it>on our side</it>. [=we have a lot of time to do what we need to do]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>side <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>side by side</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:next to each other and facing in the same direction <vi>We walked <it>side by side</it> down the hallway.</vi> <vi>They stood <it>side by side</it> at the altar.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:together or very close to each other <vi>The tribes have lived peacefully <it>side by side</it> for many years.</vi> <vi>People worked <it>side by side</it> to rescue the trapped coal miners.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>split your sides (laughing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>split</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the other side of the coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the wrong side of the tracks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>track</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>this side of</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:very nearly (something) <vi>Their actions were just <it>this side of</it> illegal. [=were almost but not quite illegal]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:that is not (something) :other than (something) <vi>the worst punishment <it>this side of</it> death</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>before</sx> <vi>She's not likely to be back <it>this side of</it> Monday week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the/one side</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to a place that is on one side :<sx>aside</sx> <vi>Please move/step <it>to the side</it>. I need to get past you.</vi> <vi>He put his luggage <it>to one side</it>.</vi> <vi>She took the boy <it>to the side</it> [=away from other people] and told him to behave.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a state in which something is not dealt with, done, or used until a later time :<sx>aside</sx> <vi>Let's put/leave that question <it>to the side</it> for a moment.</vi> <vi>He set his household chores <it>to the side</it> to finish writing his essay.</vi> <vi>They managed to put some money <it>to the side</it> every month.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>side <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two sides of the same coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>side</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="spark[1]"> <hw hindex="1">spark</hw> <sound><wav>spark001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈspɑɚk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>sparks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a small piece of burning material that comes from a fire or is produced by rubbing or hitting two hard objects together <vi>A <it>spark</it> from the fireplace set the rug on fire.</vi> <vi>The car's tailpipe made <it>sparks</it> as it scraped the road.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a short, bright flash of electricity between two points <vi>A <it>spark</it> ignites the stove's burner.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a quality that makes someone or something enjoyable, interesting, successful, etc. <vi>In its fourth year, the TV series has lost its <it>spark</it>.</vi> <vi>She's a talented gymnast but she doesn't have the <it>spark</it> of some of her competitors.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small amount of something <vi>A <it>spark</it> of hope remains.</vi> <vi>Sometimes there were surprising <it>sparks</it> of humor in his letters.</vi> <vi>occasional <it>sparks</it> of insight</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an action, occurrence, etc., that causes something larger to happen <vi>His death was the <it>spark</it> that ignited the revolution.</vi> <vi>Her suggestion was the <it>spark</it> for the entire renovation project.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bright spark</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal + disapproving</sl> <dt>:a person who says or does something that seems intelligent but is really not <vi>Who's the <it>bright spark</it> who came up with this rotten idea?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sparks fly</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>sparks fly</it>, it means that two people are either having an argument with each other or are sexually attracted to each other. <vi>The <it>sparks flew</it> [=they had an angry argument] when he arrived late for her special dinner.</vi> <vi><it>Sparks flew</it> when they met for the first time.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="tail[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">tail</hw> <sound><wav>tail0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈteɪl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>tails</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of an animal's body that extends from the animal's back end <vi>a monkey with a long <it>tail</it></vi> <dx>see pictures at <dxt>bird</dxt> <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a long piece that extends from the back end or bottom of something <vi>the <it>tail</it> of a kite</vi> <vi>a comet's <it>tail</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pigtails</dxt> <dxt>ponytail</dxt> <dxt>shirttail</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the back end of an airplane, helicopter, etc. <dx>see picture at <dxt>airplane</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>tails</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the back side of a coin :the side of a coin that is opposite the side which shows a picture of a person's head <un>usually used to refer to one of the two choices you can make when a coin is thrown in the air to decide something <vi>I call <it>tails</it>.</vi> <vi>Is it heads or <it>tails</it>? [=did the coin land with heads or tails facing up?]</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>head <dxn>5</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>tails</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:<sx>tailcoat</sx> <vi>He wore a top hat and <it>tails</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a person (such as a detective) who follows or watches someone <vi>They <phrase>put a tail on</phrase> the suspect. [=they had someone follow the suspect]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bright-eyed and bushy-tailed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bright</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not make head or/nor tail of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on someone's tail</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:following closely behind someone <vi>The sheriff was hot <it>on their tails</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the tail wagging the dog</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe a situation in which an important or powerful person, organization, etc., is being controlled by someone or something that is much less important or powerful</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn tail</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to turn around and run away from danger, trouble, etc. <vi>He <it>turned tail</it> and ran from the fight.</vi> <vi>You can't just <it>turn tail</it> and run from your problems.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your tail between your legs</dre> <def><dt>:with a feeling of being embarrassed or ashamed especially because you have been defeated <vi>He lost the fight and went home <it>with</it> <it>his tail between his legs</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>tail*less</ure> <sound><wav>tail0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈteɪlləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>tailless</it> cats</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
