<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bring"> <hw highlight="yes">bring</hw> <sound><wav>bring001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɪŋ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>brings</if></in> <in><if>brought</if> <sound><wav>bring002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>bring*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to come with (something or someone) to a place <vi>I'll <it>bring</it> a bottle of wine (with me) when I come to your party.</vi> <vi>“Should I send you a check?” “Why not just <it>bring</it> me the money when you come?”</vi> <vi>Have you <it>brought</it> the money with you from the bank?</vi> <vi>She <it>brought</it> her boyfriend home to meet her parents.</vi> <vi>You stay where you are and I'll <it>bring</it> you another drink. = I'll <it>bring</it> another drink to you.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to come <vi>Her screams <it>brought</it> [=<it>attracted</it>] help.</vi> <vi>Her screams <it>brought</it> the neighbors running. [=the neighbors ran to help her when they heard her screams]</vi> <vi>Love of adventure <it>brought</it> her here before taking her to many other places.</vi> <vi>This radio station <it>brings</it> you all the news as it happens.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to exist, happen, or start <vi>Can anything <it>bring</it> peace to this troubled region?</vi> <vi>In this part of the country, winter <it>brings</it> snow (with it).</vi> <vi>The tablets may <it>bring</it> (you) some relief.</vi> <vi>Having a baby has <it>brought</it> great happiness into her life.</vi> <vi>The sad story <phrase>brought tears to our eyes</phrase> [=made us cry] but its happy ending <phrase>brought smiles to our lips</phrase>. [=made us smile]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to reach a specified state, place, condition, etc. <vi>The dancer <it>brought</it> his hands up to his face.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) <it>Bring</it> the water to a boil. = (<it>Brit</it>) <it>Bring</it> the water to the boil. [=heat the water so that it boils]</vi> <vi>The pilot <it>brought</it> them safely out of danger.</vi> <vi>Winter snow <it>brought</it> traffic to a stop.</vi> <vi>A few steps <it>brought</it> us to the front door.</vi> <vi>The thrilling climax <it>brought</it> the audience to its/their feet.</vi> <vi>This history book <it>brings</it> us up to the present day.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to have (a particular talent, quality, etc.) when you start to do something (such as a job) <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>brings</it> years of experience <it>to</it> the position. [=she comes to the position with years of experience]</vi> <vi>He <it>brings</it> a rare talent for solving problems <it>to</it> his new job as company president.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to start a case against someone in a court of law <vi>They threatened to <it>bring</it> [=<it>institute</it>] legal action against him.</vi> <vi>They are going to <phrase>bring charges against</phrase> him. [=they are going to charge him with a crime]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to reach a total <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>Last week's sales figures <it>brought</it> our pretax profits for the year <it>to</it> just over $35,000,000.</vi> <vi>The donation <it>brought</it> the fund <it>to</it> over a million dollars.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to get (an amount of money) as a price :to be sold for (a price) <vi>The painting ought to <it>bring</it> [=<it>fetch</it>] a high price.</vi></dt> <snotebox>In addition to the phrases shown below, <it>bring</it> occurs in many idioms that are shown at appropriate entries throughout the dictionary. For example, <it>bring to bear</it> can be found at <sc>bear</sc> and <it>bring to an end</it> can be found at <sc>end</sc>.</snotebox></def> <dro><dre>bring about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring about (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>bring (something) about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) <vi>“What <it>brought about</it> the crisis?” “It was <it>brought about</it> by many factors.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring around</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>bring round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to come around: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to accept and support something (such as an idea) after opposing it <vi>She still says she won't support us, but we'll <it>bring</it> her <it>around</it> eventually. [=we'll convince/persuade her to support us eventually]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'm sure we can <it>bring</it> her <it>around to</it> our way of thinking.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become awake again after being unconscious <vi>The boxer was knocked out and it took the doctor several minutes to <it>bring</it> him <it>around</it>. [=bring him to]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to come with (someone) for a social visit <vi>Why don't you <it>bring</it> your friend <it>around</it> (to my house) after work today?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a conversation) to go to a desired subject or area <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>We gradually <it>brought</it> the conversation <it>around to</it> the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something or someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring back (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to come back with (something or someone) <vi>What did you <it>bring back</it> (with you) from your vacation?</vi> <vi>You promised to <it>bring back</it> a present for me. = You promised to <it>bring</it> me <it>back</it> a present.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to return <vi>The death penalty was done away with in this area many years ago, but some people now want it to be <it>brought back</it>.</vi> <vi>The movie is a fantasy about a man who is <it>brought back</it> (to life) from the dead.</vi> <vi>The company is doing poorly, and its former president is being <it>brought back</it> to help solve its problems.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to return <it>to</it> a condition, subject, etc. <vi>That question <it>brings</it> us <it>back</it> (again) <it>to</it> the fundamental problem of world peace.</vi> <vi>We gradually <it>brought</it> the conversation <it>back to</it> the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to return to someone's memory <vi>Seeing her again <it>brought back</it> a lot of happy memories.</vi> <vi>I had almost forgotten about the time we spent together, but seeing her again <phrase>brought it all back</phrase> (to me).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (someone or something) before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to come to (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>He was <it>brought</it> (up) <it>before</it> the judge on a charge of obstructing justice.</vi> <vi>The case was finally <it>brought before</it> the Supreme Court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring down (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone or something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to fall down onto the ground <vi>The deer was <it>brought down</it> by a single shot.</vi> <vi>The plane was <it>brought down</it> by enemy fire.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The government was <it>brought down</it> by a vote of no confidence.</vi> <vi>a famous politician who was <it>brought down</it> by scandal</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to become lower <vi>Will anything ever <it>bring</it> house prices <it>down</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>All this rainy weather is really <it>bringing</it> me <it>down</it>. [=getting me down]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) forth</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring forth (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>The rosebushes <it>brought forth</it> an abundance of flowers.</vi> <vi>He was able to <it>bring forth</it> persuasive arguments in support of his position.</vi> :to cause (something) to occur or exist <vi>Her controversial comments <it>brought forth</it> [=<it>provoked</it>] strong reactions from the public.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to talk about or show (something) so that it can be seen or discussed by others <vi>The police have <it>brought</it> new evidence <it>forward</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make the time of (something) earlier or sooner <vi>We need to <it>bring</it> the meeting <it>forward</it> from Tuesday to Monday so that more people can attend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become involved in a process, activity, etc. <vi>The company has decided to <it>bring in</it> outside experts to help on the project.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) in</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce or earn (an amount of money) <vi>Each sale <it>brought in</it> $5.</vi> <vi>He works at a large company and <it>brings in</it> a good salary.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to report (an official decision) to a court <vi>The jury <it>brought in</it> [=<it>returned</it>] a verdict of not guilty. [=the jury said that the defendant was not guilty]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to introduce (a new law, rule, etc.) <vi>The government is going to <it>bring in</it> legislation to make such practices illegal.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring in (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (someone or something) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to come to a place <vi>The store is having a special sale in order to <it>bring in</it> [=<it>attract</it>] new customers/business.</vi> <vi>The police <it>brought</it> him <it>in</it> (to the police station) for questioning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (something) off</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>bring off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something difficult) :to achieve or accomplish (something) <vi>It's a challenging role. She's the only actress I know with enough talent to <it>bring</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring on (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) on</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to appear or occur <vi>The crisis was <it>brought on</it> by many factors.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something bad) to happen to (someone) <vi>You've <it>brought</it> nothing but shame <it>on</it> your family since the day you were born!</vi> <vi>I can't help thinking you've <it>brought</it> some of this trouble <it>on</it> yourself.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to show (something) :to cause (something) to appear or to be more easily seen <vi>The debate <it>brought out</it> [=<it>highlighted</it>] the differences between the two candidates.</vi> <vi>That blue sweater really <it>brings out</it> the color in your eyes.</vi> <vi>Our school aims to <it>bring out</it> [=<it>develop</it>] the talents in each of our students.</vi> <vi>A crisis <phrase>brings out the best in</phrase> some people and <phrase>brings out the worst in</phrase> others. [=a crisis causes some people to behave very well and other people to behave very badly]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as a book) :to cause (something) to become available or to come out <vi>a writer who's expected to <it>bring out</it> a new novel next year</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) out in (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to begin to have (something, such as a rash) on the skin <vi>Eating strawberries <it>brings</it> me <it>out in</it> spots. [=eating strawberries makes me break out in spots]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bring around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bring to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (someone) to</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become awake again after being unconscious <vi>The boxer was knocked out and it took the doctor several minutes to <it>bring</it> him <it>to</it>. [=bring him around]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bring (people) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring together (people)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to join or meet :to cause (people) to come together <vi>She and her husband were <it>brought together</it> by a shared love of the natural world.</vi> <vi>The conference has <it>brought together</it> some of the world's leading experts on laser technology.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take care of and teach (a child who is growing up) <vi>I was born and <it>brought up</it> [=<it>raised, reared</it>] in Chicago.</vi> <vi>My grandparents <it>brought</it> me <it>up</it> after my parents died.</vi> <vi>My parents <it>brought</it> me <it>up</it> to respect authority. [=my parents taught me to respect authority when I was a child]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bring up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to mention (something) when talking :to start to talk about (something) <vi>We were waiting for a suitable moment to <it>bring up</it> [=<it>introduce, raise</it>] the subject of his unpaid bills.</vi> <vi>I wasn't going to talk about money, but since you've <it>brought</it> it <it>up</it>, I guess it's something we should really discuss.</vi> <vi>I'm glad you mentioned money. That <it>brings up</it> the question of how much we can afford to spend.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a file or picture) to appear on a computer screen <vi>The system makes it easy to <it>bring up</it> (on the screen) information about any customer.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>vomit</sx> <vi>The patient tried to eat some breakfast but immediately <it>brought</it> it back <it>up</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bring (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stop suddenly <un>used in phrases like <phrase>bring up short</phrase> and <phrase>bring up suddenly</phrase> <vi>He was just starting to argue when her scream <it>brought him up short</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to force yourself <it>to do</it> something that you do not want to do <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>He knew that he should apologize, but he couldn't <it>bring himself to do</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bring*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bring*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bringer</it> of good news</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="brought"> <hw>brought</hw> <cx><cl>past tense and past participle of</cl> <ct>bring</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="bring-and-buy sale"> <hw>bring–and–buy sale</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sales</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a sale to which people bring things for others to buy usually in order to raise money for charity</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="account[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ac*count</hw> <sound><wav>accoun01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈkaʊnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*counts</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a record of money that has been paid and money that has been received :<sx>bill</sx> <vi>the difference between the debit and credit sides of an <it>account</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>expense account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>accounts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:records of income and expenses <vi>We always keep very good <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>an <it>accounts</it> department</vi> <vi>The company's <it>accounts</it> show a profit this year: our <phrase>accounts receivable</phrase> exceed our <phrase>accounts payable</phrase>. [=the money owed to us exceeds the money we owe]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a bank keeps a record of the money that a person puts in and takes out of the bank <vi>We opened new <it>accounts</it> at a bank last week.</vi> <vi>I took out my money and closed my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>You can withdraw up to $1,000 a day from your <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>Every week, she puts/deposits a part of her paycheck into a separate <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>setting up a <phrase>bank account</phrase></vi> <vi>My wife and I keep our money in a <phrase>joint account</phrase>. [=an account that both of us can use]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>Please enter your name and <it>account</it> number.</vi> <vi>You can check your <it>account</it> balance [=the amount of money in your account] on the Internet.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>checking account</dxt> <dxt>savings account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a company's record of the products or services used by a customer and of the money that the customer owes or has paid to the company <vi>I don't have the money right now. Put it on my <it>account</it>. = Charge it to my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>If you return the clothes, the store will credit your <it>account</it>. [=you will not have to pay for the clothes]</vi> <vi>When do you intend to <phrase>settle your account</phrase>? [=pay what you owe]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>charge account</dxt> <dxt>credit account</dxt></dx> <snote>In figurative use, to <phrase>settle an account</phrase> or to <phrase>settle accounts with</phrase> someone is to do something that brings a final end to an argument, disagreement, etc. <vi>She's decided to <it>settle accounts with</it> her old political rivals.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a business arrangement in which a person or company regularly buys products or services from a particular company <vi>She makes sure that all of the company's <it>accounts</it> [=<it>customers, clients</it>] make the necessary payments.</vi> <vi>We just lost the Smith <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>That company was one of our biggest/best <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>She will be our <phrase>account manager</phrase>. [=the person who manages our account]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a person uses the Internet or e-mail services of a particular company <vi>I use two separate e-mail <it>accounts</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a description of an event or situation :a story or report about something <vi>personal/firsthand/eyewitness <it>accounts</it> from the war</vi> <vi>According to one <it>account</it>, the party was a complete disaster.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She gave the police a full/complete/detailed <it>account of</it> what happened.</vi> <vi>We read an <it>account of</it> her trip to Paris.</vi> <vi>a written <it>account of</it> his long and successful career</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a list or description of facts <vi>Our goal is to give an accurate <it>account</it> of the process.</vi> <vi>an <it>account</it> of how the system works</vi> <vi>The document is an <it>account</it> of the country's reasons for going to war.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason or explanation for an action <vi>You will be asked to give an <it>account</it> of your actions. [=to explain the reasons for your actions]</vi> <vi>He could give no <it>account</it> of what he did with the money.</vi> <un>often used in the formal phrase <phrase>on that account</phrase> <vi>I hope we won't lose our friendship <it>on that account</it>. [=for that reason]</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:value or importance <un>used in the phrases <phrase>of no account</phrase> and <phrase>of little account</phrase> <vi>He felt that his opinions were <it>of no account</it> to the others. [=he thought that the other people didn't care about his opinions]</vi> <vi>It's <it>of little account</it> what I may think about it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>no-account</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring/call (someone) to account</dre> <def><dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>He was <it>called to account</it> by his boss for failing to spot the mistake in the company's records.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by/from all accounts</dre> <def><dt>:according to all of the different descriptions of something <vi><it>By all accounts</it>, the band put on a great show. [=everyone says that the band put on a great show]</vi> <vi>She was, <it>by all accounts</it>, good at her job.</vi> <vi>They seemed, <it>from all accounts</it>, to have a happy marriage.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by your own account</dre> <def><dt>:according to what you have said about your own life or experiences <vi><it>By her own account</it>, that was the worst performance of her career. [=she said that was her worst performance]</vi> <vi>They had, <it>by their own account</it>, a wonderful time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give a good account of yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to perform well especially in a competition <vi>If I ever had to fight, I think I could <it>give a good account of myself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on account of</dre> <def><dt>:because of :for the reason of <vi>The game was canceled <it>on account of</it> the rain.</vi> <vi>They were treated badly <it>on account of</it> their beliefs.</vi> <vi><it>On account of</it> his bad behavior, he will not be allowed to play with the new toy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on no account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>not on any account</va></vr> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:for no reason :under no circumstances <un>used to say that something will not or should not happen <vi><it>On no account</it> should the children be left at home alone.</vi> <vi>They said that <it>on no account</it> would they leave before the end of the game.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on someone's account</dre> <def><dt>:because of someone :in order to please someone <vi>Don't leave <it>on our account</it>. [=because of us]</vi> <vi>You didn't have to clean your room <it>on my account</it>. I don't care if your room is dirty.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your own account</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:by yourself :on your own :without the help of others <vi>She bought the house entirely <it>on her own account</it>.</vi> <vi>He left the company and went into business <it>on his own account</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for your own sake :in order to make a situation good for yourself <vi>I'm doing it <it>on my own account</it>, not for anyone else.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) into account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take account of (something)</va></vr> <def><dt>:to think about (something) before doing something (such as making a decision) :<sx>consider</sx> <vi>Try to <it>take</it> our feelings <it>into account</it>. [=try to think about how we will feel]</vi> <vi>Other issues must be <it>taken into account</it> before a choice can be made.</vi> <vi>She did very well on the test when you <it>take into account</it> how little she studied.</vi> <vi>She <it>takes no account of</it> my feelings. [=she doesn't consider how I feel]</vi> <vi>The new health plan fails to <it>take account of</it> the fact that many people cannot pay for their medicine.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn (something) to (good) account</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to gain or profit from (something) :to take advantage of (something) <vi>Is there a way to <it>turn</it> this situation <it>to good account</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="alive"> <hw highlight="yes">alive</hw> <sound><wav>alive001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈlaɪv</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having life :living :not dead <vi>It feels great to be <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>The patient was barely <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>The sheriff was ordered to find the killer and bring him back <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>She must be the happiest woman <it>alive</it>. [=the happiest woman in the world]</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>stay alive</phrase> for a week without any food.</vi> <vi>The patient is being <phrase>kept alive</phrase> by artificial means.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:continuing to exist <vi>an old tradition that is still <it>alive</it></vi> <vi>We tried to keep the organization <it>alive</it> [=<it>active</it>] despite having fewer members.</vi> <vi>We need to keep hope <it>alive</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not yet defeated :still having a chance to win or succeed <vi>The legislation is still <it>alive</it> in the Senate. [=the legislation has not been defeated yet]</vi> <vi>The team needs to win tonight in order to stay <it>alive</it> in the play-offs.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>more alive; most alive</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:filled with life and energy <vi>I love to sail because it makes me feel so <it>alive</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her face was <it>alive with</it> joy/happiness.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:filled with activity <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>flower gardens <it>alive with</it> bees [=filled with the activity of many bees]</vi> <vi>The city streets are <it>alive</it> [=<it>busy</it>] <it>with</it> shoppers.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>alive and kicking</dre> <def><dt>:healthy and active <vi>She ran a marathon late in life, just to prove she was still <it>alive and kicking</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>After years of slow earnings, the industry is now <it>alive and kicking</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>alive and well</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:living and healthy <vi>She found out that her aunt is <it>alive and well</it> and living in Arizona.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:still popular :continuing to be used <vi>Many of the old traditions are still <it>alive and well</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>alive to</dre> <def><dt>:aware of (something) :able to notice (something) <vi>Recovering from his illness has made him more <it>alive to</it> the beauty of life.</vi> <vi>We need to be <it>alive</it> [=<it>sensitive</it>] <it>to</it> new opportunities for our business to grow.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (something) alive</dre> <def><dt>:to make (something) seem more real or interesting <vi>The play <it>brings the old fairy tale alive</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come alive</dre> <def><dt>:to become lively: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become excited and filled with energy <vi>The crowd <it>came alive</it> when the singer appeared on stage.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become filled with activity <vi>This neighborhood is quiet during the day, but it <it>comes alive</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to become exciting or appealing <vi>In her kitchen, Italian food <it>comes alive</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat (someone or something) alive</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>skin (someone) alive</dre> <dx>see <dxt>skin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bacon"> <hw>ba*con</hw> <sound><wav>bacon001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪkən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:thin strips of salted and smoked meat from the sides and the back of a pig <vi>We ate <it>bacon</it> and eggs for breakfast.</vi> <vi>a slice of <it>bacon</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a rasher of <it>bacon</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>bacon</it> fat</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring home the bacon</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to earn the money that is needed to live <vi>He worked hard all week to <it>bring home the bacon</it> for his family.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's bacon</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bear[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bear</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bears</if></in> <in><if>bore</if> <sound><wav>bear0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚ</pr></in> <in><if>borne</if> <sound><wav>borne001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚn</pr></in> <in><if>bear*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to accept or endure (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bore</it> [=<it>tolerated</it>] their insults patiently.</vi> <un>usually used in questions and negative statements with <it>can, can't, could</it>, and <it>couldn't</it> <vi>He <it>could</it> hardly <it>bear</it> [=<it>stand</it>] the pain.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> cold weather. [=I strongly dislike cold weather]</vi> <vi>I <it>couldn't bear</it> the suspense.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> it if/when people behave like that!</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> doing this. = I can't <it>bear</it> to do this.</vi> <vi>How <it>can</it> you <it>bear</it> to see him again after the way he's treated you?</vi> <vi>I couldn't <it>bear</it> you to get the wrong idea.</vi> <vi>I <it>couldn't bear</it> his behavior. = His behavior was <phrase>more than I could bear</phrase>.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>couldn't bear the thought/idea</phrase> of moving again.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> (<it>US</it>) <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>I couldn't <it>bear for</it> you to get the wrong idea.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be worthy of (something) :to deserve or allow (something) <vi>a joke too silly to <it>bear</it> repeating [=a joke that is too silly to be worth repeating]</vi> <vi>It's so horrible it doesn't <it>bear</it> thinking about! [=it's so horrible that I don't want to think about it]</vi> <vi>a symphony that can <it>bear</it> comparison with Beethoven's best</vi> <vi>a plan that will not <it>bear</it> [=<it>withstand</it>] close scrutiny/examination</vi> <vi>suspicious behavior that <phrase>bears watching</phrase> [=that should be watched]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to assume or accept (something, such as cost or responsibility) <vi>The company agreed to <it>bear</it> the costs/expenses.</vi> <vi>The criminals must <it>bear</it> full responsibility for the deaths of these innocent people.</vi> <vi>Who will <it>bear</it> the blame for this tragedy?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal + literary</ssl> <dt>:to move while holding up and supporting (something) :<sx>carry</sx> <vi>The demonstrators <it>bore</it> banners and sang songs.</vi> <vi>They arrived <it>bearing</it> gifts.</vi> <vi>The leaves were <it>borne</it> aloft/away by the wind.</vi> <vi>disease-<it>bearing</it> germs [=germs that carry and spread diseases]</vi> <vi>germ-<it>borne</it> diseases [=diseases that are carried and spread by germs]</vi> <vi>He believes that citizens should have the right to <phrase>bear arms</phrase>. [=to carry weapons]</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>borne in on/upon</phrase> you, it is made very clear to you. This is a formal phrase. <vi>It was <it>borne in on</it> us by the new evidence that prompt action was very important. [=the new evidence strongly indicated that prompt action was very important]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) as a feature or characteristic <vi>His leg was badly injured in the accident and it still <it>bears</it> [=<it>shows</it>] the scars/wounds/marks.</vi> <vi>His face <it>bears</it> marks/signs of suffering.</vi> <vi>Your conclusion <it>bears</it> [=<it>has</it>] no relation to the evidence.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>bore a resemblance</phrase> to her aunt. [=she looked like her aunt]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a surface on which something is written, drawn, etc. <vi>The cornerstone <it>bears</it> a Latin inscription.</vi> <vi>a letter <it>bearing</it> the date of 1900</vi> <vi>a shield <it>bearing</it> strange symbols</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to have (a name, price, etc.) <vi>He <it>bore</it> the name (of) John.</vi> <vi>The store sells imported goods <it>bearing</it> [=<it>having, with</it>] high prices.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to have or hold (a feeling) in the mind <vi>She still <it>bears</it> a grudge against him. = She still <it>bears</it> him a grudge.</vi> <vi>She says she <it>bears</it> him no resentment for the way he treated her.</vi> <vi>I can't deny the love I still <it>bear</it> [=<it>feel</it>] for her.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give birth to (a child) <vi>She has <it>borne</it> three children.</vi> <vi>She has <it>borne</it> her husband three children.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>a bank account that <it>bears</it> interest = an interest-<it>bearing</it> bank account</vi> <vi>a bush that <it>bears</it> red flowers</vi> <vi>trees that <it>bear</it> fruit</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bear fruit <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to support the weight of (something) <vi>How much weight is that wall able to <it>bear</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go, move, or turn in a specified direction <vi><it>Bear</it> south.</vi> <vi>The road <it>bears</it> (to the) right.</vi> <vi>When you get to the fork in the road, you should <it>bear</it> [=<it>turn</it>] left.</vi></dt> <snotebox>Do not confuse <it>bear</it> with <it>bare</it>.</snotebox></def> <dro><dre>bear down</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:to use all of your strength and effort to do something :to try very hard to do something <vi>The pitcher <it>bore down</it> and struck out the last batter.</vi> <vi>If we're going to finish on time, we really have to <it>bear down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear down on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to push or lean down on (something) <vi>The old man <it>bore down</it> heavily <it>on</it> his cane.</vi> <vi>She <it>bore down</it> hard <it>on</it> her pencil.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to place pressure on (someone) <vi>Don't let your problems <it>bear down</it> too hard <it>on</it> you. [=don't let your problems weigh you down]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to approach or move toward (something or someone) quickly and in a frightening or impressive way <vi>The enemy battleship <it>bore down on</it> us.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear fruit</dre> <def><dt>:to produce a desired result or reward <vi>All his plans have finally <it>borne fruit</it>. [=all his plans have finally been realized]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bear <dxn>6b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear in mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bear on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have an effect on (something) <vi>Personal feelings did not <it>bear on</it> our decision. [=did not affect or influence our decision]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to apply or relate to (something) <vi>What are the facts <it>bearing</it> directly <it>on</it> this matter?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear out (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bear (something or someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to show the correctness of (something or someone) <vi>The facts <it>bore out</it> [=<it>confirmed</it>] her story. [=the facts showed that her story was true]</vi> <vi>Research has fully <it>borne him out</it>. [=has shown that he was completely correct]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to not be overwhelmed during a time of trouble, pain, etc. <vi>She's been going through a tough time, but she's <it>bearing up</it> pretty well.</vi> <un>often + <it>under</it> <vi>She has found it hard to <it>bear up under</it> the strain.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be patient with (someone) <vi>I'll have that information for you soon. Just <it>bear with</it> me for another minute or two.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear witness</dre> <dx>see <dxt>witness</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bear yourself</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to move, stand, or behave in a specified way <vi>The soldier <it>bore himself</it> [=<it>carried himself</it>] stiffly upright.</vi> <vi>The soldier never failed to <it>bear himself</it> [=<it>conduct himself, behave</it>] courageously on the battlefield.</vi> <vi>He always <it>bore himself</it> [=<it>behaved</it>] like a gentleman.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (something) to bear</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (something) to have an effect or influence <vi>The company's new president <it>brings</it> 30 years of experience <it>to bear</it>.</vi> <vi>If we hope to resolve these issues, more resources must be <it>brought to bear</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>on</it> <vi>They will <it>bring</it> their considerable skills/talent/experience/knowledge <it>to bear on</it> the problem.</vi> <vi>The demonstrators will continue to <phrase>bring pressure to bear on</phrase> the government.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross to bear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>grin and bear it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sn>1</sn> <bnote>the best</bnote> <dt>:the best person or thing <vi>Out of all of my workers, he's <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Our company is <it>the best</it> in the business.</vi> <vi>Thanks, Dad. You're <it>the best</it>!</vi> <vi>I have one more gift for you, and I saved <it>the best</it> for last.</vi> :the best group of people or things <vi>Our store sells nothing but <it>the best</it>. = We sell only <it>the best</it>. [=the best products]</vi> <vi>She's one of <it>the best</it> in the world. = She's among <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Bad things happen to <it>the best</it> of us.</vi> <vi>They want <it>the best</it> for their children.</vi> <vi>Even in <it>the best</it> of times, we had trouble paying our bills.</vi> <vi>In <it>the best</it> of all possible worlds, no one would be without food and clean water.</vi> <vi>He can compete <phrase>with the best of them</phrase>. [=he can compete as well as anyone]</vi> <vi>We were <phrase>the best of friends</phrase>. [=we were very good friends]</vi> <vi>I have a wonderful family and a great job, so I feel that I have <phrase>the best of both worlds</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Problems can occur even in/under <phrase>the best of circumstances</phrase>. [=even if the situation is as good as possible]</vi> <vi>All of the students are good, but these three are <phrase>the best of the bunch</phrase>. [=the best ones in the group]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sunday best</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:someone's or something's most effective, capable, or successful condition <un>used in phrases like <phrase>at your best</phrase> and <phrase>at its best</phrase> <vi>He's <it>at his best</it> in front of a live audience.</vi> <vi>She's <it>at her best</it> in the morning.</vi> <vi>This is democracy <it>at its best</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the highest level that you can do or achieve <vi>Was that your <it>best</it>? = Was that the <it>best</it> you could do?</vi> <vi>No one expects you to do the job perfectly. Just <phrase>do your best</phrase>. = Just <phrase>do the best you can</phrase>. [=do as well as you can]</vi> <vi>He <it>did his best</it> to help them.</vi> <vi>Her time in the race was a <phrase>personal best</phrase>. [=it was the fastest time she had ever achieved]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) for the best</dre> <def><dt>:having or producing a better result <un>used to say that something will have a good result even though it was not the intended result <vi>I won't be able to go, but maybe it'<it>s all for the best</it>. I have a lot of work to do anyway.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(all) the best</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you wish someone <it>(all) the best</it>, you hope that person will be happy and successful. <vi>We wish you <it>all the best</it> in your new job.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at best</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to a result, condition, etc., that is the best one possible even though it is not very good <vi>The company won't make a profit this year. <it>At best</it>, they'll break even.</vi> <vi>The work won't be finished for another three months <it>at best</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>best of luck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>best (out) of three (five, seven, etc.)</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that the winner of a series of games will be the one who has won the most times after three (five, seven, etc.) games have been played</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring out the best in</dre> <def><dt><snote>If someone or something <it>brings out the best in you</it>, that person or thing helps you to use or show your best qualities. <vi>She seems to <it>bring out the best in him</it>.</vi> <vi>Performing in front of an audience <it>brings out the best in me</it>. [=I perform better when I am in front of an audience]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feel your best</dre> <def><dt>:to feel very healthy <vi>Exercise helps you look and <it>feel your best</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm not <it>feeling my best</it> this morning. [=I'm not feeling very well this morning]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <def><dt><snote>If an emotion or feeling <it>gets the best of you</it>, it causes you to do something that you should not do or that you are trying not to do. <vi>I did get a little carried away. I guess the excitement <it>got the best of me</it>. [=<it>got the better of me</it>]</vi> <vi>Their emotions have <it>gotten the best of them</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know best</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>know what's best</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look your best</dre> <def><dt>:to look very good :to look as attractive and pleasant as possible <vi>Try to <it>look your best</it> when interviewing for a job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make the best of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (something) in an effective way <vi>We may not get another chance, so we need to <it>make the best of</it> this opportunity.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to deal with (a bad situation) as well as possible <vi>Life is not very good right now—but let's try to <phrase>make the best of it</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We're trying to <phrase>make the best (out) of a bad situation</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) We're trying to <phrase>make the best of a bad job</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the best is yet to come/be</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that good things have happened but that even better things will happen in the future <vi>Life is good now, but <it>the best is yet to come</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of my knowledge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knowledge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your ability</dre> <def><dt>:as well as you are able to <vi>Every game, we go out and play <it>to the best of our ability</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your belief</dre> <dx>see <dxt>belief</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="book[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">book</hw> <sound><wav>book0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>books</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a set of printed sheets of paper that are held together inside a cover :a long written work <vi>The shelves in his office are filled with <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>That's one of the best <it>books</it> I've read in a long time.</vi> <vi>a novelist who has written some wonderful <it>books</it></vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> about plumbing</vi> <vi>The library has many dictionaries and other reference <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>a hardcover/paperback <it>book</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can learn many things by studying the great <it>book</it> of nature. [=by studying nature]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long written work that can be read on a computer :<sx>e-book</sx> <vi>an electronic <it>book</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of sheets of paper that are inside a cover and that you can write information on <vi>an appointment <it>book</it></vi> <vi>an address <it>book</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>notebook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a major section of a long written work (such as the Bible) <vi>the <it>books</it> of the Bible</vi> <vi>a story that is told in the <it>Book</it> of Job</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good book</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of things held together inside a cover like the pages of a book <vi>a <it>book</it> of stamps</vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> of matches [=a matchbook]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkbook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>books</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the financial records of a business <vi>The company's <it>books</it> [=<it>accounts</it>] show a profit.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the official records of a business or organization <vi>I'm sorry, but your name does not appear in/on our <it>books</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the knowledge or information that relates to a particular subject, person, etc. <vi><it>The book</it> on him is that he can't hit a curveball. [=people have seen and reported that he can't hit a curveball]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>phone book</sx> <vi>Give me a call if you need to. I'm in <it>the book</it>. [=my telephone number is listed in the telephone book]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a closed book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is difficult to understand <vi>Even to his closest friends, he was always something of <it>a closed book</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>an open book <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an open book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is easy to learn about and understand <vi>My life is <it>an open book</it>. I have nothing to hide.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (someone) to book</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>The people responsible for these crimes must be <it>brought to book</it>. [=<it>brought to account</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by the book</dre> <def><dt>:by following the official rules very strictly <vi>My boss insists on doing everything <it>by the book</it>.</vi> <vi>They ran all the investigations <it>by the book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cook the books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cook</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every trick in the book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the books</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to study or begin studying very intensely <vi>I've got to <it>hit the books</it> all weekend if I'm going to pass this test.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in my book</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She deserves credit, <it>in my book</it>, for much of the company's recent success.</vi> <vi>He isn't even a good boss, at least not <it>in my book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's bad books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are not liked or treated nicely by someone <vi>He remains <it>in her bad books</it>. [=she is still displeased with him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's good books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are liked or are treated nicely by someone <vi>He's trying to get back <it>in his boss's good books</it> by offering to work overtime.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one for the books</dre> <def><dt>:a very unusual, important, or surprising situation, statement, event, etc. <vi>There have been a lot of scandals in local politics over the years, but this is <it>one for the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the books</dre> <def><dt>:part of the set of official laws <vi>It's an outdated law that's still <it>on the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>read someone like a book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>read</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>suit someone's book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>suit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>throw the book at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to punish (someone) as severely as possible <vi>The judge threatened to <it>throw the book at</it> him if he committed another offense.</vi> <vi>I thought I would get off with just a warning, but they <it>threw the book at</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>write the book on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>write</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bottle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tle</hw> <sound><wav>bottle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*tles</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a glass or plastic container that has a narrow neck and usually has no handle <snote>Bottles are usually used to store liquid or tablets. <vi>Shall I open another <it>bottle</it> of wine?</vi> <vi>There's a <it>bottle</it> of aspirin in the cabinet.</vi> <vi>empty soda <it>bottles</it></vi> <vi>She kept a <it>bottle</it> [=a bottle of some strong alcoholic drink like whiskey] tucked away in the coat closet.</vi> <vi>Be sure to bring a <phrase>water bottle</phrase> [=bottle containing water] on your hike.</vi> <vi>Would you get me the <phrase>bottle opener</phrase> [=a tool used to remove metal tops from some bottles], please?</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount contained in a bottle <vi>We drank a <it>bottle</it> of wine.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the bottle</bnote> <dt>:alcoholic drink <vi>He says he's lost too many years to <it>the bottle</it>, and that he's giving up alcohol.</vi> <vi>Her struggles with <it>the bottle</it> affected her entire family.</vi> <vi>I hear he's <phrase>(gone) off the bottle</phrase>. [=stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>After his divorce he <phrase>took to the bottle</phrase>. [=began to drink a lot of alcohol]</vi> <vi>When she gets depressed she <phrase>hits the bottle</phrase>. [=begins drinking a lot of alcohol]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a special bottle for feeding babies that contains milk or a drink which contains milk <vi>Has the baby finished her <it>bottle</it> yet?</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) a baby <it>bottle</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a baby's <it>bottle</it></vi> <vi>raised on a <it>bottle</it> instead of breast milk</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottle-feed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:courage or strength of spirit <vi>I don't think he's got <it>bottle</it> [=<it>guts</it>] enough to confront them.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring your own bottle</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bring a bottle</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to tell the people who are invited to a party that they should bring their own alcoholic drinks</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch/capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tle*ful</ure> <sound><wav>bottle02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟ˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>singular</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bottleful</it> of water</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
