<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="buck[1]"> <hw hindex="1">buck</hw> <sound><wav>buck0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bucks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:<sx>dollar</sx> <vi>I owe you a <it>buck</it>.</vi> <vi>Those toys are five <it>bucks</it> apiece.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>money</sx> <vi>That car costs <phrase>big bucks</phrase>. [=a lot of money]</vi> <vi>I am just working hard, trying to <phrase>make a buck</phrase>. [=to make money]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>fast/quick buck</phrase> [=money earned or gotten quickly]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a male animal (such as a male deer) <dx>compare <dxt>doe</dxt></dx> <vi>He's an outdoorsman who enjoys <it>buck</it> hunting.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>man</sx> <vi>a veteran tennis star competing against an ambitious young <it>buck</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bang for the/your buck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look/feel like a million bucks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>million</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass the buck</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid a responsibility by giving it to someone else <vi>Stop trying to <it>pass the buck</it> and take responsibility for what you've done.</vi> <vi>The federal government <it>passed the buck</it> to the state governments.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the buck stops here</dre> <def><dt><snote>Expressions like <it>the buck stops here</it> are used to say that you accept a responsibility and will not try to give it to someone else. <vi>I'm willing to accept the blame for what happened. <phrase>The buck stops with me</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="buck[2]"> <hw hindex="2">buck</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bucks</if></in> <in><if>bucked</if></in> <in><if>buck*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a horse</ssl> <dt>:to jump violently into the air with the back bent upward <vi>a <it>bucking</it> horse/bronco</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The plane <it>bucked</it> when we went through some dark clouds.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to oppose or resist (something or someone) <vi>He is reluctant to <it>buck</it> [=<it>go against, defy</it>] the leaders of his own political party.</vi> <vi>The local decline in crime <it>bucked</it> a nationwide trend. [=crime declined locally but is increasing nationally]</vi> <vi>He was always trying to <phrase>buck the system</phrase>. [=to oppose the rules of the system; to do things that were not allowed]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>buck for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>buck for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to try very hard or work very hard to get (something) <vi>He is <it>bucking for</it> a promotion at work.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>buck up</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become happier or more confident <vi><it>Buck up</it>, buddy. You'll feel better soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>buck (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>buck up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be happier or more confident :to cheer up (someone) <vi>The shows were meant to <it>buck up</it> the soldiers.</vi> <vi>trying to <it>buck up</it> [=<it>improve</it>] the morale of the troops</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="buck naked"> <hw>buck naked</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:completely naked :not wearing any clothes <vi>He was standing in front of the window, <it>buck naked</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="buck private"> <hw>buck private</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -vates</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a private in the U.S. Army or Marines <un>used to stress that a private has the lowest rank in the military <vi>He enlisted as a <it>buck private</it> and rose through the ranks to become a general.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="buck teeth"> <hw>buck teeth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <dt>:upper teeth that stick out in the front of the mouth <vi>She wore braces to fix her <it>buck teeth</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>buck–toothed</ure> <pr>ˈbʌkˌtu:θt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bang[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bang</hw> <altpr>ˈbæŋ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bangs</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sudden loud noise <vi>I heard a loud <it>bang</it>.</vi> <vi>The door slammed shut with a <it>bang</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as an interjection to imitate a loud noise (such as the sound of a gun being fired) <vi>“<it>Bang, bang</it>! You're dead.”</vi></un> <snote>In British English the informal phrase <phrase>bang goes</phrase> is used when you are saying that something you wanted or planned has become impossible. <vi>The airport closed and <it>bang went</it> our holiday plans! [=our holiday plans were ruined because the airport closed]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a hard hit or blow <vi>She got a nasty <it>bang</it> [=<it>bump</it>] on her head.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bang for the buck</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bang for your buck</va></vr> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe how much value is received when money is spent <vi>This restaurant offers people the most <it>bang for the buck</it>. [=offers more than other restaurants for the same price]</vi> <vi>He claims that the new stadium offers taxpayers too little <it>bang for the buck</it>. [=that the new stadium is not worth the tax money that is being spent on it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get a bang out of</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to enjoy (something) very much <vi>You'll <it>get a bang out of</it> [=you'll like] this story.</vi> <vi>She <it>got a bang out of</it> [=<it>got a kick out of</it>] watching her grandson at the beach.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with a bang</dre> <def><dt>:in a sudden and exciting way <vi>The movie begins/starts <it>with a bang</it> and never slows down.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="pass[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">pass</hw> <sound><wav>pass0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpæs, <it>Brit</it> ˈpɑ:s</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>pass*es</if></in> <in><if>passed</if></in> <in><if>pass*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move past someone or something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The boat was too tall to <it>pass</it> beneath/under the bridge.</vi> <vi>A flock of geese were <it>passing</it> overhead.</vi> <vi>Stand here and don't let anyone <it>pass</it>. [=move past you]</vi> <un>often + <it>by</it> <vi>They <it>pass by</it> the library on their way to school.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>passing by</it> and thought I'd stop and say hello.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>pass</it> the library every morning on their way to school.</vi> <vi>The ships <it>passed</it> each other in the night.</vi> <vi>We <it>passed</it> each other in the hallway without looking up.</vi> <un>often + <it>by</it> <vi>She was hoping he would stop and talk to her, but he <it>passed</it> her <it>by</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move past someone or something that is moving more slowly in the same direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>(<it>US</it>) “Is it safe to <it>pass</it>?” [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>overtake</it>] “No, there's a car coming in the other lane.”</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>passed</it> two other runners just before the finish line.</vi> <vi>He <it>passed</it> the slower cars on the highway.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go into or through a particular place <vi>The drug <it>passes</it> quickly into the bloodstream.</vi> <vi>In a solar eclipse, the moon <it>passes</it> between the sun and the Earth.</vi> <vi>The airplane <it>passed</it> out of sight.</vi> <un>often + <it>through</it> <vi>Fear and panic <it>passed through</it> the crowd.</vi> <vi>A river <it>passes through</it> the middle of the city.</vi> <vi>Millions of tourists <it>pass through</it> the museum every year.</vi> <vi>The paper <it>passes through</it> the fax machine and comes out the other end.</vi> <vi>The bullet <it>passed through</it> his shoulder.</vi> <vi>We <it>passed through</it> Texas on our way to Mexico.</vi> <vi>We're just <phrase>passing through</phrase>. [=staying here for a very short time]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to move or go in a specified way <vi><it>Pass</it> the end of the string through the loop.</vi> <vi>He <it>passed</it> the rope around the pole.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give (something) to someone using your hands <vi>She <it>passed</it> the baby back to his mother.</vi> <vi>Would you please <it>pass</it> the salt?</vi> <vi><it>Pass</it> [=<it>hand</it>] me the butter, please.</vi> <vi>They started <it>passing</it> around pictures of their trip.</vi> <vi>Take one sheet and <it>pass</it> the rest down/on/along. [=take one sheet and give the rest to the next person]</vi> <vi>Can you <it>pass</it> that screwdriver over to me?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to throw, hit, or kick a ball or puck to a teammate <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Pass</it> me the ball! = <it>Pass</it> the ball to me!</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>passed</it> to her teammate who then scored a goal.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to have or be affected by (something that you have had or been affected by) <vi>The disease was <it>passed</it> from mother to child. = She <it>passed</it> the disease to her child.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>She contracted the disease and <it>passed</it> it <it>on</it> to her child.</vi> <vi>Gas prices have risen, forcing companies to <it>pass</it> the cost <it>on</it> to the consumer.</vi> <vi>We lowered our costs and are now able to <it>pass on</it> the savings to our customers.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>along</it> <vi>We're <it>passing</it> the savings <it>along</it> to our customers.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (information) to another person <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>Doctors need to <it>pass</it> this information <it>on</it> to their patients.</vi> <vi>Everyone's invited to the party. <phrase>Pass it on</phrase>! [=tell people that everyone is invited]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>along</it> <vi>They quickly <it>passed</it> the word <it>along</it> that the meeting was postponed.</vi> <vi>He told me about it, and now I'm <it>passing</it> it <it>along</it> to you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to go from one person to another person <vi>The rumor quickly <it>passed</it> [=<it>spread</it>] from person to person.</vi> <vi>The book <it>passed</it> from hand to hand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given to someone especially according to a law, rule, etc. <vi>The throne <it>passed</it> to the king's son.</vi> <vi>Ownership <it>passes</it> to the buyer upon payment in full.</vi> <vi>After her death, the house <phrase>passed into the hands of</phrase> her granddaughter. [=her granddaughter became the owner of the house]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go by <vi>Several months <it>passed</it> before I received a reply.</vi> <vi>He became sleepy as the time <it>passed</it>.</vi> <vi>The days <it>pass</it> quickly when you're on vacation.</vi> <vi>Another day <it>passed</it> without any news about the whereabouts of their missing son.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to let (time or a period of time) go by especially while you are doing something enjoyable <vi>He <it>passes</it> [=<it>spends</it>] his days reading and taking walks around the neighborhood.</vi> <vi>They <it>passed</it> the evening playing cards.</vi> <vi>We played games to <phrase>pass the time</phrase> on the bus.</vi> <vi>I walked over to my neighbor's house to <phrase>pass the time of day</phrase>. [=to have a friendly and informal conversation]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to happen or take place <vi>The meeting <it>passed</it> without incident.</vi> <vi>He hoped that his mistake would <phrase>pass unnoticed</phrase>. [=not be noticed by anyone]</vi> <un>often + <it>between</it> <vi>A meaningful glance <it>passed between</it> them. [=they glanced at each other in a meaningful way]</vi> <vi>It's hard to believe that they're still friends after everything that's <it>passed between</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to end or go away <vi>She couldn't let the moment <it>pass</it> (away) without saying something.</vi> <vi>This crisis will soon <it>pass</it>. [=will soon be over]</vi> <vi>A storm had just <it>passed</it>.</vi> <vi>They waited until it was clear that the danger had <it>passed</it>.</vi> <vi>They were happy once, but that time has <it>passed</it>. [=that time is over]</vi> <vi>The era of the traveling salesman has <phrase>passed into history</phrase>. [=traveling salesmen no longer exist]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be done, said, etc., without producing a response <vi>I disagreed with what he said, but I let it <it>pass</it>. [=I did not say anything in response to his remark]</vi> <vi>She let his remark <it>pass</it> without comment.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not take, accept, or use something that is offered to you <vi>Thanks for the offer, but I'll <it>pass</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>passed on</it> the cake. [=he did not eat any cake]</vi> <vi>I think I'll <it>pass on</it> going with you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to decide not to do something at a particular point in a game (such as a card game) when it is your turn <vi>“I bid three of hearts.” “I <it>pass</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt>:to complete (a test, class, etc.) successfully <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He failed his driver's test the first time he took it, but he <it>passed</it> it the second time.</vi> <vi>I almost didn't <it>pass</it> my French class this semester.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“How did you do on the test?” “I <it>passed</it>!”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to decide that (someone) has passed an examination or course of study <vi>The teacher said she couldn't <it>pass</it> me because I failed all of my tests.</vi></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to officially approve (a law, bill, etc.) <vi>Congress <it>passed</it> a law banning the sale of automatic rifles.</vi> <vi>The measure was <it>passed</it> by both the House and the Senate.</vi> <vi>We've been trying to get this legislation <it>passed</it> for several months now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to become approved by (a legislature) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The measure <it>passed</it> both the House and the Senate.</vi> <vi>The bill <it>passed</it> the House but was defeated/rejected by the Senate.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The proposal <it>passed</it> (into law).</vi> <vi>The bill failed to <it>pass</it> in the Senate.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to say or state (something) especially in an official way <vi>Before <phrase>passing sentence</phrase> [=announcing the punishment], the judge commented on the seriousness of the crime.</vi> <vi>The court is now ready to <phrase>pass judgment</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It would be premature to <phrase>pass judgment on</phrase> [=to state an opinion on] his place in history.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>pass judgment on</it> me [=don't criticize me] until you know all the facts.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go beyond (a number or amount) <un>usually used with <it>mark</it> <vi>It's an extremely successful movie that has just <it>passed</it> [=<it>exceeded, surpassed</it>] the $100 million <it>mark</it>. [=it has earned more than $100 million]</vi> <vi>I've <it>passed</it> the half-century <it>mark</it>. [=I am over 50 years old]</vi></un></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change from one state or form to another <vi>The water <it>passes</it> from a liquid to a gas.</vi> <vi><it>passing</it> through the different stages of human development</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be good enough :to be adequate <vi>The work isn't perfect, but it <phrase>will pass</phrase>. [=<it>will do</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to illegally use (checks, bills, etc., with no real value) as money <vi>They were charged with <it>passing</it> bad checks.</vi> <vi>He was trying to <it>pass</it> counterfeit money.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) come out from your body <vi>He had been <it>passing</it> blood in his urine. [=blood had been appearing in his urine]</vi> <vi><it>pass</it> a kidney stone</vi> <dx>see also <tag>pass gas</tag> at <dxt>gas</dxt> <tag>pass water</tag> at <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to die <un>used as a polite way to avoid saying the word “die” <vi>I'm sorry, but your grandfather has <it>passed</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>pass away</dxt> <dxt>pass on <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>come to pass</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass as</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass as (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause people to believe that you are (someone or something that you are not) <vi>He thought that growing a mustache would help him <it>pass as</it> an adult.</vi> <vi>Your mom could <it>pass as</it> your sister!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or regarded as (something) <vi>the ancient practices that once <it>passed as</it> [=<it>passed for</it>] science</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to die <un>used as a polite way to avoid saying the word “die” <vi>Her father <it>passed away</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pass (someone) by</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to happen without being noticed or acted upon by (someone) <vi>Don't let this opportunity <it>pass</it> (you) <it>by</it>!</vi> <vi>I realized that I was letting life <it>pass</it> me <it>by</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pass <dxn>1a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pass (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (something) to a younger person especially within the same family <vi>She will <it>pass down</it> her diamond ring to her niece.</vi> <vi>It's a family recipe <it>passed down</it> [=<it>handed down</it>] from my great-grandmother.</vi> <vi>The painting is a family heirloom that has been <it>passed down</it> through the generations.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pass for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or regarded as (something) <vi>I can't believe the garbage that's <it>passing for</it> [=<it>passing as</it>] art these days.</vi> <vi>the tasteless soup that was supposed to <it>pass for</it> our dinner</vi> <vi>What <it>passes for</it> entertainment around here?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pass (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (something) to a person who will review it <vi>Students should <it>pass</it> their papers <it>in</it> before they leave.</vi> <vi>He <it>passed in</it> [=<it>handed in</it>] his test.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass muster</dre> <dx>see <dxt>muster</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass (someone or something) off as (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass off (someone or something) as (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause people to wrongly believe that someone or something is someone or something else <vi>amateurs <it>passing</it> themselves <it>off as</it> professionals</vi> <vi>He managed to <it>pass</it> himself <it>off as</it> the son of the famous actor.</vi> <vi>She <it>passed</it> the poem <it>off as</it> her own.</vi> <vi>They tried to <it>pass</it> it <it>off as</it> an original painting, but I suspected it was a copy.</vi> <vi>a cheap piece of glass <it>passed off as</it> a diamond</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to happen or take place in a particular way <vi>The event <it>passed off</it> [=<it>went off</it>] with no major incidents.</vi> <vi>The evening <it>passed off</it> quietly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to die <un>used as a polite way to avoid saying the word “die” <vi>Her parents have <it>passed on</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall asleep or become unconscious <vi>They both <it>passed out</it> in front of the TV.</vi> <vi>I felt like I was going to <it>pass out</it> from exhaustion.</vi> <vi>He drank until he <it>passed out</it>.</vi> <vi>Someone was <it>passed out</it> on the floor. [=someone was lying unconscious on the floor]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (something) to several or many people <vi>They <it>passed out</it> [=<it>handed out, distributed</it>] copies of the newsletter.</vi> <vi>The teacher hasn't finished <it>passing out</it> the tests yet.</vi> <vi>She <it>passed out</it> flyers at the grocery store.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass over (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass (someone) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not choose (someone) for a job, position, etc. <vi>When it came time to select the recipient of the award, the committee once again <it>passed</it> him <it>over</it>. [=the committee did not give him an award]</vi> <vi>The quarterback was <it>passed over</it> by other teams.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>She was <it>passed over for</it> another promotion.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pass over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass (something) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave out (something) <vi><it>passing over</it> [=<it>skipping</it>] the more boring parts of the book</vi> :to not discuss or deal with (something) <vi>Let's <it>pass over</it> the technical details and get straight to the parts that really interest you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass the buck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>buck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass the hat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass the torch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pass up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pass (something) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not take or accept (something that is offered to you) <vi>We couldn't afford to <it>pass up</it> her offer.</vi> <vi>Her offer was too good to <it>pass up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pass your lips</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of words</ssl> <dt>:to come out of your mouth :to be spoken <vi>The word “quit” has never <it>passed her lips</it>. [=she has never said the word “quit”]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of food or drink</ssl> <dt>:to go into your mouth :to be eaten or drunk <vi>He refused to let alcohol <it>pass his lips</it>. [=he never drank alcohol]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="passer"> <hw>pass*er</hw> <sound><wav>passe01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpæsɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈpɑ:sə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>pass*ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:someone or something that passes something <vi>a <it>passer</it> of bad checks</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a player who passes a ball or puck to a teammate in a sport <vi>a quarterback who is an excellent <it>passer</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="stop[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">stop</hw> <sound><wav>stop0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstɑ:p</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>stops</if></in> <in><if>stopped</if></in> <in><if>stop*ping</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to not move, walk, etc., after doing so before <vi>She was walking toward me, and then she suddenly <it>stopped</it>.</vi> <vi>The bus <it>stopped</it> at the corner.</vi> <vi>He <it>stopped</it> to watch the sun set.</vi> <vi>She had to <it>stop</it> to catch her breath. = She had to <it>stop</it> and catch her breath.</vi> <vi>He <it>stopped</it> to pick up a penny.</vi> <vi>The car was going so fast that it couldn't <it>stop</it> in time.</vi> <vi>The traffic light turned red, so she had to <it>stop</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Stop</it>. [=<it>halt</it>] Who goes there?</vi> <vi>I <phrase>stopped (dead) in my tracks</phrase> [=stopped suddenly] when I saw the bear.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to not move, walk, etc., after doing so before <vi><it>Stop</it> that man! He stole my wallet.</vi> <vi>They <it>stopped</it> us at the border to check our passports.</vi> <vi>She <it>stopped</it> the car and turned back.</vi> <vi>He was <it>stopped</it> by the police for speeding.</vi> <vi>The goalie <it>stopped</it> [=<it>blocked</it>] the ball/shot.</vi> <vi>The sight of the bear <phrase>stopped me (dead) in my tracks</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to not do something that you have been doing before :to not continue doing something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He constantly teases her and never knows when to <it>stop</it>.</vi> <vi>We've been working all morning. It's time to <it>stop</it> and take a break.</vi> <vi>The boss said that he was unhappy with some of his employees, but he <phrase>stopped short of</phrase> naming which ones. [=but he did not say which ones]</vi> <vi>Did you ever <phrase>stop</phrase> [=<it>pause</it>] <phrase>to think</phrase> about the risk you took?</vi> <vi>She never <phrase>stopped to consider</phrase> how her decision might affect others.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Can you please <it>stop</it> what you are doing to help me?</vi> <vi>I <it>stop</it> work at 5 o'clock.</vi> <vi>The phone <it>stopped</it> ringing.</vi> <vi><it>Stop</it> arguing/talking/running.</vi> <vi>She <it>stopped</it> [=<it>quit</it>] smoking last year.</vi> <vi>The patient suddenly <it>stopped</it> breathing.</vi> <vi>His heart <it>stopped</it> beating.</vi> <vi><phrase>Stop it/that</phrase> or I'll tell Mom.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (someone or something) no longer do something :to keep (someone or something) from continuing to do something <vi>I'm leaving and you can't <it>stop</it> me.</vi> <vi><it>Stop</it> me if you've heard this joke before.</vi> <vi>It's too late. There's no <it>stopping</it> them now. [=they can't be stopped now]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) I couldn't <it>stop</it> him crying.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> in U.S. English <vi>I couldn't <it>stop</it> him <it>from</it> crying.</vi> <vi>He <it>stopped</it> [=<it>restrained</it>] himself <it>from</it> laughing out loud.</vi> <vi>Nothing can <it>stop</it> me <it>from</it> leaving.</vi> <vi>Environmentalists tried to <it>stop</it> them <it>from</it> cutting down the trees.</vi> <vi>There is nothing to <it>stop</it> you <it>from</it> going.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>stop</it> the disease <it>from</it> spreading.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to end :to end (something) <vi>The teacher <it>stopped</it> the fight.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>stop</it> the violence in our city.</vi> <vi>They tried to <it>stop</it> the bleeding.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (a recording) to not play <vi>She <it>stopped</it> the CD because it was skipping.</vi> <vi>We <it>stopped</it> [=<it>paused</it>] the movie to grab some snacks.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to no longer happen or exist :to end <vi>The music suddenly <it>stopped</it>.</vi> <vi>The path <it>stops</it> about halfway up the mountain.</vi> <vi>The rain had <it>stopped</it> by the time we left. [=it was not raining anymore when we left]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to suddenly not work or function <vi>The engine just <it>stopped</it>.</vi> <vi>His heart <it>stopped</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not travel during a journey for a short period of time in order to rest, eat, etc. <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>We <it>stopped for</it> lunch.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>stop for</it> gas. [=we need to get gas]</vi> <vi>We <it>stopped for</it> a night in Atlanta. [=we stayed in Atlanta for a night]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go to a place during a journey <vi>I'll <it>stop</it> for a short visit.</vi> <vi>The tour <it>stops</it> in several cities.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make a brief social visit <vi>I'm not <it>stopping</it>. [=<it>staying</it>] I just wanted to drop this off.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stop by</dxt> <dxt>stop in</dxt> <dxt>stop off</dxt> <dxt>stop over <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to close, block, or fill (a hole) <vi>He <it>stopped</it> his ears with his fingers. [=he put his fingertips in his ears so that he couldn't hear]</vi> <un>usually + <it>up</it> <vi>She <it>stopped up</it> the cracks with plaster.</vi> <vi>The sink is <it>stopped up</it> [=<it>blocked</it>] with food.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to tell your bank not to pay a check <vi>I called to <it>stop</it> payment on the check. = I called to <it>stop</it> the check.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to take (money) from something <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>£200 will be <it>stopped</it> [=<it>withheld</it>] <it>from</it> your wages next week.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stay or remain <vi>I am <it>stopping</it> at home.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stop in</dxt> <dxt>stop out</dxt> <dxt>stop up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>stop and smell the roses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stop at nothing</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone will do anything to achieve a goal or purpose <vi>She will <it>stop at nothing</it> to get what she wants.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop by</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to visit someone briefly <vi>Feel free to <it>stop by</it> [=<it>drop by, drop in</it>] anytime.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>stop by</it> for a short visit.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to visit someone briefly <vi>You should <it>stop in</it> [=<it>stop by</it>] for tea sometime.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stay at home <vi>I'm <it>stopping</it> [=<it>staying</it>] <it>in</it> tonight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop off</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go or stay somewhere briefly while traveling to another place <vi>I'll <it>stop off</it> (at the store) to pick up some milk.</vi> <vi>She is <it>stopping off</it> in Miami to visit a friend.</vi> <vi>Could you <it>stop off</it> at the house to water the plants?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop out</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stay out at night <vi>He doesn't normally <it>stop out</it> late.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go to or stay in a place while traveling to another place <vi>The plane <it>stops over</it> in Chicago before going on to Seattle.</vi> <vi>She <it>stopped over</it> at a friend's house for a couple of days.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stop up</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stay up at night <vi>She <it>stopped up</it> late last night.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stop <dxn>7 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the buck stops here</dre> <dx>see <dxt>buck</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
