<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="budget[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bud*get</hw> <sound><wav>budget01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌʤət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bud*gets</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:an amount of money available for spending that is based on a plan for how it will be spent <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What's the average weekly/monthly/annual <it>budget</it> for a family of five?</vi> <vi>The film has a million-dollar <it>budget</it>.</vi> <vi>He's been trying to live on a <it>budget</it> of less than $1,500 a month.</vi> <vi>a movie with a big <it>budget</it> = a <phrase>big-budget</phrase> movie [=a movie that costs a lot of money to make]</vi> <vi>a movie with a low/small <it>budget</it> = a <phrase>low-budget</phrase> movie [=a movie that does not cost a lot of money to make]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The project was completed on schedule and <phrase>under budget</phrase>. [=it was completed for less money than had been planned]</vi> <vi>We're still <phrase>within budget</phrase>. [=we still are not spending more money than we planned to spend]</vi> <vi>The director always goes <phrase>over budget</phrase> on his films. [=the director always spends more money than is planned]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>The governor will discuss the state's <it>budget</it> deficit/surplus.</vi> <vi>a <it>budget</it> crisis</vi> <vi><it>budget</it> cuts</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a plan used to decide the amount of money that can be spent and how it will be spent <vi>We'll have to work out a <it>budget</it> so we can buy a new car.</vi> <vi>The government may have to raise taxes to <phrase>balance the budget</phrase>. [=to have enough money to provide the amount that is being spent]</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>on a budget</phrase>, you have planned how you will spend your money usually because you do not have a lot to spend and need to save money. <vi>The store has great bargains for people <it>on a budget</it>. [=people who do not have much money to spend]</vi> <vi>She started her business <phrase>on a small/tight/shoestring budget</phrase> [=she did not have much money when she started her business] and could not afford to overspend.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an official statement from a government about how much it plans to spend during a particular period of time and how it will pay for the expenses</dt></def> <uro><ure>bud*get*ary</ure> <sound><wav>budget02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌʤəˌteri, <it>Brit</it> ˈbʌʤətri</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <sl>formal</sl> <utxt><vi><it>budgetary</it> plans/matters/issues/constraints/cuts</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="budget[2]"> <hw hindex="2">budget</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌʤət</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>budgets</if></in> <in><if>budget*ed</if></in> <in><if>budget*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to plan to spend (an amount of money) for a particular purpose <vi>They <it>budgeted</it> millions of dollars to make the film.</vi> <vi>The project is <it>budgeted</it> at more than $100,000.</vi> <vi>He <it>budgets</it> $50 for entertainment each month.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make and follow a plan for spending your money <vi>If we <it>budget</it> carefully, we will be able to go on the trip.</vi> <vi>We're <it>budgeting</it> [=saving our money] for a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to plan how to use (something, such as your time) <vi>I need to learn how to <it>budget</it> my time more wisely.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>budgeting</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>Careful <it>budgeting</it> is essential to running a business.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="budget[3]"> <hw hindex="3">budget</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌʤət</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:low in price :suitable for someone who is on a budget <vi><it>budget</it> hotels</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
