<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bump[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bump</hw> <sound><wav>bump0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌmp</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bumps</if></in> <in><if>bumped</if></in> <in><if>bump*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hit (something, such as part of your body) against an object in a sudden and forceful way <vi>I have a bruise from where I <it>bumped</it> my head.</vi> <un>often + <it>against</it> or <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>bumped</it> his head <it>against</it> the shelf.</vi> <vi>I fell and <it>bumped</it> my elbow <it>on</it> the floor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hit and move (someone or something) <vi>Be careful not to <it>bump</it> the vase.</vi> <vi>You nearly <it>bumped</it> me off/over the edge!</vi> <vi>The jolt <it>bumped</it> him right out of his seat.</vi> <vi>He accidentally <it>bumped</it> [=<it>knocked</it>] my drink out of my hand when he passed by.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move <it>into</it> or <it>against</it> (someone or something) in a sudden and forceful way <vi>They <it>bumped into</it> us from behind.</vi> <vi>The boat <it>bumped against</it> the pier.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>The boat <it>bumped up against</it> the pier.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>They're <it>bumping</it> (<it>up</it>) <it>against</it> the limits of technology.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bump into <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>bump up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move (someone or something) to a different level, position, rank, etc. <vi>The TV show will be <it>bumped</it> to a new time.</vi> <vi>Increasing fuel costs are <it>bumping</it> the company's prices higher.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove (someone or something) from a group or position <vi>The loss <it>bumped</it> us out of first place.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) bumped</it> <vi>The flight was overbooked, and I was the first to <it>be bumped</it>. [=my seat on the flight was the first seat to be given to someone else]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in an up and down motion over a rough surface <vi>The truck <it>bumped</it> along the dirt road.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bump into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bump into (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet (someone) by chance :to see and usually talk to (someone you did not expect to see) <vi>I <it>bumped into</it> [=<it>ran into</it>] a friend at the store.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bump <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bump off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bump (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bump off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to murder (someone) <vi>He knew too much, so they <it>bumped</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bump up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bump up (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bump (something or someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to move (something or someone) to a higher level, position, rank, etc. <vi>Prices are being <it>bumped up</it>. [=<it>raised</it>]</vi> <vi>They're <it>bumping</it> her <it>up</it> [=promoting her] to district manager.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bump <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bump[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bump</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌmp</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bumps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an area of skin that is raised because it was hit, injured, etc. <vi>He wound up with a few minor <it>bumps</it> and bruises from the fight.</vi> <vi>Feel this <it>bump</it> [=<it>lump</it>] on the back of my head.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>goose bumps</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a small raised area on a surface <vi>The car hit a <it>bump</it> (in the road).</vi> <un>often used figuratively in U.S. English <vi>His career hit a <it>bump</it> in the road. = His career hit a road <it>bump</it>. [=something happened that slowed the progress of his career]</vi> <vi>When you're doing something for the first time, you're bound to hit a few <it>bumps</it> along the way.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>speed bump</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an act of something hitting against something else <vi>Did you feel/hear a <it>bump</it>?</vi> <vi>The airplane landed <phrase>with a bump</phrase>. [=the airplane went up again and then down when it hit the ground]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:the act of pushing the hips forward in a sexual way <vi>a dancer doing the <it>bump</it> and grind</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>grind</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="speed bump"> <hw>speed bump</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bumps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a low raised ridge across a road or parking lot that causes people to drive more slowly <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>speed hump</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
