<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="burn[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">burn</hw> <sound><wav>burn0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚn</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>burns</if></in> <in><if>burned</if> <sound><wav>burn0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚnd</pr> <il>or</il> <if>burnt</if> <sound><wav>burn0004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚnt</pr></in> <in><if>burn*ing</if></in> <def><dt><snote>The forms <it>burned</it> and <it>burnt</it> are used in both U.S. and British English. <it>Burned</it> is more common in U.S. English; <it>burnt</it> is more common in British English.</snote></dt> <sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a fire or flame</ssl> <dt>:to give off heat, light, and gases <vi>A flame is kept constantly <it>burning</it> at the monument.</vi> <vi>A small fire <it>burned</it> brightly in the fireplace.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to contain a fire <vi>There was a little stove <it>burning</it> in the front room.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burning</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <slb>always used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be on fire :to have or produce a flame <vi>I could smell smoke and knew that something was <it>burning</it>.</vi> <vi>Be sure not to leave any candles <it>burning</it> when you go to bed.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to set (something) on fire :to make (something) have or produce a flame <vi>We came to the memorial to <it>burn</it> [=<it>light</it>] a candle for the victims of the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to destroy or damage (something) by fire or heat <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>burned</it> the letter when I had finished reading it.</vi> <vi>The new town law makes it illegal to <it>burn</it> trash.</vi> <vi>The wildfire has <it>burned</it> acres of forest.</vi> <vi>Parts of the house were badly <it>burned</it> in the fire.</vi> <vi><it>burnt</it> pieces of wood</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The wood <it>burned</it> slowly.</vi> <vi>a material that <it>burns</it> easily</vi> <snote>A building or other structure that <phrase>burns to the ground</phrase> or <phrase>is burned to the ground</phrase> is completely destroyed by fire. <vi>The house (<it>was</it>) <it>burned to the ground</it> in the fire.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to injure or damage (someone or a part of the body) by fire, heat, acid, etc. <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He was badly <it>burned</it> in the accident.</vi> <vi>She <it>burned</it> her hand on the hot stove. = The hot stove <it>burned</it> her hand.</vi> <vi>The hot sun <it>burned</it> her skin.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>burned myself</phrase> on the iron. [=I injured part of my body with the hot iron]</vi> <vi>Several people were trapped in the building and were <phrase>burned to death</phrase>. [=were killed by fire]</vi> <vi>The captives were <phrase>burned alive</phrase>. [=killed by being set on fire]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She has to stay out of the sun because her skin <it>burns</it> easily. [=she gets sunburned easily]</vi> <vi>Several people <it>burned to death</it> in the fire.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to ruin (food) by cooking it too long or with too much heat <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I'm afraid I <it>burned</it> the potatoes.</vi> <vi>She <it>burned</it> the toast.</vi> <vi><it>burnt</it> toast</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The toast <it>burned</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <ssl>of an acid, chemical, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to damage (something) by causing a strong chemical reaction <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The acid <it>burned</it> his hand.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The acid <it>burned</it> into/through the metal.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Her words <it>burned</it> themselves into his memory. = Her words were <it>burned</it> into his memory. [=he always remembered her words]</vi> <vi>The image is <it>burned</it> in my mind. [=I cannot forget the image]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce (something, such as a hole) by fire, heat, acid, etc. <vi>He dropped his cigarette and accidentally <it>burned</it> a hole in the carpet.</vi> <vi>The acid <it>burned</it> a hole in the cloth.</vi> <snote>If you have money and you want to spend it, the money is <phrase>burning a hole in your pocket</phrase>. <vi>He just got his tax refund and has some extra cash <it>burning a hole in his pocket</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>always used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be very hot <vi>The pavement was <it>burning</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burning</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:to have or produce an unpleasantly hot and painful feeling <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The hot peppers <it>burned</it> my mouth.</vi> <vi>The cigarette smoke <it>burned</it> my throat and made my eyes water.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My mouth is still <it>burning</it> from the hot peppers.</vi> <vi>The iodine <it>burned</it> a little when I put it on the cut.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to feel a pain that is like being injured by heat or fire <vi>My nose was bright red and my ears were <it>burning</it> from the cold.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a high fever <vi>She was <it>burning</it> with fever.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>I'm going to call the doctor: you're <it>burning up</it>!</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>burn up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>burning</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to feel a strong emotion <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>She was <it>burning with</it> anger at his rudeness. [=she was very angry because of his rudeness]</vi> <vi>As a young man he <it>burned with</it> ambition. [=he was very ambitious]</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>for</it> <vi>She was <it>burning for</it> a chance to prove herself. [=she wanted very much to get a chance to prove herself]</vi></un> <un>sometimes followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She was <it>burning to prove</it> herself.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become hot and red because of a strong emotion <vi>Her cheeks were <it>burning</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her cheeks were <it>burning with</it> shame.</vi> <vi>His face <it>burned with</it> anger/embarrassment.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cheat or deceive (someone) :to take advantage of (someone) <un>usually used as <it>(be) burned</it> <vi>He doesn't like giving interviews because he's been/gotten <it>burned</it> by reporters in the past. [=reporters have treated him unfairly in the past]</vi> <vi>He's <it>been burned</it> in love before.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) very angry <vi>It really <it>burns</it> me to see people being treated so badly.</vi> <un>usually + <it>up</it> <vi>His arrogance really <it>burns</it> me <it>up</it>!</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>burn up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be used as fuel <vi>Some kinds of coal <it>burn</it> better than others.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use (something) as fuel <vi>This furnace <it>burns</it> oil/gas.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>an engine that <it>burns up</it> more fuel</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use (food, calories, etc.) as a source of energy <vi>Our bodies <it>burn</it> food/calories.</vi> <vi>exercising to <it>burn</it> fat [=exercising to lose fat by using it to produce energy]</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> or <it>up</it> <vi>exercising to <it>burn off/up</it> calories/fat</vi> <vi>Your body <it>burns up</it> more oxygen when you are active than when you are resting.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>burn off <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>burn up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to give off light :to shine or glow <vi>There was a light <it>burning</it> in the window.</vi> <vi>a star that <it>burns</it> brightly in the evening sky</vi> <vi>Lanterns <it>burned</it> in the boats on the canal.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:to record information or music on a disk <vi><it>burn</it> a CD/DVD</vi> <vi>You can buy the songs online and then <it>burn</it> them onto a CD.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>burn away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>burn away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn away (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be removed or to remove (something) by fire or heat <vi>The outer layer of wooden shingles <it>burned away</it> quickly in the fire. = The fire quickly <it>burned</it> the outer layer of wooden shingles <it>away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn down (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a building or other structure</ssl> <dt>:to be destroyed or to destroy (something) by fire <vi>The hotel <it>burned down</it> [=<it>burned to the ground</it>] in 1922. = A fire in 1922 <it>burned down</it> the hotel.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a fire</ssl> <dt>:to become smaller :to gradually produce less and less flame <vi>We watched the fire as it slowly <it>burned down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>burn off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of fog, smoke, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to go away because of the sun's heat <vi>We waited for the fog to <it>burn off</it>. = We waited for the sun to <it>burn off</it> the fog.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be removed or to remove (something) by fire or heat <vi>The hot sun had <it>burned</it> the paint <it>off</it> the sign years before.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burn <dxn>10c (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (itself) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a fire</ssl> <dt>:to stop burning <vi>The campfire eventually <it>burned out</it>. = The campfire eventually <it>burned itself out</it>.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>His anger finally <it>burned itself out</it>. [=he finally stopped being angry]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn (a building) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn out (a building)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to destroy the inside of (a building) by fire <vi>The apartment building was completely <it>burned out</it> by the fire.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burned out <dxn>1</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop working or cause (something) to stop working because of too much use or careless use <vi>The engine <it>burned out</it>.</vi> <vi>If you keep running the engine like that you're going to <it>burn it out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>burn out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (someone) out</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>burn out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become or cause (someone) to become very physically and emotionally tired after doing a difficult job for a long time :to suffer burnout or cause (someone) to suffer burnout <vi>Teaching can be very stressful, and many teachers eventually <it>burn out</it>. = Teaching can be very stressful, and many teachers eventually <it>burn themselves out</it>.</vi> <vi>All that hard work <it>burned her out</it> eventually.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burned out <dxn>2</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn rubber</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rubber</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>burn the candle at both ends</dre> <def><dt>:to do too much by being active late at night and during the day <vi>She's going to wear herself out if she keeps <it>burning the candle at both ends</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn the midnight oil</dre> <def><dt>:to work or study until very late at night <vi>The students have been <it>burning the midnight oil</it> as they prepare for their final exams.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>burn through (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use all of (something) quickly <vi>They've <it>burned through</it> 2 million dollars already, and the renovations are far from complete.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>burn up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>burn up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be destroyed or cause (something) to be destroyed by fire <vi>Most asteroids <it>burn up</it> upon entering the Earth's atmosphere.</vi> <vi>Wildfires have been raging across the region <it>burning up</it> acres of forest.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>burn <dxn>7c</dxn> <dxn>9b</dxn> <dxn>10b</dxn> <dxn>c (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn your bridges</dre> <vr><vl>also Brit</vl> <va>burn your boats</va></vr> <def><dt>:to do something that makes you unable to go back to a previous situation <vi>Even after leaving his job, he tried to stay on friendly terms with his former boss because he didn't want to <it>burn his bridges</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>crash and burn</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crash</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>money to burn</dre> <dx>see <dxt>money</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>burn*able</ure> <sound><wav>burn0005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɚnəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more burn*able; most burn*able</gram> <utxt><vi>an easily <it>burnable</it> material</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="burn[2]"> <hw hindex="2">burn</hw> <altpr>ˈbɚn</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>burns</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an injury caused by fire, heat, acid, etc. <vi>He suffered severe/serious <it>burns</it> on both his legs in the accident.</vi> <vi>a second-degree <it>burn</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a burned area :a mark on the surface of something caused by a flame or fire <vi>There's a small <it>burn</it> on the tabletop.</vi> <vi>a <it>burn</it> mark</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a painful red mark on the skin caused by rubbing against something <vi>rope/friction <it>burns</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a sharp, hot pain :a burning feeling <vi>the <it>burn</it> of iodine on a cut</vi> <vi>Continue doing the exercise until you feel the <it>burn</it> in your muscles.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>do a slow burn</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to slowly become very angry <vi>The boss <it>did a slow burn</it> when he saw the expense report.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="slash-and-burn"> <hw>slash–and–burn</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:done by cutting down and burning trees and plants in order to clear an area of land and grow crops on it for usually a brief time <vi><it>slash-and-burn</it> agriculture</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:using extremely harsh methods :<sx>ruthless</sx> <vi><it>slash-and-burn</it> tactics/politics</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bridge[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bridge</hw> <sound><wav>bridge01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɪʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bridg*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a structure built over something (such as a river) so that people or vehicles can get across <vi>a <it>bridge</it> connecting the island to the mainland</vi> <vi>the Brooklyn <it>Bridge</it></vi> <vi>a <phrase>railroad bridge</phrase> [=a bridge for trains]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>drawbridge</dxt> <dxt>footbridge</dxt> <dxt>suspension bridge</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that joins or connects different people or things <vi>Her work serves as a <it>bridge</it> between the past and the present.</vi> <vi>They hope to <phrase>build a bridge</phrase> between the two cultures. [=they hope to help the people in the two cultures understand each other]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the place on a ship where the ship is steered</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the upper part of the nose <vi>He broke <phrase>the bridge of his nose</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a pair of eyeglasses that rests on a person's nose</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the part of a guitar, violin, or similar musical instrument that raises the strings away from the surface</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:part of a song that connects one section to the next section</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a false tooth or row of false teeth that fits between two real teeth</dt></def> <dro><dre>burn your bridges</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cross that bridge when you come to it</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you say you will <it>cross that bridge when you come to it</it>, you mean that you will not worry about a possible problem until it actually happens. <vi>I don't know how we'll pay the bills if you quit your job, but <it>we'll cross that bridge when we come to it</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>water under the bridge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bridge</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="candle"> <art><artref id="candle.tif"/><capt>candle</capt><dim>30,137.5</dim></art> <hw>can*dle</hw> <sound><wav>candle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkændl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>candles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:wax that has been formed into a stick or another shape and has a string in the middle that can be burned</dt></def> <dro><dre>burn the candle at both ends</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold a candle to</dre> <def><dt>:to be on the same level as or as good as (something or someone) <un>used in negative statements <vi>The new movie doesn't <it>hold a candle to</it> [=it is not as good as] the original version.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not worth the candle</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:not worth the necessary effort, cost, or trouble <vi>The car is so old that replacing the engine is <it>not worth the candle</it>. [=the effort isn't worth the cost]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="crash[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">crash</hw> <sound><wav>crash001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkræʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>crash*es</if></in> <in><if>crashed</if></in> <in><if>crash*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit something hard enough to cause serious damage or destruction <vi>Investigators are still trying to determine why the airplane <it>crashed</it>. [=why the airplane hit the ground]</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>The car <it>crashed into</it> the fence/wall/guardrail.</vi> <vi>She <it>crashed into</it> another car.</vi> <vi>A large meteorite may have <it>crashed into</it> the Earth 65 million years ago.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to damage (a vehicle) by causing it to hit something <vi>She <it>crashed</it> the car into a tree, but no one was hurt.</vi> <vi>He has <it>crashed</it> two cars, a truck, and a motorcycle.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a loud noise by falling, hitting something, etc. <vi>We listened to the waves <it>crashing</it> against the shore.</vi> <vi>The stuntman <it>crashed</it> through the window on a motorcycle.</vi> <vi>The walls <it>crashed</it> down around them.</vi> <vi>He came <it>crashing</it> [=<it>tearing</it>] through the woods.</vi> <vi>The books <it>crashed</it> to the floor.</vi> <vi>The whole stack of cans <phrase>came crashing down</phrase>. [=fell down with a lot of noise and force]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The whole theory <it>came crashing down</it> when it was revealed that some of the supporting evidence had been falsified.</vi> <vi>His world <it>came crashing down</it> when he lost his job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a loud noise <vi>The cymbals <it>crashed</it> and the trumpets blew.</vi> <vi>Thunder <it>crashed</it> as the rain started to pour.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause two things to hit against each other and make a loud noise <vi>He <it>crashed</it> the cymbals together.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a computer</ssl> <dt>:to stop working suddenly <vi>My computer keeps <it>crashing</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a computer) to stop working suddenly <vi>This program always <it>crashes</it> my computer.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to go to sleep <vi>I was exhausted after the long flight, so I just checked into the hotel and <it>crashed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stay or live for a short time with someone <vi>You can <it>crash</it> [=<it>sleep</it>] here tonight.</vi> <vi>She's <it>crashing</it> with friends for a few days while her apartment is being repaired.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a business, price, market, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to go down in value very suddenly and quickly <vi>They lost thousands of dollars when the stock market <it>crashed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to go to (a party) without being invited <vi>He tried to <it>crash</it> the party but they wouldn't let him in.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to move very quickly and forcefully toward (something, such as the goal in ice hockey) <vi>The players <it>crashed</it> the net.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>crash and burn</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to fail completely <vi>The company <it>crashed and burned</it> after only two years in business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>crash*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>crash*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a party <it>crasher</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="end[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">end</hw> <sound><wav>end00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ends</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a point that marks the limit of something :the point at which something no longer continues to happen or exist <vi>The report is due at/by the <it>end</it> of the month.</vi> <vi>She interviewed several players at the <it>end</it> of the game.</vi> <vi>There is no <it>end</it> [=<it>limit</it>] to their generosity. [=they are extremely generous]</vi> <vi>I'm <phrase>at the end of</phrase> my patience. = I've <phrase>reached the end of</phrase> my patience. [=I can no longer be patient; I have run out of patience]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the last part of a story, movie, song, etc. <vi>I liked most of the book, but I didn't like the <it>end</it>. [=<it>ending</it>]</vi> <vi>He read the book from beginning to <it>end</it> [=he read the entire book] in one day.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the part at the edge or limit of an area <vi>The restaurant is in the north <it>end</it> of the city.</vi> <vi>We biked from one <it>end</it> of the island to the other.</vi> <vi>The house is at the <it>end</it> of the road.</vi> <vi>They live at opposite <it>ends</it> of town.</vi> <vi>He left the car at the far <it>end</it> [=most distant part] of the parking lot.</vi> <vi>the deep/shallow <it>end</it> of a swimming pool</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dead end</dxt> <dxt>rear end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the first or last part or section of something that is long <vi>She drove the <it>end</it> of the stake into the ground.</vi> <vi>The car's front/rear/back <it>end</it> was damaged.</vi> <vi>One <it>end</it> of the rope was tangled.</vi> <vi>Smoke curled off the <it>end</it> of the cigarette.</vi> <vi>The hose is leaking at both <it>ends</it>.</vi> <vi>the pointed <it>end</it> of the knife</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:either limit of a scale or range <vi>The car was in the high/low <it>end</it> of the price range.</vi> <vi>The candidates represent opposite <it>ends</it> of the political spectrum.</vi> <vi>The resort attracts tourists from the upper <it>end</it> of the social scale.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the stopping of a condition, activity, or course of action <vi>The agency's goal is the <it>end</it> of world hunger.</vi> <vi>The treaty marked the <it>end</it> of the war.</vi> <vi>His death marks the <it>end</it> of an era.</vi> <snote>When something is <phrase>at an end</phrase> it is finished or completed. <vi>The battle was <it>at an end</it>. [=<it>over</it>]</vi> <vi>We would like to see this matter <it>at an end</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>bring something to an end</phrase> or <phrase>bring an end to something</phrase>, you stop, finish, or complete it. <vi>She <it>brought</it> the concert <it>to an end</it> with a piano solo.</vi> <vi>Negotiations <it>brought an end to</it> the conflict.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>put an end to something</phrase>, you cause it to stop or prevent it from continuing. <vi>They promise to <it>put an end to</it> unfair policies.</vi> <vi>The new mayor vowed to <it>put an end to</it> the violence.</vi></snote> <snote>Something <phrase>comes to an end</phrase> when it stops or finishes. <vi>After three weeks the strike finally <it>came to an end</it>.</vi> <vi>Summer always seems to <it>come to an end</it> much too quickly.</vi> <vi>The curtain fell as the play <it>came to an end</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If there is <phrase>no end in sight</phrase>, the point at which something will be finished is not known. <vi>There is <it>no end in sight</it> to this heat wave.</vi> <vi>Prices continue to go up with <it>no end in sight</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the point at which someone is no longer living :<sx>death</sx> <vi>He came to a tragic <it>end</it> [=he died] in a freak accident.</vi> <vi>The doctors told her that the <it>end</it> was near. [=that she would die soon]</vi> <un>sometimes used with <it>meet</it> <vi>He <it>met</it> his <it>end</it> [=he died] in the icy water.</vi> <vi>She <it>met</it> an untimely <it>end</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a goal or purpose <vi>Our ultimate <it>end</it> [=<it>aim</it>] in sponsoring the event is to raise money for charity.</vi> <vi>corrupt leaders who use their power for their own <it>ends</it></vi> <vi>There are several ways to achieve/accomplish the same <it>end</it>.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>an end in itself</phrase>, it is something that you do because you want to and not because it will help you achieve or accomplish something else. <vi>She started exercising for her health, but she enjoyed it so much that exercising became <it>an end in itself</it>.</vi> <vi>For him, taking classes was <it>an end in itself</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If <phrase>the end justifies the means</phrase>, a desired result is so good or important that any method, even a morally bad one, may be used to achieve it. <vi>They believe that <it>the end justifies the means</it> and will do anything to get their candidate elected.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:a player whose position is at the end of the line of scrimmage <dx>see also <dxt>end run</dxt> <dxt>split ends</dxt> <dxt>tight end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a specific part of a project, activity, etc. <vi>She is in the creative <it>end</it> of the business.</vi> <vi>It's important to know what's going on in all <it>ends</it> of a business.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:the part of a project, activity, etc., that you are responsible for <vi>Let me know if you have any problems at your <it>end</it>.</vi> <un>usually used with <it>keep up</it> or <it>hold up</it> <vi>He promised to <it>keep up</it> his <it>end</it> of the agreement. [=he promised to do what he had agreed to do]</vi> <vi>You can count on her to <it>hold up</it> her <it>end</it>. [=to do what she is supposed to do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:any one of the places connected by a telephone call <vi>She picked up the phone and heard an unfamiliar voice at the other <it>end</it>.</vi> <vi>I can't hear you very well—there is a lot of noise at this <it>end</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <bnote>ends</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:parts of something that are left after the main part has been used <vi>a quilt made from bits and <it>ends</it> of fabric</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>loose end</dxt> <dxt>odds and ends</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a light at the end of the tunnel</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at the end of the day</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:when all things are considered :in the end <vi>It was a difficult decision, but <it>at the end of the day</it>, we knew we made the right choice.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at (your) wits'/wit's end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>burn the candle at both ends</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to a bad end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to end up in a bad situation because of your actions <vi>If he keeps living this way he's sure to <it>come to a bad end</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to die in an unpleasant way <vi>According to legend, more than one person <it>came to a bad end</it> because of her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>end to end</dre> <def><dt>:with ends touching each other <vi>Put the two small tables <it>end to end</it>.</vi> <vi>railroad cars lined up <it>end to end</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go off the deep end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>deep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:finally or after a long time <vi>We worked hard, and <it>in the end</it> [=<it>ultimately</it>], we achieved our goal.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:when all things are considered <vi>He thought about moving to the city, but <it>in the end</it>, decided to stay where he was.</vi> <vi><it>In the end</it>, what really matters in a relationship is trust.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make ends meet</dre> <def><dt>:to pay for the things that you need to live when you have little money <vi>We had a hard time <it>making ends meet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make your hair stand on end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>never/not hear the end of it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not the end of the world</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If something is <it>not the end of the world</it>, it is not as terrible or unpleasant as it seems to be. <vi>It <it>won't be the end of the world</it> if it rains on the day of the wedding.</vi> <vi>Losing your job does <it>not</it> have <it>to be the end of the world</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:without interruption <vi>For days <it>on end</it> [=for many days] she didn't answer the phone.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in an upright position :not lying flat <vi>We set the bricks <it>on end</it> around the garden.</vi> <vi>His skis stood <it>on end</it> in the corner.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/at the receiving end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>receive</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the end of the line</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the end of the road</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the point or time when someone or something stops or cannot continue :the end <vi>A loss in the primary elections will mean <it>the end of the road</it> for his campaign.</vi> <vi>It will be <it>the end of the line</it> for me unless there are some changes around here.</vi> <vi>They reached <it>the end of the road</it> as a couple [=their relationship was over] a long time ago.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the end of time</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>forever</sx> <sx>always</sx> <un>used figuratively after <it>to, till</it>, or <it>until</it> <vi>He promised to love her <it>to the end of time</it>.</vi> <vi>Their heroism will be remembered <it>until the end of time</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the end of your rope</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>the end of your tether</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a state in which you are not able to deal with a problem, difficult situation, etc., any longer <vi>It was clear from her outburst that she was at <it>the end of her rope</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been dealing with their lies for too long. I'm at the <it>end of my rope</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the ends of the earth</dre> <def><dt>:places in the world that are very far away from cities, large groups of people, etc. :the most remote places in the world <un>used figuratively <vi>He would go to <it>the ends of the earth</it> [=he would do anything] to please her.</vi> <vi>We will search <it>the ends of the earth</it> [=<it>everywhere; for a long time</it>] if we have to.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the short end of the stick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the wrong end of the stick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(to) no end</dre> <def><dt>:a lot :a great deal <vi>It pleases me <it>to no end</it> [=<it>very much</it>] to see you so happy.</vi> <vi>We've had <it>no end</it> of trouble finding somewhere to live.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to that/this end</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:as a way of dealing with or doing something <vi>We want to save the building. <it>To this end</it>, we have hired someone to assess its current state.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to/till/until the bitter end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bitter</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="ground[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ground</hw> <sound><wav>ground01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>grounds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the ground</bnote> <dt>:the surface of the earth <vi>An apple fell to <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>Mechanical problems kept the plane on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They were lying/sitting on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>close to <it>the ground</it> = low to <it>the ground</it></vi> <vi>The flight was watched by many observers on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They sent in <phrase>ground forces/troops</phrase>. [=soldiers who fight on the ground instead of in the air or at sea]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>ground war</phrase> [=a war fought by soldiers on the ground]</vi> <vi><phrase>ground transportation</phrase> [=transportation that is over the ground instead of on water or in the air]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the soil that is on or under the surface of the earth <vi>planting seeds in the <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>She drove a spike into the <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>damp/frozen <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>solid/firm/dry <it>ground</it></vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of land <vi>They built their house on bare/level/flat <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>We realized that we were on hallowed/sacred <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They built their house on high <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area of land or sea that is used for a particular purpose <vi>a camping <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>fishing/hunting <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>Each fall the birds return to their wintering <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a football <it>ground</it> [=(<it>US</it>) a soccer field]</vi> <vi>an ancient <phrase>burial ground</phrase> [=a place where people were buried in ancient times]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>spawning ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the land around a building <vi>the capitol <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>He was trespassing on school <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>We toured the <it>grounds</it> of the estate.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the bottom of the ocean, a lake, etc. <vi>The boat struck <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of knowledge or interest <vi>We have a lot of <it>ground</it> to go over before the test.</vi> <vi>We covered much more <it>ground</it> [=we went over more information] than we expected to at the meeting.</vi> <vi>The book covers <phrase>familiar ground</phrase>. [=subjects that have often been discussed before]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a place or situation in which someone or something is developed or tested <vi>The laboratory has become a <phrase>testing ground</phrase> for ideas about the origins of the universe.</vi> <vi>The tournament has come to be regarded as a <phrase>proving ground</phrase> for young players.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a set of beliefs, opinions, or attitudes <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The two sides are trying to find some <phrase>common ground</phrase> [=an area in which they can agree with each other] on these issues.</vi> <vi>When a politician talks about raising taxes, he's <phrase>on dangerous ground</phrase>. [=he is doing or saying something that may cause anger or criticism]</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>The two sides continue to look for a <phrase>middle ground</phrase> [=a middle position] between two extremes.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>high ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason for doing or thinking something <un>usually plural <vi>The company has been accused of discriminating on the <it>grounds</it> of race.</vi> <vi>We have no <it>grounds</it> for believing that the crisis will end soon.</vi> <vi>Her husband's infidelity was <it>grounds</it> for divorce.</vi> <vi>Many critics have objected to the proposal <phrase>on the grounds that</phrase> [=because] it would be too costly.</vi> <vi>The law was rejected <it>on the grounds that</it> it was not constitutional. = The law was rejected on constitutional <it>grounds</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:very small pieces of crushed coffee beans <vi>coffee <it>grounds</it></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a wire or metal object that makes an electrical connection with the earth <un>usually singular <vi>This metal bracket provides the <it>ground</it>.</vi></un> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>earth</cat></ca></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the area behind or around a design <vi>The wallpaper has red tulips on a white <it>ground</it>. [=<it>background</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above ground</dre> <def><dt>:on top of the earth's surface <vi>The bird's nest is located high <it>above ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>below ground</dre> <def><dt>:under the earth's surface <vi>The seeds should be planted a few inches <it>below ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to dig into the ground at the start of building something <vi>Workers <it>broke ground</it> on the new stadium last week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>break new ground</va></svr> <dt>:to make new discoveries <vi>Critics say that the study does not <it>break</it> (any) <it>new ground</it> in the search for a cure for cancer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn to the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>down to the ground</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:completely or perfectly <vi>The job <phrase>suits her down to the ground</phrase>. [=suits her perfectly]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from the ground up</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:completely or thoroughly <vi>The car has been redesigned <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:from a point at which nothing has been done :from the very beginning <vi>They built the resort <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>gain ground</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make up ground</va></vr> <def><dt>:to move faster so that you come closer to someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was trailing in the race, but she was beginning to <it>gain ground</it> (on the leaders).</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Alternative forms of energy are quickly <it>gaining ground</it>. [=becoming more popular or successful]</vi> <vi>The company has been <it>gaining ground on</it> [=<it>catching up with</it>] its competitors.</vi> <vi>The campaign is trying to <it>make up ground</it> by advertising heavily in key states.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get off the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin to operate or proceed in a successful way <vi><it>The project</it> never really <it>got off the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off the ground</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to operate or proceed in successful way <vi>We're still trying to <it>get</it> this project <it>off the ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move backward when you are being attacked :<sx>retreat</sx> <vi>The troops were forced to <it>give ground</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The controversy has continued, and both sides are still refusing to <it>give ground</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep your feet on the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the ground running</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold/stand your ground</dre> <def><dt>:to not change your position when you are being attacked :to not retreat <vi>The troops managed to <it>hold their ground</it> despite a fierce enemy attack.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company has managed to <it>hold its ground</it> in the marketplace.</vi> <vi>The president has continued to <it>stand his ground</it> despite criticism.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to the point of being very tired or exhausted <vi>She's been working/running/driving herself <it>into the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to the point of complete failure or ruin <vi>He ran that company <it>into the ground</it>. [=he destroyed that company]</vi> <vi>She drove that old car <it>into the ground</it>. [=she drove it until it would not run anymore]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move slower so that you are farther away from someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was beginning to <it>lose ground</it> (to the leaders) in the race.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The political party <it>lost ground</it> [=became less popular or successful; did not do well] in the election.</vi> <vi>The company is <it>losing ground to</it> [=falling behind; not doing as well as] its competitors.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="midnight"> <hw highlight="yes">mid*night</hw> <sound><wav>midnig01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmɪdˌnaɪt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the middle of the night :12 o'clock at night <vi>Her parents wanted her home before <it>midnight</it>.</vi> <vi>The clock struck <it>midnight</it>.</vi> <vi>It was <phrase>12 midnight</phrase> when we arrived home.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>midnight</it> snack</vi> <vi>at <phrase>the midnight hour</phrase> [=at midnight]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>burn the midnight oil</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="money"> <hw highlight="yes">mon*ey</hw> <sound><wav>money001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmʌni</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>mon*ies</if> <sound><wav>money002.wav</wav></sound> <il>or</il> <if>mon*eys</if> <pr>ˈmʌniz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:something (such as coins or bills) used as a way to pay for goods and services and to pay people for their work <vi>Dinner cost a lot of <it>money</it> last night. = We were charged a lot of <it>money</it> for dinner last night.</vi> <vi>a sum of <it>money</it></vi> <vi>That painting must be worth a lot of <it>money</it>.</vi> <vi>She's been making a lot of <it>money</it> in her new job. = (<it>informal</it>) She's been making big/good <it>money</it> in her new job.</vi> <vi>He earned some <it>money</it> last summer as a musician.</vi> <vi>We're trying to save enough <it>money</it> for a new car.</vi> <vi>The town is raising <it>money</it> for the elementary school.</vi> <vi>Friends would always ask her for <it>money</it>.</vi> <vi>It's an interesting idea, but there's no <it>money</it> in it: it'll never sell.</vi> <vi>The club <phrase>made money</phrase> [=earned money; made a profit] by selling advertisements in the newsletter.</vi> <vi>She knew she could <it>make money</it> [=earn a profit] on the deal. = She knew there was <it>money</it> to be <it>made</it> from/on the deal.</vi> <vi>When they take a vacation, <phrase>money is no object</phrase>. [=they are not concerned about the price of things] They always stay at the most expensive places.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blood money</dxt> <dxt>funny money</dxt> <dxt>hush money</dxt> <dxt>old money</dxt> <dxt>paper money</dxt> <dxt>pocket money</dxt> <dxt>seed money</dxt> <dxt>soft money</dxt> <dxt>spending money</dxt> <tag>smart money</tag> at <dxt>smart</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a person's wealth :the money that a person has <vi>He made his <it>money</it> in the insurance business.</vi> <vi>He lost his <it>money</it> on foolish investments. = He threw all his <it>money</it> away on foolish investments.</vi> <vi>They decided to put all their <it>money</it> in the stock market.</vi> <vi>We didn't have much <it>money</it> when I was growing up.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>comes from money</phrase>. [=her family is rich]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>married into money</phrase>. [=she married a wealthy man]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>marry money</tag> at <dxt>marry</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>monies</bnote> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>moneys</va></svr> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:amounts of money <vi>Most of the project is being paid for by federal <it>monies</it>.</vi> <vi>All <it>monies</it> received will be deposited in a special account.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a run for your money</dre> <dx>see <dxt>run</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for love or/nor money</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for my money</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>This book is, <it>for my money</it>, her best novel yet. [=I think this is her best novel yet]</vi> <vi><it>For my money</it>, nothing beats a juicy peach on a hot summer day.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the money</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:among the top three finishers in a race (such as a horse race) <vi>Whatever horse I bet on, it never finishes <it>in the money</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:having lots of money <vi>They struggled for many years but now they're <it>in the money</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>made of money</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:having a lot of money :<sx>rich</sx> <vi>Do I look like I'm <it>made of money</it>?</vi> <vi>Stop asking your father for a bigger allowance. He's not <it>made of money</it>, you know!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>money for jam</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>money for old rope</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:money that is easily earned or gotten :easy money</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>money talks</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that money has a strong influence on people's actions and decisions <vi>In politics, <it>money talks</it>. [=people and companies with a lot of money have a powerful influence in politics]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>money to burn</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a large amount of money to spend <vi>expensive cars for people with <it>money to burn</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the money</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:exactly right or accurate <vi>His prediction that it would rain was (right) <it>on the money</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put (your) money on</dre> <def><dt>:to bet on (something or someone) <vi>Everyone there <it>put their money on</it> the underdog.</vi> <un>often used to say that you feel very sure that something is true, will happen, etc. <vi>“Do you think he'll win?” “I'd <it>put money on</it> it.”</vi> <vi>It's going to rain tomorrow. I'd <it>put money on</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your money where your mouth is</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to give or spend money or take some action in order to do or support something that you have been talking about <vi>It's time for the mayor to <it>put his money where his mouth is</it> and increase funding for schools.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>throw money around</dre> <def><dt>:to spend money in a foolish or careless way <vi>He really <it>throws</it> (his) <it>money around</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>throw money at</dre> <def><dt>:to try to solve (a problem) by spending a large amount of money on it without giving enough thought to exactly what should be done <vi>The flaws in our school system will never be fixed as long as the government continues to just <it>throw money at</it> the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>time is money</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a person's time is as valuable as money</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your money's worth</dre> <def><dt>:as much as you deserve because of the money you paid or the effort you made <vi>His new movie gives his fans <it>their money's worth</it>. [=his new movie is good and is worth the money that his fans pay to see it]</vi> <vi>The people who showed up for the concert certainly <phrase>got their money's worth</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He insisted on staying until the end of the show so that he could <it>get his money's worth</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
