<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="but[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">but</hw> <sound><wav>but00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌt, bət</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that adds something to a previous statement and usually contrasts with it in some way <vi>I don't know her, <it>but</it> my husband does.</vi> <vi>He wants to go to the movies, <it>but</it> I want to go to the museum.</vi> <vi>He plans to visit Boston and Chicago, <it>but</it> not New York.</vi> <vi>The book is not a biography at all <it>but</it> (instead is) a fictional account.</vi> <vi>It's not the music I don't like <it>but</it> (rather) the band themselves.</vi> <vi>She got the promotion not by luck <it>but</it> by hard work.</vi> <vi>The fighting has been going on for years. <it>But</it> to really understand the current situation, you have to look at the history of the region.</vi> <vi>She called his name, <it>but</it> he did not answer.</vi> <vi>He fell <it>but</it> (he) wasn't hurt/injured.</vi> <vi>I told him to stay, <it>but</it> he refused to.</vi> <vi>It might have been raining, <it>but</it> it was still a nice wedding.</vi> <vi>I'd love to come to the party, <it>but</it> [=<it>however</it>] I'll be away that weekend.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry, <it>but</it> I won't be able to help you.</vi> <vi>The dress is quite plain <it>but</it> (it's) pretty.</vi> <vi>They were polite, <it>but</it> not really friendly.</vi> <vi>Not only was it quite cold on our trip, <it>but</it> it rained the whole time too.</vi> <vi>I can't do it—<it>but</it> neither can you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:other than :<sx>except</sx> <vi>We had no choice <it>but</it> to leave.</vi> <vi>They've done nothing <it>but</it> argue all afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in speech at the beginning of a sentence that expresses surprise, shock, etc. <vi><it>But</it> you promised (that) you would help me with this.</vi> <vi><it>But</it> it's not fair for them to treat him this way!</vi> <vi>They've arrived? <it>But</it> I thought they were coming Tuesday.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used with a repeated word for emphasis <vi>Nobody <it>but</it> nobody could solve the riddle.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>but then</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that adds another and different thought to a preceding statement <vi>I'm surprised to hear that Tom has left the army. <it>But then</it> I suppose he never was the type to obey orders.</vi> <vi>I'm sure she would do a wonderful job on the project, <it>but then</it> I know she's very busy.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used to introduce an explanation for something <vi>His cakes are amazing—<it>but then</it> he did study with some of the best pastry chefs in the world.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that tells about something different or surprising that happened next <vi>The team won the first two games, <it>but then</it> failed to win any of the next five.</vi> <vi>The disease was said to be untreatable, <it>but then</it> a new medication was introduced.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="but[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">but</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌt, bət</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><dt>:other than (something or someone) :<sx>except</sx> <vi>We had nothing <it>but</it> rain all week. [=it rained for the entire week]</vi> <vi>There was no one there <it>but</it> him.</vi> <vi>I didn't tell anyone <it>but</it> my sister.</vi> <vi>Who <it>but</it> you would think that?</vi> <vi>No one <it>but</it> you would try that. = No one would try that <it>but</it> you.</vi> <vi>I was anything <it>but</it> tired. [=I was not at all tired]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>but for</dre> <def><dt>:if not for (something or someone) :without (something or someone) <vi>We would never have visited the town <it>but for</it> [=<it>except for</it>] the newspaper article about local artists.</vi> <vi>The score would have been higher <it>but for</it> some excellent goaltending.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="but[3]"> <hw hindex="3">but</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌt, bət</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>only</sx> <vi>They have <it>but</it> two weeks to get ready.</vi> <un>sometimes used for emphasis <vi>If they had <it>but</it> given me a chance, I know I could have done it.</vi> <vi>He was here <it>but</it> five minutes ago.</vi> <vi>She is still <it>but</it> a child.</vi> <vi>This new product offers many advantages: speed, convenience, and durability, <phrase>to name but a few</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in negative statements to say that something must happen <vi>Anyone who reads the book <phrase>cannot but</phrase> feel sympathy for him. [=must feel sympathy for him]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>could not (help) but</phrase> wonder [=I felt compelled to wonder, I could not help wondering] why she had lied.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>all but</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="but[4]"> <hw hindex="4">but</hw> <sound><wav>but00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>buts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a reason someone gives for not doing or agreeing with something <un>usually plural <vi>I want this done today, and I don't want to hear any <it>buts</it> about it.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) As far as I'm concerned, she's the most qualified candidate, and there are <phrase>no ifs, ands, or buts</phrase> about it! = (<it>Brit</it>) There are <phrase>no ifs and buts</phrase> about it! [=it is certain that she is the most qualified candidate]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="then[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">then</hw> <sound><wav>then0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈðɛn</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at that time :at the time mentioned <vi>It was <it>then</it> believed (that) the Earth was flat.</vi> <vi>She lived in the Soviet Union, as it <it>then</it> was called.</vi> <vi>Just <it>then</it> he walked in.</vi> <vi>Back <it>then</it>, he was living in New York.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate what happened or happens next <vi>He walked down the street, <it>then</it> turned the corner.</vi> <vi>First the clowns come out, (and) <it>then</it> the elephants and lions (come out).</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate what should be done next <vi>“Take your first right, (and) <it>then</it> turn left at the light,” he said.</vi> <vi>Bring the soup to a boil, <it>then</it> turn down the heat and let it simmer for half an hour.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate something more that must be done or thought of <vi>We need to choose the menu, rent a banquet hall, and <it>then</it> there are the invitations to send.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate what must be true or what must or should happen if something else is true or happens <vi>If you were there, <it>then</it> you must have seen him.</vi> <vi>If it rains, <it>then</it> we can't go.</vi> <vi>“It's raining.” “<it>Then</it> we can't go.”</vi> <vi>“He confessed.” “The case is closed, <it>then</it>.”</vi> <vi>If you want it, <it>then</it> take it. = Take it, <it>then</it>, if you want it.</vi> <vi>Hurry, <it>then</it>, if you want to catch the bus.</vi> <vi>What if there should be a fire? <phrase>What then</phrase>? [=what will happen then?]</vi></un> <snote><it>Then</it> is often omitted following <it>if</it>. <vi>If it rains, (<it>then</it>) we can't go.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say or ask about what appears to be true based on what has happened or been said <vi>You did go, <it>then</it>, after all.</vi> <vi>Your mind is made up, <it>then</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to say what has been agreed to or decided <vi>OK, <it>then</it>, I'll see you at seven o'clock.</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt><un>used to make a final statement that refers back to the things that have just been mentioned or described <vi>These, <it>then</it>, are the things you must do.</vi> <vi>All of us, <it>then</it>, must accept some blame for these problems.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used after words like <it>all right</it> and <it>OK</it> at the beginning of a statement <vi>All right, <it>then</it>, let's get started.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>and then some</dre> <dx>see <dxt>some</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>but then</dre> <dx>see <dxt>but</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>even then</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(every) now and then</dre> <dx>see <dxt>now</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>then and there</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>there and then</va></vr> <def><dt>:immediately at that place <vi>I decided (right) <it>then and there</it> that I would accept the offer.</vi> <vi>I made up my mind <it>then and there</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all but"> <hw>all but</hw> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:very nearly :<sx>almost</sx> <vi>Without you the job would have been <it>all but</it> impossible.</vi> <vi>We had <it>all but</it> given up hope.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="anything"> <hw highlight="yes">any*thing</hw> <sound><wav>anythi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛniˌθɪŋ</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a thing of any kind <vi>We were allowed to do <it>anything</it> we wanted to.</vi> <vi>If you're not sure what to say, just say <it>anything</it> that comes to mind.</vi> <vi>She didn't say <it>anything</it> at all. [=she said nothing at all]</vi> <vi>That dog will eat almost/nearly/practically/virtually <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>We didn't talk about <it>anything</it> much.</vi> <vi>The new stadium is spectacular. There's never been <it>anything</it> like it.</vi> <vi>She never does <it>anything</it> but complain. [=all she does is complain]</vi> <vi>I'll do <it>anything</it> I can to help.</vi> <vi>They were ready for <it>anything</it> (that might happen).</vi> <vi>You can't tell him <it>anything</it> about computers. He thinks he's an expert.</vi> <vi>I can't think of her as <it>anything</it> but a good friend. [=I can only think of her as a good friend]</vi> <vi>He'll do <it>anything</it> for a laugh.</vi> <vi>I'd do/give <it>anything</it> to see her again.</vi> <vi>He won't take <it>anything</it> from anyone. [=he won't allow anyone to mistreat him, to be rude to him, etc.]</vi> <vi>She ate hardly <it>anything</it>. [=she ate almost nothing]</vi> <vi>He said he was sorry, but that doesn't really mean <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>I don't have <it>anything</it> against them. [=I don't have any reason for disliking them]</vi> <vi>She thought it was funny but I didn't see <it>anything</it> funny about it. [=I didn't think it was funny at all]</vi> <vi>They've been doing <phrase>everything and anything</phrase> to finish on time. = They've been doing <phrase>anything and everything</phrase> to finish on time.</vi> <vi>The problems were caused by lack of time <phrase>as much as anything</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <phrase>anything goes</phrase>. [=anything is acceptable; there are no rules that have to be followed]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>something</sx> <un>used in questions <vi>Would you like <it>anything</it> else?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> wrong?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> (good/interesting) on TV tonight?</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Do you want some pretzels <phrase>or anything</phrase>? [=or a similar thing]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything but</dre> <def><dt>:not at all <vi>He looked <it>anything but</it> happy. [=he looked very unhappy]</vi> <vi>Though he said he was happy, he looked <it>anything but</it> (happy).</vi> <vi>This problem is <it>anything but</it> new.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>anything like</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at all like <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>anything near</va></svr> <dt>:in any way :at all <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi> <vi>The movie wasn't <it>anything like/near</it> what I expected it to be. [=the movie was completely different from what I expected it to be]</vi> <vi>We don't have <it>anything like/near</it> enough time. [=we don't have nearly enough time]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:as any person or thing <un>used to make a statement more forceful <vi>He was (<it>as</it>) calm <it>as anything</it>. [=he was very calm]</vi> <vi>It was as obvious <it>as anything</it> [=it was extremely obvious] that she didn't want to go.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for anything</dre> <def><dt>:for any reason <un>used in negative statements <vi>I like my life, and I wouldn't change it <it>for anything</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if anything</dre> <dx>see <dxt>if</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very much :very forcefully <vi>It was raining <it>like anything</it>. [=it was raining very hard]</vi> <vi>She was hoping <it>like anything</it> that the weather would be good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than anything</dre> <def><dt>:very much :very badly <vi>I wanted to believe her <it>more than anything</it> [=I very much wanted to believe her], but I couldn't.</vi> <vi><it>More than anything</it> (in the world), I'd like to visit Paris again. [=the thing I most want to do is to visit Paris again]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cannot"> <hw>can*not</hw> <sound><wav>cannot01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkænɑt, kəˈnɑ:t, <it>Brit</it> ˈkænət</pr> <def><dt><un>used as the negative form of <it>can</it> <vi>We <it>cannot</it> [=<it>can't</it>] allow that to happen.</vi> <vi>I <it>cannot</it> [=<it>can't</it>] believe that he would do such a thing.</vi></un></dt> <usage>In speech, <it>can't</it> is much more common than <it>cannot</it>. In formal writing, <it>cannot</it> is much more common than <it>can't</it>.</usage></def></entry>

	<entry id="none[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">none</hw> <sound><wav>none0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnʌn</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><dt>:not any of a group of people or things :no amount or part of something <vi><it>None</it> of this was necessary.</vi> <vi>Why are all the guests standing in the kitchen and <it>none</it> sitting in the living room?</vi> <vi>Half a piece is better than <it>none</it>.</vi> <vi>The frozen yogurt tastes like ice cream but has <it>none</it> of the fat (that ice cream has).</vi> <vi>Though the languages are related they share almost/virtually <it>none</it> of the same vocabulary.</vi> <vi><it>None</it> of it is finished yet.</vi> <vi>“Can I have some soup?” “I'm afraid there's <it>none</it> left.” [=there is no more soup; no soup remains]</vi> <vi><it>None</it> of the birds was/were singing.</vi> <vi>Of all the competitions, <it>none</it> is/are more important than this one. = Of all the competitions, there is/are <it>none</it> as important as this one.</vi> <vi>To cut back on cholesterol my doctor said I should eat less meat or <phrase>none at all</phrase>.</vi> <vi>“You have no doubts?” “<phrase>None whatsoever</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>This is <phrase>none of your affair/business</phrase>. [=you should not interfere in this situation; it is not proper for you to say, do, or ask anything about this]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>have none of</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to accept, allow, or be influenced by (a particular behavior) :to not allow someone to do (something) <vi>I will <it>have none of</it> that kind of talk in my house.</vi> <vi>The group petitioned to have the votes counted again, but the government would <it>have none of</it> that.</vi> <vi>They begged their mother to take them out for ice cream, but she was <phrase>having none of it</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>none but</dre> <def><sl>somewhat formal</sl> <dt>:no person or kind of person except :<sx>only</sx> <vi>a sport for <it>none but</it> the most brave</vi> <vi>It was a request that <it>none but</it> the most coldhearted (person) could refuse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>none other than</dre> <def><dt><un>used to show that you are surprised or impressed by the person or thing you are about to mention <vi>It turns out I was sitting next to <it>none other than</it> the founder of the magazine.</vi> <vi><it>None other than</it> my favorite actor was cast in the lead role.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>none the less</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>nonetheless</sx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>second to none</dre> <def><dt>:better than all others of the same kind <vi>His cakes are <it>second to none</it>. [=the cakes he makes are better than all other cakes]</vi> <vi>The city's public transportation system is <it>second to none</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="see[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">see</hw> <sound><wav>see00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>sees</if></in> <in><if>saw</if> <sound><wav>see00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɑ:</pr></in> <in><if>seen</if> <sound><wav>see00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:n</pr></in> <in><if>see*ing</if> <sound><wav>see00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:jɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to notice or become aware of (someone or something) by using your eyes <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>It was so dark that I couldn't <it>see</it> anything.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>see</it> a thing without my glasses.</vi> <vi>Would you turn on the light? I can hardly <it>see</it> a thing.</vi> <vi>Let me <it>see</it> what you're holding in your hand.</vi> <vi>I <it>saw</it> your sister at the party, but I didn't talk to her.</vi> <vi>I <it>saw</it> her take the money.</vi> <vi>Nobody <it>saw</it> the accident happen.</vi> <vi>He was last <it>seen</it> leaving his house yesterday morning.</vi> <vi>This is the prettiest garden I've ever <it>seen</it>! = I've never <it>seen</it> such a pretty garden (before)!</vi> <vi>You have to <it>see</it> it to believe it.</vi> <vi>“He says he's coming.” “I'll believe it when I <it>see</it> it.”</vi> <vi>It's nice to <it>see</it> you (looking) so happy!</vi> <vi>I can <it>see</it> how happy you are.</vi> <vi>I could <it>see</it> (that) she was tired.</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> (that) you bought a new car. = You bought a new car, I <it>see</it>.</vi> <vi>This club is the place to be <it>seen</it> (at) these days. [=this club is the place where people go to be noticed by important or fashionable people]</vi> <vi>“Have you met the new guy yet?” “No, but I've <phrase>seen him around</phrase>.” [=I have noticed him in some of the places I often go to]</vi> <vi>A mall's a mall. <phrase>If you've seen one, you've seen them all</phrase>. [=all shopping malls look the same]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>It was so dark that I couldn't <it>see</it>.</vi> <vi>He can no longer <it>see</it> to read without his glasses.</vi> <vi>I couldn't <it>see</it> through/out the foggy window.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>see</it> over the person in front of me.</vi> <vi>On a clear day, you can <it>see</it> for miles from the top of the mountain.</vi> <vi>“He broke his leg.” “<phrase>So I see</phrase>.” [=I can see that his leg is broken]</vi> <vi>If you don't believe me, go and <phrase>see for yourself</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the ability to see :to have the power of sight <vi>She doesn't/can't <it>see</it> very well.</vi> <vi>She cannot <it>see</it>. [=she is blind]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be or become aware of (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>saw</it> the opportunity and took it.</vi> <vi>He only <it>sees</it> [=<it>notices</it>] my faults.</vi> <vi>I <it>saw</it> a big difference in her behavior.</vi> <vi>It was easy to <it>see</it> that she was lying.</vi> <vi>Can't you <it>see</it> that he needs help?</vi> <vi>Anyone can <it>see</it> that they're in love.</vi> <vi>I can <it>see</it> there has been a mistake.</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> that the school has raised its tuition again.</vi> <vi>He claims that he can <it>see</it> the future. [=that he knows what will happen in the future]</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> by/from the newspaper that they've won the election.</vi> <vi>Looking at the sales figures, we can <it>see</it> a steady rise in profits.</vi> <vi>Investors never <it>saw</it> this turn in the stock market coming.</vi> <vi>The book's ending is so predictable that you can <phrase>see it coming a mile away/off</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He claims that he can <it>see</it> into the future.</vi> <vi><phrase>As you can see</phrase>, the sales figures show a steady rise in profits.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to learn or find out (something) especially by looking or waiting <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>see</it> who's at the door.</vi> <vi>It will be interesting to <it>see</it> if the team can pull off a win.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure if I'm going to the party. I have to <it>see</it> how I feel tomorrow.</vi> <vi>You should try on the dress to <it>see</it> if it fits.</vi> <vi>Can you check to <it>see</it> if the car needs oil?</vi> <vi>She brought the car to a mechanic to <it>see</it> what was wrong with it.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>see</it> what I can do to help.</vi> <vi>We'll have to <it>see</it> how it goes.</vi> <vi>We <it>saw</it>, in the previous lecture, how Newton came up with his theory.</vi> <vi>He called to <it>see</it> if we would be home tonight.</vi> <vi>I have to <phrase>wait and see</phrase> whether or not I got the job.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>remains to be seen</phrase> [=it is uncertain] whether or not she was lying.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“Can you fix the car?” “I will have to <it>see</it>.”</vi> <vi>“Can I go to the party?” “<phrase>We'll see</phrase>.” [=<it>maybe, perhaps</it>]</vi> <vi>Things will get better, <phrase>you'll see</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to read (something written or printed) <vi>Have you <it>seen</it> today's newspaper?</vi> <vi>I <it>saw</it> in the newspaper that the team lost.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>see</it> your license.</vi> <vi>He posted his journal online <phrase>for all (the world) to see</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to tell someone where to look for information <vi>For further information, <it>see</it> Appendix A.</vi> <vi><it>See</it> the explanatory notes at the beginning of the book.</vi> <vi><it>See</it> [=<it>look</it>] below for details.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to watch (a television program, movie, etc.) <vi>Did you <it>see</it> the baseball game (on TV) last night?</vi> <vi>I <it>saw</it> that movie, too.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go to and watch (a performance, play, event, etc.) <vi>We <it>saw</it> the parade.</vi> <vi>We are <it>seeing</it> a play tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used in speech to direct someone's attention to something or someone <vi><it>See</it>, I told you it would rain.</vi> <vi><it>See</it>, the bus is coming.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to think of (someone or something) in a certain way <vi>Looking back, I <it>see</it> things differently now.</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> myself to be an understanding person.</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> you now for what you really are: a liar and cheat.</vi> <vi>Try to <it>see</it> things from my point of view.</vi> <vi>In order to understand them, you have to <phrase>see the world through their eyes</phrase>.</vi> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>She <it>saw</it> herself <it>as</it> an independent woman. [=she thought of herself as independent]</vi> <vi>He is <it>seen as</it> one of the best players in baseball.</vi> <vi>I <it>see</it> the job <it>as</it> a great opportunity.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what your opinion is about something <vi>“Can we do it?” “I <phrase>don't see why not</phrase>.” [=yes, I believe that we can do it]</vi> <vi><phrase>As I see it</phrase>, you have only two choices.</vi> <vi><phrase>The way he sees it</phrase>, we should be done by Friday. [=he thinks we should be done by Friday]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to imagine (someone) as being or doing something specified <vi>Can you really <it>see</it> yourself any happier than you are now?</vi> <vi>I can't <it>see</it> her becoming a doctor.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>see</it> him objecting to our plan, can you?</vi> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>She <it>sees</it> herself <it>as</it> a doctor in the future.</vi> <vi>I can still <it>see</it> her <it>as</it> she was years ago.</vi> <vi>Somehow, I just couldn't <it>see</it> him <it>as</it> a banker.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form a mental picture of (something) <vi>He <it>saw</it> a great future for himself in baseball.</vi> <vi>I can <it>see</it> it now in my mind: you and her married with two kids.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to understand (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>see</it> what you mean.</vi> <vi>I can <it>see</it> why/how you would feel that way.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>see</it> the point of your story.</vi> <vi>What's so funny? I don't <it>see</it> the joke.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>see</it> why we have to do that.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>see</it> how/that/why it matters.</vi> <vi>I can't get him to <phrase>see reason/sense</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>“You should hold the club like this.” “Oh, <phrase>I see</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>I can <it>see</it> you later this afternoon.</vi> <vi>I'll be <it>seeing</it> my lawyer on Friday.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>see</it> your dentist regularly?</vi> <vi>The doctor is <it>seeing</it> a patient at the moment.</vi> <vi>He has been <it>seeing</it> a psychotherapist.</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>You should <it>see</it> a doctor <it>about</it> your rash.</vi> <vi>What would you like to <it>see</it> me <it>about</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to visit (someone) <vi>I <it>saw</it> him at the hospital.</vi> <vi>I am <it>seeing</it> an old friend tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to allow yourself to be visited by (someone) <vi>He's not <it>seeing</it> anyone today.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to be with and talk to (someone) <vi>I can't tell you how glad/pleased I am to <it>see</it> you again!</vi> <vi>We'll <it>see</it> you again real soon.</vi> <vi>They <it>see</it> each other less [=they spend less time together] now that he has a new job.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>see more/less of</phrase> and <phrase>see a lot of</phrase> to describe how much time people spend with each other <vi>I'd like to <it>see more of</it> you. [=I'd like to spend more time with you]</vi> <vi>They've been <it>seeing a lot of</it> each other lately. [=they've been spending a lot of time together lately]</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to spend time with (someone) as part of a romantic relationship <un>usually used as <it>be seeing</it> <vi>They've <it>been seeing</it> each other for over a year.</vi> <vi><it>Are</it> you <it>seeing</it> [=<it>dating</it>] anyone right now?</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make sure (something) is done :to check that (something) is done <vi><it>See</it> (that) the work gets finished on time. [=make sure that the work is finished on time]</vi> <vi><it>See</it> that the door is locked before you leave the building.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to experience (something) <vi>He <it>saw</it> a lot of action during the war.</vi> <vi>I never thought I would live to <it>see</it> the day when gas would cost so much.</vi> <vi>Nothing bothers him—he's <it>seen</it> it all before.</vi> <vi>Oil prices have <it>seen</it> a large increase.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be the place or time in which (something) happens <vi>The city has <it>seen</it> a lot of growth in recent years. [=the city has grown a lot in recent years]</vi> <vi>This year has <it>seen</it> a drop in profits. [=profits have dropped this year]</vi> <vi>The last decade <it>saw</it> many technological advances.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go somewhere with (someone) <vi>I'll <it>see</it> [=<it>accompany</it>] you home.</vi> <vi>They <it>saw</it> [=<it>escorted</it>] him out (of the club).</vi> <vi>My secretary will <it>see</it> you to the door.</vi> <vi>I can <phrase>see myself out</phrase>, thank you. [=I can leave without having anyone show me where to go]</vi> <vi>He kissed her goodbye and <it>saw</it> her onto the plane. [=he watched her get onto the plane]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>see off <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to help or support (someone or something) for a particular period of time <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>see</it> us (out) to the end of winter. [=the supplies were enough to last until the end of winter]</vi> <un>usually + <it>through</it> <vi>The support of his friends <it>saw</it> him <it>through</it> his depression. [=helped him to get through his depression]</vi> <vi>The legislators vowed to <it>see</it> the bill <it>through</it> Congress to make sure that it became a law.</vi> <vi>They have enough money to <it>see</it> them <it>through</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a bet that is equal to (another player's bet) in poker <vi>I'll <it>see</it> your 10 and raise you 10.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>see</it> you and raise 10.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>has seen better days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>I'll be seeing you</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say goodbye</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let me see, let's see</dre> <dx>see <dxt>let</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>long time no see</dre> <dx>see <dxt>long</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not see the forest/wood for the trees</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tree</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see about (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do what is required for (something) :to deal with (something) <vi>She is <it>seeing about</it> getting tickets to the concert.</vi> <vi>I should <it>see about</it> [=<it>attend to</it>] dinner soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>we'll (soon) see about that</pva></phrasev> <dt><un>used in speech to say that you are not going to allow someone to do something or to behave in a particular way <vi>“He says that he's not going.” “Well, <it>we'll (soon) see about that</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see after (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take care of (someone or something) <vi><it>See after</it> [=<it>look after</it>] the baggage, while I see if our flight is on time.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>see after</it> the baby for me?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see and be seen</dre> <def><dt>:to see and be noticed by important or fashionable people <vi>We go to the club to <it>see and be seen</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see around/round</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see around/round (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to move about while looking at (something) :to tour (something) <vi>If you'd like to <it>see around</it> [=<it>look around</it>] the factory, someone can accompany you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see double</dre> <dx>see <dxt>double</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see eye to eye</dre> <def><dt>:to have the same opinion :<sx>agree</sx> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>They don't <it>see eye to eye</it> on this issue.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see fit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see here</dre> <def><dt><un>used to introduce a statement when you want someone to notice what you are saying <vi><it>See here</it> [=<it>look here</it>], you need to start behaving more responsibly.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see if I care</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see (something) in (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to notice or perceive (something good or attractive) in (someone or something) <vi>She <it>saw</it> great musical talent <it>in</it> her son.</vi> <vi>I think their plan is crazy, but he apparently <it>sees</it> something <it>in</it> it.</vi> <vi>I can't understand what she <it>sees in</it> him. = I don't know what she <it>sees in</it> him. [=I don't know why she likes/admires him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>seeing is believing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>see off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go to an airport, train station, etc., with (someone who is leaving) in order to say goodbye <vi>She <it>saw</it> him <it>off</it> at the train station.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to chase or force (someone) away from a place <vi>The police finally <it>saw</it> them <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to defeat or stop (an enemy, opponent, etc.) <vi>They <it>saw off</it> the opposition.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to work at (something) until it is completed <vi>He <it>saw</it> the project <it>out</it> to its very end.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>see over (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to walk around and examine (a place) carefully <vi>They went to <it>see</it> the house <it>over</it>. [=look the house over]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see red</dre> <dx>see <dxt>red</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see stars</dre> <dx>see <dxt>star</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the back of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>back</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the light, see the light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see things</dre> <def><dt>:to see things that do not really exist :<sx>hallucinate</sx> <vi>There's no one there—you must be <it>seeing things</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>see through (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to realize the true nature of (someone or something) <vi>She <it>saw through</it> his lies. [=she knew he was lying]</vi> <vi>I can't lie to her—she'd <phrase>see right through</phrase> me.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>see (something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to work at (something) until it is completed <vi>He <it>saw</it> the project <it>through</it> to the end.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>see <dxn>16 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>see to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or provide what is needed for (something) <vi>His uncle <it>saw to</it> his education. [=his uncle made the necessary payments, arrangements, etc., for his education]</vi> <vi>The hotel staff <it>saw to</it> [=<it>attended to</it>] my every need.</vi> :to deal with (something) <vi>I have to <it>see to</it> [=<it>attend to</it>] dinner.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>see to</it> your order at once.</vi> <vi>You really ought to have that rash <it>seen to</it> by a doctor.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>see to it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make sure that something is done <vi>Can you <it>see to it</it> that everyone gets a copy of this memo?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see you</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>see you around</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>see you later</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say goodbye <vi>“I guess I'll be going now.” “OK. (I'll) <it>See you later</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see your way (clear) to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>what/who should you see but</dre> <dx>see <dxt>should</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
