<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="by[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">by</hw> <sound><wav>by000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪ, bə</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:close to or next to (something or someone) :<sx>near</sx> <vi>She was standing <it>by</it> [=<it>beside</it>] the window.</vi> <vi>His wife was sitting <it>by</it> him.</vi> <vi>They have a house <it>by</it> the lake.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:up to and beyond (something or someone) :<sx>past</sx> <vi>The bus went right <it>by</it> him without stopping.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:at or to (someone's home) <vi>Some friends stopped/came <it>by</it> our house for a chat.</vi> <vi>Why don't you come <it>by</it> my place later?</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used following a passive verb to indicate the person or thing that does something <vi>The decision was made <it>by</it> the company president. [=the company president made the decision]</vi> <vi>Coal has been replaced <it>by</it> oil. [=oil has replaced coal]</vi> <vi>He was killed <it>by</it> a falling rock. [=a falling rock killed him]</vi> <vi>I was greatly surprised <it>by</it> the result. [=the result surprised me greatly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the thing that is used to do something <vi>He opened the door <it>by</it> (using) force. [=he used force to open the door]</vi> <vi>She succeeded <it>by</it> pure determination.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an action that is done for a particular purpose <vi>You can reset the machine <it>by</it> pressing this button. [=you can press this button to reset the machine]</vi> <vi>He began his speech <it>by</it> thanking the President and ended it <it>by</it> telling a joke.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the person who wrote or created something <vi>a play (written) <it>by</it> William Shakespeare</vi> <vi>This is a portrait of Gaugin (that was painted) <it>by</it> Van Gogh.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the method used to go somewhere, send something, etc. <vi>Some people came <it>by</it> [=<it>via</it>] train while others came <it>by</it> car.</vi> <vi>He returned <it>by</it> [=<it>on, via</it>] the last train.</vi> <vi>They sent him a message <it>by</it> [=<it>via</it>] e-mail.</vi> <vi>We drove here <it>by</it> the back roads.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the method used to enter or leave a place <vi>We entered <it>by</it> [=<it>through, via</it>] the front door.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the name that is used for someone or something <vi>The American writer Samuel L. Clemens was known <it>by</it> the name “Mark Twain.”</vi> <vi>Her full name is Elizabeth but she goes <it>by</it> (the nickname) “Lizzie.”</vi> <vi>The Federal Bureau of Investigation is usually referred to <it>by</it> its initials “FBI.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate how someone is spoken to, identified, etc. <vi>He called her <phrase>by name</phrase>. [=he used her name when he spoke to her]</vi> <vi>I know her <phrase>by sight</phrase> but not <it>by name</it>. [=I know what she looks like but I don't know her name]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce the name of someone or something important as proof that you are speaking the truth <vi>I swear <it>by</it> [=in the name of] all that's sacred that everything I've said is true.</vi></un> <un>often used in phrases like <phrase>by God</phrase> to add emphasis <vi>He always said he'd retire to Hawaii, and <it>by God</it>, he did it!</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:when using (a specified word or phrase) <vi>What do you mean <it>by</it> “acceptable levels?” [=what levels do you consider acceptable?]</vi> <vi>She called my theory “interesting,” but I don't know what she meant <it>by</it> that. [=I don't know whether she was being sincere, polite, etc.]</vi> <vi>It's hard to know what the author intended <it>by</it> this phrase.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the part of something or of a person's body that is held, grasped, etc. <vi>He grasped the shovel <it>by</it> the/its handle. [=he grasped the handle of the shovel]</vi> <vi>She grabbed him <it>by</it> the arm. [=she grabbed his arm]</vi> <vi>He held/took his daughter <it>by</it> the/her hand. [=he held/took his daughter's hand]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:during the time of (day or night) <vi>New York <phrase>by night</phrase> [=at night, during the night] is very different from New York <phrase>by day</phrase>. [=during the day]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the kind of light that occurs or is used when something is being looked at, read, etc. <vi>The landscape looked very different when we saw it <it>by</it> daylight than it had <it>by</it> moonlight.</vi> <vi>She was trying to read <it>by</it> the light of a single candle.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <dt>:not later than (a specified time) :at, in, on, or before (a specified time) <vi>We need to leave <it>by</it> noon at the latest.</vi> <vi>They should be here <it>by</it> tomorrow.</vi> <vi>I don't know where she is. She should have been back <it>by</it> now.</vi> <vi><it>By</it> this time next year she hopes to have a new job.</vi> <vi>She's planning to get married next year, <it>by</it> which time she hopes to have a new job.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:during the time until (a specified time) <vi><it>By</it> 2000 the U.S. had been an independent country for more than 200 years.</vi></dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <dt>:in a way that agrees with or follows (something, such as a rule) <vi>They didn't play <it>by</it> the rules.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in a way that is based on (something) <vi>You shouldn't judge other people <it>by</it> (their) appearances.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:according to (something) <vi><it>By</it> my watch it's nearly noon. [=my watch says that it's nearly noon]</vi></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate units of measurement or quantity <vi>The eggs are sold <it>by</it> the dozen.</vi> <vi>She gets paid <it>by</it> the hour.</vi> <vi>They have been making progress <it>by</it> small degrees.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the number that multiplies or divides another number <vi>multiply 8 <it>by</it> 12</vi> <vi>divide 10 <it>by</it> 4</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the numbers of a measurement <vi>The room measures 15 feet <it>by</it> 20 feet.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an amount, length, etc. <vi>The horse won the race <it>by</it> a nose.</vi> <vi>She's taller than I am <it>by</it> several inches. [=she's several inches taller than I am]</vi> <vi>The price has been increased <it>by</it> five dollars.</vi> <vi>This one is better <phrase>by far</phrase> than that one. [=this one is much better than that one]</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate someone's job, origin, character, etc. <vi>She's a lawyer <it>by</it> profession.</vi> <vi>He's French <it>by</it> birth, although he has lived in America for many years.</vi> <vi>I'm an optimist <it>by</it> nature. [=it is my nature to be optimistic]</vi></un></dt> <sn>14 a</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases to describe the speed at which something happens or changes <vi>The work is getting done <phrase>bit by bit</phrase>. [=the work is getting done gradually in small amounts]</vi> <vi>He's getting better <phrase>little by little</phrase>.</vi> <vi>His health is growing worse <phrase>day by day</phrase>. = His health is growing worse <phrase>by the day</phrase>. [=his health is growing worse every day]</vi> <vi>The situation is getting more dangerous <phrase>by the second/minute/hour</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases to describe how a series of people or things proceed or are dealt with <vi>They entered the room <phrase>two by two</phrase>. [=<it>two at a time</it>] [=two of them entered the room, then two more entered the room, etc.]</vi> <vi>I solved the problems <phrase>one by one</phrase>. [=I solved the first problem, then the second one, etc.]</vi></un></dt> <sn>15</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:in the opinion of (someone) <vi>Whatever you want to do is <phrase>fine/okay by me</phrase>. [=I am willing to agree to whatever you want to do]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:on behalf of (someone) <vi>He always did right <it>by</it> his children. [=he always did the right things to help his children]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the husband or wife who is the parent of someone's child <vi>He had two daughters <it>by</it> his first wife and a son <it>by</it> his second wife. [=his first wife was the mother of his two daughters and his second wife was the mother of his son]</vi> <vi>She has two children <it>by</it> her first husband.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>by the by</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>by the bye</va></vr> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement that provides added information or that mentions another subject <vi>I recently met his wife who, <it>by the by</it> [=<it>by the way, incidentally</it>], is a well-known author.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by yourself</dre> <def><dt>:without others :<sx>alone</sx> <vi>He sat (all) <it>by himself</it>, reading the newspaper.</vi> <vi>The new law will help, but it can't solve the problem (all) <it>by itself</it>.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't lift that heavy box (all) <it>by yourself</it>. Let me help you.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="by[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">by</hw> <sound><wav>by000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>past</sx> <vi>The bus went right <it>by</it> without stopping.</vi> <vi>We stood and applauded as the parade went/passed <it>by</it>.</vi> <vi>The last few years have <phrase>gone by</phrase> [=have passed] so quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>put</it> to describe something that is being kept or saved for a future use <vi>You should be <it>putting</it> some money <it>by</it> [=<it>aside</it>] for your old age. [=you should be saving some money for your old age]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:at or to someone's home <vi>Some friends stopped/came <it>by</it> for a chat. [=some friends came by our house for a chat]</vi> <vi>Why don't you come <it>by</it> later?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:close or near <vi>He did it when nobody was <it>by</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>around</it>]</vi> <vi>She lives <phrase>close by</phrase>. [=<it>nearby</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by and by</dre> <def><sl>literary + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:before too long :<sx>eventually</sx> <vi>I feel sure that we'll succeed <it>by and by</it>. [=<it>ultimately, in the end</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by and large</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a general way :in general <vi><it>By and large</it> [=<it>generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in most cases :in general <vi><it>By and large</it> [=<it>generally, usually</it>] it takes a month for the shipment to arrive.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="accident"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*ci*dent</hw> <sound><wav>accide02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæksədənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*ci*dents</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a sudden event (such as a crash) that is not planned or intended and that causes damage or injury <vi>We got in a car <it>accident</it>. = We had a car <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>a traffic <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>a fatal <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>a motorcycle <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>He was injured in an <it>accident</it> at work.</vi> <vi>The <it>accident</it> happened when her car slid on a patch of ice.</vi> <vi>Investigators are still trying to determine the cause of the <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>“I'm sorry that I broke the bowl.” “That's OK. It was just an <it>accident</it>.” = “That's OK. <phrase>Accidents will happen</phrase>.”</vi> <snote>An <phrase>accident waiting to happen</phrase> is a person or thing that is dangerous or unsafe. <vi>My brother is the clumsiest person I know. He's just an <it>accident waiting to happen</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an event that is not planned or intended :an event that occurs by chance <vi>Their meeting was an <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>It is just an <it>accident</it> that they arrived when they did.</vi> <vi>She says that her pregnancy was an <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>His wealth is a mere <phrase>accident of birth</phrase>. [=he is wealthy only because he was born into a wealthy family]</vi> <vi>He says that no one is to blame for his illness. It was just an <phrase>accident of nature</phrase>. [=something that happened naturally]</vi> <vi>It is <phrase>no accident</phrase> that the assistant he hired is so good-looking. [=he deliberately chose a good-looking person to be his assistant]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by accident</dre> <def><dt>:in a way that is not planned or intended <vi>They met <it>by accident</it>. [=<it>by chance</it>]</vi> <vi>She says that she became pregnant <it>by accident</it>. [=<it>unintentionally</it>]</vi> <vi>Scientists discovered the vaccine almost/quite/entirely <it>by accident</it>.</vi> <vi>Did it happen <it>by accident</it> [=<it>accidentally</it>] or by design?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="account[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ac*count</hw> <sound><wav>accoun01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈkaʊnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*counts</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a record of money that has been paid and money that has been received :<sx>bill</sx> <vi>the difference between the debit and credit sides of an <it>account</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>expense account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>accounts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:records of income and expenses <vi>We always keep very good <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>an <it>accounts</it> department</vi> <vi>The company's <it>accounts</it> show a profit this year: our <phrase>accounts receivable</phrase> exceed our <phrase>accounts payable</phrase>. [=the money owed to us exceeds the money we owe]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a bank keeps a record of the money that a person puts in and takes out of the bank <vi>We opened new <it>accounts</it> at a bank last week.</vi> <vi>I took out my money and closed my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>You can withdraw up to $1,000 a day from your <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>Every week, she puts/deposits a part of her paycheck into a separate <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>setting up a <phrase>bank account</phrase></vi> <vi>My wife and I keep our money in a <phrase>joint account</phrase>. [=an account that both of us can use]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>Please enter your name and <it>account</it> number.</vi> <vi>You can check your <it>account</it> balance [=the amount of money in your account] on the Internet.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>checking account</dxt> <dxt>savings account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a company's record of the products or services used by a customer and of the money that the customer owes or has paid to the company <vi>I don't have the money right now. Put it on my <it>account</it>. = Charge it to my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>If you return the clothes, the store will credit your <it>account</it>. [=you will not have to pay for the clothes]</vi> <vi>When do you intend to <phrase>settle your account</phrase>? [=pay what you owe]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>charge account</dxt> <dxt>credit account</dxt></dx> <snote>In figurative use, to <phrase>settle an account</phrase> or to <phrase>settle accounts with</phrase> someone is to do something that brings a final end to an argument, disagreement, etc. <vi>She's decided to <it>settle accounts with</it> her old political rivals.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a business arrangement in which a person or company regularly buys products or services from a particular company <vi>She makes sure that all of the company's <it>accounts</it> [=<it>customers, clients</it>] make the necessary payments.</vi> <vi>We just lost the Smith <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>That company was one of our biggest/best <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>She will be our <phrase>account manager</phrase>. [=the person who manages our account]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a person uses the Internet or e-mail services of a particular company <vi>I use two separate e-mail <it>accounts</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a description of an event or situation :a story or report about something <vi>personal/firsthand/eyewitness <it>accounts</it> from the war</vi> <vi>According to one <it>account</it>, the party was a complete disaster.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She gave the police a full/complete/detailed <it>account of</it> what happened.</vi> <vi>We read an <it>account of</it> her trip to Paris.</vi> <vi>a written <it>account of</it> his long and successful career</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a list or description of facts <vi>Our goal is to give an accurate <it>account</it> of the process.</vi> <vi>an <it>account</it> of how the system works</vi> <vi>The document is an <it>account</it> of the country's reasons for going to war.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason or explanation for an action <vi>You will be asked to give an <it>account</it> of your actions. [=to explain the reasons for your actions]</vi> <vi>He could give no <it>account</it> of what he did with the money.</vi> <un>often used in the formal phrase <phrase>on that account</phrase> <vi>I hope we won't lose our friendship <it>on that account</it>. [=for that reason]</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:value or importance <un>used in the phrases <phrase>of no account</phrase> and <phrase>of little account</phrase> <vi>He felt that his opinions were <it>of no account</it> to the others. [=he thought that the other people didn't care about his opinions]</vi> <vi>It's <it>of little account</it> what I may think about it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>no-account</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring/call (someone) to account</dre> <def><dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>He was <it>called to account</it> by his boss for failing to spot the mistake in the company's records.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by/from all accounts</dre> <def><dt>:according to all of the different descriptions of something <vi><it>By all accounts</it>, the band put on a great show. [=everyone says that the band put on a great show]</vi> <vi>She was, <it>by all accounts</it>, good at her job.</vi> <vi>They seemed, <it>from all accounts</it>, to have a happy marriage.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by your own account</dre> <def><dt>:according to what you have said about your own life or experiences <vi><it>By her own account</it>, that was the worst performance of her career. [=she said that was her worst performance]</vi> <vi>They had, <it>by their own account</it>, a wonderful time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give a good account of yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to perform well especially in a competition <vi>If I ever had to fight, I think I could <it>give a good account of myself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on account of</dre> <def><dt>:because of :for the reason of <vi>The game was canceled <it>on account of</it> the rain.</vi> <vi>They were treated badly <it>on account of</it> their beliefs.</vi> <vi><it>On account of</it> his bad behavior, he will not be allowed to play with the new toy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on no account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>not on any account</va></vr> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:for no reason :under no circumstances <un>used to say that something will not or should not happen <vi><it>On no account</it> should the children be left at home alone.</vi> <vi>They said that <it>on no account</it> would they leave before the end of the game.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on someone's account</dre> <def><dt>:because of someone :in order to please someone <vi>Don't leave <it>on our account</it>. [=because of us]</vi> <vi>You didn't have to clean your room <it>on my account</it>. I don't care if your room is dirty.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your own account</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:by yourself :on your own :without the help of others <vi>She bought the house entirely <it>on her own account</it>.</vi> <vi>He left the company and went into business <it>on his own account</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for your own sake :in order to make a situation good for yourself <vi>I'm doing it <it>on my own account</it>, not for anyone else.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) into account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take account of (something)</va></vr> <def><dt>:to think about (something) before doing something (such as making a decision) :<sx>consider</sx> <vi>Try to <it>take</it> our feelings <it>into account</it>. [=try to think about how we will feel]</vi> <vi>Other issues must be <it>taken into account</it> before a choice can be made.</vi> <vi>She did very well on the test when you <it>take into account</it> how little she studied.</vi> <vi>She <it>takes no account of</it> my feelings. [=she doesn't consider how I feel]</vi> <vi>The new health plan fails to <it>take account of</it> the fact that many people cannot pay for their medicine.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn (something) to (good) account</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to gain or profit from (something) :to take advantage of (something) <vi>Is there a way to <it>turn</it> this situation <it>to good account</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="any[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">any</hw> <sound><wav>any00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛni</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a person or thing that is not particular or specific <vi>Ask <it>any</it> man you meet, and he will tell you the same thing.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> one of them could have answered the question.</vi> <vi>You can return the product if <it>any</it> defect appears within the first six months.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> plan (at all) is better than no plan.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> [=<it>every</it>] child knows that. [=all children know that]</vi> <vi>He is as good as <it>any</it> other pitcher in the league.</vi> <vi>We can meet <it>any</it> day but Monday.</vi> <vi>You could have seen him <it>any</it> afternoon last week.</vi> <vi>The recipe uses a large amount of pepper, and <phrase>not just any</phrase> pepper, but a special blend imported from India.</vi> <vi>You have to be a member to go there. They won't let <phrase>just any</phrase> person in.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an amount greater than zero or none</un> <un>usually used in negative statements, in questions, and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>You haven't eaten <it>any</it> salad. [=no salad has been eaten]</vi> <vi>I can't find <it>any</it> stamps.</vi> <vi>Don't pay <it>any</it> attention to him.</vi> <vi>There is hardly <it>any</it> difference between the two teams.</vi> <vi>They dropped by without <it>any</it> warning.</vi> <vi>We don't want there to be <it>any</it> misunderstandings.</vi> <vi>The company has denied <it>any</it> [=<it>all</it>] responsibility for the accident.</vi> <vi>There are <phrase>few if any</phrase> [=few or no] details about the accident.</vi> <vi>Do you have <it>any</it> money?</vi> <vi>He asked if/whether you had <it>any</it> money.</vi> <vi>If there are <it>any</it> errors, report them to me. = Report <it>any</it> errors to me.</vi> <vi>If you can give me <it>any</it> help, I'd appreciate it. = I'd appreciate <it>any</it> help you can give me.</vi></un></dt> <usage><it>Some</it> is used instead of <it>any</it> in positive statements. <vi>I have <it>some</it> money.</vi> It is sometimes used instead of <it>any</it> in questions and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it>. <vi>Do you have <it>some</it> money?</vi> <vi>If I had <it>some</it> money, I would spend it on books.</vi></usage></def> <dro><dre>any moment</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moment</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <dx>see <dxt>old</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at any cost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>by any chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go to any length/lengths</dre> <dx>see <dxt>length</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any case</dre> <dx>see <dxt>case</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any event</dre> <dx>see <dxt>event</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blood"> <hw highlight="yes">blood</hw> <sound><wav>blood001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblʌd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the red liquid that flows through the bodies of people and animals <vi>The accident victim has already lost a lot of <it>blood</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>blood</it> in your veins</vi> <vi>She <phrase>donates/gives blood</phrase> twice a year. [=twice a year she has blood taken out of her body so that it can be put into the body of a person who needs it]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad blood</dxt> <dxt>cold-blooded</dxt> <dxt>full-blooded</dxt> <dxt>hot-blooded</dxt> <dxt>red-blooded</dxt> <dxt>warm-blooded</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that a person's ancestors were of a particular kind <vi>There's some Italian <it>blood</it> in her family. [=one or more of her family's ancestors was Italian]</vi> <vi>a man of royal <it>blood</it> [=a man with kings and queens in his family]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>blue blood</dxt> <dxt>blue-blooded</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:members of a team, company, or organization <un>usually used in the phrases <phrase>new blood</phrase> or <phrase>young blood</phrase> <vi>Our company could benefit from some <it>new blood</it>. [=new employees]</vi> <vi>We've just added some <it>young blood</it> to the team.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>blood and guts</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>blood is thicker than water</dre> <def><dt><snote>The saying <it>blood is thicker than water</it> means that a person's family is more important than a person's other relationships or needs.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blood is up</dre> <def><dt><snote>In British English, when you say that someone's <it>blood is up</it>, you mean that someone is angry and wants to fight or argue. <vi>It's best to avoid her when her <it>blood is up</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blood on your hands</dre> <def><dt><snote>If someone's <it>blood is on your hands</it>, you are responsible for that person's death. <vi>Her <it>blood is on your hands</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by blood</dre> <def><dt>:by a relationship that connects two people through their natural parents, grandparents, etc. <vi>My aunt and I are <phrase>related by blood</phrase>. [=my aunt is the sister of one of my parents]</vi> <vi>My aunt and I are not <phrase>related by blood</phrase>. [=my aunt is/was married to the brother of one of my parents]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw blood</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to take blood from a person's body for medical reasons <vi>We need to <it>draw</it> some <it>blood</it> to test you for the virus.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause blood to flow from a person's body <vi>The punch to the nose <it>drew blood</it>. [=caused the nose to bleed]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Some politicians view debates as chances to <it>draw blood</it> from their opponents.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>flesh and blood</dre> <dx>see <dxt>flesh</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in cold blood</dre> <def><dt>:in a deliberate way :following a plan <vi>They were killed <it>in cold blood</it> by terrorists.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your blood</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something (such as an ability or activity) is <it>in your blood</it>, it is part of your nature and is often shared by your family members. <vi>With two parents who are painters, art is <it>in her blood</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood boil</dre> <def><dt>:to make someone very angry <vi>His hate-filled speeches <it>make my blood boil</it>! [=<it>make me see red</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood curdle</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make someone's blood run cold</va></vr> <def><dt>:to cause someone to be very afraid or disgusted <vi>The horrible news <it>made our blood run cold</it>.</vi> <vi>a ghost story that will <it>make your blood curdle</it></vi> <vi>The mere sight of a cockroach <it>makes my blood curdle</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out for blood</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>out for blood</it> or <it>out for someone's blood</it>, you are very angry and you want to kill someone or to cause someone pain or discomfort. <vi>Those soldiers were <it>out for blood</it>.</vi> <vi>His ex-wife is <it>out for his blood</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>spill/shed blood</dre> <def><dt>:to kill people violently <vi>The <it>blood</it> of too many young people <it>has been spilled/shed</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweat blood</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to care a lot about something and work very hard for it <vi>basketball players who <it>sweat blood</it> for their teams</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>taste blood</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to experience pleasure as a result of defeating an opponent <vi>She has <it>tasted blood</it> now, and can't wait to meet her rival on the court again.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="book[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">book</hw> <sound><wav>book0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>books</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a set of printed sheets of paper that are held together inside a cover :a long written work <vi>The shelves in his office are filled with <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>That's one of the best <it>books</it> I've read in a long time.</vi> <vi>a novelist who has written some wonderful <it>books</it></vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> about plumbing</vi> <vi>The library has many dictionaries and other reference <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>a hardcover/paperback <it>book</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can learn many things by studying the great <it>book</it> of nature. [=by studying nature]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long written work that can be read on a computer :<sx>e-book</sx> <vi>an electronic <it>book</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of sheets of paper that are inside a cover and that you can write information on <vi>an appointment <it>book</it></vi> <vi>an address <it>book</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>notebook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a major section of a long written work (such as the Bible) <vi>the <it>books</it> of the Bible</vi> <vi>a story that is told in the <it>Book</it> of Job</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good book</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of things held together inside a cover like the pages of a book <vi>a <it>book</it> of stamps</vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> of matches [=a matchbook]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkbook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>books</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the financial records of a business <vi>The company's <it>books</it> [=<it>accounts</it>] show a profit.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the official records of a business or organization <vi>I'm sorry, but your name does not appear in/on our <it>books</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the knowledge or information that relates to a particular subject, person, etc. <vi><it>The book</it> on him is that he can't hit a curveball. [=people have seen and reported that he can't hit a curveball]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>phone book</sx> <vi>Give me a call if you need to. I'm in <it>the book</it>. [=my telephone number is listed in the telephone book]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a closed book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is difficult to understand <vi>Even to his closest friends, he was always something of <it>a closed book</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>an open book <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an open book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is easy to learn about and understand <vi>My life is <it>an open book</it>. I have nothing to hide.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (someone) to book</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>The people responsible for these crimes must be <it>brought to book</it>. [=<it>brought to account</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by the book</dre> <def><dt>:by following the official rules very strictly <vi>My boss insists on doing everything <it>by the book</it>.</vi> <vi>They ran all the investigations <it>by the book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cook the books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cook</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every trick in the book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the books</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to study or begin studying very intensely <vi>I've got to <it>hit the books</it> all weekend if I'm going to pass this test.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in my book</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She deserves credit, <it>in my book</it>, for much of the company's recent success.</vi> <vi>He isn't even a good boss, at least not <it>in my book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's bad books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are not liked or treated nicely by someone <vi>He remains <it>in her bad books</it>. [=she is still displeased with him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's good books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are liked or are treated nicely by someone <vi>He's trying to get back <it>in his boss's good books</it> by offering to work overtime.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one for the books</dre> <def><dt>:a very unusual, important, or surprising situation, statement, event, etc. <vi>There have been a lot of scandals in local politics over the years, but this is <it>one for the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the books</dre> <def><dt>:part of the set of official laws <vi>It's an outdated law that's still <it>on the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>read someone like a book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>read</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>suit someone's book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>suit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>throw the book at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to punish (someone) as severely as possible <vi>The judge threatened to <it>throw the book at</it> him if he committed another offense.</vi> <vi>I thought I would get off with just a warning, but they <it>threw the book at</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>write the book on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>write</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bootstraps"> <hw>boot*straps</hw> <pr>ˈbu:tˌstræps</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>by your own bootstraps</dre> <def><dt>:without help from other people :as a result of your own hard work <vi>Despite many obstacles, she has pulled herself up <it>by her own bootstraps</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bound[4]"> <hw hindex="4">bound</hw> <altpr>ˈbaʊnd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bounds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a leap or long jump <vi>He leapt over the puddle in/with a single <it>bound</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by/in leaps and bounds</dre> <dx>see <dxt>leap</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bound</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bye[1]"> <hw hindex="1">bye</hw> <sound><wav>by000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbaɪ</pr> <fl>interjection</fl> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>goodbye</sx> <vi><it>Bye</it>. I'll see you tomorrow.</vi> <un>often + <it>now</it> <vi>“See you later.” “OK. <it>Bye now</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
