<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="call[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">call</hw> <sound><wav>call0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:l</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>calls</if></in> <in><if>called</if></in> <in><if>call*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to speak in a loud voice <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>called</it> to passersby for help.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> up to her husband, who was at the top of the stairs.</vi> <vi>Her husband <it>called</it> back down to her.</vi> <vi>She saw her friends across the street and <it>called</it> over/across to them.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>called</it> her name in his sleep.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call out <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to announce or read (something) in a loud voice <vi><it>call</it> the roll</vi> <vi><it>call</it> (off) a row of figures</vi> <vi>They're <it>calling</it> [=<it>announcing</it>] our flight: it's boarding at gate 57.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call out <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a bird or animal</ssl> <dt>:to make the sound that is usual for a particular type of bird or animal <vi>The birds were <it>calling</it> as the sun rose.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it> once a week to talk to my parents.</vi> <vi>Where are you <it>calling</it> from?</vi> <vi>May I say who's <it>calling</it>?</vi> <vi>Thank you for <it>calling</it>.</vi> <vi>Please <it>call</it> back/again later.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> long-distance.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I try to <it>call</it> my parents at least once a week.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> me long-distance.</vi> <vi>I <it>called</it> the office to get some information.</vi> <vi>Please <it>call</it> us back/again later.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>call</it> us—we'll <it>call</it> you.</vi> <vi>In an emergency you should <it>call</it> [=<it>dial</it>] 911.</vi> <vi><it>Call</it> me when you get back from your vacation.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call <dxn>3b (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call in <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call up <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to tell, order, or ask (someone or something) to come <vi>I <it>called</it> the waiter over (to my table) and asked for the check, and then I <it>called</it> him back to order something else.</vi> <vi>My dog comes running when he's <it>called</it>.</vi> <vi>She was <it>called</it> to court to testify.</vi> <vi>He was <it>called</it> to the office for an interview.</vi> <vi>soldiers who have been <it>called</it> to active duty</vi> <vi>He's not home because he was <phrase>called away</phrase> on business.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to tell, order, or ask (someone or something) to come <vi>We had to <it>call</it> an ambulance.</vi> <vi>He <it>called</it> a taxi but it still hasn't come.</vi> <vi>He <it>called</it> a taxi for me. = He <it>called</it> me a taxi.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give a name to (someone or something) <vi>Her parents <it>called</it> [=<it>named</it>] her Katherine after/for her grandmother.</vi> <vi>The immigrants settled along the river and <it>called</it> their new town “Brookhaven.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk to or refer to (someone or something) with a specified name <vi>Her name is Katherine but her friends all <it>call</it> her “Kitty.”</vi> <vi>This part of the city is <it>called</it> “The Old Town.”</vi> <vi>It's important to <it>call</it> things by their right names.</vi> <vi>Human beings belong to a large group of animals <it>called</it> “mammals.”</vi> <vi>The other children <phrase>called him (bad) names</phrase>. [=the other children spoke to him with cruel and insulting words in place of his name]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>name-calling</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to regard or think of (someone or something) in a certain way <vi>Some people say he's a good man, but I <it>call</it> him a fool. [=I consider him to be a fool]</vi> <vi>She went out in the rain without an umbrella? I <it>call</it> that pretty foolish.</vi> <vi>He's not what you would <it>call</it> a generous man. [=he's not a generous man]</vi> <vi>Her sense of humor is what you might <it>call</it> subtle. [=she has a subtle sense of humor]</vi> <vi>(You can) <it>Call</it> me foolish if you like, but I still think people are basically good.</vi> <vi>It costs 99 cents: let's <it>call</it> it an even dollar for simplicity's sake.</vi> <vi>You may not agree with him, but he <phrase>calls them like he sees them</phrase>! [=he states his opinion in an open, honest, and direct way]</vi> <vi>You did me a favor and I did you a favor, so let's <phrase>call it even</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give the order for (something, such as a meeting) <vi><it>call</it> [=<it>convene</it>] a meeting</vi> <vi><it>call</it> an election</vi> <vi>The union has threatened to <it>call</it> a strike against the company.</vi> <vi>The chairman <phrase>called a halt to</phrase> [=<it>stopped</it>] the discussion.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a brief visit <vi>He <it>called</it> to pay his respects.</vi> <vi>We're planning to <it>call</it> [=<it>stop</it>] at a friend's house on the way home.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call at <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call for <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call in <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call on <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or guess what the result of something will be <vi>Nobody else thought the election would turn out as it did, but he <it>called</it> [=<it>predicted</it>] it exactly right!</vi> <vi>You <it>called</it> it! [=you correctly said what would happen]</vi> <vi><it>call</it> the toss of a coin</vi> <vi>We flipped a coin; he <it>called</it> heads, and heads it was!</vi> <vi>The election is still <phrase>too close to call</phrase>. [=the election is too close to say who will win]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop or cancel (something, such as a baseball game) because of bad conditions <vi>The game was <it>called</it> on account of rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make an official ruling or decision about (something, such as a pitched ball or a player's action) <vi>Only the umpire has the right to <it>call</it> balls and strikes.</vi> <vi>The pitch was <it>called</it> a strike. [=the umpire said that the pitch was a strike]</vi> <vi>The umpire <it>called</it> the runner safe/out.</vi> <vi><it>call</it> a serve in/out</vi> <vi>She was <it>called</it> for being offside. [=the official said that she was offside]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:to say or decide what kind of play will be used <vi>The quarterback <it>called</it> a running play.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>poker</ssl> <dt>:to require (a player) to show a hand by making an equal bet <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it> you.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>call a spade a spade</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spade</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call at (a place)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to stop at (a place) briefly <vi>The ship <it>called at</it> the port.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to pray or ask God to do something to someone <vi>He <it>called down</it> a blessing/curse on the king. [=he prayed that the king would be blessed/cursed]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say or demand publicly that something is needed or should be done <vi>The opposition has <it>called for</it> an investigation.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>called for</it> [=<it>asked for</it>] calm and restraint.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to indicate that something is needed or should be done <vi>The plan <it>calls for</it> three windows to be added.</vi> <vi>You've won! That <it>calls for</it> a celebration! [=we should celebrate because you've won]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to require or demand (something) as necessary or proper <vi>The job <it>calls for</it> typing skills. [=you must have typing skills to do the job]</vi> <vi>Action is urgently <it>called for</it> [=<it>needed</it>] in order to avert catastrophe!</vi> <vi>These new problems <it>call for</it> [=<it>require</it>] further investigation.</vi> <vi>His rude behavior was <phrase>not called for</phrase>. [=his behavior was uncalled-for/inappropriate]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to a place to get (someone or something) <vi>I'll <it>call for</it> you (at your house) after dinner.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (a memory, image, etc.) into the mind <vi>These events <it>call forth</it> [=<it>elicit, evoke</it>] strong feelings.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to a place (such as the place where you work) <vi>She <phrase>called in sick</phrase> yesterday. [=she telephoned the place where she works to say that she was sick and would not be coming to work]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to a radio or television program <vi>Thousands of people <it>called in</it> to make a donation.</vi> <vi>Many people have <it>called in</it> (to the show) with questions about the new law.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call-in</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to deliver (something, such as a message) by making a telephone call <vi>He <it>called in</it> an order for pizza.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go in somewhere to make a visit <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I <it>called in on</it> an old friend [=I visited an old friend] while I was in New York on business.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say that something that has been given or sent should be returned <vi>The manufacturer has <it>called in</it> all its defective products.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to demand payment of (a loan) <vi>The bank has <it>called in</it> the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for the help or services of (someone) <vi>They may have to <it>call in</it> a mediator to settle the strike.</vi> <vi>Rescue workers have been <it>called in</it> to help search for survivors.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call into action</dre> <dx>see <dxt>action</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call into question</dre> <vr><vl>also US</vl> <va>call into doubt</va></vr> <def><dt>:to make people doubt something <vi>His report <it>calls into question</it> the earlier reports we had. [=his report makes us feel not certain that the earlier reports were true]</vi> <vi>This news <it>calls</it> her loyalty <it>into question</it>. [=makes people doubt that she is loyal]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call it a day/night</dre> <def><dt>:to stop an activity (such as work) for the remainder of the day or night <vi>We've done enough work for now: let's <it>call it a day</it>.</vi> <vi>It's getting late. I think we should <it>call it a night</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call it quits</dre> <dx>see <dxt>quits</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop doing or planning to do (something) <vi>We had to <it>call off</it> [=<it>cancel</it>] our trip.</vi> <vi>The police have decided to <it>call</it> the investigation <it>off</it>. [=to stop the investigation]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call off (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (someone or something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or tell (a person or animal) to stop attacking, chasing, etc. <vi>The dog was barking and growling at me until its owner <it>called</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask (someone or something) to do something :to say that someone or something should do something <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>The opposition has <it>called on/upon</it> the governor <it>to resign</it>. [=the opposition has said that the governor should resign]</vi> <vi>You may be <it>called upon to do</it> several jobs.</vi> <vi>Universities are <it>called upon to produce</it> trained professionals. [=it is the job of universities to produce trained professionals]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for help from (someone) <vi>Is there anyone you can <it>call on</it> in an emergency?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something, such as a talent or skill) <vi>She had to <it>call on/upon</it> all her reserves of strength and skill to meet the challenge.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for a response from (someone, such as a student) <vi>I was hoping the teacher wouldn't <it>call on</it> me, because I didn't know the answer.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a brief visit to (someone) <vi>I'm planning to <it>call on</it> an old friend after I leave here.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to directly criticize (someone) for (something, such as bad behavior) <vi>He's incredibly rude, but no one ever <it>calls</it> him <it>on</it> it. [=no one ever tells him that he should stop being so rude]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to speak in a loud voice <vi>He <it>called out</it> to passersby for help.</vi> <vi>He <it>called out</it> in his sleep.</vi> :to say (something) in a loud voice <vi>He <it>called out</it> her name in his sleep.</vi> <vi>He <it>called out</it> a cry for help.</vi> :to announce or read (something) in a loud voice <vi><it>call out</it> a number</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call out (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (a group of people, such as soldiers) to come or go somewhere <vi>The governor has <it>called out</it> troops to help control the riot.</vi> <vi>Emergency workers were <it>called out</it> to help with efforts to control the flood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (workers) to go on strike <vi>Factory workers are expected to be <it>called out</it> on strike if a new contract isn't signed by tomorrow.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call (someone) on the carpet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>carpet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call (something) to order</dre> <dx>see <dxt>order</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call the shots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call the tune</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tune</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call to account</dre> <dx>see <dxt>account</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call to mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to make a telephone call to (someone) <vi>I haven't spoken to her in years, but I <it>called</it> her <it>up</it> last night and we talked for hours.</vi> <vi><it>Call</it> me <it>up</it> when you get back from your vacation.</vi> <vi>I <it>called up</it> my doctor and made an appointment.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bring (something, such as a memory) into the mind <vi>The sound of the ocean <it>called up</it> [=<it>brought back</it>] memories of my childhood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring (strength, courage, etc.) from within yourself <vi>He will have to <it>call up</it> all his reserves of strength to meet this challenge.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to get (something) from the memory of a computer and show it on the screen <vi><it>call up</it> an old document for revision</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (someone) to come or appear <vi>The prisoner was <it>called up</it> before a magistrate.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring (an athlete) to a higher league <vi>a minor-league player who is being <it>called up</it> to the major leagues</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to order (soldiers) to come for active military duty <vi><it>call up</it> the reserves</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call your bluff</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bluff</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="call[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">call</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:l</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>calls</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an act of using the telephone :an act of calling someone on the telephone <vi>a phone/telephone <it>call</it></vi> <vi>A local <it>call</it> costs less than a long-distance or an international <it>call</it>.</vi> <vi>If there are any <it>calls</it> for me during the meeting, say that I'll call back later.</vi> <vi>I got a <it>call</it> from my brother last night.</vi> <vi>incoming/outgoing <it>calls</it></vi> <vi>“There's someone on the phone for you, sir.” “Tell them I can't <phrase>take their call</phrase> now [=I can't speak to them on the phone now] but I'll <phrase>return their call</phrase> [=I'll call them back] as soon as I can.”</vi> <vi><phrase>Give me a call</phrase> when you get back from your trip. [=call me when you get back]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>toll call</dxt> <dxt>trunk call</dxt> <dxt>wake-up call</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an act of calling with the voice :a loud cry or shout <vi>He gave a <it>call</it> to passersby for help.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the sound made by an animal or bird <vi>We heard a bird that had a very loud and unusual <it>call</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:an imitation of the sound made by a bird or animal <vi>He's an expert at doing bird <it>calls</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:a device that is used to imitate the sound made by a bird <vi>He has a large collection of duck <it>calls</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:a loud sound or signal made with a musical instrument <vi>a bugle <it>call</it></vi> <vi>the <it>call</it> of a trumpet</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a public request or statement that asks or tells people to do something <vi>The government has issued a <it>call</it> to its supporters to defend it and hopes they will answer/heed its <it>call</it>.</vi> <vi>issue a <it>call</it> = put out a <it>call</it></vi> <vi>The campaigners renewed their <it>calls</it> for reform.</vi> <vi>Their <it>calls</it> have gone unheeded.</vi> <vi>The political party has issued a <phrase>call to action</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clarion call</dxt> <dxt>curtain call</dxt> <tag>call to arms</tag> at <dxt>arm</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a request for something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We get many <it>calls</it> for Christmas stories.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There's <phrase>not much call for</phrase> ice cream at this time of year. [=not many people want ice cream at this time of year]</vi> <vi>There is <phrase>very little call for</phrase> his services during the summer.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a reason for doing something <un>used in negative statements to criticize someone's behavior <vi>There was <phrase>no call for</phrase> your rudeness. = There was <it>no call for</it> you to behave so rudely. [=you were wrong to behave so rudely; your rudeness was uncalled-for]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a brief visit <vi>I made/paid a brief social <it>call</it> on an old friend. = I paid an old friend a brief social <it>call</it>.</vi> <vi>The ship made a <it>call</it> at Newport [=the ship stopped briefly at Newport] before proceeding to New Orleans.</vi> <vi>The doctor was on a <it>call</it> when her patient came to the office.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>house call</dxt> <dxt>port of call</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is called or announced <vi>I flipped a coin, and the <it>call</it> was heads.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:an announcement telling passengers to get on a plane, train, etc., that will be leaving soon <vi>This is the last <it>call</it> for Flight 139, now boarding at Gate 57. = This is the last <it>call</it> for passengers to board Flight 139 at Gate 57.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>last call</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a decision made by an official in a sports contest <vi>The runner was called out at home plate, and the manager came out to argue about the <it>call</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a decision <vi>“Should we stay or go?” “I don't know. It's a tough <it>call</it> (to make).”</vi> <vi>I'll let you make the <it>call</it>.</vi> <vi>“How should we deal with this problem?” “I don't know: <phrase>it's your call</phrase>.” [=you can decide how we should deal with this problem]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close call</dxt> <dxt>judgment call</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the appeal or attraction of something that makes a person want to go somewhere <vi>sailors who cannot resist the <it>call</it> of the open ocean</vi> <vi>He <phrase>heard the call of the wild</phrase>. [=he felt the desire to go out to wild places far away from most people]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call of nature</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that requires a person's attention or effort <un>+ <it>on</it> <vi>There are many <it>calls</it> [=<it>demands</it>] <it>on</it> the time of a busy housewife. [=there are many things that a busy housewife must spend time doing]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at someone's beck and call</dre> <dx>see <dxt>beck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on call</dre> <def><dt>:available to be called when needed :ready to come when needed <vi>a doctor who is <it>on call</it> throughout the day</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="call box"> <hw>call box</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boxes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a telephone that is located on the side of a road and that is used for reporting emergencies</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a public telephone booth</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call forwarding"> <hw>call forwarding</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a service that allows you to have a telephone call sent to a different number</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call girl"> <hw>call girl</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ girls</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a prostitute who arranges to meet with men who call her on the telephone</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call-in"> <hw>call–in</hw> <sound><wav>call_i01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:lˌɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>call–ins</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a radio or television show in which telephone calls from members of the audience are included as part of the broadcast <un>usually used before another noun <vi>a <it>call–in</it> radio show</vi></un> <ca>called also (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>phone-in</cat></ca> <dx>see also <tag>call in</tag> 1b at <dxt>call</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call letters"> <hw>call letters</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <dt>:<sx>call sign</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call number"> <hw>call number</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -bers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a combination of numbers and letters that is used to show where a book is located in a library</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="call of nature"> <hw>call of nature</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the call of nature</dre> <def><sl>humorous</sl> <dt>:the need to use a toilet <vi>He had to leave suddenly to answer/obey <it>the call of nature</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="call sign"> <hw>call sign</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ signs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a combination of letters and numbers that is used to identify someone or something in a radio broadcast</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
