<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="calm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">calm</hw> <sound><wav>calm0001.wav</wav><wav>calm0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:m</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>calm*er</if></in> <in><if>calm*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not angry, upset, excited, etc. <vi>The teacher asked us to remain/stay <it>calm</it> after the fire alarm went off.</vi> <vi>The capital city was <it>calm</it> despite rumors of a possible terrorist attack. [=people in the city behaved in the usual way; there was not a lot of excited or fearful activity in the city]</vi> <vi>Let's try to have a <it>calm</it> discussion about your grades.</vi> <vi>My brother is always <phrase>calm, cool, and collected</phrase>. [=he never gets very upset]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to describe weather that is not windy, stormy, etc. <vi>a <it>calm</it> day</vi> <vi>They're predicting <it>calm</it> winds today.</vi> <vi>a <it>calm</it> sea [=a sea that has no waves or only very small waves]</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>calm*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <gram>more calm*ly; most calm*ly</gram> <utxt><vi>The coach <it>calmly</it> told her players what to do next.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>calm*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>I suddenly had a great feeling of <it>calmness</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="calm[2]"> <hw hindex="2">calm</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:m</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a quiet and peaceful state or condition <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>After two days of violent protests, the mayor appealed/pleaded for <it>calm</it>.</vi> <vi>The <it>calm</it> was broken by another terrorist bombing.</vi> <vi>the <it>calm</it> of a church</vi> <vi>Police tried to <phrase>restore calm</phrase> after the riot.</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>A quiet <it>calm</it> settled over the city.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a peaceful mental or emotional state <un>usually singular <vi>The coach was able to keep his <it>calm</it> during the game.</vi> <vi>Everyone noticed her outward <it>calm</it> at the funeral.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>the calm before the storm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>storm</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="calm[3]"> <hw hindex="3">calm</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:m</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>calms</if></in> <in><if>calmed</if></in> <in><if>calm*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become or to cause (someone) to become less upset, emotional, excited, etc. <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The mayor tried to <it>calm</it> [=<it>quiet, settle</it>] the protesters.</vi> <vi>His words were effective in <it>calming</it> her fears.</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi>The mayor tried to <it>calm down</it> the crowd.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>down</it> <vi>The mayor asked the protesters to <it>calm down</it> so he could speak.</vi> <vi>He needs to <it>calm down</it> enough to tell police about the accident.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become or to cause (something) to become less active, violent, forceful, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The winds <it>calmed</it> overnight.</vi> <un>usually + <it>down</it> <vi>The winds <it>calmed down</it> overnight.</vi> <vi>The dispute over the new factory has finally <it>calmed down</it>.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The medicine helped <it>calm</it> her breathing.</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi>We need to <it>calm</it> the situation <it>down</it> a little.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="storm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">storm</hw> <sound><wav>storm001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstoɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>storms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an occurrence of bad weather in which there is a lot of rain, snow, etc., and often strong winds <vi>The sky got dark and it looked like a <it>storm</it> was coming.</vi> <vi>A <phrase>storm was brewing</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We made it home before the <phrase>storm struck/broke</phrase>. [=before the <it>storm</it> began]</vi> <vi>I went out for a walk and got <phrase>caught in a storm</phrase>. [=I was outside when the storm began]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dust storm</dxt> <dxt>electrical storm</dxt> <dxt>electric storm</dxt> <dxt>firestorm</dxt> <dxt>hailstorm</dxt> <dxt>ice storm</dxt> <dxt>rainstorm</dxt> <dxt>sandstorm</dxt> <dxt>snowstorm</dxt> <dxt>thunderstorm</dxt> <dxt>tropical storm</dxt> <dxt>windstorm</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a sudden occurrence of something in large amounts <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> publicity</vi> <vi>The speaker was greeted with a <it>storm of</it> applause.</vi> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> punches</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>brainstorm</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a situation in which many people are angry, upset, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>His racial comments <phrase>kicked/whipped/stirred up a storm</phrase> in the newspapers. [=newspapers criticized his racial comments very strongly]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> controversy/protest</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>any port in a storm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>port</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a storm in a teacup</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a situation in which people are very angry or upset about something that is not important <vi>The whole controversy turned out to be <it>a storm in a teacup</it>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>a tempest in a teapot</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) by storm</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to quickly become very successful or popular in (a particular place) or among (a particular group) <vi>The writer has <it>taken</it> the literary world <it>by storm</it>.</vi> <vi>The new fashion has <it>taken</it> London <it>by storm</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to attack and capture (a place) suddenly by using a lot of force or a large number of people <vi>The soldiers <it>took</it> the castle <it>by storm</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the calm/lull before the storm</dre> <def><dt>:a period of quiet that comes before a time of activity, excitement, violence, etc. <vi>The college was quiet that morning, but it was <it>the calm before the storm</it>. Thousands of students would arrive later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up a storm</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is being done with a lot of energy or enthusiasm <vi>They danced/sang <it>up a storm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was cooking <it>up a storm</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>weather the storm</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>ride out the storm</va></vr> <def><dt>:to deal with a difficult situation without being harmed or damaged too much <vi>Newspapers have <it>weathered the storm</it> of online information by providing news online themselves.</vi> <vi>It was a difficult time but they managed to <it>ride out the storm</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
