<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="capacity"> <hw highlight="yes">ca*pac*i*ty</hw> <sound><wav>capaci07.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈpæsəti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ca*pac*i*ties</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the ability to hold or contain people or things <un>usually singular <vi>The restaurant has a large seating <it>capacity</it>. [=many people can sit in the restaurant; it has many seats]</vi> <vi>What is the hard drive's storage <it>capacity</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the largest amount or number that can be held or contained <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The nightclub has a 1,000-person <it>capacity</it>.</vi> <vi>a bottle with a <it>capacity</it> of two liters</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The prison has reached <it>capacity</it>. [=the prison is full]</vi> <vi>The auditorium was <phrase>filled to capacity</phrase>. [=was completely full]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the ability to do something :a mental, emotional, or physical ability <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Some species of birds do not have the <it>capacity</it> [=<it>ability</it>] to fly.</vi> <vi>Does he have the <it>capacity</it> to handle this job?</vi> <vi>The disease causes a deterioration of breathing <it>capacity</it>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>the machine's computational <it>capacities</it> [=<it>capabilities</it>]</vi> <un>usually singular <vi>a character with a great <it>capacity</it> for love [=a character who is able to love people very deeply]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a usually official position or job :<sx>role</sx> <vi>He was acting in his <it>capacity</it> as judge.</vi> <vi>She's worked for the company in various <it>capacities</it> over the years. [=she has had various jobs at the company]</vi> <vi>serving in a supervisory <it>capacity</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the amount of something that can be produced or managed by a factory, company, etc. <vi>a plan to double the factory's <it>capacity</it></vi> <vi>We can't hire more people because we lack the training <it>capacity</it>.</vi> <vi>the nation's oil refining <it>capacity</it></vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the largest amount that a factory, company, etc., can produce or manage <vi>The factory is currently running at three-quarter <it>capacity</it>. [=the factory is producing three quarters of what it can produce]</vi> <vi>The airport is not expected to reach <it>capacity</it> [=the highest number of planes it can deal with] for several years.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
