<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="careful"> <hw highlight="yes">care*ful</hw> <sound><wav>carefu01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeɚfəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more care*ful; most care*ful</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:using care <vi>He is a <it>careful</it> driver.</vi> <vi>You can never be too <it>careful</it> about these things.</vi> <vi><it>Be careful</it>! The stove is hot!</vi> <vi>They are very <it>careful</it> with their money. [=they only spend what they can afford]</vi> <vi>She was <it>careful</it> of their feelings.</vi> <vi>The police were <it>careful</it> to leave the room exactly as they found it.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>(be) careful what you wish for</tag> at <dxt>wish</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:made, done, or said with care <vi>Police made a <it>careful</it> examination of the scene.</vi> <vi>We kept <it>careful</it> [=<it>meticulous</it>] records of the project.</vi> <vi>They produced a <it>careful</it> study of the building.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>care*ful*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>He opened the door <it>carefully</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>carefully</it> picked up the vase.</vi> <vi>Drive <it>carefully</it>.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>care*ful*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="wish[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">wish</hw> <sound><wav>wish0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɪʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>wish*es</if></in> <in><if>wished</if></in> <in><if>wish*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to want (something) to be true or to happen <vi>I <it>wish</it> (that) you were here.</vi> <vi>I only <it>wish</it> (that) I knew what was going on.</vi> <vi>He was <it>wishing</it> (that) she would leave him alone.</vi> <vi>I <it>wish</it> (that) you would be quiet and listen to me.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to want or ask to do (something) <vi>You may use the telephone, if you <it>wish</it>.</vi> <vi>You can <phrase>do as you wish</phrase>. [=you can do whatever you want to do]</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Ms. Jones <it>wishes to see</it> you.</vi> <vi>I <it>wish to speak</it> with your supervisor.</vi> <vi>He <it>wished to be</it> left alone.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to want (someone) to be in a particular state <vi>I <it>wish</it> him well. [=I hope that good things happen to him]</vi> <vi>She <it>wished</it> him dead.</vi> <vi>I <it>wish</it> you no harm. [=I don't want to harm you; I don't want you to be harmed]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>well-wisher</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to say that you hope someone will have happiness, health, etc. <vi>I <it>wish</it> you both much happiness. = I <it>wish</it> great happiness for you both. [=I hope that you will both be very happy]</vi> <vi>She <it>wished</it> them a happy New Year.</vi> <vi>We <it>wish</it> you a Merry Christmas.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>wish you luck</phrase>. [=I hope you will have good luck]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to think about something that you want and hope that you will get it or that it will happen in some magical way :to make a wish <vi>Children <it>wished</it> upon a star [=made a wish while looking at a star] in the hopes that their dreams would come true.</vi> <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>She closed her eyes, <it>wished for</it> a pony, and blew out the candles on her birthday cake.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hope for something that usually cannot be had <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>He <it>wished for</it> a second chance.</vi> <vi>We all <it>wish for</it> world peace.</vi> <vi>I couldn't <it>wish for</it> a better friend than you. [=you are the best friend I could have]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>(be) careful what you wish for</dre> <def><dt><un>used to tell people to think before they say that they want something and to suggest that they may not actually want it <vi>You think having twins would be fun? <it>Be careful what you wish for</it>, you may just get it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I wish</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>don't I wish</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you want something to happen but that you know it will probably not happen <vi>“Did he ask you to the dance?” “<it>I wish</it>!” [=I wish he would ask me to the dance but he hasn't]</vi> <vi>“Will you be getting the job?” “<it>Don't I wish</it>!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wish away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>wish (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>wish away (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to stop or go away just by wanting it to stop or go away <vi>You can't just <it>wish</it> your problems <it>away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wish on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>wish (someone or something) on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to want (someone) to have or be affected by (someone or something bad or unpleasant) <vi>I wouldn't <it>wish</it> that terrible illness <it>on</it> anyone. [=I wouldn't want anyone to have that terrible illness]</vi> <vi>I wouldn't <it>wish</it> it <it>on</it> my worst enemy.</vi> <vi>I wouldn't <it>wish</it> that man <it>on</it> any woman.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>you wish</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>don't you wish</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell people in a rude way that it is unlikely that they will get what they want <vi>Give you a kiss? <it>You wish</it>. [=<it>dream on</it>]</vi> <vi>You think she's going to ask you out? <it>Don't you wish</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
