<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="carpet[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">car*pet</hw> <sound><wav>carpet01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑɚpət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>car*pets</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a heavy fabric cover for a floor <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We bought a new <it>carpet</it> for the bedroom.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Which brand of <it>carpet</it> did you choose?</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>rug</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>magic carpet</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thick covering :a thick layer of something <vi>The ground was covered by a <it>carpet</it> of leaves/snow/grass.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>call (someone) on the carpet</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to criticize someone for doing something wrong <vi>He was/got <it>called on the carpet</it> for missing the deadline.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep (something) under the carpet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sweep</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="carpet[2]"> <hw hindex="2">carpet</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑɚpət</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>carpets</if></in> <in><if>carpet*ed</if></in> <in><if>carpet*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to put a carpet on the floor of a room <vi>We decided to <it>carpet</it> the bedroom.</vi> <vi><it>carpet</it> the floor</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cover (something) with a thick layer <vi>Leaves <it>carpeted</it> the lawn. = The lawn was <it>carpeted</it> with leaves.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) for doing something wrong <un>often used as <it>(be) carpeted</it> <vi>He <it>was carpeted</it> for missing the deadline.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>carpeted</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>carpeted</it> room</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="carpet-bomb"> <hw>carpet–bomb</hw> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>carpet–bombs</if></in> <in><if>carpet–bombed</if></in> <in><if>carpet–bomb*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to drop many bombs in order to cause great destruction over (an area) <vi>a city that was <it>carpet-bombed</it> during World War II</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Television viewers are being <it>carpet-bombed</it> with political advertisements as election day approaches.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>carpet–bombing</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>a city destroyed by <it>carpet-bombing</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="carpet slipper"> <hw>carpet slipper</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -pers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:<sx>slipper</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="carpet sweeper"> <hw>carpet sweeper</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a device with a long handle and a rolling brush that is used for cleaning carpets</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="magic carpet"> <hw>magic carpet</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -pets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>in stories</sl> <dt>:a carpet that can carry a person through the air</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="red carpet"> <hw>red carpet</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>roll out the red carpet</dre> <def><dt>:to formally greet or welcome an important guest who has just arrived <vi>The governor <it>rolled out the red carpet</it> for his dinner guests.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>red–carpet</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>a <it>red-carpet</it> welcome</vi> <vi>We got the <phrase>red-carpet treatment</phrase> [=we were treated like very important people] when we arrived.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="call[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">call</hw> <sound><wav>call0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:l</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>calls</if></in> <in><if>called</if></in> <in><if>call*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to speak in a loud voice <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>called</it> to passersby for help.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> up to her husband, who was at the top of the stairs.</vi> <vi>Her husband <it>called</it> back down to her.</vi> <vi>She saw her friends across the street and <it>called</it> over/across to them.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>called</it> her name in his sleep.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call out <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to announce or read (something) in a loud voice <vi><it>call</it> the roll</vi> <vi><it>call</it> (off) a row of figures</vi> <vi>They're <it>calling</it> [=<it>announcing</it>] our flight: it's boarding at gate 57.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call out <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a bird or animal</ssl> <dt>:to make the sound that is usual for a particular type of bird or animal <vi>The birds were <it>calling</it> as the sun rose.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it> once a week to talk to my parents.</vi> <vi>Where are you <it>calling</it> from?</vi> <vi>May I say who's <it>calling</it>?</vi> <vi>Thank you for <it>calling</it>.</vi> <vi>Please <it>call</it> back/again later.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> long-distance.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I try to <it>call</it> my parents at least once a week.</vi> <vi>She <it>called</it> me long-distance.</vi> <vi>I <it>called</it> the office to get some information.</vi> <vi>Please <it>call</it> us back/again later.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>call</it> us—we'll <it>call</it> you.</vi> <vi>In an emergency you should <it>call</it> [=<it>dial</it>] 911.</vi> <vi><it>Call</it> me when you get back from your vacation.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call <dxn>3b (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call in <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call up <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to tell, order, or ask (someone or something) to come <vi>I <it>called</it> the waiter over (to my table) and asked for the check, and then I <it>called</it> him back to order something else.</vi> <vi>My dog comes running when he's <it>called</it>.</vi> <vi>She was <it>called</it> to court to testify.</vi> <vi>He was <it>called</it> to the office for an interview.</vi> <vi>soldiers who have been <it>called</it> to active duty</vi> <vi>He's not home because he was <phrase>called away</phrase> on business.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to tell, order, or ask (someone or something) to come <vi>We had to <it>call</it> an ambulance.</vi> <vi>He <it>called</it> a taxi but it still hasn't come.</vi> <vi>He <it>called</it> a taxi for me. = He <it>called</it> me a taxi.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give a name to (someone or something) <vi>Her parents <it>called</it> [=<it>named</it>] her Katherine after/for her grandmother.</vi> <vi>The immigrants settled along the river and <it>called</it> their new town “Brookhaven.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk to or refer to (someone or something) with a specified name <vi>Her name is Katherine but her friends all <it>call</it> her “Kitty.”</vi> <vi>This part of the city is <it>called</it> “The Old Town.”</vi> <vi>It's important to <it>call</it> things by their right names.</vi> <vi>Human beings belong to a large group of animals <it>called</it> “mammals.”</vi> <vi>The other children <phrase>called him (bad) names</phrase>. [=the other children spoke to him with cruel and insulting words in place of his name]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>name-calling</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to regard or think of (someone or something) in a certain way <vi>Some people say he's a good man, but I <it>call</it> him a fool. [=I consider him to be a fool]</vi> <vi>She went out in the rain without an umbrella? I <it>call</it> that pretty foolish.</vi> <vi>He's not what you would <it>call</it> a generous man. [=he's not a generous man]</vi> <vi>Her sense of humor is what you might <it>call</it> subtle. [=she has a subtle sense of humor]</vi> <vi>(You can) <it>Call</it> me foolish if you like, but I still think people are basically good.</vi> <vi>It costs 99 cents: let's <it>call</it> it an even dollar for simplicity's sake.</vi> <vi>You may not agree with him, but he <phrase>calls them like he sees them</phrase>! [=he states his opinion in an open, honest, and direct way]</vi> <vi>You did me a favor and I did you a favor, so let's <phrase>call it even</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give the order for (something, such as a meeting) <vi><it>call</it> [=<it>convene</it>] a meeting</vi> <vi><it>call</it> an election</vi> <vi>The union has threatened to <it>call</it> a strike against the company.</vi> <vi>The chairman <phrase>called a halt to</phrase> [=<it>stopped</it>] the discussion.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a brief visit <vi>He <it>called</it> to pay his respects.</vi> <vi>We're planning to <it>call</it> [=<it>stop</it>] at a friend's house on the way home.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call at <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call for <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call in <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>call on <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or guess what the result of something will be <vi>Nobody else thought the election would turn out as it did, but he <it>called</it> [=<it>predicted</it>] it exactly right!</vi> <vi>You <it>called</it> it! [=you correctly said what would happen]</vi> <vi><it>call</it> the toss of a coin</vi> <vi>We flipped a coin; he <it>called</it> heads, and heads it was!</vi> <vi>The election is still <phrase>too close to call</phrase>. [=the election is too close to say who will win]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop or cancel (something, such as a baseball game) because of bad conditions <vi>The game was <it>called</it> on account of rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make an official ruling or decision about (something, such as a pitched ball or a player's action) <vi>Only the umpire has the right to <it>call</it> balls and strikes.</vi> <vi>The pitch was <it>called</it> a strike. [=the umpire said that the pitch was a strike]</vi> <vi>The umpire <it>called</it> the runner safe/out.</vi> <vi><it>call</it> a serve in/out</vi> <vi>She was <it>called</it> for being offside. [=the official said that she was offside]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:to say or decide what kind of play will be used <vi>The quarterback <it>called</it> a running play.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>poker</ssl> <dt>:to require (a player) to show a hand by making an equal bet <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it> you.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>call</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>call a spade a spade</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spade</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call at (a place)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to stop at (a place) briefly <vi>The ship <it>called at</it> the port.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to pray or ask God to do something to someone <vi>He <it>called down</it> a blessing/curse on the king. [=he prayed that the king would be blessed/cursed]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say or demand publicly that something is needed or should be done <vi>The opposition has <it>called for</it> an investigation.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>called for</it> [=<it>asked for</it>] calm and restraint.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to indicate that something is needed or should be done <vi>The plan <it>calls for</it> three windows to be added.</vi> <vi>You've won! That <it>calls for</it> a celebration! [=we should celebrate because you've won]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to require or demand (something) as necessary or proper <vi>The job <it>calls for</it> typing skills. [=you must have typing skills to do the job]</vi> <vi>Action is urgently <it>called for</it> [=<it>needed</it>] in order to avert catastrophe!</vi> <vi>These new problems <it>call for</it> [=<it>require</it>] further investigation.</vi> <vi>His rude behavior was <phrase>not called for</phrase>. [=his behavior was uncalled-for/inappropriate]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to a place to get (someone or something) <vi>I'll <it>call for</it> you (at your house) after dinner.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>call forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (a memory, image, etc.) into the mind <vi>These events <it>call forth</it> [=<it>elicit, evoke</it>] strong feelings.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to a place (such as the place where you work) <vi>She <phrase>called in sick</phrase> yesterday. [=she telephoned the place where she works to say that she was sick and would not be coming to work]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a telephone call to a radio or television program <vi>Thousands of people <it>called in</it> to make a donation.</vi> <vi>Many people have <it>called in</it> (to the show) with questions about the new law.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call-in</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to deliver (something, such as a message) by making a telephone call <vi>He <it>called in</it> an order for pizza.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go in somewhere to make a visit <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I <it>called in on</it> an old friend [=I visited an old friend] while I was in New York on business.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say that something that has been given or sent should be returned <vi>The manufacturer has <it>called in</it> all its defective products.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to demand payment of (a loan) <vi>The bank has <it>called in</it> the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call in (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for the help or services of (someone) <vi>They may have to <it>call in</it> a mediator to settle the strike.</vi> <vi>Rescue workers have been <it>called in</it> to help search for survivors.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call into action</dre> <dx>see <dxt>action</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call into question</dre> <vr><vl>also US</vl> <va>call into doubt</va></vr> <def><dt>:to make people doubt something <vi>His report <it>calls into question</it> the earlier reports we had. [=his report makes us feel not certain that the earlier reports were true]</vi> <vi>This news <it>calls</it> her loyalty <it>into question</it>. [=makes people doubt that she is loyal]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call it a day/night</dre> <def><dt>:to stop an activity (such as work) for the remainder of the day or night <vi>We've done enough work for now: let's <it>call it a day</it>.</vi> <vi>It's getting late. I think we should <it>call it a night</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call it quits</dre> <dx>see <dxt>quits</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop doing or planning to do (something) <vi>We had to <it>call off</it> [=<it>cancel</it>] our trip.</vi> <vi>The police have decided to <it>call</it> the investigation <it>off</it>. [=to stop the investigation]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call off (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (someone or something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or tell (a person or animal) to stop attacking, chasing, etc. <vi>The dog was barking and growling at me until its owner <it>called</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask (someone or something) to do something :to say that someone or something should do something <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>The opposition has <it>called on/upon</it> the governor <it>to resign</it>. [=the opposition has said that the governor should resign]</vi> <vi>You may be <it>called upon to do</it> several jobs.</vi> <vi>Universities are <it>called upon to produce</it> trained professionals. [=it is the job of universities to produce trained professionals]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for help from (someone) <vi>Is there anyone you can <it>call on</it> in an emergency?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something, such as a talent or skill) <vi>She had to <it>call on/upon</it> all her reserves of strength and skill to meet the challenge.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for a response from (someone, such as a student) <vi>I was hoping the teacher wouldn't <it>call on</it> me, because I didn't know the answer.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>call on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a brief visit to (someone) <vi>I'm planning to <it>call on</it> an old friend after I leave here.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to directly criticize (someone) for (something, such as bad behavior) <vi>He's incredibly rude, but no one ever <it>calls</it> him <it>on</it> it. [=no one ever tells him that he should stop being so rude]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to speak in a loud voice <vi>He <it>called out</it> to passersby for help.</vi> <vi>He <it>called out</it> in his sleep.</vi> :to say (something) in a loud voice <vi>He <it>called out</it> her name in his sleep.</vi> <vi>He <it>called out</it> a cry for help.</vi> :to announce or read (something) in a loud voice <vi><it>call out</it> a number</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call out (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (a group of people, such as soldiers) to come or go somewhere <vi>The governor has <it>called out</it> troops to help control the riot.</vi> <vi>Emergency workers were <it>called out</it> to help with efforts to control the flood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (workers) to go on strike <vi>Factory workers are expected to be <it>called out</it> on strike if a new contract isn't signed by tomorrow.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call (someone) on the carpet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>carpet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call (something) to order</dre> <dx>see <dxt>order</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call the shots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call the tune</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tune</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call to account</dre> <dx>see <dxt>account</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call to mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to make a telephone call to (someone) <vi>I haven't spoken to her in years, but I <it>called</it> her <it>up</it> last night and we talked for hours.</vi> <vi><it>Call</it> me <it>up</it> when you get back from your vacation.</vi> <vi>I <it>called up</it> my doctor and made an appointment.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bring (something, such as a memory) into the mind <vi>The sound of the ocean <it>called up</it> [=<it>brought back</it>] memories of my childhood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring (strength, courage, etc.) from within yourself <vi>He will have to <it>call up</it> all his reserves of strength to meet this challenge.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to get (something) from the memory of a computer and show it on the screen <vi><it>call up</it> an old document for revision</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>call (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>call up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to order or tell (someone) to come or appear <vi>The prisoner was <it>called up</it> before a magistrate.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring (an athlete) to a higher league <vi>a minor-league player who is being <it>called up</it> to the major leagues</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to order (soldiers) to come for active military duty <vi><it>call up</it> the reserves</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>call-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call your bluff</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bluff</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="roll[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">roll</hw> <sound><wav>roll0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈroʊl</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>rolls</if></in> <in><if>rolled</if></in> <in><if>rol*ling</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move across the ground or another surface by turning over and over <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The children <it>rolled</it> down the hill.</vi> <vi>The ball <it>rolled</it> slowly to a stop.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>rolled</it> the dice.</vi> <vi>He <it>rolled</it> the ball to me. = He <it>rolled</it> me the ball.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to turn over one or more times <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>rolled</it> (over) onto his back.</vi> <vi>The pigs <it>roll</it> (around) in the mud to keep cool.</vi> <vi>The car <it>rolled</it> (over) into the ditch.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Roll</it> the chicken wings in the batter.</vi> <vi>The paramedics <it>rolled</it> him onto the gurney.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <it>rolled</it> his car in the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to move smoothly on wheels <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The car <it>rolled</it> slowly to a stop.</vi> <vi>A police car <it>rolled</it> up next to us.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The children <it>rolled</it> the toy car to each other.</vi> <vi>The patient was <it>rolled</it> into the emergency room.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in a smooth, continuous way <vi>We left the movie theater as the final credits <it>rolled</it>. [=were moving across the screen]</vi> <vi>The fog soon <it>rolled</it> away.</vi> <vi>The clouds <it>rolled</it> past.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to form (something) into the shape of a ball or tube <vi>She <it>rolled</it> the dough into a ball.</vi> <vi>He <it>rolled</it> up the newspaper and swatted the fly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put (something) inside a tube <vi>He <it>rolled</it> the coins.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to wrap up (something or someone) in a way that forms the shape of a tube <vi>He <it>rolls</it> his own cigarettes.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She <it>rolled up</it> the meat in a tortilla.</vi> <vi>He lay there snugly <it>rolled up</it> in blankets.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to form your body into a ball <un>usually + <it>up</it></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He lay down on the bed and <it>rolled</it> [=<it>curled</it>] <it>up</it> (into a ball).</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <phrase>rolled himself up</phrase> (into a ball).</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) smooth, even, or flat with a special tool (called a roller or rolling pin) <vi>She <it>rolled</it> (out) the dough.</vi> <vi>He <it>rolled</it> the clay flat.</vi> <vi><it>rolled</it> steel/oats</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to spread (something) <it>on</it> a surface with a special tool (called a roller) <vi>She <it>rolled</it> the paint <it>on</it> (the wall).</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move forward along the normal course of time <vi>The days <it>rolled</it> [=<it>passed</it>] quickly by.</vi> <vi>It got hotter as the day <it>rolled</it> on/along.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or lean from side to side <vi>The ship heaved and <it>rolled</it> in the storm.</vi> <vi>He walked with a <it>rolling</it> gait.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make a deep, continuous sound <vi>Thunder <it>rolled</it> in the distance.</vi> <vi><it>rolling</it> thunder</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a continuous, quick, beating sound <vi>The drums <it>rolled</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:to operate (something, such as a movie camera) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Roll</it> the cameras when I say “action.”</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The camera was not <it>rolling</it> [=<it>filming</it>] at the time.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a series of successes <vi>The team <it>rolled</it> through the play-offs.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:to cause (your eyes) to look up toward the sky in an expression which shows that you think someone or something is foolish or annoying <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <phrase>rolled his eyes</phrase> at her suggestion.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Her eyes <it>rolled</it> when he told her his idea.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get rolling</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave <vi>We ought to <it>get rolling</it> if we don't want to be late.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You should <it>get rolling</it> on that assignment.</vi> <vi>The project finally <it>got rolling</it>. [=got started]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get/set/start the ball rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>heads roll</dre> <dx>see <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep the ball rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>let's roll</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell another person or a group of people to start leaving a place or to start doing something <vi>“<it>Let's roll</it>,” the sergeant shouted to his men.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ready to roll</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:ready to leave <vi>I am all packed and <it>ready to roll</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:ready to start doing something <vi>After we got the loan approved, we were <it>ready to roll</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll around</dre> <vr><vl>also Brit</vl> <va>roll about</va></vr> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to arrive or happen again <vi>By the time Friday <it>rolls around</it>, I'm ready for the weekend.</vi> <vi>We'll be better prepared the next time the elections <it>roll around</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>roll back (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>roll (something) back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to reduce (something, such as a price) <vi>The store is <it>rolling back</it> its prices for this weekend only.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change (something) back to the way it was at an earlier time :to reverse or undo (something) <vi>The manufacturers are lobbying to <it>roll back</it> [=<it>rescind</it>] environmental regulations.</vi> <vi>His proposal would <phrase>roll back the clock</phrase> on civil rights.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>roll down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>roll (something) down</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move (something) down especially by turning a handle <vi>She <it>rolled down</it> the car window.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to unfold the edge of (something, such as a shirt sleeve or pants leg) to make it longer <vi>He <it>rolled down</it> his sleeves.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rolled into one</dre> <def><dt>:combined together into one thing or person <vi>It's a shopping center, amusement park, and nightclub (all) <it>rolled into one</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>be rolling in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have a large amount of (something) <vi>They <it>were rolling in</it> money/cash. = They <phrase>were rolling in (the) dough</phrase>. = They <phrase>were rolling in it</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to appear or arrive in large numbers or amounts <vi>The money has been <it>rolling in</it>.</vi> <vi>Donations <it>rolled in</it> to help the hurricane victims.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place especially later than usual or expected <vi>Delegates <it>rolled in</it> from all parts of the country.</vi> <vi>He finally <it>rolled in</it> at 3:30 in the morning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rolling in the aisles</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aisle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roll off the tongue</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tongue</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roll on</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you want a time or event to come quickly <vi><it>Roll on</it> Friday. I can't wait for the weekend!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>roll out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>roll (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to offer or sell (something) for the first time <vi>The company is expected to <it>roll out</it> [=<it>launch</it>] several new products next year.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rollout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (something that has been rolled into the shape of a tube) long and flat again <vi>He <it>rolled out</it> [=<it>unrolled</it>] the sleeping bags.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll out of bed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to rise after sleeping in a bed and especially after sleeping later than usual <vi>She <it>rolled out of bed</it> just before noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll out the red carpet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>red carpet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roll over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to allow yourself to be easily defeated or controlled :to make no effort to fight or compete <vi>I'm not going to just <it>roll over</it> and let them do what they want.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>roll over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>roll (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to delay the payment of (something, such as a debt) <vi>He wanted to <it>roll over</it> the repayment of the loan until later.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to place (invested money) in a new investment of the same kind <vi>She <it>rolled over</it> her investments from one fund to another.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rollover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll the dice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roll up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>roll up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>roll (something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move (something) up especially by turning a handle <vi>She <it>rolled up</it> the car window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to fold up the ends of (something, such as a shirt sleeve or pants leg) to make it shorter <vi>She <it>rolled up</it> her jeans and stepped into the water.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to arrive at a place in a vehicle <vi>Celebrities <it>rolled up</it> in their limousines.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt><un>used to invite people to gather around to see a show or to buy things <vi><it>Roll up, roll up</it> [=(<it>chiefly US</it>) <it>step right up</it>]—you won't find cheaper watches anywhere else!</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>roll <dxn>4c, 5 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll up your sleeves</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to prepare to work hard <vi>It's time to <it>roll up our sleeves</it> and get the job done.</vi> <vi>Congress needs to <it>roll up its sleeves</it> and pass the bill now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll with the punches</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to not allow yourself to become upset by things that happen <vi><it>Roll with the punches</it> and don't let life get you down!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>roll your r's</dre> <def><dt>:to pronounce the sound /r/ with a trill <vi>He <it>rolls his r's</it> when he speaks Spanish.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="sweep[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">sweep</hw> <sound><wav>sweep001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈswi:p</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>sweeps</if></in> <in><if>swept</if> <sound><wav>sweep002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈswɛpt</pr></in> <in><if>sweep*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (something, such as dust or dirt) from a surface with a broom or brush or with a quick movement of your hand, fingers, etc. <vi>He <it>swept</it> the dirt off the driveway.</vi> <vi>He <it>swept</it> the crumbs from the table.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove dust, dirt, etc., from (something) with a broom or brush <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>swept</it> the floor.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>sweep</it> the kitchen.</vi> <vi>Are you finished <it>sweeping</it> the porch?</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Have you <it>swept</it> yet?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sweep out <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>sweep up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or pass quickly, forcefully, or smoothly <vi>A storm <it>swept</it> across the plains.</vi> <vi>Fires <it>swept</it> through the forest.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She <phrase>swept to victory</phrase> on a wave of popularity.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or walk in a smooth, quick, and impressive way <vi>She proudly <it>swept</it> into the room.</vi> <vi>The limo <it>swept</it> up to the door.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to push or move (something) quickly or forcefully <vi>He <it>swept</it> the curtains aside.</vi> <vi>She <it>swept</it> the books off the desk.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to push, carry, or lift (someone or something) with great force <vi>The debris was <it>swept</it> [=<it>carried</it>] out to sea by the tide.</vi> <vi>She was <it>swept</it> toward the door by the crowd.</vi> <vi>He <it>swept</it> her into his arms.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We were <it>swept</it> along/away by her enthusiasm.</vi> <vi>The party was <phrase>swept into power</phrase> in the last election.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a feeling or emotion</ssl> <dt>:to be felt suddenly <vi>Fear <it>swept</it> over/through her. [=she suddenly felt afraid]</vi> <vi>A feeling of relief <it>swept</it> over him.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (your hand, arm, etc.) in a wide, curving motion <vi>He <it>swept</it> his arm across the table.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to pass over (all of an area or place) in a continuous motion <vi>The teacher's gaze <it>swept</it> the classroom.</vi> <vi>A searchlight <it>swept</it> the area.</vi> <vi>Strong winds <it>sweep</it> the mountainside.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become very popular or common suddenly in (a particular place) <vi>It's the latest craze <it>sweeping</it> the nation.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to win everything that can be won in (something, such as an election) in an easy or impressive way <vi>The opposition party <it>swept</it> the election.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to win all of the games in a series of games against another team <vi>They <it>swept</it> their rivals in a three-game series.</vi> <vi>They <it>swept</it> the series/doubleheader.</vi> <vi>They were <it>swept</it> in the play-offs last year.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to brush or pull (your hair) away from your face <vi>She <it>swept</it> her hair up/back and clipped it in place.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to form a long, smooth curve <vi>The property <it>sweeps</it> down to the water's edge.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>sweep aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>sweep (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to treat (something) as not important :to ignore (something) <vi>He <it>swept aside</it> [=<it>brushed aside</it>] questions about his son's arrest.</vi> <vi>He <it>swept aside</it> [=<it>dismissed</it>] their objections, refusing to change his plans.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>sweep (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep away (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to destroy or remove (something) completely <vi>Floods <it>swept away</it> several houses.</vi> <vi>an ancient civilization <it>swept away</it> by war</vi> <vi>His performance today <it>swept away</it> any doubts about his ability to play.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>sweep (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove dust, dirt, etc., from (something) by using a broom or brush <vi>Please <it>sweep out</it> the room when you're done working.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep (someone) off his/her feet</dre> <def><dt>:to make (someone) suddenly become very attracted to you in a romantic way <vi>She says that he <it>swept</it> her <it>off her feet</it>, and they were married six months later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep (something) under the rug</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>sweep (something) under the carpet</va></vr> <def><dt>:to hide (something that is illegal, embarrassing, or wrong) <vi>He tried to <it>sweep</it> his past mistakes <it>under the rug</it>.</vi> <vi>This is not something we can just <it>sweep under the rug</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep the board</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to win everything that can be won in a competition <vi>She <it>swept the board</it> at the awards ceremony.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>sweep up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove dust, dirt, etc., from (something) by using a broom or brush <vi>When I was <it>sweeping up</it>, I found an earring that I had lost.</vi> <vi>Can you please <it>sweep up</it> the porch?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>sweep (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something, such as dust, dirt, etc.) from a surface by using a broom or brush <vi>She <it>swept up</it> the broken glass.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>sweep (someone or something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>sweep up (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pick up (someone or something) in one quick, continuous motion <vi>She <it>swept</it> the baby <it>up</it> and carried her to the crib.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
