<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="catch[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">catch</hw> <sound><wav>catch001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃ, ˈkɛtʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>catch*es</if></in> <in><if>caught</if> <sound><wav>catch002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>catch*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use your hands to stop and hold (an object that is moving through the air) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Catch</it> the ball and throw it to first base.</vi> <vi>She <it>caught</it> the ball with one hand.</vi> <vi>I dropped the book but managed to <it>catch</it> it before it hit the ground.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll throw you the keys. Ready? <it>Catch</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use your hands to grasp and hold onto (someone or something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>, <it>seized</it>] her by the wrist.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>caught hold of</phrase> her wrist.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to capture and not allow (a person, animal, or fish) to escape <vi>The police are working hard to <it>catch</it> the criminals and put them in jail.</vi> <vi>“I bet you can't <it>catch</it> me!” she yelled to her brother.</vi> <vi>I once <it>caught</it> 10 fish in a single day.</vi> <vi>In the summer, we would <it>catch</it> fireflies and put them in jars.</vi> <vi><it>catching</it> mice in traps</vi> <vi>lions <it>catching</it> their prey</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage to find, meet, or reach (someone) at a particular time or in a particular state or condition <vi>I <it>caught</it> her just as she was leaving for work.</vi> <vi>I'm afraid you've <it>caught</it> me at a bad time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find (someone who is doing something wrong) <vi>The police <it>caught</it> him trying to steal the painting.</vi> <vi>My teacher <it>caught</it> me cheating on a test.</vi> <vi>Her father <it>caught</it> her smoking in the basement.</vi> <vi>You'd never <it>catch</it> me doing that! [=I would never do that]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>caught him in the act</phrase> (of stealing the painting). = He was <phrase>caught red-handed</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to affect (someone) in a sudden and surprising way <vi>They were <phrase>caught unprepared</phrase> by the crisis. = The crisis <phrase>caught them unawares</phrase>. [=they were not prepared when the crisis occurred]</vi> <vi>The announcement <phrase>caught me by surprise</phrase>. [=I was surprised by the announcement]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to suddenly stop (yourself) before you do something <vi>Luckily, he <it>caught</it> himself before he gave away the secret.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suddenly become aware that you are doing something <vi>He <it>caught</it> himself staring at her.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be stopped, delayed, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be/get) caught</it> <vi>We <it>got caught</it> in a rain storm and had to find shelter.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I'm late. I <it>was caught</it> in traffic.</vi> <vi>We <phrase>got caught up in</phrase> traffic and were late for our flight.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>caught up in <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to become stuck and unable to move <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>caught</it> my sleeve on a nail.</vi> <vi>The kite got <it>caught</it> [=<it>tangled</it>] in the tree.</vi> <vi>She tried to stand up, but her foot was <it>caught</it> in the strap.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My sleeve <it>caught</it> on a nail.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the parts connect firmly <vi>I tried to lock the door, but the lock wouldn't <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop and hold (falling water) <vi>They kept a bucket outside to <it>catch</it> the rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become covered with (something that moves through the air) <vi>These curtains <it>catch</it> a lot of dust.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hit or touch (someone or something) <vi>The bullet <it>caught</it> him in the leg.</vi> <vi>His last punch <it>caught</it> me in the jaw.</vi> <vi>Isn't it beautiful the way the setting sun <it>catches</it> the tips of the trees?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be hit or touched by (something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> a bullet in the leg.</vi> <vi>The tips of the trees <it>catch</it> the light as the sun sets.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become affected with (a sickness or disease) <vi>We both <it>caught</it> [=<it>contracted</it>] the flu.</vi> <vi>I seem to <it>catch</it> a cold every winter.</vi> <vi>children <it>catching</it> colds from each other</vi> <snote>When people say that you will <phrase>catch your death (of cold)</phrase>, they mean that you will become sick or catch a very bad cold. <vi>It's freezing! You'll <it>catch your death</it> if you go out without a coat!</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to feel excitement or interest about something <vi>I haven't <it>caught</it> the holiday spirit yet this year.</vi> <vi>People are getting really interested in the sport. The whole country is starting to <phrase>catch the fever</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to attract and hold (someone's attention, interest, etc.) <vi>I tried to <it>catch</it> the waiter's attention, but I guess he didn't see me.</vi> <vi>The show is more likely to <it>catch</it> the interest of an older audience.</vi> <vi>Her books have <phrase>caught the imagination</phrase> of children from around the world. [=children find her books very exciting and enjoyable]</vi> <snote>If someone or something <phrase>catches your eye</phrase>, you notice that person or thing. <vi>There was one dress in particular that <it>caught my eye</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>eye-catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see, smell, or notice (something) <vi>I <it>caught</it> [=<it>got</it>] a faint whiff of her perfume.</vi> <vi>While you're in Hollywood, you might <phrase>catch a glimpse</phrase> of some movie stars.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>caught sight</phrase> of his red shirt and started calling to him.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to hear or understand (something) <vi>What was that again? I didn't quite <it>catch</it> [=<it>hear, get</it>] what you said.</vi> <vi>I didn't <it>catch</it> your name.</vi> <vi>Do you <phrase>catch my drift</phrase>? [=do you understand what I mean?]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become aware of (something, such as an illness) <vi>The disease is curable if <it>caught</it> [=<it>detected</it>] early.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or do (something) <vi>You can <it>catch</it> [=<it>take</it>] a quick nap on the train.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get (something) through effort <vi>I managed to <it>catch</it> [=<it>get</it>] a ride into town with some friends.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>“See you soon.” “Yup. <phrase>Catch you later</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move fast enough to be next to or in front of (someone) <vi>She <it>caught</it> [=<it>overtook</it>] the leader in the final meters of the race.</vi> <vi>He left before I did so I had to hurry to <it>catch</it> him. [=to catch up with him]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get on a bus, train, etc., before it leaves <vi>If you miss the first bus, you can <it>catch</it> the next one in 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>If you'll excuse me, I have a plane to <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see or hear (a show, game, etc.) <vi>I only <it>caught</it> the last few minutes of the game.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>catch</it> the show on Channel 4 last night?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to describe or show (someone or something) in an accurate way in art <vi>The new portrait <it>catches</it> her likeness perfectly.</vi> <vi>The novel successfully <it>catches</it> the atmosphere of 19th-century Paris.</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to play the position of catcher <vi>He <it>catches</it> for the New York Yankees.</vi> <vi>If you pitch, I'll <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>catch at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach for and try to hold (something) <vi>The baby <it>caught at</it> my dress as I walked past.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch fire</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or US</vl> <va>catch on fire</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to burn <vi>Newspaper <it>catches fire</it> [=<it>ignites</it>] easily.</vi> <vi>Their house <it>caught fire</it> and burned to the ground.</vi> <vi>Don't leave the towel on the stove. It could <it>catch fire</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become very popular or effective <vi>The idea failed to <it>catch fire</it>.</vi> <vi>The singer hasn't <it>caught fire</it> in this country yet.</vi> <vi>a new technology that has <it>caught fire</it> with the public</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch hell</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch it</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be punished or scolded <vi>He's really going to <it>catch it</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>catch hell</it>] (from his boss) if he comes in late again!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become popular <vi>This trend is <it>catching on</it> with/among college students.</vi> <vi>Soccer is finally starting to <it>catch on</it> in America.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn or understand something <vi>Once you start playing the game, the kids will <it>catch on</it> pretty quickly.</vi> <vi>It took her a while to <it>catch on</it>, but she eventually got the joke.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to show that (someone) does not know something or is doing something bad <vi>She loved <it>catching</it> teachers <it>out</it> by asking tough questions.</vi> <vi>The police tried to <it>catch</it> him <it>out</it> in a lie.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch (someone) dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move fast enough to join someone or something that is in front of you <vi>They went so fast we couldn't <it>catch up</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>Slow down so that I can <it>catch up with</it> you.</vi> <vi>She ran as fast as she could, but she couldn't <it>catch up with</it> her brother. = (<it>US</it>) She couldn't <it>catch up to</it> him.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>In order to <it>catch up with</it> its competitors in the industry, the company will need to start using more advanced technologies.</vi> <vi>She missed several months of school and may never <it>catch up with</it> the other children in her class. = (<it>US</it>) She may never <it>catch up to</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn about recent events <vi>We haven't seen each other in such a long time; we've got lots of <it>catching up</it> to do!</vi> <vi><it>catching up</it> with old friends</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He reads the newspaper on Sunday mornings to <it>catch up on</it> the news.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something) that you could have done earlier <vi>She has to <it>catch up on</it> her homework.</vi> <vi>I hope to <it>catch up on</it> some much-needed sleep this weekend.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to join someone who is ahead of you <vi>He was ahead of me for most of the race, but I <it>caught him up</it> [=I caught up with him] at the end.</vi> <vi>Go on ahead: I'll <it>catch you up</it> later.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to begin to affect (someone) usually in a bad way <vi>All those late nights are really starting to <it>catch up with</it> me!</vi> <vi>Old age <it>catches up with</it> everyone in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find and arrest (someone) <vi>The police eventually <it>caught up with</it> him in Texas.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>I've got to go. I'll <it>catch up with</it> you later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught in the middle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>middle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught short</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not having enough of something <vi>Don't be <it>caught short</it>! Make sure you stock up on supplies before you set out on your trip.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:having a sudden urge to use the toilet</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>caught up in</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:involved in (a difficult or confusing situation) <vi>Several members of Congress were <it>caught up in</it> the scandal.</vi> <vi>How did you get <it>caught up in</it> this mess?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>catch <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:excited about something and having trouble thinking about anything else <vi>Everyone was <it>caught up in</it> the excitement.</vi> <vi>Try not to get too <it>caught up in</it> the moment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>catch*able</ure> <sound><wav>catch003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃəbəl, ˈkɛtʃəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>catchable</it> ball</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="catch[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">catch</hw> <altpr>ˈkætʃ, ˈkɛtʃ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>catch*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a hidden problem that makes something more complicated or difficult to do <un>usually singular <vi>The phone only costs $20, but there's a <it>catch</it>: you have to sign a two-year contract with the phone company.</vi> <vi>He said he would let me borrow his car, but I knew there had to be a <it>catch</it>.</vi> <vi>What's/Where's the <it>catch</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of stopping a moving object (such as a ball) and holding it in your hands :the act of catching something <vi>Great <it>catch</it>!</vi> <vi>The shortstop made a tough <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a game in which two or more people throw and catch a ball <vi>She used to play <it>catch</it> with her dad.</vi> <vi>Let's play a game of <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an amount of fish that has been caught <vi>a <it>catch</it> of about 20 fish</vi> <vi>She ordered the <phrase>catch of the day</phrase>. [=the fish offered on a particular day at a restaurant]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a person who would be very desirable as a husband or wife <vi>He was an excellent <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that holds an object or stops the parts of an object from moving <vi>She fastened the <it>catch</it> on her purse.</vi> <vi>The <it>catch</it> on my grandmother's pin broke.</vi> <vi>a safety <it>catch</it> on a gun</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a short, sharp change or stop in a person's voice or breath while speaking <vi>I could hear the <it>catch</it> in his voice when he said his dead wife's name.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="caught"> <hw>caught</hw> <cx><cl>past tense and past participle of</cl> <ct>catch</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="catch-22"> <hw>catch–22</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>Catch–22</va> <sound><wav>catch_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃˌtwɛntiˈtu:, ˈkɛtʃˌtwɛntiˈtu:</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>catch–22's</if> <il>or</il> <if>catch–22s</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a difficult situation for which there is no easy or possible solution <vi>I'm in a <it>catch-22</it>: to get the job I need experience, but how do I get experience if I can't get the job?</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>catch-22</it> dilemma/situation</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="catch-up"> <hw>catch–up</hw> <sound><wav>catch_02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃˌʌp, ˈkɛtʃˌʌp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>play catch-up</dre> <def><dt>:to try to reach the same position, score, etc., as a competitor after you have fallen behind <vi>The team fell behind in the second inning and has had to <it>play catch-up</it> ever since.</vi> <vi>The company has been trying to <it>play</it> a difficult game of <it>catch-up</it> ever since its competitor introduced the new product.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>catch up</tag> at <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="shoestring catch"> <hw>shoestring catch</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ catches</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:a catch made when the ball is just above the ground <vi>The left fielder made a <it>shoestring catch</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tle</hw> <sound><wav>bottle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*tles</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a glass or plastic container that has a narrow neck and usually has no handle <snote>Bottles are usually used to store liquid or tablets. <vi>Shall I open another <it>bottle</it> of wine?</vi> <vi>There's a <it>bottle</it> of aspirin in the cabinet.</vi> <vi>empty soda <it>bottles</it></vi> <vi>She kept a <it>bottle</it> [=a bottle of some strong alcoholic drink like whiskey] tucked away in the coat closet.</vi> <vi>Be sure to bring a <phrase>water bottle</phrase> [=bottle containing water] on your hike.</vi> <vi>Would you get me the <phrase>bottle opener</phrase> [=a tool used to remove metal tops from some bottles], please?</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount contained in a bottle <vi>We drank a <it>bottle</it> of wine.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the bottle</bnote> <dt>:alcoholic drink <vi>He says he's lost too many years to <it>the bottle</it>, and that he's giving up alcohol.</vi> <vi>Her struggles with <it>the bottle</it> affected her entire family.</vi> <vi>I hear he's <phrase>(gone) off the bottle</phrase>. [=stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>After his divorce he <phrase>took to the bottle</phrase>. [=began to drink a lot of alcohol]</vi> <vi>When she gets depressed she <phrase>hits the bottle</phrase>. [=begins drinking a lot of alcohol]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a special bottle for feeding babies that contains milk or a drink which contains milk <vi>Has the baby finished her <it>bottle</it> yet?</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) a baby <it>bottle</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a baby's <it>bottle</it></vi> <vi>raised on a <it>bottle</it> instead of breast milk</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottle-feed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:courage or strength of spirit <vi>I don't think he's got <it>bottle</it> [=<it>guts</it>] enough to confront them.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring your own bottle</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bring a bottle</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to tell the people who are invited to a party that they should bring their own alcoholic drinks</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch/capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tle*ful</ure> <sound><wav>bottle02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟ˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>singular</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bottleful</it> of water</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="dead[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dead</hw> <sound><wav>dead0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer alive or living :no longer having life <vi>Her husband is <it>dead</it>. He died last year.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>dead</it> for over 10 years now. [=she died more than 10 years ago]</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> insect/bird/dog</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> trees/leaves/skin</vi> <vi>the <it>dead</it> [=<it>lifeless</it>] bodies of the soldiers</vi> <vi>He was found <it>dead</it> in his apartment yesterday.</vi> <vi>He lay <it>dead</it> on the floor.</vi> <vi>The lost mountain climbers were believed/presumed <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>She shot him <it>dead</it>. [=she killed him by shooting him]</vi> <vi>When we found her, she was <phrase>more dead than alive</phrase>. [=almost dead; very close to death]</vi> <vi>The poster said that the robbers were wanted <phrase>dead or alive</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>as good as dead</phrase>. [=he was almost dead]</vi> <vi>She taught her dog to <phrase>play dead</phrase>. [=to lie on its back and pretend to be dead]</vi> <usageref>deceased</usageref> <snote>To <phrase>leave (someone or something) for dead</phrase> is to leave a person or animal that you know will probably die instead of trying to help. <vi>They hit the dog with their car and <it>left it for dead</it> on the side of the road.</vi> <vi>He had been badly beaten and <it>left for dead</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sin><if>dead*er</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:not able to feel or move <vi>My hand was <it>dead</it> [=<it>numb</it>] after holding the bag for so long.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very tired <vi>Our legs were completely <it>dead</it> after hiking all day.</vi> <vi>I arrived home from work <phrase>half dead</phrase>. [=<it>exhausted</it>]</vi> <vi>By the end of the day the workers were <phrase>dead on their feet</phrase>. [=very tired but still standing, working, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:feeling no emotions <vi>After the war, I was emotionally <it>dead</it>. [=I was no longer able to feel happiness, sadness, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:certain to be punished or hurt <vi>I'm <it>dead</it> if I come in late for work again.</vi> <vi>If I ever get my hands on you, you're <it>dead</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a machine or device</ssl> <dt>:no longer working especially because of not having electricity <vi>The car's battery is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> electrical outlets</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> telephone line</vi> <vi>The phones <phrase>went dead</phrase> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:no longer active or operating <vi>a <it>dead</it> [=<it>extinct</it>] volcano</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> companies</vi> <vi>That plan is <it>dead</it> for now. We've started developing a new one.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> deal</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:naturally not living <vi>rocks and other <it>dead</it> [=<it>inanimate</it>] matter</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sin><if>deader</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:lacking in activity or excitement <vi>The store's been <it>dead</it> [=<it>quiet</it>] all day.</vi> <vi>This party's completely <it>dead</it>. [=it is not lively]</vi> <vi>The audience was kind of <it>dead</it> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a time when nothing is being said or done <vi>We played cards to fill in the <it>dead</it> time between the two performances.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:no longer performed or enjoyed <vi>He says that disco is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> art form</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>of a language</ssl> <dt>:no longer spoken <vi>Latin is a <it>dead</it> language.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe a situation in which play stops during a game <vi>In American football, the ball is <it>dead</it> [=<it>out of play</it>] after an incomplete forward pass.</vi> <vi>The ball is <it>dead</it> if it goes beyond the white line.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <dt>:complete, total, or absolute <vi>There was <it>dead</it> silence in the room.</vi> <vi>She spoke with <it>dead</it> certainty.</vi> <vi>I chased them at a <it>dead</it> run for three miles.</vi> <vi>The camera is a <phrase>dead giveaway</phrase> [=clearly shows] that you're a tourist.</vi> <vi>She fell to the floor in a <phrase>dead faint</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The evening wasn't all I had hoped for, but is wasn't a <phrase>dead loss</phrase>. [=it wasn't completely bad]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>a dead ringer for</phrase> [=he looks exactly like] his father.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) They're <phrase>a dead cert</phrase> [=<it>a sure thing, a sure bet</it>] to win. [=they are certain to win]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:sudden and complete <vi>The bus came to a <it>dead</it> [=<it>abrupt</it>] stop.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:perfect or exact <vi>Her arrow hit the <it>dead</it> [=<it>very</it>] center of the target.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) dead as a doornail</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) dead as a dodo</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to stress that someone or something is dead <vi>The old captain was <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The negotiations are <it>as dead as a doornail</it>.</vi> <vi>The deal is <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat a dead horse</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>flog a dead horse</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch/see (someone) dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that people <phrase>wouldn't/won't catch/see you dead</phrase> or that you <phrase>wouldn't/won't be caught/seen dead</phrase> doing something, you refuse to let others see you doing it because it would cause you to be embarrassed. <vi>I <it>wouldn't be caught/seen dead</it> wearing that hideous outfit.</vi> <vi>She <it>won't be caught dead</it> going to the movies with her obnoxious brother.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead and buried</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>dead and gone</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer living :<sx>dead</sx> <vi>He's been <it>dead and buried</it> for 50 years.</vi> <vi>relatives long <it>dead and gone</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:no longer used or accepted <vi>Those old family traditions are <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>That idea is <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>The days of our childhood are <it>dead and gone</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead from the neck up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very stupid or foolish <vi>Most of his friends are <it>dead from the neck up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead in the water</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not making any progress :not having any chance of success <vi>The peace talks were <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi> <vi>His election campaign is <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead men tell no tales</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tale</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead on arrival</dre> <def><dt>:having died before getting to a hospital, emergency room, etc. <vi>The victim was <it>dead on arrival</it> at the hospital.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Some are saying that any new tax proposal would be <it>dead on arrival</it>. [=would have no chances of being approved]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead to rights</dre> <dx>see <dxt>right</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead to the world</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:sleeping very deeply <vi>You can't wake him up. He's <it>dead to the world</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall to the ground and die very suddenly <vi>She <it>dropped dead</it> while playing basketball.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used as a rude way to tell someone to leave you alone <vi>“He asked you for help after being such a jerk? You should have told him to <it>drop dead</it>!”</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>drop-dead</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>over my dead body</dre> <dx>see <dxt>body</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>dead*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="death"> <hw highlight="yes">death</hw> <sound><wav>death001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>deaths</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the end of life :the time when someone or something dies <vi>birth, life, and eventual <it>death</it></vi> <vi>fear of <it>death</it></vi> <vi>She is close to <it>death</it>. [=she will die soon]</vi> <vi><it>death</it> threats</vi> <vi>The hostage managed to <phrase>escape death</phrase>. [=avoid being killed]</vi> <vi>The newspaper did not report the <phrase>cause of death</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She was convicted of murder and <phrase>sentenced/condemned to death</phrase>. [=told that she would be killed as punishment]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>brain death</dxt> <tag>death knell</tag> at <dxt>knell</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the ending of a particular person's life <vi>People around the world mourned his <it>death</it>.</vi> <vi>She worked at the newspaper until her <it>death</it> at (age) 74.</vi> <vi>The accident resulted in two <it>deaths</it>.</vi> <vi>The number of <it>deaths</it> from cancer is rising.</vi> <vi>He died a violent/tragic <it>death</it>.</vi> <vi>There has been <phrase>a death in the family</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She survived the plane crash and many years later died <phrase>a natural death</phrase>. [=from natural causes; because she was old]</vi> <vi>The general <phrase>met his death</phrase> on the battlefield.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the permanent end of something that is not alive :the ruin or destruction of something <vi>the <it>death</it> of innocence</vi> <vi>the <it>death</it> of vaudeville</vi> <vi>the <it>death</it> of a marriage</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>Death</bnote> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:the force that ends life and is often shown in art or literature as a skeleton <vi><it>Death</it> could be seen lurking in the corner of the painting.</vi> <vi>when <it>Death</it> comes to take me away</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a matter of life and death</dre> <dx>see <dxt>life</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at death's door</dre> <def><dt>:about to die :very sick and in danger of dying <vi>He is sick, but he's not <it>at death's door</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be the death of</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (someone) to die <vi>I worry that his drug addiction will <it>be the death of</it> him.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Those kids <phrase>will be the death of</phrase> me! [=they worry and upset me very much]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your death (of cold)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like death warmed over</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>like death warmed up</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very tired or sick <vi>We worked through the night, and by morning we looked <it>like death warmed over</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put to death</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person or animal that is <it>put to death</it> is killed at a scheduled time by someone who is legally allowed to do so. <vi>a serial killer who was <it>put to death</it> [=<it>executed</it>] for the murder of 28 people</vi> <vi>The dog that attacked the children was later <it>put to death</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to death</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say how someone died or was killed <vi>He was shot/stabbed <it>to death</it>.</vi> <vi>They froze/starved <it>to death</it>.</vi> <vi>She drank herself <it>to death</it>. [=drank a lot of alcohol until it made her so sick that she died]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:very much :to a great degree <vi>We were bored/scared <it>to death</it>. [=extremely bored/scared]</vi> <vi>That teacher works her students <it>to death</it>. [=she makes them work too hard]</vi> <vi>He's wonderful! I just love him <it>to death</it>!</vi> <vi>I'm <phrase>sick to death</phrase> of hearing about the scandal. [=I don't want to hear anything more about the scandal; I've heard too much about it]</vi> <vi>That song has been <phrase>done to death</phrase>. [=many musicians have performed that song]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the death</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:until someone is dead <vi>The warriors would fight <it>to the death</it>.</vi> <vi>a battle <it>to the death</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:with all of your energy and effort <vi>Some parents do not want the school to be closed, and say they'll fight <it>to the death</it> for it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>black death</dxt> <dxt>kiss of death</dxt> <dxt>sudden death</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>death*like</ure> <sound><wav>death01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛθˌlaɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>deathlike</it> state</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="eye[1]"> <art><artref id="eye.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,72.5</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">eye</hw> <sound><wav>eye00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈaɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>eyes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you see with <vi>Her <it>eyes</it> slowly became accustomed to the dark.</vi> <vi>He wears a patch over one <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>I have something in my <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has (a pair of) bright blue <it>eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>bright/sad/sleepy <it>eyes</it></vi> <vi>She has good/strong/bad/weak <it>eyes</it>. [=<it>eyesight</it>]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes lit up</phrase> [=she looked excited and happy] when he showed her the ring.</vi> <vi>His <phrase>eyes were popping out of his head</phrase> with astonishment [=he looked very astonished] when he saw how big it was!</vi> <vi>He punched him <phrase>right between the eyes</phrase>. [=punched him hard in the face]</vi> <vi>She looked me (right) <phrase>in the eye</phrase> [=she looked directly at me] and told me I was fired.</vi> <vi>The garden is <phrase>a feast for the eyes</phrase>. [=the garden is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The display was very pleasing <phrase>to the eye</phrase>. [=pleasing to look at]</vi> <vi>I measured the distance <phrase>by eye</phrase>. = I measured the distance <phrase>with my eye</phrase>. [=by looking at it to get a rough idea of its size]</vi> <vi>Their daughter came home from school <phrase>with tears in her eyes</phrase>. [=she was crying]</vi> <vi>Seeing her again <phrase>brought tears to my eyes</phrase>. = Seeing her again <phrase>brought a tear to my eye</phrase>. [=made me shed tears]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>had/kept half an eye on</phrase> [=he occasionally looked at] the TV while he read the paper.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something seen <vi>Only a trained <it>eye</it> can tell the difference between the original painting and a good copy.</vi> <vi>For decorating, they rely on her discerning/discriminating/expert <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has an artist's <it>eye</it> for color.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>have an eye for</phrase> something or <phrase>a good/keen/sharp eye for</phrase> something, you have a special ability to recognize a particular thing or quality. <vi>He <it>has a keen eye for</it> detail.</vi> <vi>He <it>has a good eye</it> for quality.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something looks to you <vi>It looks a little awkward to my <it>eye</it>. [=it looks awkward to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a way of looking at or judging something <vi>He reviewed the proposal with a jaundiced/critical <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>The biographer <phrase>cast a cold/critical/skeptical eye</phrase> on the artist's life.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe where someone is looking <vi>Her <it>eye</it> was attracted to the bright colors in the painting.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>dropped her eyes</phrase> [=she looked down] when he looked at her. = Her <phrase>eyes fell</phrase> when he looked at her.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>averted his eyes</phrase> [=he looked away] when she approached him.</vi> <vi>I saw something moving <phrase>out of the corner of my eye</phrase>. [=to the side of where I was looking]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes fell on</phrase> [=she noticed] a piece of evidence no one had noticed before.</vi> <vi><phrase>All eyes were on her</phrase> [=everyone was looking at her] as she entered the room.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>fixed her eyes on</phrase> me [=she kept looking or staring at me] for a long time before answering.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of looking at or thinking about something <vi>We need to look at this problem with a fresh <it>eye</it>. [=to look at the problem in a new way]</vi> <vi><phrase>Beauty is in the eye of the beholder</phrase>. [=different people have different ideas about what is beautiful]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He was guilty in the <it>eyes</it> of the police. [=the police considered him guilty]</vi> <vi>He was handsome in her <it>eyes</it>. [=she thought he was handsome]</vi> <vi>In the <it>eyes</it> [=<it>opinion</it>] of many, he is the best person for the job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hole through the top of a needle <vi>the <it>eye</it> of a needle</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a loop that a hook fits into to fasten or attach something</dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area on a potato from which a new plant can grow :a bud on a potato</dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the center of a storm (such as a hurricane) where there is little wind or rain and sometimes there is clear sky <vi>The <it>eye</it> of the storm should reach the coast by morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all eyes</dre> <def><dt>:watching something or someone closely :very attentive <vi>She was <it>all eyes</it> as I opened the box.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an eye for an eye</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that a person who has committed a crime should be given punishment that is the same as or as serious as the crime <vi>The ancient code of law called for punishment in the form of <it>an eye for an eye</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as far as the eye could see</dre> <def><dt>:as far as could be seen <vi>The crowd stretched away <it>as far as the eye could see</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a sight for sore eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a twinkle in your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twinkle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bawl your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bawl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>before your eyes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>in front of your eyes</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If something happens (<it>right</it>) <it>before your eyes</it> or <it>in front of your (very) eyes</it>, it happens in a very open and visible way so that you can see it very clearly. <vi>Technology is changing <it>right before our eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>We were watching a disaster take place <it>in front of our very eyes</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast/run your eye over</dre> <def><dt>:to read it or look at (something) quickly. <vi>Please <it>run your eye over</it> this and let me know what you think.</vi> <vi>She <it>cast her eye over</it> the apartment, appalled by the mess.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close/shut your eyes to</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to notice or accept the truth or existence of (something) :to ignore (something) <vi>Our legislators have <it>closed their eyes to</it> the poverty that surrounds them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cry your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy on the eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people are surprised that you have seen or noticed something that is behind you, they may say that you have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>. <vi>How did you know we were here? You must have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feast your eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>feast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for your eyes only</dre> <def><dt>:intended to be seen only by you <vi>This memo is <it>for your eyes only</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Several men were <it>giving her the eye</it> across the bar.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep an/your eye out for</dre> <def><dt>:to be looking for (someone or something) :to hope to see or find (someone or something) <vi>I'm <it>keeping my eye out for</it> a good cheap used car.</vi> <vi>He'll be here soon, so <it>keep your eye out for</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:to have (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>She <it>has an eye to</it> attending graduate school. [=she hopes to attend graduate school]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(have) stars in your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>star</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have your eye on</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to watch (someone or something) closely <vi>I'll <it>have my eye on</it> the kids while they're swimming.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be thinking about buying (something) <vi>I <it>have my eye on</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>She's <it>had her eye on</it> that house for a long time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a pig's eye</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt><un>used to express strong disagreement <vi>You want me to apologize to him? <it>In a pig's eye</it>! [=<it>Never!</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the blink of an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blink</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the public eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a position that receives a lot of public notice and attention <vi>The job requires someone who is comfortable being <it>in the public eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a very short time :very quickly <vi>He was back <it>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your mind's eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you see something <it>in your mind's eye</it>, you imagine or remember how it looks. <vi>I can still see the old playground <it>in my mind's eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep an/your eye on</dre> <def><dt>:to watch or take care of (someone or something) <vi>Will you <it>keep an eye on</it> my suitcase (for me) while I get something to eat?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eye on the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes glued to</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to watch (something) very closely for a long time <vi>They <it>kept their eyes glued to</it> the television, waiting for more news about the accident.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes open</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>keep your eyes peeled</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>keep your eyes skinned</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look or watch closely in order to see or find (something) <vi>We <it>kept our eyes peeled</it> for a sign that would tell us where to turn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/set eyes on</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>clap eyes on</va></vr> <def><dt>:to see or look at (someone or something) <vi>I hope never to <it>lay eyes on</it> him again!</vi> <vi>We liked the house from the moment we <it>set eyes on</it> it. [=the moment when we first saw it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Some guy was <it>making eyes at</it> her from across the room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than meets the eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>more than meets the eye</it> or there is <phrase>more to something than meets the eye</phrase>, there is more to it than there appears to be at first. <vi>There is <it>more to this proposal than meets the eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>my eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise or mild disagreement <vi>A diamond, <it>my eye</it>! That's glass!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not bat an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>only have eyes for</dre> <def><dt>:to only be attracted to (a particular person) :to only feel love for (someone) <vi>He <it>only has eyes for</it> you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open someone's eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to notice or be aware of something important <vi>The experience really <it>opened his eyes</it> and changed the way he felt about his life.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>It's time they <it>opened their eyes to</it> the truth.</vi> <vi>His film helped <it>open people's eyes to</it> the problem.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to notice or be aware of something important <vi>You need to <it>open your eyes</it> and face the truth.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We have to <it>open our eyes to</it> these problems and stop ignoring them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull the wool over someone's eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wool</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roving eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roving</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>run your eye down</dre> <def><dt>:to quickly read or look at (something, such as a list) <vi>She <it>ran her eye down</it> the list looking for her name.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see eye to eye</dre> <def><dt>:to have the same opinion :<sx>agree</sx> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>They don't <it>see eye to eye</it> (with each other) on this issue.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your eyes off</dre> <def><dt>:to stop looking at (someone or something) <vi>I <it>took my eyes off</it> the road for one second.</vi> <vi>She was so beautiful, he <phrase>couldn't take his eyes off</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the apple of someone's eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>apple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>under the eye of</dre> <def><dt>:while being watched by (someone) <vi>Students work <phrase>under the watchful/vigilant eye of</phrase> their teacher.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in or affected by something <vi>We're <it>up to our eyes</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi> <vi>They're <it>up to their eyes</it> in debt.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:with (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>They hired him <it>with an eye toward</it> increased sales.</vi> <vi>They bought the house <it>with an eye toward</it> its restoration.</vi> <vi>He took the job <phrase>with an eye to the future</phrase>. [=he took the job because he felt it would help him in the future]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your/both eyes open</dre> <def><dt>:fully aware of what could happen <vi>I went into the job <it>with my eyes (wide) open</it>.</vi> <vi>If you do this, you need to do it <it>with both eyes open</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes shut/closed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:with little or no effort :very easily <vi>She could run that company <it>with her eyes shut</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</it>, you have taken more food than you can possibly eat. <vi>I can't finish my meal—I guess <it>my eyes were bigger than my stomach</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>black eye</dxt> <dxt>evil eye</dxt> <dxt>private eye</dxt> <dxt>rib eye</dxt> <dxt>seeing eye</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
