<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cease"> <hw highlight="yes">cease</hw> <sound><wav>cease001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:s</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ceas*es</if></in> <in><if>ceased</if></in> <in><if>ceas*ing</if></in> <def><sl>formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop happening :to end <vi>The fighting along the border has temporarily <it>ceased</it>.</vi> <vi>The conversation abruptly <it>ceased</it>. [=<it>halted</it>]</vi> <vi>The noise <it>ceased</it> [=<it>stopped</it>] altogether.</vi> <vi>when the weary <it>cease</it> from their labors [=when people who are very tired stop working]</vi> <vi>The company was ordered by the court to <phrase>cease and desist</phrase> from selling the photographs. [=was ordered to immediately stop selling the photographs]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cease and desist order</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop doing (something) <vi>The factory <it>ceased</it> operations last year.</vi> <vi>The child would not <it>cease</it> his constant whining/complaining.</vi> <vi>The soldiers were ordered to <phrase>cease fire</phrase>. [=to stop shooting their weapons]</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>The program would <it>cease to exist</it> without private funding.</vi> <vi>He had long <it>ceased to have</it> any regrets.</vi> <vi>Her courage <phrase>never ceases to amaze</phrase> me. [=I am always amazed by her courage]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cease-fire</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>wonders never cease</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wonder</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cease and desist order"> <hw>cease and desist order</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ders</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>law</sl> <dt>:an official order to stop doing something immediately <vi>A <it>cease and desist order</it> was issued by the state.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cease-fire"> <hw>cease–fire</hw> <sound><wav>cease_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:sˈfajɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cease–fires</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an agreement to stop fighting a war for a period of time so that a permanent agreement can be made to end the war :<sx>truce</sx> <vi>The countries each sent representatives to negotiate a <it>cease-fire</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>cease-fire</it> agreement</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="wonder[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">won*der</hw> <sound><wav>wonder01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwʌndɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>won*ders</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something or someone that is very surprising, beautiful, amazing, etc. <vi>The Grand Canyon is one of the natural <it>wonders</it> of the world.</vi> <vi>This new computer is a technological <it>wonder</it>.</vi> <vi>She's a <it>wonder</it> with a paintbrush. [=she is very good at painting]</vi> <vi>the <it>wonders</it> of science</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>nine days' wonder</dxt> <dxt>one-hit wonder</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a feeling caused by seeing something that is very surprising, beautiful, amazing, etc. <vi>The child's eyes were filled with <it>wonder</it> during the trip to the circus.</vi> <vi>We watched the fireworks show with <it>wonder</it> and amazement.</vi> <vi>She gazed up at the tall buildings in <it>wonder</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is surprising or hard to believe <vi>It's a <it>wonder</it> we made it this far. [=it is surprising we made it this far]</vi> <vi>Is it any <it>wonder</it> why this movie is so popular?</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>do/work wonders</dre> <def><dt>:to help or improve something greatly <vi>A vacation will <it>do wonders</it> for your mood.</vi> <vi>The treatment <it>worked wonders</it> on my skin.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no wonder</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>small/little wonder</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is not surprising <vi>It's <it>no wonder</it> you're hungry; you didn't have any breakfast.</vi> <vi><it>Small wonder</it> that we're lost, since we didn't ask for directions.</vi> <vi>They failed to realize how costly the work would be. <it>Little wonder</it>, then, that their plan was rejected.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wonders never cease</dre> <def><sl>humorous</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you are happy and surprised by something good that has happened <vi>He was on time for work all week. <it>Wonders never cease</it>!</vi> <vi>My story is finally getting published! <phrase>Will wonders never cease</phrase>? [=isn't that amazing/surprising?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
