<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="ceiling"> <hw highlight="yes">ceil*ing</hw> <sound><wav>ceilin01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsi:lɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ceil*ings</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the inside surface at the top of a room <vi>The house has low <it>ceilings</it>.</vi> <vi>a plaster <it>ceiling</it></vi> <vi>a <it>ceiling</it> fan [=a fan that hangs from the ceiling of a room]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a <it>ceiling</it> of stars/clouds</vi></un> <dx>opposite <dxt>floor</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an upper limit <un>usually singular <vi>a price <it>ceiling</it></vi> <vi>The government has put/set/imposed a <it>ceiling</it> on automobile emissions.</vi> <vi>Fuel prices are going <phrase>through the ceiling</phrase>. [=fuel prices are quickly getting much higher]</vi></un> <dx>opposite <dxt>floor</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>glass ceiling</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:the greatest height at which an aircraft can fly <vi>The airplane has a <it>ceiling</it> of 32,000 feet.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>hit the ceiling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>ceilinged</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><un>used in combination <vi>a high-<it>ceilinged</it> room [=a room with a high ceiling]</vi></un></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="cathedral ceiling"> <hw>cathedral ceiling</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ings</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a high ceiling that has two sides that slant downwards from a pointed top</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="glass ceiling"> <hw>glass ceiling</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ings</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an unfair system or set of attitudes that prevents some people (such as women or people of a certain race) from getting the most powerful jobs <un>usually singular <vi>women executives trying to break through the <it>glass ceiling</it></vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hit[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">hit</hw> <sound><wav>hit00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>hits</if></in> <in><if>hit</if></in> <in><if>hit*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move your hand, a bat, etc., quickly so that it touches someone or something in a forceful or violent way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She told her son to stop <it>hitting</it> his sister.</vi> <vi>She <it>hit</it> him hard with her purse.</vi> <vi>He <it>hit</it> the fence with a stick. = He <it>hit</it> a stick against/on the fence.</vi> <vi>The boxers <it>hit</it> each other with their fists.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The boxers were <it>hitting</it> furiously at each other.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a ball) to move by hitting it forcefully with a bat, racket, etc. <vi>He <it>hit</it> a fastball (over the fence) for a home run.</vi> <vi>She <it>hit</it> the ball right to the shortstop.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to touch (something or someone) in a forceful or violent way after moving at a high speed <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The ball <it>hit</it> the house.</vi> <vi>The plate shattered when it <it>hit</it> the floor.</vi> <vi>The tank was <it>hit</it> by enemy fire.</vi> <vi>He was <it>hit</it> by a car.</vi> <vi>The ship <it>hit</it> an iceberg.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The plate shattered when it <it>hit</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or allow (something, such as part of your body) to touch something in a forceful or violent way <vi>I accidentally <it>hit</it> my head on/against the side of the door while I was getting into the car.</vi> <vi>She <it>hit</it> her elbow on the edge of the table.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to attack (something or someone) <vi>Our plan is to <it>hit</it> the enemy before they can <it>hit</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to affect (something or someone) in a harmful or damaging way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The ship was <it>hit</it> by a sudden storm.</vi> <vi>A powerful earthquake <it>hit</it> the city.</vi> <vi>Many families have been <phrase>hit hard</phrase> by the layoffs. = Many families have been <phrase>hard hit</phrase> by the layoffs. [=many families have been badly affected/hurt by the layoffs]</vi> <vi>If you really want to teach your son a lesson you should <phrase>hit him where it hurts</phrase> and take away his cell phone.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Many people were unprepared when the storm <it>hit</it>.</vi> <vi>The layoffs have <it>hit hard</it> here.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to come to (something) by chance or accident while you are moving <vi>We <it>hit</it> a west wind coming out of port.</vi> <vi>I was late because I <it>hit</it> a traffic jam on the way over.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to have or experience (problems, trouble, etc.) <vi>The project went smoothly at first, but then we started to <it>hit</it> [=<it>encounter</it>] some problems.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become suddenly or completely clear to (someone) :<sx>strike</sx> <vi>It suddenly <it>hit</it> [=<it>occurred to</it>] me that I was doing something wrong. [=I suddenly realized that I was doing something wrong]</vi> <vi>The importance of the victory hasn't really <it>hit</it> her yet.</vi> <vi>I was just about to give up when the solution <it>hit</it> me.</vi> <vi>When you meet him, the first thing that <it>hits</it> you [=the first thing that you notice] is his air of confidence.</vi> <vi>The smell <it>hit</it> me [=I noticed the smell] as soon as I opened the door.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get or come to (a goal, level, etc.) :<sx>reach</sx> <vi>He <it>hit</it> 100 mph on his motorcycle.</vi> <vi>They expect the temperature to <it>hit</it> 90 this afternoon.</vi> <vi>Sales <it>hit</it> $100 million last year alone.</vi> <vi>Gold prices <it>hit</it> an all-time high last week.</vi> <vi>a singer who can <it>hit</it> the high notes</vi> <vi>He kept digging until he <it>hit</it> [=<it>struck</it>] water.</vi> <vi>The stock market <phrase>hit bottom</phrase>. [=reached an extremely low point]</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Next year he'll <phrase>hit the big four-oh/five-oh</phrase>. [=turn 40/50 years of age]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to arrive or appear at, in, or on (a place) <vi>We <it>hit</it> [=went to] the beach nearly every day this summer.</vi> <vi>They got up early and headed out to <it>hit</it> the (ski) slopes. [=to go skiing]</vi> <vi>The magazine's new issue <it>hits</it> newsstands tomorrow. [=the new issue becomes available on newsstands tomorrow]</vi> <vi>The new product should <it>hit</it> the shelves/market soon. = The new product should <it>hit</it> stores soon. [=the new product should be available in stores soon]</vi> <vi>These new illegal drugs only recently <phrase>hit the street</phrase>. [=became available for illegal purchase]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to turn (something) on or off with a switch <vi>Could someone please <phrase>hit the lights</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move (a switch) to an on or off position <vi>The lights came on when she <phrase>hit the switch</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to push down on (the brake pedal or accelerator in a vehicle) in a sudden and forceful way <vi>I had to <phrase>hit the brakes</phrase> hard to avoid an accident.</vi> <vi>She suddenly <it>hit</it> the accelerator and sped away. = (<it>US</it>) She suddenly <phrase>hit the gas</phrase> and sped away.</vi></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:to succeed in hitting (something aimed at) with a shot, throw, etc. <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>hit</it> the bull's-eye</vi> <vi><it>hit</it> the target</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Her criticism really <phrase>hit the mark</phrase>. [=her criticism was very accurate]</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The first shot <it>hit</it> but the second shot missed.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to succeed in making (a shot) <vi>She <it>hit</it> [=<it>made, sank</it>] 40 percent of her shots last season.</vi> <vi>She <it>hit</it> her first basket but then missed the next one.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to succeed in making a pass to (another player) <vi>The quarterback <it>hit</it> the wide receiver (with a pass) for a touchdown.</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to try to hit the ball with a bat in baseball, cricket, or a similar game <vi>It's your turn to <it>hit</it>. [=<it>bat</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce (a home run, a ground ball, etc.) by batting <vi>He <it>hit</it> 30 home runs last year.</vi> <vi>He <it>hit</it> a ground ball to the shortstop.</vi> <vi>She <it>hit</it> a double to left field.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a specified batting average <vi>This year he's <it>hitting</it> [=<it>batting</it>] .300. [=his batting average is .300]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to hit the pitches thrown by (a pitcher) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He has <it>hit</it> this pitcher well/poorly in the past.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He has <it>hit</it> well/poorly against this pitcher in the past.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to deal another card to (a player in blackjack) <vi><it>Hit</it> me. [=deal another card to me]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>hit a nerve</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nerve</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit a/the wall</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wall</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to attack or criticize someone who has attacked or criticized you <vi>If you hit me, I'll <it>hit back</it>.</vi> <vi>The team <it>hit back</it> with a touchdown of their own.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>The Senator <it>hit back at</it> his critics.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit home</dre> <dx>see <dxt>home</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell a group of musicians to begin playing <vi><it>Hit it</it>, boys! [=let's begin playing music]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit it big</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hit big</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>big</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit it off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to become friends :to get along well <vi>The two of them <it>hit it off</it> (with each other) immediately.</vi> <vi>Though we work together, we've never really <it>hit it off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>hit on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk to (someone) in order to try to start a sexual relationship <vi>She's always being/getting <it>hit on</it> at the gym.</vi> <vi>Some drunk at the bar was <it>hitting on</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hit on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to succeed in finding (something, such as a solution) <vi>She thought about the problem for days before she finally <it>hit on</it> a solution.</vi> <vi>He <it>hit on</it> a new way to do things.</vi> <vi>We <it>hit upon</it> the answer accidentally.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit out at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hit out at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make an angry attack against (someone) <vi>The singer <it>hit out at</it> [=(more commonly) <it>lashed out at</it>] her critics.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit someone for six</dre> <dx>see <dxt>six</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>book</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the buffers</dre> <dx>see <dxt>buffer</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the deck</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hit the dirt</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>hit the ground</va></vr> <def><dt>:to drop down to the ground or floor suddenly <vi>She <it>hit the deck</it> when the gunfire started.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the fan</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fan</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the ground running</dre> <def><dt>:to begin an effort or activity in a quick, energetic, and effective way <vi>The new administration <it>hit the ground running</it> after the inauguration.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the hay</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hit the sack</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go to bed <vi>I'm tired. I'm going to <it>hit the hay</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the jackpot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>jackpot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the nail on the head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be exactly right <vi>He <it>hit the nail on the head</it> with that analysis.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the panic button</dre> <dx>see <dxt>panic button</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the road</dre> <dx>see <dxt>road</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the roof</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hit the ceiling</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to become very angry or upset <vi>His parents really <it>hit the roof</it> when they found out he had flunked out of school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the skids</dre> <dx>see <dxt>skid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the spot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the streets</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>hit the pavement</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go out in search of something or for a specific purpose <vi>I grabbed the classifieds and <it>hit the pavement</it>, looking for a new job.</vi> <vi>The reporters <it>hit the streets</it> to interview passersby.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hit <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the town</dre> <dx>see <dxt>town</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the trail</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trail</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hit (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hit up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to ask (someone) <it>for</it> something (such as money) <vi>She's waiting for the right moment to <it>hit up</it> her father <it>for</it> a loan. [=to ask her father for a loan]</vi> <vi>I donated money to that charity a few months ago, and they're already <it>hitting</it> me <it>up for</it> more.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit your stride</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stride</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know what hit you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="hitter"> <hw>hit*ter</hw> <pr>ˈhɪtɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>hit*ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person who hits someone or something</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:a player who is trying to hit the ball <vi>The pitcher walked the first <it>hitter</it>. [=<it>batter</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a good fielder but a poor <it>hitter</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>designated hitter</dxt> <dxt>heavy hitter</dxt> <dxt>pinch hitter</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
