<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="century"> <hw highlight="yes">cen*tu*ry</hw> <sound><wav>centur02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛntʃəri</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cen*tu*ries</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a period of 100 years <vi>It took more than a <it>century</it> to complete the cathedral.</vi> <vi>This photograph was taken half a <it>century</it> [=50 years] ago.</vi> <vi>The herb has been used to treat headaches for <it>centuries</it>. [=hundreds of years]</vi> <vi>a <it>centuries</it>-old tradition</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a period of 100 years counted from the beginning of the Christian era <vi>Millions of people celebrated the beginning of the 21st <it>century</it> on January 1, 2000.</vi> <vi>the third <it>century</it> A.D.</vi> <vi>The pottery dates back to the sixth <it>century</it> B.C.E.</vi> <vi>When the prince got married, it was called the wedding of the <it>century</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="turn[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">turn</hw> <altpr>ˈtɚn</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>turns</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an opportunity or responsibility to do or use something before or after other people <vi>You have to wait your <it>turn</it> in line.</vi> <vi>Is it my <it>turn</it> yet?</vi> <vi>Can I please have/take a <it>turn</it> on your bike? [=can I have a chance to use your bike?]</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to</it> + <it>verb</it> <vi>Whose <it>turn</it> is it <it>to do</it> the dishes?</vi> <vi>It's her <it>turn to bat</it>.</vi> <vi>You've made me suffer in the past, so now it's your <it>turn to suffer</it>!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an act of turning something around a central point <vi>Give the wheel another <it>turn</it>.</vi> <vi>He tightened the screw with one last <it>turn</it>.</vi> <vi>With a <it>turn</it> of the switch, the lights came back on.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an act of changing the direction that someone or something is facing or moving in <vi>Take a left-hand <it>turn</it> at the next intersection.</vi> <vi>I made a right <it>turn</it> [=I turned right] onto Main Street.</vi> <vi>a quick <it>turn</it> of her head</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>three-point turn</dxt> <dxt>u-turn</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a change in the state or condition of something <un>usually used with <it>take</it> <vi>The stock market <it>took</it> a sharp downward <it>turn</it> today.</vi> <vi>The conversation suddenly <it>took</it> an unexpected <it>turn</it> when he announced that he was getting married.</vi> <vi>Business <phrase>took a turn for the worse/better</phrase>. [=it became worse/better]</vi> <vi>There has been a dramatic <phrase>turn of events</phrase>. [=something important and surprising has happened]</vi> <vi>It's hard to follow all the <phrase>twists and turns</phrase> [=the surprising changes] of the plot.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a place where a road connects to another road that goes in a different direction <vi>I think we took a wrong <it>turn</it>. [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>turning</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a place where a road, path, etc., changes direction <vi>There is a dangerous <it>turn</it> up ahead.</vi> <vi>The runners are coming down the straightaway and heading into the <it>turn</it>.</vi> <vi>The road through the mountains has many <phrase>twists and turns</phrase>. [=curves and frequent changes of direction]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:an act that affects someone in a particular way <vi>He did me a nasty <it>turn</it>.</vi> <vi>You have done me a few good <it>turns</it>, so now let me help you.</vi> <vi><phrase>One good turn deserves another</phrase>. [=if someone does something nice for you, you should do something nice for that person]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a public appearance or performance <vi>The actor makes frequent guest <it>turns</it> on the show.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>star turn</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a short walk or ride <un>usually singular <vi>They <phrase>took a turn</phrase> [=went for a stroll] through the park.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a sudden feeling of being frightened <un>usually singular <vi>He startled me and <phrase>gave me quite a turn</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a sudden, short period of feeling slightly ill, faint, or dizzy <un>usually singular <vi>He <phrase>had a turn</phrase> and had to lie down.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at every turn</dre> <def><dt>:in a constant or continuous way :each time a person tries to do something <vi>They opposed her <it>at every turn</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by turns</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe different things that happen one after another <vi>The book was praised and criticized <it>by turns</it>.</vi> <vi>The stories in the collection are, <it>by turns</it>, curious, tragic, disturbing, and heartening.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>done to a turn</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:cooked, performed, etc., in a perfect way :done to perfection <vi>The chicken was <it>done to a turn</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in turn</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:following one after another in a particular order <vi>Each witness <it>in turn</it> gave his or her version of what happened.</vi> <vi>The algae feeds the fish, which <it>in turn</it> become food for larger sea animals.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:as a result <vi>I supported him and expected that he, <it>in turn</it>, would support me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the turn</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:about to start changing <vi>The political situation in the country is <it>on the turn</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of turn</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not at the time you are expected to do something according to a set order <vi>She rolled the dice <it>out of turn</it>. [=when it was not her turn]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:at a wrong or improper time or place <vi>Excuse me for speaking <it>out of turn</it> [=for speaking when it is not proper for me to speak], but I don't believe you are treating him fairly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take turns</dre> <vr><vl>also Brit</vl> <va>take it in turns</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If people <it>take turns</it> doing or using something or <it>take it in turns</it> to do or use something, they do or use it one after another in order to share the responsibility or opportunity of doing or using it. <vi>We <it>take turns</it> washing the dishes.</vi> <vi>The kids <it>took turns</it> on the swing.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the turn of the century</dre> <def><dt>:the beginning of a new century <vi>We were discussing how Americans lived at <it>the turn of the</it> 19th/last <it>century</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn of mind</dre> <def><dt>:a way of thinking <vi>He has a philosophical/inquiring <it>turn of mind</it>.</vi> <vi>Her <it>turns of mind</it> are revealed in her journals.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn of phrase</dre> <def><dt>:a way of saying or describing something <vi>a nice <it>turn of phrase</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn of speed</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:an increase in speed or progress <vi>The horse gave an impressive <it>turn of speed</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
