<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="center[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cen*ter</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>cen*tre</va> <sound><wav>center01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛntɚ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cen*ters</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the middle point or part of something <vi>the <it>center</it> of the room/circle</vi> <vi>The candies have a soft <it>center</it>. [=<it>middle</it>]</vi> <vi>The staircase is in the <it>center</it> of the building.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the <it>center</it> aisle/lane</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person or thing that is causing a lot of interest, argument, etc. <vi>The proposed memorial has become a <it>center</it> of controversy. [=there is a lot of controversy about the proposed memorial]</vi> <vi>He likes to be the <phrase>center of attention</phrase>. [=he likes to be noticed and watched by many people]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the position of a person or thing that is causing a lot of interest, argument, etc. <vi>They are <phrase>at the center of</phrase> a furious debate over whether or not to expand the city's public transportation system.</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>at the center of things</phrase>, you are closely involved in things that are happening. <vi>He always likes to be <it>at the center of things</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a building or set of buildings used by the people of a city, town, area, etc., for a particular purpose <vi>a communications/conference <it>center</it></vi> <vi>a day-care <it>center</it></vi> <vi>The vaccine is being tested at several medical <it>centers</it> around the country.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>community center</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place where a particular activity happens <vi>the financial/business/cultural <it>center</it> of the city</vi> <vi>The university is becoming a <phrase>center of excellence</phrase> for genetic engineering. [=becoming a place where genetic engineering is done very well]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>nerve center</dxt> <dxt>shopping center</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area where many people live <vi>a population/urban <it>center</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the main part of a town or city where there are many stores, restaurants, offices, etc. <vi>the town/city <it>center</it></vi> <vi>efforts to rebuild the city's <it>center</it> [=<it>downtown</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the political position of people who support ideas that are not extreme :a moderate political position between the positions of people who are conservative and liberal <vi>The party's new policies show a shift toward the <it>center</it>.</vi> <vi>His political views are slightly <phrase>right/left of center</phrase>. [=are slightly conservative/liberal]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:someone who plays a middle position on a team in sports like basketball, hockey, football, and soccer</dt></def> <dro><dre>front and center</dre> <dx>see <dxt>front</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>left, right, and centre</dre> <dx>see <dxt>left</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="center[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">center</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre</va> <altpr>ˈsɛntɚ</altpr></vr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>centers</if></in> <in><if>centered</if></in> <in><if>center*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to place (something) in the middle of something <vi><it>Center</it> the picture on the wall.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) centered</it> <vi>The sign <it>isn't centered</it>. Move it a little to the left.</vi> <vi>The pain <it>is centered</it> around/in his lower back.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be mainly concerned about or involved with someone or something <un>usually + <it>around, round, on</it>, or <it>upon</it> <vi>Her life <it>centers on/around</it> her children. [=her children are the most important part of her life]</vi> <vi>The story <it>centers on/upon</it> a teenage girl.</vi> <vi>The investigation has <it>centered</it> [=<it>focused</it>] mainly <it>on/upon</it> the alleged misuse of public funds.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to be mainly concerned about or involved with something <un>usually + <it>around, round, on</it>, or <it>upon</it>, <vi>She <it>centers</it> her life <it>on/around</it> her children. = Her life is <it>centered on/around</it> her children.</vi> <vi>You should <it>center</it> your attention <it>on</it> the most important problems.</vi> <vi>The group is <it>centering</it> its efforts <it>on</it> getting food to the poor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the main or most important part of (something, such as an organization or activity) <it>in</it> or <it>at</it> a specified place <un>usually used as <it>(be) centered</it> <vi>an industry that <it>is centered in</it> the country's north</vi> <vi>The organization has members worldwide but <it>is centered in</it> Cairo.</vi> <vi>a series of arts events <it>centered at</it> the city park</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>centered</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="centre"> <hw>centre</hw> <cx><cl>Brit spelling of</cl> <ct>center</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="center field"> <hw>center field</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre field</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the part of the baseball outfield between right field and left field <vi>a fly ball to <it>center field</it></vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the position of the player defending center field <vi>She used to be a shortstop but now she plays <it>center field</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>center fielder</ure> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre fielder</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a good <it>center fielder</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="center forward"> <hw>center forward</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre forward</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -wards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:someone who plays in the middle of the front line of players in field hockey, soccer, and other sports</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="center ice"> <hw>center ice</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre ice</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the middle section of an ice hockey rink <vi>She skated back to <it>center ice</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="center of gravity"> <hw>center of gravity</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre of gravity</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:the point at which the entire weight of something can be balanced <vi>Its low <it>center of gravity</it> makes the car very stable.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="center stage"> <hw>center stage</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>centre stage</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the middle section of a theater's stage <vi>The actor stood alone at <it>center stage</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a main or very important position <vi>As we wrap up work on the old project, a new one moves to <it>center stage</it>.</vi> <vi>The issue is expected to <phrase>take center stage</phrase> in the elections.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civic center"> <hw>civic center</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>civic centre</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a large public building for sports events, concerts, etc.</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a section of a city or town where the public buildings are</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="community center"> <hw>community center</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>community centre</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a building or group of buildings where there are classes and activities for the people who live in a community</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
