<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="change[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">change</hw> <sound><wav>change01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃeɪnʤ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chang*es</if></in> <in><if>changed</if></in> <in><if>chang*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to become different <vi>Her mood <it>changes</it> every hour.</vi> <vi>He's <it>changed</it> in appearance. = His appearance has <it>changed</it>.</vi> <vi>The leaves <it>change</it> (in color) from green to red in the fall.</vi> <vi>The cars were stopped, waiting for the light/lights to <it>change</it> (from red to green).</vi> <vi>My, how you've <it>changed</it>!</vi> <vi>He <it>changed</it> from an optimist to/into a pessimist.</vi> <vi>The town has <it>changed</it> little in recent years.</vi> <vi>the <it>changing</it> times</vi> <vi>the ever-<it>changing</it> [=constantly changing] fashions of teenagers</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (someone or something) different <vi>These events have <it>changed</it> me in my attitude to/toward life.</vi> <vi>He's <it>changed</it> his appearance with a new haircut. = His new haircut has <it>changed</it> his appearance.</vi> <vi>You can't <it>change</it> human nature.</vi> <vi>Life <it>changed</it> him from an optimist into a pessimist.</vi> <vi>The leaves <phrase>change color</phrase> from green to red in the fall.</vi> <un>sometimes + <it>up</it> in informal U.S. English <vi>She <it>changed up</it> her daily routine.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>change</it> things <it>up</it> a little.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to become something else <un>usually + <it>to</it> or <it>into</it> <vi>Winter <it>changed to/into</it> spring.</vi> <vi>The magician made the rope <it>change into</it> a ribbon and then <it>change</it> back <it>into</it> a rope.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to replace one thing or person with another <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>changed</it> her name when she got married.</vi> <vi>We'll have a better view if we <it>change</it> our seats for better ones. [=if we move to better seats]</vi> <vi>Could you <it>change</it> my appointment (from Monday) to Friday?</vi> <vi><it>change</it> a record/CD</vi> <vi>France has <it>changed</it> its monetary unit from the franc to the euro.</vi> <vi>She's thinking about <it>changing</it> jobs/dentists. [=about leaving her current job/dentist and going to a new one]</vi> <vi><it>change</it> the channel on the TV</vi> <vi><phrase>change a (flat) tire</phrase> [=replace a flat tire with one that is not flat]</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>change the subject</phrase>. [=let's talk about a different subject]</vi> <vi>I've <phrase>changed my opinion/views</phrase> on that subject. [=my opinion on that subject is different now from what it was before]</vi> <vi>The police did not believe her because she had <phrase>changed her story</phrase>. [=she said something different from what she had said before]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>While watching TV, he would constantly <it>change</it> from one channel to another.</vi> <vi>France has <it>changed</it> from the franc to the euro.</vi> <vi>The U.S. has been slow to <it>change</it> to the metric system.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move from one position, place, etc., to another <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Mary <it>changed</it> [=<it>exchanged, switched</it>] places/seats with John. = John and Mary <it>changed</it> places/seats (with each other).</vi> <vi>He may be rich and famous but I wouldn't <it>change</it> places with him for anything in the world.</vi> <vi>He was opposed to the project at first, but then he <phrase>changed sides</phrase> and voted in favor of it.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Neither of them liked his seat so they <it>changed</it> with each other.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to exchange one kind of money for another kind <vi><it>change</it> money from dollars into pounds = <it>change</it> dollars into/for pounds</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to exchange a larger bill for an equal amount in smaller bills or coins <vi>I need to <it>change</it> [=<it>break</it>] a $10 bill: can you give me a five and five ones?</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to put on different clothes <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Let me <it>change</it> out of this suit into something more comfortable.</vi> <vi>Do they still <it>change</it> (to more formal clothes) for dinner?</vi> <vi>I'll need a few minutes to <it>change</it> before we go out.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll need a few minutes to <phrase>change my clothes</phrase> before we go out.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put clean clothes on (a baby) <vi><phrase>change a baby</phrase> = <it>change</it> a baby's diaper [=remove a baby's dirty diaper and replace it with a clean one]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put a fresh covering on (a bed) <vi><phrase>change a bed</phrase> = <it>change</it> the sheets on a bed [=remove dirty sheets from a bed and replace them with clean ones]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to move from one plane, train, etc., to another in order to continue a journey <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We'll have to <it>change</it> planes in Chicago. [=we'll have to get on another plane in Chicago]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>On the bus trip he had to <it>change</it> twice.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>change around</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>change round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>change (something) around/round</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>change around/round (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to change the order or positions of the parts of (something) <vi>When I got back everything in my office had been <it>changed around</it>.</vi> <vi>The schedule has been <it>changed around</it> a little.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change down</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to change to a lower gear in a motor vehicle :<sx>downshift</sx> <vi><it>Change down</it> to go uphill.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change gear/gears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>change hands</dre> <def><dt>:to go from one owner to another <vi>The property has <it>changed hands</it> many times in recent decades. [=the property has been sold many times]</vi> <vi>The restaurant recently <it>changed hands</it>. [=the restaurant was recently bought by a new owner]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change horses in midstream</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>change over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>change over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>change (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>change over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go from one system, method, etc., to another or to change (one system, method, etc.) to another <vi>It will take a week to <it>change over</it> from the old computer network to the new one.</vi> <vi>It will take a week to <it>change</it> the old computer network <it>over</it> to the new one.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>changeover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change someone's/your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>change up</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to change to a higher gear in a motor vehicle :<sx>upshift</sx> <vi><it>Change up</it> on the highway.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>change <dxn>1b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change your tune</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tune</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>change your ways</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>chang*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chang*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a CD <it>changer</it></vi> <vi>a money <it>changer</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="change[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">change</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃeɪnʤ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>changes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act, process, or result of changing: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of becoming different or of causing someone or something to become different <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There has been little if any <it>change</it> in her daily routine.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't be afraid of <it>change</it>. <it>Change</it> is a natural part of life.</vi> <vi>The terms of this contract are subject to <it>change</it> without notice. [=the terms can be changed at any time]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The years have brought many <it>changes</it> to the town's economy.</vi> <vi>We need to make some <it>changes</it> in/to the system.</vi> <vi>Many voters believe that it's time for a <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>We've had to make a slight <it>change</it> in the schedule.</vi> <vi>There has been a <it>change</it> in/to our plans. = There's been a <phrase>change of plan</phrase>. [=we have changed our plans]</vi> <vi><phrase>a change for the better</phrase> [=an improvement]</vi> <vi><phrase>a change for the worse</phrase></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sea change</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of replacing one thing with another <vi>a <it>change</it> of address/name</vi> <vi><it>changes</it> of mood/attitude/tone</vi> <vi>I enjoy the <phrase>change of seasons</phrase> every year. [=I enjoy seeing the seasons change from winter to spring, etc.]</vi> <vi>The car needs an <phrase>oil change</phrase>. [=needs to have the old, dirty oil removed and replaced with clean oil]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of moving from one plane, train, etc., to another in order to continue a journey <vi>If you take this flight you'll need to make a <it>change</it> (of planes) in Chicago. [=you'll need to change planes in Chicago]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is different from what is usual or expected <vi>We've been so busy that a quiet day at home was a welcome <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>We eat at home a lot, so dining out sometimes is/makes a nice <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) So you've done the cooking for once in your life! Well, that <phrase>makes a change</phrase>!</vi> <vi>I've been stuck here in the city for months. I could really use <phrase>a change of scene/scenery</phrase>. = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) I could really use a <phrase>change of air</phrase>. [=I would like to go somewhere else for a time]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>for a change <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:smaller bills or coins that are given for a larger bill <vi>Have you got <it>change</it> for a $10 bill?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the money returned when a payment is more than the amount needed <vi>It cost $9 and I gave you $10, so I should be getting $1 in <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>“It costs $9.” “Here's $10. You can <phrase>keep the change</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Can you <phrase>make change</phrase> for a twenty? [=can you give me change if I pay with a $20 bill?]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:money in the form of coins <vi>I've got a $10 bill and about $3 in <it>change</it>. [=<it>coins</it>]</vi> <vi>a pocketful of <phrase>loose change</phrase></vi> <vi>The beggar asked us if we had any <phrase>spare change</phrase>. [=a small amount of money that we did not need]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>change purse</dxt> <dxt>small change</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>money</sx> <un>used in the phrase <phrase>chunk of change</phrase> <vi>She inherited a large/hefty/nice <it>chunk of change</it> [=a large amount of money] from her aunt.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a clean set of clothes that someone can wear if they are needed <vi>For a weekend in the country you'll need several <it>changes</it> of clothes.</vi> <vi>The only extra clothes he took with him were a pair of socks and a <it>change</it> of underwear.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>changeup</sx> <vi>The batter struck out on a straight <it>change</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the change</bnote> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:<sx>change of life</sx> <vi>women who are going through <it>the change</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and change</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:and a very small additional amount <vi>There's only six minutes <it>and change</it> left in the game. [=there's only a little more than six minutes left in the game]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for a change</dre> <def><dt>:as something different from what is usual <vi>Let's eat out <it>for a change</it>.</vi> <vi>Why don't you help me out <it>for a change</it> instead of me always helping you?!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ring the changes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ring</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="change of heart"> <hw>change of heart</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:an important change in the way a person feels or thinks about something <vi>He had planned to retire but he had a sudden <it>change of heart</it> and decided to continue working.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="change of life"> <hw>change of life</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the change of life</dre> <def><sl>somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:<sx>menopause</sx> <vi>women approaching or going through <it>the change of life</it></vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="change of pace"> <hw>change of pace</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>changes of pace</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a new activity or situation that comes after another activity or situation which has lasted for long time <un>usually singular <vi>He took a few days off work to give himself a welcome and much-needed <it>change of pace</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:<sx>changeup</sx> <un>usually singular <vi>The batter struck out on a <it>change of pace</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="change purse"> <hw>change purse</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ purses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a very small bag for carrying coins</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="chump change"> <hw>chump change</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a small amount of money :an amount of money that is not important or impressive <vi>His share of the profits was <it>chump change</it>. [=his share of the profits was not very big]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="loose change"> <hw>loose change</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:coins that a person is carrying <vi>He had a few dollars in <it>loose change</it> in his pockets.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sea change"> <hw>sea change</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ changes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a big and sudden change <un>usually singular <vi>There's been a <it>sea change</it> in public opinion.</vi> <vi>Her attitude has undergone a <it>sea change</it> [=her attitude has changed completely] in recent months.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="small change"> <hw>small change</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:coins that are not worth a lot of money <vi>a pocket full of <it>small change</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an amount of money that is not large or important <vi>The fine is a lot of money to some people, but to him it's <it>small change</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:something or someone that is not important <vi>My problems are <it>small change</it> compared to yours.</vi> <vi>He wasn't a major criminal. He was strictly <it>small change</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
