<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="chance[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chance</hw> <sound><wav>chance01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃæns, <it>Brit</it> ˈtʃɑ:ns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chanc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:an opportunity to do something :an amount of time or a situation in which something can be done <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I wanted to call you, but I never got/had the <it>chance</it> (to).</vi> <vi>I go to the beach every <it>chance</it> I get. [=I go whenever I can]</vi> <vi>This is the <it>chance</it> of a lifetime!</vi> <vi>You missed your <it>chance</it>.</vi> <vi>Everyone deserves a fair <it>chance</it> of winning the award.</vi> <vi>If you give me a <it>chance</it>, I know I can do a good job.</vi> <vi>He doesn't give <phrase>second chances</phrase>. [=opportunities to try something again after failing one time]</vi> <vi>If <phrase>given half a chance</phrase> [=if given some opportunity], she could show everyone how talented she is.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Here's your <it>chance to try</it> something new.</vi> <vi>Give me a <it>chance to explain</it>.</vi> <vi>You have to give the wound a <it>chance to heal</it>. [=you have to allow time for the wound to heal]</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>We didn't have much <it>chance to talk</it> about it.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>jump/leap/grab at the chance to do something</phrase> is to have an opportunity to do something and to say in an excited way that you will do it or to do it in a very eager way. <vi>She <it>jumped at the chance</it> to go to New York City.</vi></snote> <snote>If you have a <phrase>fighting chance</phrase> to do something, you may be able to do it by making a great effort. <vi>The patient still has a <it>fighting chance</it> to survive.</vi> <vi>Their help gave us a <it>fighting chance</it> to finish the project on time.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the possibility that something will happen <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>There's a good <it>chance</it> that we'll finish on time.</vi> <vi>There's still a <phrase>slim chance</phrase> [=a small possibility] that we can win.</vi> <vi>There's an <phrase>outside chance</phrase> [=a small possibility] that something could go wrong.</vi> <vi><phrase>Chances are</phrase> [=it is very likely that] she has already heard the news.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>It increases/reduces the <it>chance of</it> getting the disease.</vi> <vi>There's a 50 percent <it>chance of</it> rain this afternoon.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) The challenger may not have much experience, but I still think he's <phrase>in with a chance of</phrase> winning. [=he has a possibility of winning]</vi></un> <un>often plural <vi>What are the <it>chances</it> [=how likely is it] that we'll have nice weather today?</vi> <vi>I think her <it>chances</it> of winning the election are good.</vi> <vi>“How do you think the team will do this year?” “I <phrase>like their chances</phrase>.” [=I think they have a good chance of succeeding/winning]</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>If you are free tonight, is there any <it>chance</it> you could join me for dinner?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>If you want to have any <it>chance of</it> getting the job, you'll have to dress nicely.</vi> <vi>The prisoners had little/no <it>chance of</it> escape/escaping.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>by any chance</phrase> is used when asking questions in a polite way. <vi>Are you free tonight, <it>by any chance</it>?</vi></snote> <snote>The informal phrases <phrase>fat chance</phrase> and <phrase>not a chance</phrase> are used as a forceful way of saying that there is no possibility that something will happen. <vi>“He says that he'll get here on time.” “<it>Fat chance</it>!”</vi> <vi>“Do you think they'll win?” “<it>Not a chance</it>!”</vi> <vi><it>Fat chance</it> of that happening!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way that events happen when they are not planned or controlled by people :<sx>luck</sx> <vi>There is an element of <it>chance</it> [=<it>luck</it>] to winning a card game.</vi> <vi>Which cards you're given is simply a matter of <it>chance</it>.</vi> <vi>We planned for everything and <phrase>left nothing to chance</phrase>. [=we prepared for everything possible]</vi> <vi>That's not the kind of thing you want to <phrase>leave to chance</phrase>. [=that's not the kind of thing you don't want to plan or prepare for]</vi> <snote>If something happens <phrase>by chance</phrase>, people have not planned it or tried to make it happen. <vi><it>By</it> (pure/sheer) <it>chance</it>, I saw him again at the grocery store.</vi> <vi>We found the house entirely <it>by chance</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>The phrase <phrase>as chance would have it</phrase> is used to say that something happened because of good or bad luck. <vi>Our car broke down on the road, but <it>as chance would have it</it> [=<it>as it turned out</it>], there was a garage nearby.</vi></snote> <snote>A <phrase>game of chance</phrase> is a game (such as a dice game) in which luck rather than skill decides who wins. <vi><it>Games of chance</it> are illegal in some states.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>chance would be a fine thing</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something good or desirable is not likely to happen <vi>This candidate promises to solve all the country's financial problems in six months. <it>Chance would be a fine thing</it>! [=if only that were possible]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the off chance</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about something that might happen or be true but that is not likely <vi>I called his office <it>on the off chance</it> that he would still be there [=I called because I thought there was a slight chance that he would still be there], but he had already left.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand a chance</dre> <def><dt>:to have a possibility of succeeding <vi>The team <it>stands a chance</it> of doing well this year.</vi> <vi>I think she <phrase>stands a good chance</phrase> of winning the election.</vi> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>He <phrase>doesn't stand a chance</phrase> against the champion.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>stands no chance</phrase> of winning. [=she has no chance of winning]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take a chance</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that could have either good or bad results <vi>She's trying to find a publisher who will <it>take a chance</it> on her book. [=will publish her book without knowing for certain that it will succeed]</vi> <vi>It might not work, but it's a <it>chance</it> we'll have to <it>take</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm not willing to <it>take that chance</it>.</vi> <vi>He said he couldn't afford to <it>take any chances</it>.</vi> <vi>He's not afraid to <phrase>take chances</phrase>. [=to do things that are risky or dangerous]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>was taking no chances</phrase>. = She <phrase>wasn't taking any chances</phrase>.</vi> <vi>“You might not succeed.” “I know, but I'll <phrase>take my chances</phrase> anyway.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chance[2]"> <hw hindex="2">chance</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃæns, <it>Brit</it> ˈtʃɑ:ns</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chances</if></in> <in><if>chanced</if></in> <in><if>chanc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to accept the danger of (doing something) :<sx>risk</sx> <vi>We knew that the trip was dangerous, but we decided to <it>chance</it> it. [=we decided to go on the trip]</vi> <vi>He couldn't <it>chance</it> playing with a broken toe.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe something that happens because of luck or chance</un> <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>It <it>chanced</it> [=(more commonly) <it>happened</it>] <it>to rain</it> that day.</vi> <vi>We <it>chanced to arrive</it> at the same time.</vi> <vi>a conversation that <it>chanced to take place</it> outside my apartment</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>chance upon</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>chance on</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chance upon/on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to find (something) or meet (someone) by chance <vi>She <it>chanced upon</it> an original copy of the book in her grandfather's attic.</vi> <vi>We <it>chanced upon</it> a good restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chance your arm</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to take a chance :to do something that could have bad results <vi>The newspaper <it>chanced its arm</it> by printing the story.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chance[3]"> <hw hindex="3">chance</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃæns, <it>Brit</it> ˈtʃɑ:ns</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:happening without being planned or controlled by people :happening by chance <vi>It was a <it>chance</it> encounter/meeting between the two men.</vi> <vi>a <it>chance</it> event/occurrence/discovery</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="any[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">any</hw> <sound><wav>any00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛni</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a person or thing that is not particular or specific <vi>Ask <it>any</it> man you meet, and he will tell you the same thing.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> one of them could have answered the question.</vi> <vi>You can return the product if <it>any</it> defect appears within the first six months.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> plan (at all) is better than no plan.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> [=<it>every</it>] child knows that. [=all children know that]</vi> <vi>He is as good as <it>any</it> other pitcher in the league.</vi> <vi>We can meet <it>any</it> day but Monday.</vi> <vi>You could have seen him <it>any</it> afternoon last week.</vi> <vi>The recipe uses a large amount of pepper, and <phrase>not just any</phrase> pepper, but a special blend imported from India.</vi> <vi>You have to be a member to go there. They won't let <phrase>just any</phrase> person in.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an amount greater than zero or none</un> <un>usually used in negative statements, in questions, and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>You haven't eaten <it>any</it> salad. [=no salad has been eaten]</vi> <vi>I can't find <it>any</it> stamps.</vi> <vi>Don't pay <it>any</it> attention to him.</vi> <vi>There is hardly <it>any</it> difference between the two teams.</vi> <vi>They dropped by without <it>any</it> warning.</vi> <vi>We don't want there to be <it>any</it> misunderstandings.</vi> <vi>The company has denied <it>any</it> [=<it>all</it>] responsibility for the accident.</vi> <vi>There are <phrase>few if any</phrase> [=few or no] details about the accident.</vi> <vi>Do you have <it>any</it> money?</vi> <vi>He asked if/whether you had <it>any</it> money.</vi> <vi>If there are <it>any</it> errors, report them to me. = Report <it>any</it> errors to me.</vi> <vi>If you can give me <it>any</it> help, I'd appreciate it. = I'd appreciate <it>any</it> help you can give me.</vi></un></dt> <usage><it>Some</it> is used instead of <it>any</it> in positive statements. <vi>I have <it>some</it> money.</vi> It is sometimes used instead of <it>any</it> in questions and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it>. <vi>Do you have <it>some</it> money?</vi> <vi>If I had <it>some</it> money, I would spend it on books.</vi></usage></def> <dro><dre>any moment</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moment</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <dx>see <dxt>old</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at any cost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>by any chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go to any length/lengths</dre> <dx>see <dxt>length</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any case</dre> <dx>see <dxt>case</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any event</dre> <dx>see <dxt>event</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="arm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">arm</hw> <sound><wav>arm00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>arms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:either one of the two long body parts that join the top of your body at the shoulder and that end at the hand or wrist <vi>He has big, strong, muscular <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>She broke her left <it>arm</it>. = Her left <it>arm</it> was/got broken.</vi> <vi>He hurt his throwing/pitching <it>arm</it> [=the arm that he uses to throw/pitch a ball] in the last game.</vi> <vi>She put/threw her <it>arms</it> around him. [=she hugged him]</vi> <vi>She had a newspaper tucked under her <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was carrying a bag of groceries in each <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He gave/offered his <it>arm</it> to her, and she took it. [=she held onto his arm]</vi> <vi>She grabbed my <it>arm</it>. = She grabbed me by the <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was standing there with his <it>arms</it> crossed/folded.</vi> <vi>She stood with her <it>arms</it> outstretched. = She stood with her <it>arms</it> wide open.</vi> <vi>She sat cradling the baby in her <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her since she was <phrase>a babe in arms</phrase>. [=a baby who is too young to walk and has to be held]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her in/into his arms</phrase> [=he embraced her] and kissed her passionately.</vi> <vi>She found him <phrase>in the arms of</phrase> [=being embraced by] another woman.</vi> <vi>He showed up at the party with a young woman <phrase>on his arm</phrase>. [=holding his arm]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her (by the) arm</phrase> and they walked in to dinner.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the part of a piece of clothing (such as a shirt or coat) that covers the arm :<sx>sleeve</sx> <vi>The jacket's <it>arms</it> are too tight. = The jacket is too tight in the <it>arms</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a part of a piece of furniture (such as a chair or couch) that gives support for a person's arm <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the sofa</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>armchair</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:a long thin piece that is connected to the main part of a machine, structure, etc., and that looks or moves like a human arm <vi>the robot's mechanical <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the machine's robotic <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the record player</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long and narrow area of water <vi>an <it>arm</it> of the sea</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the part of a group or organization that performs a specific job or function <un>usually singular <vi>the organization's political <it>arm</it> [=the part of the organization that deals with politics]</vi> <vi>It is the most powerful <it>arm</it> [=<it>division</it>] of the organization.</vi> <vi>the military <it>arm</it> of the government</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a person's ability to throw a ball <un>usually singular <vi>Their pitcher's got a great <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>a strong/weak <it>arm</it></vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>an arm and a leg</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a very large amount of money <vi>It's a reliable car, and it doesn't cost <it>an arm and a leg</it>. [=it isn't too expensive]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>arm in arm</dre> <def><dt>:next to each other with the arm of one person linked at the elbow to the arm of another person <vi>an elderly couple walking down the street <it>arm in arm</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a shot in the arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as long as someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>long</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at arm's length</dre> <def><dt>:from a distance that is the length of a person's arm <vi>It's best to view the painting <it>at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>holding a candle <it>at arm's length</it></vi> <snote>To <phrase>keep someone or something at arm's length</phrase> is to avoid being very close to or friendly with someone or something. <vi>Since going to college, he has <it>kept his old friends at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>They no longer trust her and are <it>keeping her at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>kept the group at arm's length</it> until now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chance your arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your right arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>give</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the long arm of the law</dre> <def><dt>:the ability of the police to find and catch people who commit crimes <vi><it>The long arm of the law</it> finally caught up with him [=the police caught him] 30 years later.</vi> <vi>So far, she's been able to escape <it>the long arm of the law</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>twist someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twist</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with open arms</dre> <def><dt>:in a very kind and friendly way <vi>We were welcomed back <phrase>with open arms</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>arm</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="fat[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fat</hw> <sound><wav>fat00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfæt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>fat*ter</if></in> <in><if>fat*test</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a lot of extra flesh on your body :having a lot of body fat <vi>The dog is getting <it>fat</it> because you feed him too much.</vi> <vi>a cute, <it>fat</it> baby</vi> <vi>I can't believe I've let myself get so <it>fat</it>.</vi> <vi>a movie that has a lot of <phrase>fat jokes</phrase> [=jokes about fat people]</vi> <snote><it>Fat</it> can be an insulting word when it is used to describe a person. <vi>She called him a big, <it>fat</it> slob.</vi> <vi>She's gotten really <it>fat</it>. [=(more politely) <it>big, heavy</it>]</vi></snote> <dx>opposite <dxt>thin</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a full, rounded form <vi>a <it>fat</it> belly</vi> <vi>a <it>fat</it>, juicy peach</vi> <snote>A <phrase>fat lip</phrase> is a lip that is swollen because of injury, especially from being punched. <vi>He threatened to give me a <it>fat lip</it>. [=he threatened to punch me]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:unusually wide or thick <vi>a <it>fat</it> book of poems</vi> <vi>a <it>fat</it> envelope</vi> <vi>a truck with <it>fat</it> tires</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:containing, providing, or costing a large amount of money <vi>a <it>fat</it> bank account</vi> <vi>He signed a <it>fat</it> contract.</vi> <vi>The company offered her a <it>fat</it> salary.</vi> <vi>a <it>fat</it> check [=a check for a large amount of money]</vi> <vi>He had to pay a <it>fat</it> [=<it>big</it>] fine.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal + disapproving</ssl> <dt>:successful or wealthy <vi>The company grew <it>fat</it> on profits during the war.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:easy to hit <vi>a <it>fat</it> pitch right down the middle of the plate</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>big fat</dre> <def><dt><un>used for emphasis <vi>That's a <it>big fat</it> lie!</vi> <vi>Come here and give me a <it>big fat</it> kiss.</vi> <vi>He came home with a <it>big fat</it> F [=a failing grade] on his report card.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fat chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>it ain't over until/till the fat lady sings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lady</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>fat*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>body <it>fatness</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="fine[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fine</hw> <sound><wav>fine0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfaɪn</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>fin*er</if></in> <in><if>fin*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:good, acceptable, or satisfactory :<sx>ok</sx> <vi>That's <it>fine</it> with me.</vi> <vi>“Is there anything wrong?” “No, everything's <it>fine</it>.”</vi> <vi>The house looks <it>fine</it> to me.</vi> <vi>“Would you like more coffee?” “No, I'm <it>fine</it>, thanks.” [=I am happy with the amount of coffee I have now]</vi> <vi>“Would you like more coffee?” “No, this is <it>fine</it>, thanks.” [=no, this is as much as I want]</vi> <vi>That's just <phrase>fine and dandy</phrase> with me. [=that is fine with me; I approve of that]</vi> <snote><it>Fine</it> is often used as a response to show acceptance or approval. <vi>“I have to leave early, all right?” “<it>Fine</it>.”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in an ironic way to refer to things that are not good or acceptable <vi>This is a <it>fine</it> mess we're in.</vi> <vi>“Those kids are no good.” “You're a <phrase>fine one to talk</phrase>, considering all the trouble you caused when you were young.” [=you should not say bad things about others because those same things could be said about you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:very good <vi>I think that's a <it>fine</it> idea.</vi> <vi>You did a <it>fine</it> job.</vi> <vi>The house is in <it>fine</it> shape.</vi> <vi>This is a <it>fine</it> example of what can go wrong when one person is given too much power.</vi> <vi>They make a <it>fine</it> pair. [=they are well suited to each other]</vi> <vi>She has a <it>fine</it> grasp of the problem. [=she understands the problem very well]</vi> <vi>He was in <it>fine</it> form. [=he performed very well]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:deserving praise, admiration, or respect <vi>He's a <it>fine</it> young man.</vi> <vi>a <it>fine</it> musician</vi> <vi>a <it>fine</it> mind</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:well or healthy :not sick or injured <vi>I feel <it>fine</it>.</vi> <vi>“Did you hurt yourself?” “No, I'm <it>fine</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of weather</ssl> <dt>:sunny and pleasant <vi>a <it>fine</it> spring day</vi> <vi>The weather has been <it>fine</it> lately.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:very thin <vi><it>fine</it> thread/wire/yarn</vi> <vi>Her head was covered with <it>fine</it>, silky hair.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very sharp or narrow <vi>a knife with a <it>fine</it> edge</vi> <vi>a pen/brush with a <it>fine</it> tip</vi> :having a sharp point <vi>a <it>fine</it> pen/brush</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:made up of very small pieces, drops, etc. <vi><it>fine</it> sand/dust/powder</vi> <vi><it>fine</it> gravel</vi> <vi>a <it>fine</it> mist/spray</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:very small <vi>The print was so <it>fine</it> that I could barely read it.</vi> <vi>very <it>fine</it> details on the sculpture</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fine print</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:having very small holes <vi>a <it>fine</it> mesh</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:small and delicate <vi>She has <it>fine</it> features. [=her eyes, nose, and mouth are small and delicate]</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:small and done with a lot of care and accuracy <vi><it>fine</it> measurements</vi> <vi><it>fine</it> movements</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:small and difficult to see or understand :<sx>subtle</sx> <vi>a <it>fine</it> distinction</vi> <vi>He's still learning the <it>finer</it> points of the job.</vi> <vi>Some very <it>fine</it> legal points were involved.</vi> <vi>There's a <phrase>fine line</phrase> [=a very small difference] between being helpful and being intrusive.</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:expensive and of high quality <vi><it>fine</it> dining</vi> <vi><it>fine</it> china</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:formal and graceful <vi><it>fine</it> handwriting</vi> <vi>His manners are very <it>fine</it>. [=<it>refined</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a fine figure of a man/woman</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>chance would be a fine thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>finest hour</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hour</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not to put too fine a point on it</dre> <def><dt><un>used in an ironic way to introduce a very strong and usually critical statement <vi><it>Not to put too fine a point on it</it>, (but) his suggestions have been worthless.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>fine*ly</ure> <sound><wav>finely01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfaɪnli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>The onions should be <it>finely</it> chopped. [=should be chopped in small pieces]</vi> <vi>a <it>finely</it> judged response that was just right</vi> <vi>a <it>finely</it> balanced election that could go either way</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>fine*ness</ure> <sound><wav>fine0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfaɪnnəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>fineness</it> of the thread</vi> <vi><it>fineness</it> of detail</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="snowball[1]"> <hw hindex="1">snow*ball</hw> <sound><wav>snowba01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsnoʊˌbɑ:l</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>snow*balls</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a ball of snow that someone makes usually for throwing <vi>This snow is perfect for making <it>snowballs</it>.</vi> <vi>During recess, the children had a <phrase>snowball fight</phrase>. [=a playful fight in which people throw snowballs at each other]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a snowball's chance in hell</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:any chance at all <un>used to say that something is extremely unlikely or impossible <vi>Let's be honest—there isn't <it>a snowball's chance in hell</it> that we'll win this game. [=there's no chance that we'll win]</vi> <vi>Unfortunately, he <phrase>doesn't have a snowball's chance in hell</phrase> of getting the job. [=there is no chance that he will get the job; he will not get the job]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="stand[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">stand</hw> <sound><wav>stand001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstænd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>stands</if></in> <in><if>stood</if> <sound><wav>stand002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstʊd</pr></in> <in><if>stand*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be in an upright position with all of your weight on your feet <vi>She was <it>standing</it> near the window.</vi> <vi>He was <it>standing</it> next to me.</vi> <vi>All of the seats on the bus were taken so we had to <it>stand</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't just <it>stand</it> there (doing nothing)—do something!</vi> <vi>He can <it>stand</it> using a cane.</vi> <vi>You're <it>standing</it> on my foot. [=you're standing with your foot on top of my foot]</vi> <vi>He was <it>standing</it> in a puddle of water.</vi> <vi>The deer <phrase>stood still</phrase>, listening for danger.</vi> <vi>The soldiers <phrase>stood (up) straight</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We had to <phrase>stand in line</phrase> for over an hour.</vi> <vi>People were just <phrase>standing around</phrase> [=standing without doing anything], waiting to get inside the theater.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move onto your feet from a sitting or low position <vi>Please <it>stand</it> [=(more formally) <it>rise</it>] for the national anthem.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>He <it>stood up</it> to greet her.</vi> <vi>She was crouching down to look at something, but she <it>stood up</it> when she saw me.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in an upright position <vi>Two bowling pins were left <it>standing</it>.</vi> <vi>A shovel and rake <it>stood</it> in the corner.</vi> <vi>The house she grew up in is no longer <it>standing</it>. [=the house has been destroyed or knocked down; the house no longer exists]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put (something or someone) in an upright position <vi>She <it>stood</it> the ladder against the house.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>He <it>stood</it> the boy <it>up</it> on a chair.</vi> <vi>Could you <it>stand</it> the picture frame back <it>up</it>?</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to be in a particular place or position <vi>A clock <it>stood</it> on the mantelpiece.</vi> <vi>The mansion <it>stands</it> on a hill.</vi> <vi>A row of trees <it>stands</it> between the two houses.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>A single putt <phrase>stands between</phrase> her and the title. [=if she makes the putt, she will win the title]</vi> <vi>Go ahead and leave. I won't <phrase>stand in your way</phrase>. [=I won't try to stop you]</vi> <vi>We won't let anyone or anything <phrase>stand in the way</phrase> of our happiness. [=prevent us from being happy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remain in a place or position without moving or being moved <vi>The plane <it>stood</it> on the runway ready for takeoff.</vi> <vi>The machine <it>stood</it> idle.</vi> <vi>rainwater <it>standing</it> in stagnant pools</vi> <vi>Add the water and let the mixture <it>stand</it> for three minutes.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be a specified height <vi>He <it>stands</it> six feet two (inches tall).</vi> <vi>The tower <it>stands</it> over 1,000 feet high.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in a particular state or situation <vi>Where do we <it>stand</it> financially? [=what is our financial condition?]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>stands accused of</phrase> murder. [=she has been accused of murder]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a particular belief or opinion about something <vi>Where do you <it>stand</it> on the death penalty? Do you think it should be used or not?</vi> <vi>We still don't know where he <it>stands</it> on this issue.</vi> <vi>They <it>stand</it> divided [=they disagree] on this issue.</vi> <vi>She <it>stands</it> for/against the new regulations. [=she supports/opposes the new regulations]</vi> <vi>We ask you to <it>stand</it> (with us) in support of this proposal. [=we ask you to support this proposal]</vi> <vi><phrase>From where I stand</phrase>, I think we have to do it.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a particular rank or position within a group <vi>The team still <it>stands</it> [=<it>ranks</it>] first in the division.</vi> <vi>She is currently <it>standing</it> in second place.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) He <phrase>stands high/low</phrase> with the voters. [=the voters have a good/bad opinion of him]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to be at a specified number or amount <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>Interest rates <it>stand at</it> 13 percent.</vi> <vi>The home run record <it>stands at</it> 73.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to not be changed :to remain valid or effective <vi>The decision still <it>stands</it>.</vi> <vi>The record she set seems likely to <it>stand</it> for many years.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to exist at the present time <vi>You must take or leave our offer as it <it>stands</it>.</vi> <vi>That is how the situation <it>stands</it> at present.</vi> <vi><phrase>As things stand</phrase>, we will not be able to meet your deadline.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in a position in which you are likely to gain or lose something <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>We <it>stand to make</it> a sizable profit from the sale.</vi> <vi>They <it>stand to lose</it> their home if they can't find a way to pay their bills.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be willing or able to accept (something or someone unpleasant) without complaint <un>usually used with <it>can, can't, cannot, could</it>, and <it>couldn't</it> <vi><it>Can</it> you <it>stand</it> [=<it>tolerate</it>, <it>put up with</it>] waiting a few more minutes? = <it>Can</it> you <it>stand</it> to wait a few more minutes?</vi> <vi>How <it>can</it> you <it>stand</it> her friends?</vi> <vi>He <it>couldn't stand</it> [=<it>bear, endure</it>] the pain.</vi> <vi>I <it>can</it> only <it>stand</it> so much of your nonsense.</vi> <vi>His behavior was <phrase>more than I could stand</phrase>.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>couldn't stand the thought/idea</phrase> of having to move again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone strongly dislikes a person or thing <vi>I <phrase>can't stand</phrase> him. [=I hate him]</vi> <vi>She <it>can't stand</it> cooking. = She <it>can't stand</it> to cook.</vi> <vi>They <it>can't stand</it> being apart.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't stand</it> it when people behave like that!</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to not be harmed by (something) :<sx>withstand</sx> <vi>I need a frying pan that can <it>stand</it> being placed in the oven.</vi> <vi>These plants can <it>stand</it> [=<it>endure</it>] very cold temperatures.</vi> <vi>His plays have <phrase>stood the test of time</phrase>. [=his plays are still read by many people today]</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something should have or do something or would be helped by something</un> <un>usually used after <it>could</it> <vi>You look like you <it>could stand</it> some sleep. [=you look very tired; you look like you need some sleep]</vi> <vi>He <it>could stand</it> losing a few pounds. = He <it>could stand</it> to lose a few pounds.</vi> <vi>That bush <it>could stand</it> to be trimmed. [=that bush needs to be trimmed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be a candidate in an election for a particular office <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>He is <it>standing</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>running</it>] <it>for</it> a seat in Parliament.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to pay for (a meal or drink) <vi>I'll <it>stand</it> a meal for you. = I'll <it>stand</it> you a meal.</vi> <vi>He <it>stood</it> drinks for the table.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) sure as I'm standing here</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you believe that something is certainly true, will happen, etc. <vi>They may claim that this was a surprise to them, but <it>as sure as I'm standing here</it>, they planned it all along.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>I stand corrected</dre> <dx>see <dxt>correct</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make your hair stand on end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not have a leg to stand on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>leg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand a chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand alone</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be in a position or situation in which you are not helped or supported by others <vi>She <it>stood alone</it> in her opposition to the proposal.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something is better than all others <vi>For great sound quality, this system <it>stands alone</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:move to the left or right with one or a few small steps <vi>Please <it>stand aside</it> and let me pass.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to allow something to happen :to not try to stop someone from doing something <vi>I'm not going to <it>stand aside</it> [=<it>stand by</it>] and watch you ruin your life.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to take a few steps backwards <vi>The paramedics told the crowd to <it>stand back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop doing something or being actively involved in something for a time so that you can think about it and make decisions in a calm and reasonable way <vi>It's time to <it>stand back</it> [=<it>step back</it>] and take a long hard look at your problems.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>stand behind (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to support (someone or something) <vi>I'll <it>stand behind</it> you no matter what you decide to do.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>stand behind</it> your decision 100 percent.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stand or be present without taking any action while something is happening <vi>A group of students <it>stood by</it> and watched the boys fight.</vi> <vi>How can you <it>stand by</it> and do nothing?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be ready or available for use <vi>An ambulance was <it>standing by</it> in case anyone got seriously injured.</vi> <vi>Operators are <it>standing by</it> (to take your calls).</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>standby</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand by (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to support or defend (something) <vi>He said that he was <it>standing by</it> what he said earlier.</vi> <vi>I <it>stand by</it> my actions and have no regrets.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to act in the way that is required by (something, such as belief or promise) <vi>She <it>stood by</it> her promise.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand by (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remain loyal to (someone) :to continue to support (someone) <vi>They promised to <it>stand by</it> each other until the end.</vi> <vi>She <it>stood by</it> her husband throughout the trial.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand down</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave the witness stand in a court of law <vi>The judge thanked the witness and allowed her to <it>stand down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to leave a job or official position <vi>He <it>stood down</it> [=<it>stepped down</it>] (from his office) as Lord Mayor.</vi> <vi>She <it>stood down</it> in favour of a more popular candidate.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand firm</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to change your decision, position, etc. <vi>The judge <it>stood firm</it> in her ruling.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>stand for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have (a specified meaning) <vi>“FYI” <it>stands for</it> “for your information.”</vi> <vi>The sign @ <it>stands for</it> “at.”</vi> <vi>The color white often <it>stands for</it> [=<it>represents</it>] innocence and purity.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to support (something) <vi>The political party has always <it>stood for</it> reform.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to allow (something) to continue to happen <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I will not <it>stand for</it> [=<it>put up with</it>] any more of this nonsense.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>stand <dxn>15 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand guard/watch</dre> <def><dt>:to stand in a position and guard or watch someone or something in order to look for possible danger, threats, etc. <vi>A soldier <it>stood guard</it> by the door.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to take the place of (someone who is away for a time) <vi>He can't be here today, so he asked me to <it>stand in</it>. [=<it>fill in</it>]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>He asked me to <it>stand in for</it> him while he was away.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>stand-in</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand on ceremony</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ceremony</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand on your head/hands</dre> <def><dt>:to be in a position in which your legs and feet are straight up in the air and your weight is supported by your head or hands <vi>She can <it>stand on her head/hands</it>. [=she can do a headstand/handstand]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand on your own two feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand or fall</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that the future or success of someone or something depends on another person or thing <vi>We (will) <it>stand or fall</it> by their decision. [=their decision will control what happens to us]</vi> <vi>Our company will <it>stand or fall</it> on our ability to make better products than our competitors. [=our success or failure depends on our ability to make better products than our competitors]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be easily seen or noticed <vi>His bright tie made him <it>stand out</it> (in the crowd).</vi> <vi>The trees' red leaves <it>stood out</it> against the gray sky.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be better or more important than the other people or things in a group in a way that is easily seen or noticed <vi>As a student, she <it>stood out</it> above/from the rest.</vi> <vi>Only one contestant really <it>stands out</it> [=<it>sticks out</it>] in my mind.</vi> <vi>Two facts <it>stand out</it> from her testimony.</vi> <vi>His performance really <it>stood out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stick out from a surface <vi>The hat made her ears <it>stand out</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>standout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand out like a sore thumb</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sore</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand pat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand someone/something in good stead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand tall</dre> <def><dt>:to stand with your body very straight <un>often used figuratively in U.S. English <vi>We can <it>stand tall</it> and take pride in what we've accomplished.</vi> <vi>Despite the criticism, he has continued to <it>stand tall</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand to reason</dre> <dx>see <dxt>reason</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand trial</dre> <def><dt>:to be on trial in a court of law <vi>He is <it>standing trial</it> for the murder of his wife.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to remain valid or acceptable when tested or examined <vi>We need evidence that will <it>stand up</it> in court.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to fail to meet or keep an appointment with (someone) <vi>You <it>stood</it> me <it>up</it> yesterday.</vi> <vi>I got <it>stood up</it> by my date.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand up for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to defend (someone or something) against attack or criticism <vi>He <it>stood up for</it> his friend.</vi> <vi>You have to <it>stand up for</it> yourself.</vi> <vi>They were <it>standing up for</it> their rights.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand up to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to refuse to accept bad treatment from (someone) <vi>She finally <it>stood up to</it> the girl who had been teasing her at school.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remain in good condition despite (something) <vi>These boots have <it>stood up to</it> [=<it>withstood</it>] a lot of abuse.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>stand up and be counted</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make your opinions or beliefs publicly known especially when such action may cause trouble <vi>It's time for everyone who cares about this issue to <it>stand up and be counted</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stand <dxn>1b, 2b (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>stand-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand your ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="thing"> <hw highlight="yes">thing</hw> <sound><wav>thing001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈθɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>things</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an object whose name is not known or stated <vi>What is that <it>thing</it> on the floor?</vi> <vi>That <it>thing</it> is loud.</vi> <vi>He is good at making <it>things</it> out of clay.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an object, animal, quality, etc., of any kind <vi>My doctor told me to avoid fatty <it>things</it> like donuts and potato chips.</vi> <vi>We must respect all living <it>things</it>.</vi> <vi>She loves all <it>things</it> chocolate. [=she loves anything made out of chocolate]</vi> <vi>Her voice is a <it>thing</it> of great beauty. [=her voice is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The disease is said to be <phrase>a thing of the past</phrase>. [=the disease no longer exists]</vi> <vi>The drawer has pens, paper clips, <phrase>and things (like that)</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a particular event, occurrence, or situation <vi>Birth is a miraculous <it>thing</it>.</vi> <vi>It was the worst <it>thing</it> that could have happened.</vi> <vi>That sunset was the most beautiful <it>thing</it> I have ever seen.</vi> <vi>Let's just forget about the whole <it>thing</it> and move on.</vi> <vi>The one <it>thing</it> I hate most is being lied to.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>a good thing</phrase> (that) no one was injured.</vi> <vi>Becoming friends with your boss is <phrase>not a bad thing</phrase>. = Becoming friends with your boss is <phrase>no bad thing</phrase>. [=becoming friends with your boss could have good results]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:objects that belong to a person :personal possessions or belongings <vi>Are all your <it>things</it> packed?</vi> <vi>I need a place to store my <it>things</it>.</vi> <vi>The children's <it>things</it> are always lying around on the floor.</vi> <vi>When she realized she was late for work, she quickly put on her <it>things</it> [=she put on her clothes, shoes, etc.] and left.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:objects that are used for a particular activity <vi>Put the cleaning <it>things</it> away when you are done.</vi> <vi>She got out the cooking <it>things</it> to bake some cookies.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an action that is done, that will be done, or that needs to be done <vi>I have many <it>things</it> to do today. = I have lots of <it>things</it> that need to get done today.</vi> <vi>There are a few <it>things</it> we still have to deal with.</vi> <vi>There is actually one <it>thing</it> you can do to help.</vi> <vi>Let's get this <it>thing</it> over with quickly.</vi> <vi>That was a mean/cruel/kind/generous/thoughtful <it>thing</it> to do.</vi> <vi>They expect great <it>things</it> from her. [=they expect her to be very successful]</vi> <vi>The boy did <phrase>the right thing</phrase> and gave back the toy he took.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>no easy thing</phrase> [=it's not easy] to raise three children by yourself.</vi> <vi>Cathy and I hit it off on our first date. <phrase>One thing led to another</phrase>, and pretty soon we were engaged.</vi> <un>sometimes used to say that one action is more serious, difficult, or important than another. <vi>It is one <it>thing</it> to say you're sorry but (it is) another (<it>thing</it>) to actually mean it.</vi> <vi>Planning a project is one <it>thing</it>; doing it is another.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an activity <vi>What <it>things</it> do you like to do in your spare time?</vi> <vi>I like hiking, biking—that sort of <it>thing</it>.</vi> <vi>The students are allowed to <phrase>do their own thing</phrase>. [=do the activities that they want to do]</vi> <vi>Just <phrase>do your thing</phrase> [=do what you usually do] and pretend I'm not here.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity that is done by a particular group of people <vi>They spent the evening doing guy <it>things</it>. [=doing the kind of things that guys/men tend to like doing]</vi> <vi>You wouldn't understand, Dad. It's a girl <it>thing</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity and everything that is related to it <un>usually singular <vi>He tried the college <it>thing</it> [=he tried going to college] but dropped out after the first semester.</vi> <vi>She's done with the whole rebellious teenager <it>thing</it>. [=she's done being a rebellious teenager]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an activity that someone enjoys or does well <un>usually singular <vi>Ballroom dancing is his <it>thing</it>, not mine.</vi> <vi>It's not really my (kind of) <it>thing</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>things</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the conditions that exist at a particular time and in a particular place <vi><it>Things</it> are improving. [=the situation is improving]</vi> <vi>How are <it>things</it> with the new baby?</vi> <vi>You're just making <it>things</it> more difficult for yourself.</vi> <vi>As <it>things</it> stand now [=in the current situation], we can't afford a new car.</vi> <vi>An apology would not change <it>things</it> between us.</vi> <vi><phrase>All things considered</phrase> [=<it>overall</it>; when you think about everything that happened], the party went very well.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a fact or piece of information about something or someone <vi>He checks every little <it>thing</it>. [=<it>detail</it>]</vi> <vi>There are a lot of <it>things</it> you don't know about us.</vi> <vi>The <it>thing</it> I don't understand is why the car costs so much.</vi> <vi>When buying a car, price and performance are important <it>things</it> to consider.</vi> <vi>There is one more <it>thing</it> I'd like to ask you.</vi> <vi>Several <it>things</it> were discussed at the meeting.</vi> <vi>I'll give you a couple of days to <phrase>think things over</phrase>. [=to think about the situation and make a decision]</vi> <vi>We are always arguing, but <phrase>the (funny) thing is</phrase>, I think I love him.</vi> <vi><it>The thing is</it> that [=it is important to understand that] you can never predict who will win.</vi> <vi>I make excellent chili. <it>The thing is</it> to pick the right peppers. [=to make excellent chili, you need to pick the right peppers]</vi> <vi><phrase>The thing with/about</phrase> him [=an important characteristic to know about him] is that he is not reliable.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thought, idea, or opinion <vi>He just says the first <it>thing</it> that pops into his mind.</vi> <vi>Don't say <it>things</it> you might regret later.</vi> <vi>That was a terrible <it>thing</it> to say.</vi> <vi>He had some interesting <it>things</it> to suggest.</vi> <vi>She always knows the right <it>thing</it> to say.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a reason for something <vi>I can't stand being around him. <phrase>For one thing</phrase>, he smokes. For another, he's rude.</vi> <vi>OK, <phrase>here's the thing</phrase>: I don't have enough money to go to college.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I didn't call you. <phrase>The thing is</phrase>, I've been really busy with work and school.</vi> <vi><phrase>The thing is that</phrase> I haven't had time to call you.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a goal or purpose <vi>The <it>thing</it> is to get well, and then you can think about playing again.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a way of reaching or achieving a goal <vi>There is only one <it>thing</it> left for us to do: fight back!</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) <phrase>There's only one thing for it</phrase>: we must fight.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used for a person, animal, or object that causes strong feelings of affection or dislike in you <vi>You poor <it>thing</it>, you must be freezing.</vi> <vi>She's a pretty little <it>thing</it>, isn't she!</vi> <vi>Get that dirty <it>thing</it> out of my house!</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a strong feeling of liking or disliking something or someone <un>usually singular</un> <un>used with <it>have</it> <vi>She <it>has</it> a <it>thing</it> about snakes. [=she's afraid of snakes]</vi> <vi>He has always <it>had</it> this <it>thing</it> with flying.</vi> <vi>My teacher <it>had</it> this/a <it>thing</it> against me. [=my teacher disliked me for some unknown reason]</vi> <vi>He <it>has</it> a <it>thing</it> for [=he likes] women with red hair.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <bnote>the thing</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the item that is the most fashionable or popular <vi>Long skirts are <it>the thing</it> to wear this season.</vi> <vi>It's <it>the</it> newest/latest <it>thing</it> in fashion.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the fashionable or proper way of behaving, talking, or dressing <vi>It's <it>the thing</it> this year to buy products made from recycled materials.</vi> <vi>Wearing athletic shoes with a suit is not quite <it>the thing</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all/other things being equal</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt><un>used to say what should happen or be true if two situations, products, etc., are different in a specified way but not in other ways <vi><it>All things being equal</it>, a person with a PhD should be getting a higher salary than someone with only a Master's degree.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all things to all people/men</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that makes all people happy by giving them what they want or need <vi>It was clear that the senator was trying to be <it>all things to all people</it> in her campaign.</vi> <vi>The museum is <it>all things to all people</it>, young and old.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>amount to the same thing</dre> <def><dt><snote>If two or more things <it>amount to the same thing</it>, there is very little difference between them. <vi>“Lying and cheating <it>amount to the same thing</it>,” she said.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a thing</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>anything</sx> <un>used in negative statements <vi>I can't see <it>a thing</it> [=I can see nothing] without my glasses on.</vi> <vi>The guests will be here soon, and I don't have <it>a thing</it> (that is appropriate) to wear.</vi> <vi>Don't worry about <it>a thing</it>. I'll take care of everything.</vi> <vi>I can't do <it>a thing</it> to stop them!</vi> <vi>I got there early so I wouldn't miss <it>a thing</it>.</vi> <vi>The police couldn't get <it>a thing</it> out of him.</vi> <vi>She refused to tell me <it>a thing</it> about it.</vi> <vi>I haven't heard <it>a thing</it> from him since graduation.</vi> <vi>We haven't had <it>a thing</it> to eat all day.</vi> <vi>Forget what he said—<phrase>it doesn't mean a thing</phrase>. [=it has no meaning or importance; it's not true]</vi> <vi>None of this will <it>mean a thing</it> if we lose.</vi> <vi>She doesn't look <phrase>a thing like</phrase> [=<it>anything like</it>] her older sister.</vi> <vi>His new album doesn't sound <it>a thing like</it> his last one. [=his new album sounds nothing like his old one]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a thing or two</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:some useful information <vi>I know <it>a thing or two</it> about cars.</vi> <vi>When it comes to cooking, she could teach you <it>a thing or two</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the center of things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>center</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be hearing things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>chance would be a fine thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first things first</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have another thing coming</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone is wrong or mistaken <vi>If he thinks he can fool me, he <it>has another thing coming</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just the thing</dre> <def><dt>:the thing that is most likely to be helpful <vi>Chicken soup is <it>just the thing</it> for a cold.</vi> <vi>I know <it>just the thing</it> to cheer you up—ice cream!</vi> <vi>He always does/says <phrase>just the right thing</phrase> to make me feel better.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>last thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>last</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make a big thing</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you <it>make a big thing (out) of (something)</it> or <it>make a big thing about (something)</it>, you act as if something is very important or serious when it is not. <vi>It was a minor error, but she <it>made a big thing out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> such <it>a big thing about</it> missing the bus: there'll be another one along in a minute.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no such thing</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that a particular person, object, etc., does not really exist <vi>A perfect person? There's <it>no such thing</it>.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>There is <it>no such thing as</it> a unicorn.</vi> <vi>There is <it>no such thing as</it> bad publicity. All publicity is good.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you did not say or do something that someone believes or says you did <vi>“Why did you invite her?” “I did <it>no such thing</it>. She just showed up.”</vi> <vi>“He said that you're not going with us.” “I said <it>no such thing</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of all things</dre> <def><dt><un>used to emphasize that the thing you are referring to is the thing you would least expect <vi>The coach is making the entire football team take, <it>of all things</it>, ballet classes.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one of those things</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to refer to a bad or unfortunate experience that happened and to say that such experiences happen to everyone <vi>I missed the train and had to take a later one. It was just <it>one of those things</it>, I guess.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one thing after another</dre> <def><dt><un>used to complain about the large number of bad or unfortunate events that happen to someone <vi>It's <it>one thing after another</it> with him. Now he's in jail for drunk driving.</vi> <vi>First I locked my keys in the car, and then I spilled coffee all over myself. It was just <it>one thing after another</it> today!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>push things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>push</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see things</dre> <dx>see <dxt>see</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sure thing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the real thing</dre> <def><dt>:something that is genuine and not a copy or imitation :something that is truly valuable or important <vi>The diamond turned out to be <it>the real thing</it>.</vi> <vi>a substitute for <it>the real thing</it></vi> <vi>You've done very well in your training. Let's just hope you're ready for <it>the real thing</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(what) with one thing and another</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you have been very busy doing or dealing with many things <vi><it>What with one thing and another</it>, I have very little free time.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
