<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="charity"> <hw highlight="yes">char*i*ty</hw> <sound><wav>charit03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃerəti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>char*i*ties</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of giving money, food, or other kinds of help to people who are poor, sick, etc. <vi>The holidays are a time for <it>charity</it> and good will.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:something (such as money or food) that is given to people who are poor, sick, etc. <vi>She refused to accept <it>charity</it>.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>charity begins at home</phrase> means you should take care of yourself and your family before helping others.</snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an organization that helps people who are poor, sick, etc. <vi>The dinner was held to raise funds for several <it>charities</it>.</vi> <vi>She runs a local <it>charity</it> that gives books to children.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the organizations that help people in need <vi>All the money will go to <it>charity</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>charity</it> concert/dinner/event [=a concert/dinner/event held to raise money for a charity]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="charity shop"> <hw>charity shop</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ shops</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a store that sells used clothes, goods, etc., in order to raise money for people who are poor, sick, etc. <dx>compare <dxt>thrift shop</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="home[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">home</hw> <sound><wav>home0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhoʊm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>homes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the place (such as a house or apartment) where a person lives <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Right now his <it>home</it> is a small apartment.</vi> <vi>People are concerned about protecting their <it>homes</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) The neighborhood is filled with expensive new <it>homes</it>. [=<it>houses</it>]</vi> <vi>They've started on a major <phrase>home-improvement</phrase> project. [=a project to make their house better, bigger, more modern, etc.]</vi> <vi>They have a <phrase>second/vacation home</phrase> on the lake.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There's no place like <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>Let's stay at <it>home</it> tonight. [=let's not go out tonight]</vi> <vi>I must have left my notes at <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>We're a long way from <it>home</it>. [=we are not close to our house]</vi> <vi>I will be <phrase>away from home</phrase> [=I will not be at my house] for two weeks.</vi> <vi>He has no place to <phrase>call home</phrase>. [=he does not have a place to live]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>works at/from home</phrase>. [=he does his work in his house and not in an office building]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>at home <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>mobile home</dxt> <dxt>motor home</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a family living together in one building, house, etc. <vi>She made a good <it>home</it> for her husband and children.</vi> <vi>She came from a troubled <it>home</it>. [=a family with many problems]</vi> <vi>He comes from a <phrase>broken home</phrase>. [=a family in which the parents have divorced]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>lived at home</phrase> [=she lived with her parents or family] until she got married.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>left home</phrase> [=left his parent's house and lived in his own house] after graduating from high school.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a place where something normally or naturally lives or is located <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Australia is the <it>home</it> [=<it>habitat</it>] of the kangaroo.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The islands are <it>home</it> to many species of birds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where something began or was created <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>The restaurant advertises itself as the <it>home of</it> the “Big Burger.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place where something is placed, stored, etc. <vi>Can you find <it>homes</it> for these files in your office?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:the place where someone lives or originally comes from :the place to which you feel most strongly attached <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>New York will always be <it>home</it> to me.</vi> <vi>They <phrase>made their home</phrase> [=they settled] on the banks of the Mississippi.</vi> <vi><it>People</it> <phrase>back home</phrase> [=in his hometown; in the place he is from] would never believe how much he has changed.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He has fond memories of his boyhood <it>home</it>. [=the place where he lived as a boy]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where an organization, a company, etc., is located and operates <vi>This building will be the orchestra's new <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>The big television networks have their <it>homes</it> in the same city.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place where people who are unable to care for themselves live and are cared for <vi>an orphan's <it>home</it></vi> <vi>an old people's <it>home</it></vi> <vi>She doesn't want to put her mother <phrase>in a home</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>nursing home</dxt> <dxt>rest home</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a place that you try to reach in some games (such as baseball) <vi>He was tagged out at <it>home</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>home plate</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>at home</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in your own country and not a foreign country <vi>We face serious threats both <it>at home</it> and abroad.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:in a team's own stadium, park, etc. :in the place where a team is based <vi>The team's next six games are <it>at home</it>. [=in its own stadium]</vi> <vi>The team has done much better <it>at home</it> [=in its home games] than on the road.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>home <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:relaxed and comfortable <vi>She feels <it>at home</it> on the stage.</vi> <vi>They <phrase>made me feel (right) at home</phrase> my first day at the new job.</vi> <vi>Come on in and <phrase>make yourself at home</phrase>. [=do what you need to do to feel relaxed and comfortable]</vi> <vi>The professor is equally <phrase>at home in</phrase> politics and history. [=knows a lot about both politics and history]</vi> <vi>I've never really felt/been completely <phrase>at home with</phrase> [=comfortable and confident about using] all these new-fangled machines.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>charity begins at home</dre> <dx>see <dxt>charity</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>home away from home</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>home from home</va></vr> <def><dt>:a place that is as pleasant and comfortable as your own home <vi>Whenever he came to the city, his brother's place was like a <it>home away from home</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>home sweet home</dre> <def><dt><snote>You say <it>home sweet home</it> to show that you are happy when you return to your home after being away from it.</snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>home*like</ure> <sound><wav>homeli01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhoʊmˌlaɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more home*like; most home*like</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <utxt><vi>an inn with a <it>homelike</it> atmosphere</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
