<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="abandon[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">aban*don</hw> <sound><wav>abando01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈbændən</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>aban*dons</if></in> <in><if>aban*doned</if></in> <in><if>aban*don*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave and never return to (someone who needs protection or help) <vi>The child had been <it>abandoned</it> (by his parents) as an infant.</vi> <vi>He <it>abandoned</it> his family.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave and never return to (something) <vi><it>abandon</it> property</vi> <vi>They <it>abandoned</it> the car on a back road.</vi> <vi>That house was <it>abandoned</it> years ago.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to leave (a place) because of danger <vi>The approaching fire forced hundreds of people to <it>abandon</it> their homes.</vi> <vi>The officer refused to <it>abandon</it> his post.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>abandon ship</phrase>, you leave a boat or ship that is sinking. <vi>The captain gave the order to <it>abandon ship</it>.</vi> This phrase is sometimes used figuratively. <vi>The company is doing poorly, and many investors have decided to <it>abandon ship</it>. [=to sell their stock in the company]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop supporting or helping (someone or something) <vi>The policy <it>abandons</it> the most vulnerable members of society.</vi> <vi>She <it>abandoned</it> the party not long after the election.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to stop doing or having (something) :to give up (something) completely <vi>We <it>abandoned</it> hope of ever going back.</vi> <vi>He <it>abandoned</it> the principles that he once fought hard to defend.</vi> <vi>She had to <it>abandon</it> her plans for a vacation.</vi> <vi>Play was <it>abandoned</it> because of the bad weather.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>abandon yourself to</dre> <def><sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to allow yourself to be fully controlled or affected by (something, such as a strong emotion) <vi>He <it>abandoned himself to</it> despair. [=he was overcome by despair]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>aban*don*ment</ure> <sound><wav>abando02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈbændənmənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>abandonment</it> of a child/home</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="abandon[2]"> <hw hindex="2">abandon</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a feeling or attitude of wild or complete freedom <vi>They all danced with (wild) <it>abandon</it>.</vi> <vi>She decided <phrase>with reckless abandon</phrase> [=in a very wild and reckless way] to quit her job and move to Tahiti.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ship[1]"> <art><artref id="ship.eps"/><capt/><dim>394,144</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ship</hw> <sound><wav>ship0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈʃɪp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ships</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a large boat used for traveling long distances over the sea <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a sailing/cruise/merchant <it>ship</it></vi> <vi>the captain of the <it>ship</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He will travel by <it>ship</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>flagship</dxt> <dxt>steamship</dxt> <dxt>tall ship</dxt> <dxt>troopship</dxt> <dxt>warship</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large airplane or spacecraft <dx>see also <dxt>airship</dxt> <dxt>rocket ship</dxt> <dxt>spaceship</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>abandon ship</dre> <dx>see <dxt>abandon</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>jump ship</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave a ship without the captain's permission <vi>He planned to <it>jump ship</it> at the next port.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to suddenly or unexpectedly leave a group, team, etc. <vi>She <it>jumped ship</it> when the competition offered her a better job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>run a tight ship</dre> <def><dt>:to manage or handle a group of people in a strict and effective way <vi>The boss <it>runs a tight ship</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ship comes in</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <phrase>your ship comes in</phrase>, you become very successful or wealthy. <vi>She's still waiting for <it>her ship to come in</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
