<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="account[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ac*count</hw> <sound><wav>accoun01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈkaʊnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*counts</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a record of money that has been paid and money that has been received :<sx>bill</sx> <vi>the difference between the debit and credit sides of an <it>account</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>expense account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>accounts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:records of income and expenses <vi>We always keep very good <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>an <it>accounts</it> department</vi> <vi>The company's <it>accounts</it> show a profit this year: our <phrase>accounts receivable</phrase> exceed our <phrase>accounts payable</phrase>. [=the money owed to us exceeds the money we owe]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a bank keeps a record of the money that a person puts in and takes out of the bank <vi>We opened new <it>accounts</it> at a bank last week.</vi> <vi>I took out my money and closed my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>You can withdraw up to $1,000 a day from your <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>Every week, she puts/deposits a part of her paycheck into a separate <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>setting up a <phrase>bank account</phrase></vi> <vi>My wife and I keep our money in a <phrase>joint account</phrase>. [=an account that both of us can use]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>Please enter your name and <it>account</it> number.</vi> <vi>You can check your <it>account</it> balance [=the amount of money in your account] on the Internet.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>checking account</dxt> <dxt>savings account</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a company's record of the products or services used by a customer and of the money that the customer owes or has paid to the company <vi>I don't have the money right now. Put it on my <it>account</it>. = Charge it to my <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>If you return the clothes, the store will credit your <it>account</it>. [=you will not have to pay for the clothes]</vi> <vi>When do you intend to <phrase>settle your account</phrase>? [=pay what you owe]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>charge account</dxt> <dxt>credit account</dxt></dx> <snote>In figurative use, to <phrase>settle an account</phrase> or to <phrase>settle accounts with</phrase> someone is to do something that brings a final end to an argument, disagreement, etc. <vi>She's decided to <it>settle accounts with</it> her old political rivals.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a business arrangement in which a person or company regularly buys products or services from a particular company <vi>She makes sure that all of the company's <it>accounts</it> [=<it>customers, clients</it>] make the necessary payments.</vi> <vi>We just lost the Smith <it>account</it>.</vi> <vi>That company was one of our biggest/best <it>accounts</it>.</vi> <vi>She will be our <phrase>account manager</phrase>. [=the person who manages our account]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an arrangement in which a person uses the Internet or e-mail services of a particular company <vi>I use two separate e-mail <it>accounts</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a description of an event or situation :a story or report about something <vi>personal/firsthand/eyewitness <it>accounts</it> from the war</vi> <vi>According to one <it>account</it>, the party was a complete disaster.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She gave the police a full/complete/detailed <it>account of</it> what happened.</vi> <vi>We read an <it>account of</it> her trip to Paris.</vi> <vi>a written <it>account of</it> his long and successful career</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a list or description of facts <vi>Our goal is to give an accurate <it>account</it> of the process.</vi> <vi>an <it>account</it> of how the system works</vi> <vi>The document is an <it>account</it> of the country's reasons for going to war.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason or explanation for an action <vi>You will be asked to give an <it>account</it> of your actions. [=to explain the reasons for your actions]</vi> <vi>He could give no <it>account</it> of what he did with the money.</vi> <un>often used in the formal phrase <phrase>on that account</phrase> <vi>I hope we won't lose our friendship <it>on that account</it>. [=for that reason]</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:value or importance <un>used in the phrases <phrase>of no account</phrase> and <phrase>of little account</phrase> <vi>He felt that his opinions were <it>of no account</it> to the others. [=he thought that the other people didn't care about his opinions]</vi> <vi>It's <it>of little account</it> what I may think about it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>no-account</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring/call (someone) to account</dre> <def><dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>He was <it>called to account</it> by his boss for failing to spot the mistake in the company's records.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by/from all accounts</dre> <def><dt>:according to all of the different descriptions of something <vi><it>By all accounts</it>, the band put on a great show. [=everyone says that the band put on a great show]</vi> <vi>She was, <it>by all accounts</it>, good at her job.</vi> <vi>They seemed, <it>from all accounts</it>, to have a happy marriage.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by your own account</dre> <def><dt>:according to what you have said about your own life or experiences <vi><it>By her own account</it>, that was the worst performance of her career. [=she said that was her worst performance]</vi> <vi>They had, <it>by their own account</it>, a wonderful time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give a good account of yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to perform well especially in a competition <vi>If I ever had to fight, I think I could <it>give a good account of myself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on account of</dre> <def><dt>:because of :for the reason of <vi>The game was canceled <it>on account of</it> the rain.</vi> <vi>They were treated badly <it>on account of</it> their beliefs.</vi> <vi><it>On account of</it> his bad behavior, he will not be allowed to play with the new toy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on no account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>not on any account</va></vr> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:for no reason :under no circumstances <un>used to say that something will not or should not happen <vi><it>On no account</it> should the children be left at home alone.</vi> <vi>They said that <it>on no account</it> would they leave before the end of the game.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on someone's account</dre> <def><dt>:because of someone :in order to please someone <vi>Don't leave <it>on our account</it>. [=because of us]</vi> <vi>You didn't have to clean your room <it>on my account</it>. I don't care if your room is dirty.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your own account</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:by yourself :on your own :without the help of others <vi>She bought the house entirely <it>on her own account</it>.</vi> <vi>He left the company and went into business <it>on his own account</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for your own sake :in order to make a situation good for yourself <vi>I'm doing it <it>on my own account</it>, not for anyone else.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) into account</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take account of (something)</va></vr> <def><dt>:to think about (something) before doing something (such as making a decision) :<sx>consider</sx> <vi>Try to <it>take</it> our feelings <it>into account</it>. [=try to think about how we will feel]</vi> <vi>Other issues must be <it>taken into account</it> before a choice can be made.</vi> <vi>She did very well on the test when you <it>take into account</it> how little she studied.</vi> <vi>She <it>takes no account of</it> my feelings. [=she doesn't consider how I feel]</vi> <vi>The new health plan fails to <it>take account of</it> the fact that many people cannot pay for their medicine.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn (something) to (good) account</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to gain or profit from (something) :to take advantage of (something) <vi>Is there a way to <it>turn</it> this situation <it>to good account</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="account[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">account</hw> <altpr>əˈkaʊnt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>accounts</if></in> <in><if>account*ed</if></in> <in><if>account*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to think of (someone or something) in a specified way <un>usually used as <it>(be) accounted</it> <vi>Their first project <it>was accounted</it> [=<it>considered</it>] a success.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>account for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>account for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give a reason or explanation for (something) <vi>Eventually, you will need to <it>account for</it> your actions/behavior.</vi> <vi>How do you <it>account for</it> [=<it>explain</it>] your success?</vi> <snote>The informal saying <phrase>there's no accounting for taste</phrase> means that there is no way to understand why some people like something while other people do not. <vi>I don't see why they liked the movie, but <it>there's no accounting for taste</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be the cause of (something) <vi>The disease <it>accounted for</it> over 10,000 deaths last year.</vi> <vi>These new features <it>account for</it> the computer's higher price.</vi> <vi>The disease cannot be <it>accounted for</it> [=<it>explained</it>] by genetics alone. There must be other causes as well.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make up or form (a part of something) <vi>Women <it>account for</it> [=<it>constitute</it>, <it>compose</it>] only 25 percent of our employees.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to think about (something) before doing something :to take (something) into consideration <vi>The researchers failed to <it>account for</it> the fact that most of the students were poor.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>account for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to show what happened to (someone or something) <vi>We have to <it>account for</it> the time [=to say how much time] we spend on each activity.</vi> <vi>I'll have to <it>account for</it> the money I spent.</vi> :to know the location of (someone or something) <vi>The government couldn't <it>account for</it> millions of dollars of the taxpayers' money.</vi> <vi>Is everyone <it>accounted for</it>? [=do we know where everyone is?]</vi> <vi><phrase>All present and accounted for</phrase>. [=everyone who is supposed to be here is here]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to destroy or kill (someone or something) <vi>Enemy fighters have <it>accounted for</it> most of our bombers, Sir.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to defeat or beat (someone or something) <vi>We <it>accounted for</it> [=<it>dispatched</it>] the challengers 3–2.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="charge account"> <hw>charge account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:an arrangement in which a bank, store, etc., allows a customer to buy things with a credit card and pay for them later <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>credit account</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="checking account"> <hw>checking account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a bank account from which you can take money by writing checks <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>current account</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="credit account"> <hw>credit account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ accounts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>charge account</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="current account"> <hw>current account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>checking account</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="deposit account"> <hw>deposit account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>savings account</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="expense account"> <hw>expense account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ accounts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an arrangement that allows an employee (such as someone who is traveling for business) to pay for things using the company's money instead of the employee's money <vi>He charged dinner to his <it>expense account</it>.</vi> <vi>She put the tickets on her <it>expense account</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="individual retirement account"> <hw>individual retirement account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>ira</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="no-account"> <hw>no–account</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal + disapproving</sl> <dt>:having no worth or value :<sx>worthless</sx> <vi>I don't trust her or her lazy, <it>no-account</it> husband.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>no–account</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>no–accounts</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>Her husband is a lazy <it>no-account</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
