<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="acknowledge"> <hw>ac*knowl*edge</hw> <sound><wav>acknow01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ɪkˈnɑ:lɪʤ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ac*knowl*edgedg*es</if></in> <in><if>ac*knowl*edged</if></in> <in><if>ac*knowl*edgedg*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say that you accept or do not deny the truth or existence of (something) :<sx>admit</sx> <vi>They <it>acknowledged</it> that the decision was a mistake.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>acknowledge</it> that you caused this mess?</vi> <vi>I <it>acknowledge</it> (the fact) that I hurt you, and for that I am sorry.</vi> <vi>They readily/openly/grudgingly <it>acknowledged</it> their mistake.</vi> <vi>She won't <it>acknowledge</it> responsibility for her actions.</vi> <vi>He refuses to <it>acknowledge</it> the authority of the court. [=he denies that the court has authority]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to regard or describe (someone or something) as having or deserving a particular status <vi>They <it>acknowledge</it> him as their leader. = They <it>acknowledge</it> him to be their leader.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) acknowledged</it> <vi>She <it>is</it> widely/generally <it>acknowledged</it> as one of the world's best chefs. [=many people regard her as one of the world's best chefs]</vi> <vi>Her pastries <it>are acknowledged</it> to be the best.</vi> <vi>This part of the city <it>is acknowledged</it> to have the best restaurants.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to tell or show someone that something (such as a letter or message) has been received <vi>He quickly <it>acknowledges</it> all of my e-mails when he receives them.</vi> <vi>Please <it>acknowledge</it> receipt of this letter.</vi> <vi>She <it>acknowledged</it> the gift with a card.</vi> <vi>She <it>acknowledged</it> his greeting with a smile.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to show that someone has been seen and recognized :to look at or talk to (someone) <vi>She walked right by me without even <it>acknowledging</it> me.</vi> <vi>The players <it>acknowledged</it> their fans by waving their hands and blowing kisses into the crowd.</vi> <vi>He refuses to <phrase>acknowledge her existence/presence</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to express thanks or appreciation for (something or someone) <vi>In their paper, they <it>acknowledge</it> the important work done by past scholars.</vi> <vi>They <it>acknowledge</it> past scholars for the important work they have done.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>acknowledged</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>the <it>acknowledged</it> leader of a political party</vi> <vi>an <it>acknowledged</it> master of the art</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
