<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="across[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">across</hw> <sound><wav>across01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈkʰrɑ:s</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:from one side to the other side of (something) <vi>We took a ferry <it>across</it> the river.</vi> <vi>We saw them walking <it>across</it> the street.</vi> <vi>She reached <it>across</it> the table to shake his hand.</vi> <vi>They traveled back and forth <it>across</it> the border.</vi> <vi>Airplanes flew <it>across</it> the sky above us.</vi> <vi>She slapped him right <it>across</it> the face. [=she slapped his face]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:on the other side of (something) <vi>He was seated <it>across</it> the table from me.</vi> <vi>Our grandparents live <it>across</it> the street (from us).</vi> <vi>The accident happened just <it>across</it> the state line.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:so as to reach or spread over or throughout (something) <vi>A smile spread <it>across</it> her face.</vi> <vi>Looking out <it>across</it> the ocean, he saw land.</vi> <vi>The sun's light spread <it>across</it> the mountains.</vi> <vi>The disease spread quickly <it>across</it> the country.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in every part of (a country, region, etc.) <vi>The movie is now showing in theaters <it>across</it> [=<it>throughout</it>] America.</vi> <vi>Newspapers (all) <it>across</it> the world reported the story.</vi> <vi>We could hear the bells all <it>across</it> town.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="across[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">across</hw> <altpr>əˈkʰrɑ:s</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:from one side to the other <vi>The streams are small enough to jump <it>across</it>.</vi> <vi>They walked <it>across</it> to the other side of the street.</vi> <vi>They reached <it>across</it> and shook each other's hand.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a measurement from one side to the other side <vi>At its widest point, the pond measures 150 feet <it>across</it>.</vi> <vi>The hole was 10 feet <it>across</it>. [=10 feet wide]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:on the opposite side <vi>I saw them crossing the street and I waited until they were safely <it>across</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>across from</dre> <def><dt>:on the opposite side from (someone or something) <vi>She sat (directly) <it>across from</it> me at the table.</vi> <vi>The restaurant is (just) <it>across from</it> the high school.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="across-the-board"> <hw>across–the–board</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:affecting everyone or everything in a group <vi><it>across-the-board</it> price increases</vi> <vi>an <it>across-the-board</it> tax cut</vi> <dx>see also <tag>across the board</tag> at <dxt>board</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="board[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">board</hw> <sound><wav>board001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>boards</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a long, thin, flat piece of wood <vi>They nailed some <it>boards</it> over the broken window.</vi> <vi>Cut the <it>board</it> lengthwise.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a flat piece of material (such as wood or cardboard) that is used for a special purpose <vi>They covered the <it>board</it> in fabric and pinned some photographs to it.</vi> <vi>the <it>board</it> that is used to play games like chess and checkers</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>bulletin board <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>I saw a notice on the <it>board</it> calling for volunteers.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>message board</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a large, smooth surface for writing on <vi>Write the answers on the <it>board</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blackboard</dxt> <dxt>whiteboard</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a group of people who manage or direct a company or organization <vi>She sits on the bank's <it>board</it> of directors. = She's a <it>board</it> member at the bank.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a group of people who have been chosen to learn information about something, to give advice, etc. <vi>a member of the advisory <it>board</it> = a <it>board</it> member</vi> <vi>She is on the town's planning/zoning <it>board</it>.</vi> <vi>an investigative <it>board</it> [=(more commonly) <it>panel</it>]</vi> <vi>The parole <it>board</it> has decided that the prisoner is not yet ready for release.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>boardroom</dxt> <dxt>school board</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:daily meals that you pay for when you are paying to stay at a hotel, school, etc. <vi>He's looking for a place that provides <it>board</it> and lodging in the city.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) A week at the hotel with <phrase>half board</phrase> [=some meals] is of course less expensive than a week with <phrase>full board</phrase>. [=all meals]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>room and board</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>circuit board</sx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>boards</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:special tests that you take when you want to be accepted as a student at a college or medical school <vi>Did you pass the <it>boards</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>the boards</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the low wooden wall that surrounds the playing surface in ice hockey <vi>He crashed into <it>the boards</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>across the board</dre> <def><dt>:in a way that includes or affects everyone or everything <vi>We've been forced to cut spending <it>across the board</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>across-the-board</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go by the board</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>go by the boards</va></vr> <def><dt>:to no longer be used or considered :to be discarded, rejected, or abandoned <vi>Many of his original theories have <it>gone by the board</it> in recent years as new evidence has accumulated.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on board</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or on a train, boat, etc. :<sx>aboard</sx> <vi>She got <it>on board</it> the train.</vi> <vi>The ship's passengers are all <it>on board</it>.</vi> <vi>Is all the equipment <it>on board</it> (the boat/train/bus/plane)?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:included among the group of people who support a particular goal, project, etc. <vi>They needed to get more senators <it>on board</it> for the bill to pass.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweep the board</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sweep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) on board</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to decide to accept or deal with (something, such as a suggestion or idea) <vi>You will be pleased to note that we have <it>taken</it> your suggestions <it>on board</it> in formulating the present policy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tread the boards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tread</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="come[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">come</hw> <sound><wav>come0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>comes</if></in> <in><if>came</if> <sound><wav>come0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeɪm</pr></in> <in><if>come</if></in> <in><if>com*ing</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move toward someone or something <vi>Please <it>come</it> here for a minute. I want to show you something.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>come</it> near me.</vi> <vi>She <it>came</it> quietly into the room.</vi> <vi>He <it>came</it> home late again last night.</vi> <vi>The dog began to growl as we <it>came</it> closer.</vi> <vi>Here he <it>comes</it>. [=he is approaching us]</vi> <vi>The captain of the ship invited us to <it>come</it> aboard.</vi> <vi>The dog <phrase>came running</phrase> when she called it. [=the dog ran to her when she called it]</vi> <vi>If you need me I'll <it>come running</it>. [=I'll come to you very quickly]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place <vi>People <it>come</it> from all over the country to see him.</vi> <vi>Some people <it>came</it> by car while others <it>came</it> by plane.</vi> <vi>Why don't you <it>come</it> and/to stay with us for a while?</vi> <vi>My parents are <it>coming</it> for a visit. = My parents are <it>coming</it> to visit.</vi> <vi>I hope you'll <it>come</it> (to/and) visit us soon.</vi> <vi>About a hundred people are <it>coming</it> to the wedding.</vi> <vi>People <it>come</it> many miles to visit the shrine.</vi> <vi>They <it>came</it> very far [=they traveled a long way] to see you.</vi> <vi>My brother is <phrase>coming down</phrase> [=traveling south] to visit me this week, and I'll be going up to visit him next month.</vi> <vi>She lives uptown and rarely <it>comes down</it> to this part of the city.</vi> <vi>My parents are <phrase>coming up</phrase> [=traveling north] to visit me this weekend.</vi> <vi>She lives downtown and rarely <it>comes up</it> to this part of the city.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We've <it>come</it> so far [=we've made so much progress]; we can't stop now.</vi> <vi>It's remarkable to think of how far she's <it>come</it> since she started her career.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>come a long way <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of mail</ssl> <dt>:to be delivered to a place <vi>Did/has the mail <it>come</it> yet?</vi> <vi>The mail <it>comes</it> every day at four o'clock.</vi> <vi>A letter <it>came</it> for you.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to have or form an opinion, attitude, etc., after time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I didn't like him at first, but I eventually <it>came to regard</it> him as a friend.</vi> <vi>He has <it>come to be</it> considered one of the leading candidates for the job.</vi> <vi>They <it>came to believe</it> that no one would help them.</vi> <vi>She <it>came to be known</it> [=she became known] as the world's greatest dancer.</vi> <vi>The food wasn't as good as I've <it>come to expect</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I don't know how he <it>came to acquire</it> the property. [=I don't know how he acquired the property]</vi> <vi>How did you <it>come to have</it> such an idea? [=what caused you to have such an idea?]</vi> <vi>How did she <it>come to be</it> there? [=why was she there?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to reach a specified level, part, etc. <vi>Her dress <it>came</it> (down) to her ankles.</vi> <vi>The water <it>came</it> almost up to the window.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to reach a specified state or condition <vi>My shoe <it>came</it> untied.</vi> <vi>The screw <it>came</it> loose.</vi> <vi>Things will <it>come</it> [=<it>become</it>] clear if we are patient.</vi> <vi>The party suddenly <phrase>came alive</phrase>. [=the party suddenly became lively]</vi> <vi>The rent is <phrase>coming due</phrase> next week. [=the rent will be due next week]</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:to happen or occur <vi>These changes couldn't have <it>come</it> at a better time.</vi> <vi>I promise that no harm will <it>come</it> to you. [=I promise that you will not be harmed]</vi> <vi>Her success <it>came</it> at a high price. [=she paid a high price for her success]</vi> <vi>It's important for children to learn about the people and things that <it>came</it> before us.</vi> <vi>Success didn't <phrase>come easy</phrase> for her. [=she did not achieve success easily]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive or happen after time has passed <vi>The days will be longer when spring <it>comes</it>. = <it>Come</it> spring the days will be longer.</vi> <vi>She'll be back in school <it>come</it> September. = She'll be back in school when September <it>comes</it>.</vi> <vi>This war will end eventually, and when that day <it>comes</it>, we will all be profoundly thankful.</vi> <vi>The time has <it>come</it> to stop hesitating and make a decision.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <ssl>of a product that is being sold</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be available <vi>This model <it>comes</it> in several sizes. [=this model can be bought in several sizes]</vi> <vi>a product that <it>comes</it> in a variety of colors and shapes</vi> <vi>when the product first <phrase>came on the market</phrase> [=when the product was first being sold]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have something as a feature, quality, ability, etc. <vi>The car <it>comes</it> (equipped/complete) with air-conditioning.</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <dt>:to have a specified position or place in a series <vi>I don't know which <it>came</it> first.</vi> <vi>The letter D <it>comes</it> after C and before E.</vi> <vi>He cares about his job, but his family <phrase>comes first</phrase>. [=his family is more important than his job]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to end a race or competition in a specified position <vi>Joan won the race and her sister <it>came</it> [=<it>finished, came in</it>] second.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a mild way to urge someone to do something or to become less upset, angry, etc. <vi><it>Come</it>, it's not that bad. I'm sure you'll feel better soon.</vi> <vi><phrase>Come now</phrase>, there's no reason to be so upset.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a mild way to show that you do not approve of or agree with what someone has said <vi><phrase>Come, come</phrase>. You know as well as I do that he never said that.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <dt>:to experience an orgasm</dt></def> <dro><dre>as…as they come</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe someone or something as very good, bad, etc. <vi>Their daughter is <it>as clever as they come</it>. [=their daughter is very clever]</vi> <vi>The movie was <it>as boring as they come</it>. [=the movie was extremely boring]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>Their meeting <it>came about</it> by accident/chance.</vi> <vi>I don't know how it <it>came about</it> that she overheard our conversation.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to turn to a different direction <vi>The captain gave the order to <it>come about</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come a cropper</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cropper</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to seem to have a particular quality or character :to make a particular impression <vi>How did he <it>come across</it>? [=what kind of impression did he make?]</vi> <un>usually + <it>as</it> <vi>He <it>comes across as</it> (being) a good speaker. [=he seems to be a good speaker; people think that he is a good speaker when they hear him talk]</vi> <vi>He <it>came across as</it> a nice guy. [=he seemed to be a nice guy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be expressed to someone <vi>She says she was trying to be helpful, but that's not what <it>came across</it> when I talked to her. [=I did not get the feeling that she was trying to be helpful when I talked to her]</vi> <vi>Her enthusiasm really <it>came across</it> [=<it>came through</it>] when she talked about her job. [=we could see that she was really enthusiastic when she talked about her job]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>come across (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to meet or find (something or someone) by chance <vi>Researchers have <it>come across</it> important new evidence.</vi> <vi>As I was walking through the town, I <it>came across</it> a group of street performers.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to pay money that someone wants or demands <vi>They threatened to hurt him if he doesn't <it>come across</it> (with the money).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come adrift</dre> <dx>see <dxt>adrift</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to chase (someone) :to try to find or capture (someone you want to hurt or punish) <vi>They're worried that the government might be <it>coming after</it> them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come again</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to ask someone to repeat something that was not heard or understood clearly <vi>“Her name is Hermione.” “<it>Come again</it>? I didn't quite hear you.” “I said her name is Hermione.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go somewhere with someone <vi>They asked me to <it>come along</it> (with them) on the trip. [=they asked me to go with them on the trip]</vi> <vi>I'm going to the museum tomorrow. Would you like to <it>come along</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress :to get better or to proceed in a desired way <vi>The project started slowly, but now the work is <it>coming along</it>.</vi> :to proceed in a specified way <vi>The work is <it>coming along</it> well.</vi> <vi>The investigation is <it>coming along</it> slowly, and there's still a lot more work to be done.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to happen or appear as someone or something that might be used, chosen, etc. <vi>She says she won't just marry the first man that <it>comes along</it>.</vi> <vi>An opportunity like this doesn't <it>come along</it> [=<it>occur</it>] too often.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come a long way</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a much higher level of success :to become very successful <vi>He's <it>come a long way</it> from his days as a young reporter. Now he's one of the country's most respected journalists.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make a great amount of progress <vi>Medicine has <it>come a long way</it> in recent years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about time that has passed <vi>More than a hundred years have <it>come and gone</it> since the day of that famous battle.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about people who appear and then leave as time passes <vi>She's seen a lot of employees <it>come and go</it> during her time in the company.</vi> <vi>Politicians <it>come and go</it>. They all seem pretty much the same to me.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come apart</dre> <def><dt>:to break into parts or pieces <vi>an old house that is <phrase>coming apart at the seams</phrase> [=an old house that is in very bad condition]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>a coalition that is <it>coming apart</it></vi> <vi>Their marriage is <it>coming apart at the seams</it>. [=their marriage is failing]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>come round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to accept and support something (such as an idea) after opposing it :to stop opposing or disagreeing with something or someone <vi>She still says she won't support us, but she'll <it>come around</it> eventually. [=she'll support us eventually]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She'll <it>come around to</it> our side eventually.</vi> <vi>People are starting to <it>come around to</it> the idea.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become conscious <vi>He took a bad fall and knocked himself out. When he <it>came around</it> [=<it>woke up</it>, <it>came to</it>], he didn't remember what had happened.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go to visit someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come around</it> [=<it>come over</it>] (to my house) after work today?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to occur in the usual way as time passes <vi>I always feel a little sad when the end of the school year <it>comes around</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>what goes around comes around</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to turn to a different direction <vi>The sailboat <it>came around</it> [=<it>came about</it>] and began to head east.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come as</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe the effect that something has when people first learn about it <vi>Their decision <it>came as</it> a surprise (to me). [=their decision was a surprise to me]</vi> <vi>It should <it>come as</it> no surprise that many people oppose the plan.</vi> <vi>It <it>came as</it> a shock to me [=I was shocked] to see how old he looks now.</vi> <vi>The news of her recovery <it>came as</it> a great relief to all of us.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move toward (someone) in a threatening or aggressive way <vi>They kept <it>coming at</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be directed at or toward (someone) <vi>The questions kept <it>coming at</it> him so quickly that he didn't know how to respond to them.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to deal with or think about (something) <vi>We need to <it>come at</it> [=<it>approach</it>] these problems from a different angle.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come away from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come away from (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move away from (an area, place, etc.) <vi>The guard told him to <it>come away from</it> the door.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Most readers <it>come away from</it> the book feeling reassured. [=most readers feel reassured when they finish the book]</vi> <vi>It was a difficult experience, but she <it>came away from</it> it a stronger and more confident person.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I hope you'll <it>come back</it> and see us again soon.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a decision that may <phrase>come back to haunt us</phrase> [=a decision that may cause problems for us in the future]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a former good condition :to become strong, successful, or effective again after a time of weakness, failure, etc. <vi>It can be difficult for an athlete to <it>come back</it> [=<it>recover</it>] from an injury like this.</vi> <vi>a species that was nearly extinct but that has been <it>coming back</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become popular or fashionable again <vi>Short skirts were out of fashion for many years, but now they're <it>coming back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be successful in a game, sport, etc., after being behind <vi>The team was trailing after the first half, but they <it>came back</it> and won in the second half.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to return to someone's memory <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>I had forgotten a lot of what I learned about music, but it's all <it>coming back to</it> me now. [=I am beginning to remember it now]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to make a reply or response <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>When questioned about his involvement, he <it>came back with</it> an angry denial.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>comeback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come between</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come between (people or groups)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause disagreement between (people or groups) <vi>We shouldn't let these problems <it>come between</it> us.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a visit to someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come by</it> [=<it>come over</it>] for a while after dinner?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come by (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or acquire (something) <vi>I asked him how he <it>came by</it> the money, but he wouldn't tell me.</vi> <vi>A good job is <phrase>hard to come by</phrase>. [=it's hard to get a good job]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come cheap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cheap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come clean</dre> <dx>see <dxt>clean</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come close</dre> <dx>see <dxt>close</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move or fall downward <vi>The crowd erupted in applause as the curtain <it>came down</it>.</vi> <vi>One of the tree's branches <it>came down</it> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of rain, snow, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to fall from the sky <vi>She stood at the window, watching the rain <it>come down</it>.</vi> <vi>The rain was <it>coming down</it> in sheets. [=it was raining very heavily]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to a lower level <vi>Stock prices have continued to <it>come down</it> [=<it>fall</it>] this week. = Stocks have continued to <it>come down</it> in price this week.</vi> <vi>It's sad to see how he has <phrase>come down in the world</phrase>. [=how he has fallen to a lower position or status after being wealthy, successful, etc.]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>comedown</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to decide or say in an official or public way that you support or oppose someone or something <vi>The committee <phrase>came down in favor of</phrase> the proposal. = The committee <phrase>came down on the side of</phrase> the proposal. [=the committee approved the proposal]</vi> <vi>Some of his former supporters have <phrase>come down against</phrase> him.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>An announcement or decision that <phrase>comes down</phrase> is an announcement or decision from someone who has power or authority. <vi>Word <it>came down</it> that the strike was over.</vi> <vi>The decision <it>came down</it> in his favor.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>Something that <phrase>comes down from</phrase> the past is something that has existed for a very long time. <vi>This is a story that has <it>come down</it> from ancient times.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop feeling the effect of an illegal drug :to stop being high on a drug <vi>an addict who is <it>coming down</it> from heroin</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to criticize or punish (someone) <vi>The governor has promised to <phrase>come down hard on</phrase> corrupt officials. [=to severely punish corrupt officials]</vi> <vi>Her boss <it>came down on</it> her pretty hard when she didn't finish the report on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come down on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a strong effort to stop or oppose (something) <vi>The governor has promised to <it>come down hard on</it> corruption.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (something) as the most important part <vi>People talk about various reasons for the company's failure, but it all <it>comes down to</it> one thing: a lack of leadership.</vi> <vi>The election is going to <it>come down to</it> which candidate seems most trustworthy to the voters. [=the candidate who seems most trustworthy will win the election]</vi> <vi>It's nice to be rich, but <phrase>when you come (right) down to it</phrase>, it's more important to be healthy and happy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come down with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>She <it>came down with</it> [=<it>contracted</it>] measles.</vi> <vi>I think I may be <it>coming down with</it> [=<it>getting, catching</it>] a cold.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to say openly or publicly that you are the person who should get something or who can do something <vi>No one has yet <it>come forward</it> to claim the reward.</vi> <vi>Several people <it>came forward</it> to offer their assistance.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a specified origin or source) <vi>Wine <it>comes from</it> grapes. [=wine is made from grapes]</vi> <vi>English words <it>come from</it> a wide variety of sources.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a person's family <vi>She <it>comes from</it> a wealthy family. [=her family is wealthy]</vi> <vi>He <it>comes from</it> a long line of entertainers. [=the people in his family have been entertainers for many years]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be the result of (something) <vi>I'm not surprised that you don't feel well. That's what <it>comes from</it> not eating the right kinds of food.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be from (a place): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a person</ssl> <dt>:to have been born or raised in (a place) <vi>She <it>comes</it> (originally) <it>from</it> a small southern town.</vi> :to live in (a place) <vi>The people who attend the convention <it>come from</it> countries all around the world.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>(<it>informal</it>) I understand where you're <it>coming from</it>. [=I understand why you feel or think the way you do; I understand your point of view]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a thing</ssl> <dt>:to be produced in (a place) <vi>Where did this wine <it>come from</it>? [=where is this wine from?]</vi> <vi>There was a bad smell <it>coming from</it> the basement.</vi> <vi>A sob <it>came from</it> her throat. [=she sobbed]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>come from (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be said or told by (someone) <vi>This information <it>comes from</it> a person I trust.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Those comments are pretty surprising, <phrase>coming from you</phrase>. [=it is surprising that you would make those comments]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come full circle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>full circle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come hell or high water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come home to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>home</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>Welcome. Please <it>come in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The store will have some exciting new products <it>coming in</it> next week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be received <vi>The election results should start <it>coming in</it> soon. [=we should start receiving/getting the election results soon]</vi> <vi>The broadcast was <it>coming in</it> loud and clear. [=we could hear the broadcast very clearly]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to end a race or competition in a specified position <vi>Joan won the race and her sister <it>came in</it> [=<it>finished</it>] second.</vi> <vi>He <it>came in</it> first/last.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to have a particular role or function <vi>We're going to need someone to help with the cooking, and <phrase>that's where you come in</phrase>. [=your job will be to help us with the cooking]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>Something that <phrase>comes in handy</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>comes in useful/helpful</phrase> turns out to be useful when it is needed. <vi>A pocketknife can <it>come in handy</it>.</vi> <vi>A little extra money would <it>come in useful</it> right now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in/into bloom</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>come into flower</va></vr> <def><sl>of a plant</sl> <dt>:to begin to produce flowers :to start to bloom <vi>in early spring, when the forsythias are <it>coming into bloom</it></vi> <vi>The lilacs have begun to <it>come into flower</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or be given (something unpleasant, such as criticism) :to be subjected to (something) <vi>The government's policies are <it>coming in for</it> increasing criticism. [=more people are beginning to criticize the government's policies]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in from the cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come in on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>He says he'd like to <it>come in</it> (with us) <it>on</it> the deal.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>Everyone watched her as she <it>came into</it> the room.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to get (something) as a possession <vi>He <it>came into</it> a fortune when he inherited his father's estate.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be involved in (something) <vi>Deciding who to hire should be a business decision. You shouldn't allow personal feelings to <it>come into</it> it. [=you shouldn't allow personal feelings to affect your decision]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come into effect</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come into your own</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to have the kind of success that you are capable of having :to become very skillful, successful, etc. <vi>She has really started to <it>come into her own</it> recently.</vi> <vi>The company was struggling for many months, but now it really seems to be <it>coming into its own</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come in/into view/sight</dre> <def><dt>:to appear :to begin to be seen <vi>Another ship suddenly <it>came into view</it>.</vi> <vi>As we turned the corner, the distant mountains <it>came in sight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come naturally</dre> <dx>see <dxt>naturally</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be the result of (something) <vi>the excitement that <it>comes of</it> meeting people who share your interests</vi> <vi>They had discussions about possible new products, but <phrase>nothing came of it</phrase>. [=no new products resulted from their discussions]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come of age</dre> <dx>see <dxt>age</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>come off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop being attached to something <vi>When I tried to pick up the suitcase, the handle <it>came off</it>. = The handle <it>came off</it> the suitcase.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to produce a desired result :to succeed <vi>His plans to start his own business never <it>came off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>The meeting <it>came off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to do or perform well or badly <vi>She <it>came off</it> well in the contest.</vi> <vi>He <it>came off</it> badly/poorly in the debate.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to seem to have a specified quality or character <un>usually + <it>as</it> <vi>He's really just shy, but he <it>comes off as</it> a little arrogant. [=he seems a little arrogant]</vi> <vi>He <it>came off as</it> a stuffy old man.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>come off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to have recently completed or recovered from (something) <vi>a company that is <it>coming off</it> a very successful year</vi> <vi>an athlete who is <it>coming off</it> a serious injury</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have recently stopped using (an illegal drug) <vi>an addict who is <it>coming off</it> heroin</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>where do you come off?</phrase> to express anger or annoyance at what someone has said or done <vi><it>Where do you come off</it> talking to me like that? [=you have no right to talk to me like that; how dare you talk to me like that?]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>don't know where he comes off</phrase> making those kinds of accusations. [=he has no right to make those kinds of accusations]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come off it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop talking or acting in a foolish way <un>usually used as an interjection <vi>“I could be a pro golfer if I really tried.” “Oh, <it>come off it</it>! You're not even close to being that good!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to happen or progress as time passes <vi>Darkness <it>came on</it> rapidly/gradually [=it rapidly/gradually became dark] as the sun went down.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to happen <vi>Rain <it>came on</it> toward noon. [=it began to rain when it was almost noon]</vi> <vi>I feel a headache <it>coming on</it>.</vi> <vi>It looks like it might be <phrase>coming on to rain</phrase>. [=it looks like it might start to rain soon]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <ssl>of an electrical machine, light, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>came on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a TV or radio program</ssl> <dt>:to start <vi>That program you like is <it>coming on</it> in a few minutes.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to ask or urge someone to do something <vi>“I don't feel like going out tonight.” “Oh, <it>come on</it>! It'll do you good to get out of the house for a while.”</vi> <vi>“I don't think I can go any further.” “<it>Come on</it>! You can do it if you keep trying!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to tell someone to hurry or to go faster <vi><it>Come on</it>, let's go.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to express surprise, disbelief, etc. <vi>“I think she could win the election.” “<it>Come on</it>! She doesn't have a chance!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to have or seem to have a certain quality or nature <vi>He <it>comes on</it> [=<it>comes across</it>] as a conservative.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on strong</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be very forceful or too forceful in talking to someone or dealing with someone <vi>She didn't like him because she felt that he <it>came on</it> too <it>strong</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become stronger or more successful in a continuing contest, race, etc. <vi>The team was playing poorly in the early part of the season, but it has been <it>coming on strong</it> lately.</vi> <vi>a political candidate who has been <it>coming on strong</it> in the polls as the day of election draws closer</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come on to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to show sexual interest in (someone) :to try to start a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She complained that her boss has been <it>coming on to</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to start to talk about or deal with (something) <vi>We'll <it>come on to</it> [=<it>come to, get to</it>] that question later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become available :to begin to be produced or sold <vi>A new magazine is <it>coming out</it> next week.</vi> <vi>The book/movie <it>comes out</it> next month.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become obvious :to be clearly shown <vi>His pride <it>came out</it> in his refusal to accept help. [=his refusal to accept help showed his pride]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>The truth finally <it>came out</it>. [=people finally learned the truth]</vi> <vi>It <it>came out</it> that he had known about these problems all along, but he hadn't said anything.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to say something openly <vi>Why don't you just <it>come out</it> and say what you really think?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to say publicly that you support or oppose someone or something <vi>She <phrase>came out in favor of</phrase> the proposal.</vi> <vi>Some of his former supporters have <phrase>come out against</phrase> him.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to say openly that you are a homosexual <vi>Many gay entertainers have been reluctant to <it>come out</it>.</vi> <vi>Last year she <it>came out</it> (as a lesbian) to her parents. [=she told her parents that she is a lesbian]</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:to appear after being hidden <vi>The rain stopped and the sun/moon/stars <it>came out</it> as the clouds cleared away.</vi> :to appear in the open <vi>animals that only <it>come out</it> at night</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a flower</ssl> <dt>:to open :to blossom <vi>in the spring, when the flowers are beginning to <it>come out</it> (in bloom)</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:to end or finish in a specified way <vi>How did the game <it>come out</it>? [=<it>turn out</it>] [=who won the game?]</vi> <vi>Everything <it>came out</it> [=<it>ended up, turned out</it>] all right.</vi> <vi>She expects to <it>come out</it> ahead in the end.</vi> <vi>He's confident that he'll <it>come out</it> a winner.</vi> <vi>He's confident that he'll <phrase>come out on top</phrase> [=that he'll win] when all the votes have been counted.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a photograph</ssl> <dt>:to produce a good picture <vi>Those pictures I took at the game yesterday didn't <it>come out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the quality that something has when it is finished <vi>The picture <it>came out</it> blurry.</vi> <vi>The brownies <it>came out</it> a little too dry.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be said, expressed, or understood in a particular way <vi>That's not what I meant to say. It didn't <it>come out</it> right.</vi> <vi>He was trying to make a joke, but it <it>came out</it> wrong.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to result from (something) <vi>It's hard to see how anything good can <it>come out of</it> this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go through the experience of (something) <vi>I was lucky to <it>come out of</it> [=<it>come through</it>] the accident alive.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>come out of nowhere</phrase> is to be very surprising and unexpected or to become successful, popular, etc., in a very sudden and surprising way. <vi>That question <it>came out of nowhere</it>.</vi> <vi>a company that has <it>come out of nowhere</it> to become one of the leaders in the industry</vi></snote> <dx>see also <tag>come out of left field</tag> at <dxt>left field</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come out with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come out with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say or express (something, such as an idea) <vi>She <it>came out with</it> a new proposal.</vi> <vi>He's always saying ridiculous things. You never know what he'll <it>come out with</it> next.</vi> <vi>Why don't you just <it>come out with</it> it and say what you really think?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to publish or produce (something that will be sold to the public) <vi>a publisher that is <it>coming out with</it> a new series of children's books</vi> <vi>a car company that is <it>coming out with</it> several new models next year</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a social visit to someone <vi>Why don't you <it>come over</it> [=<it>come around</it>] (to my place) after work?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change from one side to the other in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>I've been trying to persuade her to <it>come over to</it> our side, but I haven't convinced her yet.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>become</sx> <vi>He suddenly <it>came over</it> all bashful. [=he suddenly became very bashful]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>come over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect (someone) in a sudden and strong way <vi>A sudden feeling of dread <it>came over</it> me. [=I felt a sudden feeling of dread]</vi> <vi>He's behaving so strangely. I don't know what's <it>come over</it> him lately. [=I don't know what has caused him to behave so strangely]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to succeed in doing something :to do what is needed or expected <vi>an athlete who is known for <it>coming through</it> in the clutch</vi> <vi>“I managed to get the tickets.” “Great! I knew you'd <it>come through</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to be received and understood <vi>The message <it>came through</it> loud and clear.</vi> <vi>The signal wasn't <it>coming through</it>. [=we weren't receiving the signal]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be expressed to someone <vi>Her enthusiasm really <it>came through</it> [=<it>came across</it>] when she talked about her job. [=we could see that she was really enthusiastic when she talked about her job]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be given or made official in a formal and final way <vi>We're still waiting for approval of our loan application to <it>come through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>come through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something) <vi>It was a very difficult illness, but he <it>came through</it> it in pretty good shape.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become conscious <vi>He took a bad fall and knocked himself out. When he <it>came to</it> [=<it>woke up</it>, <it>came around</it>], he didn't remember what had happened.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to reach (a place) while traveling <vi>We <it>came to</it> a fork in the road.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reach (a particular point or step in a process) <vi>Deciding to buy a new car was easy. Now we <it>come to</it> the hard part: finding the money.</vi> <vi>I can't believe that it has <it>come to</it> this.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to approach or reach (a specified condition) <vi>The water <it>came</it> slowly <it>to</it> a boil. [=the water slowly began to boil]</vi> <vi>The project suddenly <phrase>came to a stop/halt</phrase>. [=the project suddenly stopped]</vi> <vi>The work has finally <phrase>come to an end</phrase>. [=has finally ended]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>come to a bad end</tag> at <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to result in (something) <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>His ambitious plans never <it>came to</it> much.</vi> <vi>She talked about learning to fly, but it all <phrase>came to nothing</phrase> in the end. [=she never did learn to fly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to make or reach (something, such as a decision or an agreement) after thinking or talking <vi>The two sides finally <it>came to</it> an agreement/understanding after many hours of discussion.</vi> <vi>I've been thinking about what to do next, and I've <it>come to</it> a decision. [=I've made a decision]</vi> <vi>I've <phrase>come to the conclusion</phrase> [=I've decided] that we need to try a different method.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>People say that they <phrase>don't know what the world is coming to</phrase> or they ask <phrase>What is the world coming to?</phrase> when they are shocked or disgusted by something that has happened in the world. <vi>I <it>don't know what the world is coming to</it> when so many poor children have to go to bed hungry every night.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>when it comes to</phrase> is used to identify the specific topic that is being talked about. <vi><it>When it comes to</it> playing chess, he's the best I know.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>if it comes to that</phrase> means “if that is necessary.” <vi>I'm willing to pay more money <it>if it comes to that</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (an amount)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to produce (an amount) when added together <vi>The bill <it>came to</it> [=<it>amounted to</it>] 10 dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>come to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be thought of by (someone) :to occur to (someone) <vi>The answer suddenly <it>came to</it> me. [=I suddenly thought of the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>coming to</phrase> you is something that is owed to you. <vi>I have another dollar <it>coming to</it> me. [=I am owed another dollar]</vi> <vi>He wants all the credit that's <it>coming to</it> him. [=he wants all the credit that he deserves]</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get what's coming to you</phrase>, you get the punishment that you deserve. <vi>He's a dirty cheat, and I'm going to see that he <it>gets what coming to him</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>have it coming (to you)</phrase> you deserve to get something bad, such as punishment. <vi>I'm not sorry to hear that he lost his job. He <it>had it coming</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to blows</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to join or meet <vi>the place where two rivers <it>come together</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to form a group <vi>People from many different areas have <it>come together</it> to try to find a solution.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin to work or proceed in the desired way <vi>The project started slowly, but everything is finally starting to <it>come together</it> now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to grief</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grief</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to grips with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>life</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to light</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to pass</dre> <def><sl>formal + literary</sl> <dt>:to happen <vi>Many of the things he predicted have <it>come to pass</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to terms</dre> <dx>see <dxt>term</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to think of it</dre> <def><dt><un>used in speech to say that you have just remembered or thought of something <vi>The meeting is next Tuesday, which, <it>come to think of it</it>, is also the date of my doctor's appointment.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to your senses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come true</dre> <dx>see <dxt>true</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come under (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be subjected to (something) <vi>The troops were resting when they suddenly <it>came under</it> attack. [=when they were suddenly attacked]</vi> <vi>His policies have been <it>coming under</it> attack/criticism/fire from conservatives. [=conservatives have been attacking/criticizing his policies]</vi> <vi>Many people feel that their civil rights are <it>coming under</it> threat. [=are being threatened]</vi> <vi>Some of the governor's recent proposals are now <it>coming under</it> increased scrutiny. [=people are now looking more closely and critically at the proposals]</vi> <vi>The school is <it>coming under</it> pressure to change its policies.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be affected, controlled, or influenced by (something) <vi>an area that has <it>come under</it> the control of rebel forces [=an area that is now controlled by rebel forces]</vi> <vi>He was 30 years old when he first <it>came under</it> the care of a psychiatrist. [=when he first began to be treated by a psychiatrist]</vi> <vi>Many young people have <it>come under</it> his influence. [=many young people have been influenced by him]</vi> <vi>areas that <it>come under</it> his authority</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to identify the group or category that something belongs to <vi>These matters <it>come under</it> the heading of classified information.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move near to someone or something :to approach someone or something <vi>He <it>came</it> (right) <it>up</it> (to me) and introduced himself.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to be mentioned or thought of <vi>That issue never <it>came up</it>. [=<it>arose</it>]</vi> <vi>A question has <it>come up</it> about the budget.</vi> <vi>I was surprised when his name <it>came up</it> as a possible candidate for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to occur in usually a sudden or unexpected way <vi>She seems to be ready to deal with any problem that may <it>come up</it>. [=<it>arise</it>]</vi> <vi>Something has <it>come up</it> and I won't be able to attend the meeting.</vi> <vi>We need to be ready to take action if an opportunity <it>comes up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become visible in the sky :to rise <vi>She was already awake when the sun <it>came up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to first appear above the ground <vi>in the spring, when the daffodils and tulips are <it>coming up</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to finish in a specified condition or state <vi>I flipped the coin and it <it>came up</it> heads/tails.</vi> <vi>The shot <phrase>came up short</phrase>. [=the shot did not go far enough]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to move up in rank or status <vi>an officer who <phrase>came up from/through the ranks</phrase> [=who started as an ordinary soldier and rose to become an officer]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>coming up</phrase> will happen soon or will appear soon. <vi>With the election <it>coming up</it>, both candidates are spending all their time on the campaign trail.</vi> <vi>Our interview with the mayor is <it>coming</it> (right) <it>up</it> after this commercial.</vi> <vi>“I'd like a turkey sandwich and a glass of lemonade, please.” “<phrase>Coming right up</phrase>!” [=the sandwich and lemonade will be served to you very quickly]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be stopped or slowed by (something) <vi>The proposal has <it>come up against</it> some opposition. [=there is some opposition to the proposal]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up empty</dre> <def><dt>:to fail to get or find something or someone <vi>The police searched the area for clues but <it>came up empty</it>. [=they did not find any clues]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come upon</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>somewhat formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>come upon (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to meet or find (someone or something) by chance <vi>As they turned the corner, they <it>came upon</it> an unexpected scene.</vi> <vi>While researching the town's history, she <it>came upon</it> some surprising new information about its first mayor.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>come upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of a feeling</ssl> <dt>:to affect (someone) suddenly <vi>An urge to travel suddenly <it>came upon</it> him. [=he suddenly felt an urge to travel]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be as good as (something) <vi>The movie didn't <it>come up to</it> our expectations. [=was not as good as we expected it to be]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come up with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>come up with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or think of (something that is needed or wanted) <vi>We finally <it>came up with</it> a solution (to our problem).</vi> <vi>He <it>came up with</it> an interesting new method of improving the factory's efficiency.</vi> <vi>He'll be in a lot of trouble if he doesn't <it>come up with</it> the money he owes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come what may</dre> <def><dt>:regardless of what happens <vi>He promised to support her, <it>come what may</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>first come, first served</dre> <dx>see <dxt>first</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>how come</dre> <dx>see <dxt>how</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to come</dre> <def><dt>:existing or arriving in the future <vi>No one knows what will happen in the days <it>to come</it>.</vi> <vi>There will be more trouble <it>to come</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="country[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">coun*try</hw> <sound><wav>countr02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌntri</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>coun*tries</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area of land that is controlled by its own government :<sx>nation</sx> <vi>The two <it>countries</it> have a lot in common.</vi> <vi>European/foreign <it>countries</it></vi> <vi>They drove across the <it>country</it> from California to New York.</vi> <vi>They are living in different parts of the <it>country</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mother country</dxt> <dxt>old country</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the country</bnote> <dt>:the people who live in a country <vi><it>The</it> whole <it>country</it> was stunned by the news.</vi> <vi>The President has the support of most of <it>the country</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area or region that has a particular quality or feature or is known for a particular activity. <vi>He moved to the north <it>country</it> to fish and hunt.</vi> <vi>We went camping in the hill <it>country</it>.</vi> <vi>They drove through miles of open <it>country</it>.</vi> <vi>We took a trip to wine <it>country</it>. [=an area where grapes are grown and wine is made]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the country</bnote> <dt>:land that is away from big towns and cities :<sx>countryside</sx> <vi>She lives out in <it>the country</it>.</vi> <vi>They prefer <it>the country</it> to the city.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:<sx>country music</sx> <vi>She loves <it>country</it> and rock.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>across country</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:from one side of a country to the other. <vi>They drove <it>across country</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:from one side of the countryside to the other <vi>The river runs <it>across country</it>.</vi> :by a course going directly over the countryside rather than by roads <vi>The group walked <it>across country</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cross-country</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to the country</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to call for a general election to be held <vi>He <it>went to the country</it> and won.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="get"> <hw highlight="yes">get</hw> <sound><wav>get00001.wav</wav><wav>get00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɛt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gets</if></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <il>or US</il> <if>got*ten</if> <sound><wav>get00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:tn̩</pr></in> <in><if>get*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to obtain (something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to receive or be given (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> a new bicycle for his birthday.</vi> <vi>I never did <it>get</it> an answer to my question.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> a letter from my lawyer.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a phone call from her sister.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>get</it> my message?</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] a ride to town with you? [=will you give me a ride to town?]</vi> <vi>You need to <it>get</it> your mother's permission to go.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to obtain (something) through effort, chance, etc. <vi>She hasn't been able to <it>get</it> a job.</vi> <vi>It's nearly impossible to <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a reservation at that restaurant.</vi> <vi>If you want to be successful you need to <it>get</it> a good education.</vi> <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> the waiter's attention.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a look at the thief. [=she managed to look at the thief]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to obtain the use or services of (something) <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> a taxi.</vi> <vi>It's hard to <it>get</it> good help these days.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to earn or gain (something) <vi>How much does he <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a week?</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> $50 when I sold my old bicycle. = I <it>got</it> $50 for my old bicycle.</vi> <vi>He's <it>gotten</it> a bad reputation (for himself). = He's <it>gotten</it> himself a bad reputation.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> an “A” on my history exam!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>She <it>got</it> first prize in the essay contest.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to buy or pay for (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> (himself) a new car at a great price.</vi> <vi>“Did you <it>get</it> that dress at the mall?” “Yes, and I <it>got</it> it for only $20.”</vi> <vi>Do you <it>get</it> [=subscribe to] the local newspaper?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the next round of drinks.</vi> <vi>He offered to <it>get</it> the check, but I insisted on <it>getting</it> it myself.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> a beautiful necklace for his wife. = He <it>got</it> his wife a beautiful necklace.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go somewhere and come back with (something or someone) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> a pencil from the desk.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> anything for you? = Can I <it>get</it> you anything?</vi> <vi>Someone has to (go) <it>get</it> the boss from the airport and bring her back here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to send or take (something or someone) <it>to</it> a person or place <vi>I have to <it>get</it> an important message <it>to</it> her at once!</vi> <vi>We have to <it>get</it> him <it>to</it> the hospital immediately.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to move or go <vi>He quickly <it>got</it> himself and his luggage through customs.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> the car out of the garage.</vi> <vi>I could barely <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] the luggage into the car's trunk.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> this ring on/off my finger.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <vi>He <it>got</it> on the horse and rode away.</vi> <vi>We <it>got</it> on/off the bus.</vi> <vi>They quickly <it>got</it> [=<it>passed</it>] through customs.</vi> <vi>She never <it>got</it> out of the house last weekend.</vi> <vi>He lost weight to be able to <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] into his jeans again.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> between them to keep them from fighting.</vi> <vi>Ouch! <it>Get</it> off my foot!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>When did you <it>get</it> here/there?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> home last night.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have (a feeling, an idea, etc.) <vi>I <it>got</it> a funny feeling when I saw her again.</vi> <vi>He somehow <it>got</it> the idea that I was lying to him.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> the impression that he wasn't interested.</vi> <vi>One thing led to another, and—well, <phrase>you get the picture/idea</phrase>. [=you can easily guess the rest]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become affected by (a disease) <vi>I <it>got</it> a bad cold when I was on vacation.</vi> <vi>Clean the wound carefully so you don't <it>get</it> an infection.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suffer (an injury) <vi>He <it>got</it> a broken nose in a fight.</vi> <vi>Where/how did you <it>get</it> that bruise on your leg?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or experience (something) <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> a lot of rain recently.</vi> <vi>I finally <it>got</it> a good night's sleep last night. [=I finally slept well last night]</vi> <vi>The inn doesn't <it>get</it> many visitors these days.</vi> <vi>“Do people often ask if you're Irish?” “Yes, I <it>get</it> that a lot.” [=people ask me that often]</vi> <vi><phrase>You get</phrase> [=there are] so many crazy drivers these days.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a particular reaction) <vi>That joke always <it>gets</it> a laugh.</vi> <vi>Her comments <it>got</it> an angry reaction.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make progress in some activity <vi>He hasn't <it>gotten</it> far with the essay. [=he hasn't made much progress with the essay]</vi> <vi>You won't <it>get</it> anywhere with flattery. [=you won't succeed by using flattery]</vi> <vi>At last we're <phrase>getting somewhere</phrase> (with our work)!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get ahead <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to make progress <vi>All that effort didn't really <it>get</it> us very far.</vi> <vi>Flattery will <phrase>get you nowhere</phrase>. = Flattery <phrase>won't get you anywhere</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a specified position or condition <vi>He <it>got</it> his feet wet when he stepped in a puddle.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> his nose broken in a fight. [=his nose was broken in a fight]</vi> <vi>I told you not to <it>get</it> yourself dirty.</vi> <vi>You nearly <it>got</it> us both killed!</vi> <vi>I need to <it>get</it> [=<it>have</it>] my hair cut.</vi> <vi>She finally <it>got</it> her office organized.</vi> <vi>He promised to <it>get</it> the work done quickly. [=to do the work quickly]</vi> <vi>When you're making a measurement be careful to <phrase>get it right</phrase>. [=to do it correctly]</vi> <vi>Let me <phrase>get this straight</phrase> [=let me be sure that I understand this correctly]: are you saying that you won't help us?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do something <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> the children <it>to behave</it>.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>get</it> you <it>to understand</it> that this isn't a good idea?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>to work</it> again.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>working</it> again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start <it>doing</it> something <vi>We <it>got talking</it> about old times.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>1a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or be given the chance <it>to do</it> something :to be able <it>to do</it> something <vi>She never <it>got to go</it> to college.</vi> <vi>Why do I never <it>get to drive</it> the car?</vi> <vi>She hopes she'll finally <it>get to spend</it> more time working on her garden this year.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to deal with (something that needs attention): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to answer (a telephone) <vi>Would somebody please <it>get</it> the phone?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to open (a door) <vi>If you'll <it>get</it> the door for me, I'll carry that box inside.</vi> <vi>There's someone at the door. Would you please <phrase>get it</phrase>? [=open the door and deal with the person who knocked]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to understand (something or someone) <vi>I just don't <it>get</it> the point of what you're saying.</vi> <vi>He didn't <it>get</it> the joke.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>get</it> what you mean.</vi> <vi>Oh, now I <phrase>get it</phrase>. [=<it>understand</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I just don't <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>Don't <phrase>get me wrong</phrase>. [=don't misunderstand what I am saying]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>get your drift</phrase>. [=I understand what you are saying]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I didn't quite <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] his name.</vi></dt> <sn>17 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:<sx>become <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>My hands <it>got</it> dirty when I was working in the garden.</vi> <vi>I <it>get</it> very nervous when I have to speak in public.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> sick last week but I'm feeling better now.</vi> <vi>I just can't <it>get</it> used to this cold weather.</vi> <vi>She sent her sick friend a “<it>Get</it> Well Soon” card.</vi> <vi>I should go; it's <it>getting</it> late.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) Your daughter's <it>getting</it> quite a big girl now!</vi> <vi>We need to finish by 5 o'clock, so we'd better <phrase>get busy</phrase>. [=begin to work]</vi> <vi>You've never heard of the Internet? Come on, now. <phrase>Get with it</phrase>. [=become up-to-date in your knowledge]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>how stupid/lucky (etc.) can you get</phrase> to mean that someone or something is unusually stupid, lucky, etc. <vi>He tried to rob a policeman. <it>How stupid can you get</it>? [=he was very stupid to try to rob a policeman]</vi> <vi>Just look at that dress! <it>How tacky can you get</it>? [=that dress is very tacky]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change in a specified way as time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Your daughter is <it>getting to be</it> [=is becoming] quite a big girl now!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Once you <it>get to know</it> him, you will like him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>be</it> with the past participle of some verbs to form passive constructions <vi>They <it>got</it> [=<it>were</it>] married last month.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>was</it>] paid for his work.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> arrested for fraud.</vi> <vi>I nearly <it>got</it> killed.</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a meal) <vi>We <it>got</it> dinner at an Italian restaurant last night.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare (a meal) <vi>On weekends, my wife sleeps late while I <it>get</it> breakfast.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (punishment) <vi>He <it>got</it> five years in prison for his crime.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you don't stop misbehaving you're going to <phrase>get it</phrase> when your father gets home! [=your father is going to punish you]</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to grip and hold (something or someone) <vi>The dog <it>got</it> the thief by the leg.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>] me around/by the neck and wouldn't let go.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find and catch (someone) <vi>The Royal Canadian Mounted Police always <it>get</it> their man! [=they always capture the man they are trying to capture]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone) <vi>The bullet <it>got</it> him in the leg.</vi></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or cause trouble for (someone) <vi>He's convinced that his ex-wife is out to <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you if it's the last thing I do!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the death of (someone) <vi>He had heart problems for many years, but it was pneumonia that <it>got</it> him in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>It really <it>gets</it> me that such a foolish man has so much influence.</vi> <vi>What <it>gets</it> me is all these delays!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) sad <vi>The end of that movie always <it>gets</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2b (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be fooled or unable to think of an answer <vi>Well, you <it>got</it> [=<it>fooled, tricked</it>] me that time. That was very clever.</vi> <vi>That's a good question. <phrase>You've got me (there)</phrase>. [=I don't know the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a phone call and hear or speak to (a person or answering machine) <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get</it> [=<it>reach</it>] you (on the phone) all day!</vi> <vi>When I tried to call him I <it>got</it> his answering machine. [=the phone was answered by his answering machine]</vi></dt> <sn>28</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (a radio or TV station or channel) <vi>We don't <it>get</it> this channel at home.</vi></dt> <sn>29</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce or provide (a level of performance) <vi>Our new car <it>gets</it> [=<it>delivers</it>] excellent gas mileage.</vi></dt> <sn>30</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to notice (someone or something) <vi>Did you <it>get</it> the way he looked at you?</vi> <un>often used to direct someone's attention to a person or thing that is seen as foolish, surprising, etc. <vi>Just <it>get</it> him in his new pants!</vi> <vi>She showed up at the party in—<phrase>get this</phrase>—a $3,000 designer dress!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>get about</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get above yourself</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my point has finally <it>gotten across</it> to you. [=I hope you finally understand what I am trying to say]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my point <it>across</it> to you.</vi> <vi>a politician who is trying hard to <it>get</it> his message <it>across</it> (to the voters)</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>get after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to tell (someone) repeatedly to do something <vi>His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him about doing his homework. = His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him to do his homework.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to become more successful <vi>a book about how to <it>get ahead</it> in the business world</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be or remain friendly <vi>We <it>get along</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi> <vi>My brother and my uncle don't really <it>get along</it> (with each other).</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How are you <it>getting along</it> with your work? [=how's your work coming along?]</vi> <vi>He never showed up, but we managed to <it>get along</it> [=<it>get by</it>] without him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>I really must be <it>getting along</it>. [=<it>going, leaving</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become old <vi>Her parents are <phrase>getting along in years</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to go, walk, or travel to different places <vi>She <it>gets around</it> a lot because of her job.</vi> <vi>He's having trouble <it>getting around</it> because of his sore knee.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get round</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to become known by many people <vi>People will be shocked when the news about her arrest <it>gets around</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got around</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to avoid being stopped by (something) :to avoid having to deal with (something) <vi>I'm sure we can find a way to <it>get around</it> these problems.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no getting around</phrase> the fact that the current system isn't working. [=there is no way to deny that the current system isn't working]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around to (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or deal with (something that you have not yet done or dealt with) <vi>Don't you think it's about time you <it>got around to</it> tidying your room?</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call her, but I just haven't <it>gotten around to</it> it. [=I haven't called her]</vi> <vi>Sooner or later we'll have to <it>get around to</it> the subject of taxation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach (something or someone) <vi>The valve is hard to <it>get at</it> unless you have a special tool.</vi> <vi>An angry mob tried to <it>get at</it> him but the police protected him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find out (information that is hidden or hard to know) <vi>How can we ever <it>get at</it> the truth?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or suggest (something) in an indirect way <un>usually used as <phrase>getting at</phrase> <vi>Just what are you <it>getting at</it>? [=what are you suggesting?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>He says his teachers are always <it>getting at</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>getting on</it>] him unfairly.</vi> <vi>He's always being <it>got at</it> by his teachers.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You have a lot of work to do so you'd better <it>get at it</it>. [=<it>get to it</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go away from a place <vi>I'll be busy at work all day and I can't <it>get away</it> until tonight.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company is having problems because they've <phrase>gotten away from</phrase> the things they do best. [=they have stopped doing the things they do best]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go away from your home for a vacation <vi>I'm taking some time off because I really need to <it>get away</it> for a few days.</vi> <vi>We went on a cruise to <phrase>get away from it all</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to avoid being caught :to escape <vi>The robbers <it>got away</it> (from the police) in a fast car.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The robbers <it>got away with</it> a lot of stolen jewelry.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can't <it>get away</it> from the facts. = <phrase>There's no getting away from</phrase> the facts. [=you can't avoid or deny the facts; the facts are known and cannot be ignored]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>getaway</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be criticized or punished for (something) <vi>She's incredibly rude. I don't know how she <it>gets away with</it> it.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>There's a chance of rain, but I think I can probably <it>get away with</it> leaving my umbrella at home. [=I probably will not need my umbrella]</vi> <vi>It would be nice to have more food for the party, but I think we can <it>get away with</it> what we have. [=I think what we have is enough and will not cause problems for us]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given only slight or mild punishment for a crime or for doing something wrong <vi>The policeman stopped her for speeding but let her <it>get away with</it> just a warning.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get away with murder</tag> at <dxt>murder</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place after going away <vi>When did you <it>get back</it> from your vacation?</vi> <vi>We <it>got back</it> to the office in the early afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to return to an activity, condition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Things are finally <it>getting back to</it> normal.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>get back to</it> the topic we were discussing yesterday.</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>get back to work</phrase>. [=to start working again]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or obtain (something you have lost) again :to recover (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> his old job <it>back</it> after a long struggle.</vi> <vi>Someone stole his wallet but he <it>got</it> it <it>back</it> from the police.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back at (someone)</pva> <pvl>or Brit</pvl> <pva>get your own back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do something bad or unpleasant to someone who has treated you badly or unfairly <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you <it>back</it> for what you did to me!</vi> <vi>After he lost his job, he vowed that he would find a way to <it>get back at</it> his old boss.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get back to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk to or write to (someone) at a later time in order to give more information, answer a question, etc. <vi>He <it>got back to</it> me (by e-mail) in a few days with a new offer.</vi> <vi>“How much will it cost?” “I'm not sure. I'll have to <it>get back to</it> you on that.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to call (someone) back on the telephone <vi>“There's someone on the phone for you, sir.” “Tell them I can't take their call now but I'll <it>get back to</it> them as soon as I can.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back to (the) basics</dre> <dx>see <dxt>basic</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fail to do something as quickly as required or expected <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> further (and further) <it>behind</it> (schedule).</vi> <vi>We <it>got behind</it> with our car payments.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get behind (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to support (someone or something) <vi>The proposal may succeed if a few more people <it>get behind</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do enough or to do well enough to avoid failure <vi>He's doing very well in his history classes, but he's barely <it>getting by</it> in math.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be able to live or to do what is needed by using what you have even though you do not have much <vi>We don't have a lot of money, but we <it>get by</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>How can you <it>get by on</it> such a small salary?</vi></un> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>We <it>got by with</it> a minimum of clothing when we went camping.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get cracking</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>The weather was really <it>getting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Talking about politics always <it>gets</it> me <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to swallow (something) :to eat or drink (something) <vi>You'll feel better once you <it>get</it> this medicine <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to write (something) down <vi>If you have a good idea, you should <it>get</it> it <it>down</it> (in writing) so that you won't forget it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to play music or dance with skill and enthusiasm <vi>She likes to <it>get down</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) :to begin to give your attention or effort to (something) <vi>It's time to stop delaying and <it>get down to</it> work.</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>get down to business</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk about or describe (something) in a very simple and accurate way <vi><phrase>When you get right down to it</phrase>, this movie is just not very good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get even</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get going</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave <vi>We ought to <it>get going</it> if we don't want to be late.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You should <it>get going</it> on that assignment.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to start talking <vi>Once he <it>gets going</it> about the war you can't shut him up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to start talking <vi>Don't <it>get</it> him <it>going</it> about the war or you'll never shut him up!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>The burglar <it>got in</it> through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The train <it>got in</it> late.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to arrive home <vi>Her husband was out late last night. He didn't <it>get in</it> until almost midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become involved in an activity <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got in</it> at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be chosen or elected for office <vi>The mayor <it>got in</it> by a very slim margin.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>It's a very good school. I hope your daughter <it>gets in</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (someone) come to your home, business, etc., to do work <vi>We had to <it>get</it> a doctor/plumber <it>in</it> to deal with the emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do or say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get</it> a few good punches <it>in</it> before they stopped the fight.</vi> <vi>May I <phrase>get a word in</phrase> here? [=may I say something here?]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get a word in edgewise</tag> at <dxt>edgewise</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send or deliver (something) to the proper person or place <vi>Did you <it>get</it> your assignment <it>in</it> on time?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to do (something) in the amount of time that is available <vi>I was able to <it>get in</it> a few hours of reading last night.</vi> <vi>I hope we can <it>get in</it> a visit to the art museum the next time we're in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to harvest (a crop) and put it in a safe or dry place <vi>It's time to <it>get</it> the crop/harvest <it>in</it>.</vi> <vi>We'd better <it>get</it> the hay <it>in</it> before it rains.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>It sounds like an interesting project and I'd like to <it>get in on</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become friends with (someone) <vi>She <it>got in with</it> [=<it>fell in with</it>] a bad crowd and got into trouble.</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>get in good with</phrase> the boss. [=he got the boss to like him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (a place)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>The burglar <it>got into</it> the house through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The train <it>got into</it> New York late last night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become involved in (an activity) <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got into</it> it at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to be interested in and to enjoy (something) <vi>It's only recently that I've really <it>gotten into</it> music.</vi> <vi>I tried reading the book, but I just couldn't <it>get into</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>I hope your daughter <it>gets into</it> the school.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>into</it> the school.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become involved or to cause (someone) to become involved in (something bad, such as trouble or a fight) <vi>He <it>got into</it> a lot of trouble when he was a teenager.</vi> <vi>They <it>got into</it> an argument.</vi> <vi>His friends <it>got</it> him <it>into</it> trouble.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll tell you what happened, but I don't want to <it>get into</it> [=<it>go into</it>] all the reasons for why it happened.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>got into (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect the behavior of (someone) <un>used to say that someone is behaving in an unusual way and you don't know why <vi>I don't know what has <it>gotten into</it> him lately.</vi> <vi>She never used to be so rude to people. <phrase>What got into her?</phrase> [=why is she behaving this way?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get lost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get lucky</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lucky</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get moving</dre> <dx>see <dxt>move</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave at the start of a journey <vi>We <it>got off</it> early on our camping trip.</vi> <un>often used figuratively in the phrase <phrase>get off to a good/bad (etc.) start</phrase> <vi>He and I <it>got off to a bad start</it>, but now we get along well.</vi> <vi>The project <it>got off to a slow start</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>get off on the right/wrong foot</tag> at <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be punished for a crime :to be judged not guilty of a crime <vi>He's been arrested several times, but he always <it>gets off</it>.</vi> :to help (someone) to be judged not guilty <vi>His lawyer <it>got</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given or to help (someone) to be given only a slight punishment for a crime <vi>She <it>got off</it> lightly.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He <it>got off with</it> a light sentence.</vi> <vi>His lawyer tried to <it>get</it> him <it>off with</it> a light sentence.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>It was a bad accident. You're lucky that you <it>got off with</it> just a broken leg—you could have been killed!</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being on or against someone or something <vi><it>Get off</it>—you're hurting me!</vi> <vi>I took the subway and <it>got off</it> at the downtown station.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>5a</dxn> <dxn>b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop talking about (something) or to cause (someone) to stop talking about (something) <vi>We somehow <it>got off</it> (the subject of) work and started talking about our personal lives.</vi> <vi>I tried to change the subject, but I couldn't <it>get</it> her <it>off</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off work</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to finish working and leave the place where you work <vi>I <it>get off</it> early on Fridays.</vi> <vi>I <it>got off work</it> early last Thursday so I could see the parade.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write and send (a letter, an e-mail message, etc.) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the letter <it>off</it> (to them) tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to shoot (something) from a gun <vi>The policeman <it>got off</it> [=<it>fired</it>] several shots before the criminal escaped.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He managed to <it>get off</it> a few good jokes in his speech.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to fall asleep or to help (someone, such as a baby) to fall asleep <vi>I had just <it>got off</it> [=<it>dropped off</it>] when the doorbell rang. = I had just <phrase>got off to sleep</phrase> when the doorbell rang.</vi> <vi>I just <it>got</it> the baby <it>off to sleep</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have an orgasm or to cause (someone) to have an orgasm</dt> <sn>9</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal + sometimes disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy or be excited by (something) especially in a sexual way <vi>He's one of those guys who seem to <it>get off on</it> making other people feel guilty.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone) :to begin a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She found out he'd <it>gotten off with</it> another woman.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>tell someone where to get off</phrase> is to criticize or disagree with someone in a very direct and angry way. <vi>I was sick of listening to his constant complaints, so I <it>told him where to get off</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>don't know where someone gets off</phrase> (doing something), you are angry because someone has done something that is not right. <vi>I <it>don't know where he gets off</it> telling me what to do. = <phrase>Where does he get off</phrase> telling me what to do? [=he has no right to tell me what to do]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you. I'll let you <it>get on with</it> your work.</vi> <vi>You need to stop feeling sorry for yourself and just <phrase>get on with your life</phrase>. [=return to doing the things you do in your normal life]</vi> <vi>This introduction is taking forever. I wish they'd just <phrase>get on with it</phrase>. [=stop delaying and get to the interesting or important part]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be or remain friendly :to get along <vi>They've never really <it>got on</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>We <it>get on</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How is your daughter <it>getting on</it> in/at school?</vi> <vi>We can <it>get on</it> [=<it>get along, get by, manage</it>] just fine without them.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to achieve greater success :to get ahead <vi>an ambitious young woman trying to <it>get on</it> in business</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“These files need to be organized.” “I'll <it>get on</it> it right away.”</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>His boss has been <it>getting on</it> him about the quality of his work.</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>getting on his case</phrase> about cleaning his room. [=she's always telling him to clean it]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it on</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <dt>:to have sex</dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on in years</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to grow old <vi>My grandmother is <it>getting on</it> [=<it>aging</it>] a bit, but she's still very active.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become late <vi>It's <it>getting on</it>, and we really ought to go.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to move toward becoming (a specified age, time, etc.) <vi>He's <it>getting on for</it> 70. [=he's approaching 70; he is nearly 70]</vi> <vi>It was <it>getting on for</it> noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get onto</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>get on to</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“We need someone to send out the invitations.” “I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get on</it>] it right away.”</vi> :to start to talk about something <vi>How did we <it>get onto</it> this topic?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to speak to or write to (someone) about a particular problem, job, etc. <vi>I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get in touch with</it>] the doctor/plumber straightaway and see if he'll come round.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave or escape from a place, a vehicle, etc. <vi>He was trapped in the burning building/car, but he was somehow able to <it>get out</it> (of it) alive.</vi> <un>used as an angry way to tell someone to leave <vi><it>Get out</it>! I never want to see you again!</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to leave or escape <vi>The firemen managed to <it>get</it> him <it>out</it> (of the burning building) alive.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) from storage so that it can be used <vi>It's raining. I'd better <it>get out</it> the umbrella.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to places outside your home for social occasions, events, etc. <vi>You spend too much time at home. You need to <it>get out</it> more.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>Their secret <it>got out</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got out</it> that she was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get out</it> a few words before he collapsed.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to show that you are surprised by something or do not believe it <vi>“They gave the job to Jane.” “<it>Get out</it>!” = “<phrase>Get out of here</phrase>!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get out of (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone or something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to avoid doing (something) or to help (someone) to avoid doing (something) <vi>I didn't want to go to the lecture, but I couldn't <it>get out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>He tried to <it>get out of</it> doing his homework.</vi> <vi>My sister said she could <it>get</it> me <it>out of</it> going to the party if I really didn't want to go</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having (a habit) or to cause (someone) to stop having (a habit) <vi>I used to exercise every day, but I <it>got out of</it> the habit.</vi> <vi>All the extra work I've been doing has <it>gotten</it> me <it>out of</it> the habit of exercising.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop being in or involved in (something) or to cause (someone or something) to stop being in or involved in (something) <vi>The company has decided to <it>get</it> (itself) <it>out of</it> the computer business.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> her money <it>out of</it> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something) from (something or someone) <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> the gun <it>out of</it> the suspect's hand.</vi> <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> a confession <it>out of</it> the suspect.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to gain (something) from (something) <vi>What do you hope to <it>get out of</it> this experience?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop being controlled or bothered by (something, such as a problem or feeling) <vi>You need to <it>get over</it> [=<it>overcome</it>] your fear of being lied to.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy about (something) <vi>She's disappointed about their decision, but she'll <it>get over</it> it eventually.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that you are very surprised or impressed by something <vi>I just can't <it>get over</it> how much weight you've lost!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become healthy again after (an illness) <vi>He had a bad cold, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> it completely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy after ending a relationship with (someone) <vi>He broke up with his girlfriend a couple of months ago, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get (something) over with</va></svr> <dt>:to cause or experience the end of (something) :to finish (something) <vi>I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over</it>! = I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over with</it>! = I just want to <phrase>get</phrase> this ordeal <phrase>over and done with</phrase>! [=I want this ordeal to end]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get over (something)</va></svr> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my message <it>over</it> [=<it>across</it>] to them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get real</dre> <dx>see <dxt>real</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rid of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roll</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>best</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the better of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get there</dre> <def><dt>:to reach a goal :to do what you are trying to do <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we'll <it>get there</it> eventually. [=we'll make a profit eventually]</vi> :to come closer to reaching a goal <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we're <it>getting there</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to finish a job or activity <vi>When you <it>get through</it> (with that job), I've got something else for you to do.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or finish (something, such as an amount of work) <vi>We <it>got through</it> [=<it>covered</it>] all of the material that we wanted to cover.</vi> <vi>There's still a lot of paperwork to be <it>gotten through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to complete or to help (someone) to complete (a test, an exam, etc.) successfully <vi>She studied hard and <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] her exams.</vi> <vi>The extra hours of study are what <it>got</it> her <it>through</it> her exams.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pass through or beyond something that blocks you or slows you down <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting through</it> to the flood victims.</vi> :to cause (something) to pass through or beyond something <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get</it> our truck <it>through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting</it> supplies <it>through</it> to the flood victims.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something that is difficult, dangerous, etc.) <vi>It was a very difficult time in our marriage, but we <it>got through</it> it.</vi> <vi>I don't know how those early settlers managed to <it>get through</it> [=<it>survive</it>] the winter.</vi> :to help (someone) to live through (something) <vi>It was pure determination that <it>got</it> them <it>through</it> that crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] all the money he inherited in just a few years.</vi> <vi>They <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my message has finally <it>gotten through to</it> you. [=I hope you finally understand my message]</vi> <vi>I think my message finally <it>got through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through to (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express something clearly so that it is understood by (someone) <vi>I've talked to him many times, but I just can't seem to <it>get through to</it> him.</vi> <vi>I hope I've finally <it>gotten</it> my message <it>through to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a successful telephone call to someone <vi>I tried to call home but I couldn't <it>get through</it>.</vi> <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get through to</it> you (on the phone) all day!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or approved by an official group <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] and eventually became a law.</vi> <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] Congress and eventually became a law.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>She sometimes <it>gets to worrying</it> over her health.</vi> <vi>We <it>got to talking</it> about old times.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to deal with (something) <vi>The letter is on my desk, but I haven't <it>gotten to</it> it yet.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get to</it> the accounts as soon as I can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>All these delays are starting to <it>get to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel sad <vi>The movie's sad ending really <it>got to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to change or influence the behavior of (someone) wrongly or illegally by making threats, paying money, etc. <vi>The witness changed his story. Someone must have <it>gotten to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to or reach (somewhere) <vi>We <it>got to</it> the station/airport just in time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to meet and spend time together <vi>I'd like to <it>get together</it> with you soon.</vi> <vi>He often <it>gets together</it> with his friends after work.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to have a sexual or romantic relationship <vi>He and his wife first <it>got together</it> in college.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to meet or to have a relationship <vi>Their shared interest in photography is what <it>got</it> them <it>together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept something <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The two sides have been unable to <it>get together on</it> a new contract.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get together (things or people)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (things or people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to collect (things) or gather (people) into one place or group <vi>He <it>got together</it> [=<it>assembled</it>] a great art collection.</vi> <vi>The government <it>got together</it> a group of experts to study the problem.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>get together</it> [=<it>obtain</it>] the money we need to buy a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get your act together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get yourself together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get it together</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get your life together</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to live in a good and sensible way :to stop being confused, foolish, etc. <vi>His life got much better when he stopped drinking and <it>got his act together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to function in a skillful or effective way <vi>The company finally <it>got its act together</it> and started making a profit this year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to sleep</dre> <def><dt>:to start sleeping :to fall asleep <vi>She finally <it>got to sleep</it> after midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to work</dre> <def><dt>:to start working <vi>We need to stop delaying and <it>get to work</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to rise or to cause (someone) to rise after lying or sleeping in a bed <vi>I <it>got up</it> [=got out of bed] early this morning.</vi> <vi>I woke up early but I didn't <it>get up</it> till later.</vi> <vi>The alarm clock <it>got</it> me <it>up</it> earlier than usual.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stand up <vi>He <it>got up</it> to greet her when she entered the room.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as courage) in yourself by trying or making an effort <vi>He couldn't <it>get up</it> the courage to ask her out on a date.</vi> <vi>She was so tired she could hardly <it>get up</it> the energy to make dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare or organize (something that involves a group of people) <vi>They're trying to <it>get up</it> a petition to have the movie theater reopened.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to get an erection</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up on the wrong side of the bed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get what's coming to you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get wind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your goat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have got</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="knuckle[1]"> <hw hindex="1">knuck*le</hw> <sound><wav>knuckl01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnʌkəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>knuck*les</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:any one of the thick, bony parts (called joints) in your fingers <vi>She rapped her <it>knuckles</it> on the table.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a piece of meat that includes a joint from the leg of an animal <vi>a pork <it>knuckle</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a rap on/over/across the knuckles</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>rap (someone) on/over/across the knuckles</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rap</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="put[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">put</hw> <sound><wav>put00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpʊt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>puts</if></in> <in><if>put</if></in> <in><if>put*ting</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular place or position <vi>She <it>put</it> [=<it>placed, set</it>] the plant near the window.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the car in the garage.</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> the keys on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his arms around her and held her tight.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to go into or through something in a forceful way <vi>He fell and accidentally <it>put</it> his hand through a window.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be in a particular place or send (someone) to a particular place <vi>The illness <it>put</it> her in the hospital for three days.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her in prison for forgery.</vi> <vi>Her parents decided to <it>put</it> her in a special school for deaf children.</vi> <vi>If she drove 55 mph for 20 minutes, that would <it>put</it> her about halfway there by now.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to show that (someone or something) is in a particular place <vi>The evidence/report <it>puts</it> the defendant at the scene of the crime. [=it shows that the defendant was at the scene of the crime]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to write (something) with a pen or pencil in or on something <vi>Don't forget to <it>put</it> your signature on the check.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his phone number on a napkin.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> a circle around the correct answer.</vi> <vi>I wrote that the answer was option B. What did you <it>put</it>?</vi> <vi>She had always dreamed of writing a novel, but she never actually <phrase>put pen to paper</phrase>. [=started writing]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular state or condition <vi>Not exercising <it>puts</it> you at greater risk of developing heart disease.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the TV on channel 5, please.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you in charge/command/control?</vi> <vi>I told her some jokes to <it>put</it> her in/into a good mood.</vi> <vi>His careless spending <it>put</it> him in/into debt.</vi> <vi>Their actions have <it>put</it> them in serious danger.</vi> <vi>Her reassuring words <phrase>put us at ease</phrase>. [=made us feel calm and relaxed]</vi> <vi><phrase>Put</phrase> that idea <phrase>out of your mind</phrase>. [=stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>They said they shot the injured horse to <phrase>put</phrase> it <phrase>out of its misery</phrase>. [=so that it would not continue to suffer]</vi> <vi>They have <phrase>put</phrase> their competitors <phrase>out of business</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The new technology could <phrase>put him out of a job</phrase>. = It could <phrase>put him out of work</phrase>. [=it could make him lose his job]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>putting</phrase> the children <phrase>to bed</phrase>. [=helping them get into their beds]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do work or perform a task <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>put</it> the kids <it>to</it> work cleaning the basement.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) <vi>They are ready to <it>put</it> the plan in action/motion.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> an idea into action/effect/practice</vi> <vi>The new weapon was immediately <phrase>put to use</phrase> by the military.</vi> <vi>I don't need this camera, but maybe you can <phrase>put it to good use</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (something) to have an effect on someone or something <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>puts</it> [=<it>places</it>] great emphasis <it>on</it> the need for new leadership. [=he strongly emphasizes the need for new leadership]</vi> <vi>She has been <it>putting</it> pressure <it>on</it> us to finish the project early.</vi> <vi>Another child would <it>put</it> a heavy strain <it>on</it> their finances. [=would strain their finances very much]</vi> <vi>A special tax/duty/surcharge was <it>put on</it> luxury items.</vi> <vi>They want to <it>put</it> a limit <it>on</it> government spending.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to say or express (something) <vi>As she <it>put</it> it, “You can't please everyone.”</vi> <vi>How should I <it>put</it> this? I don't think you're cut out for this job.</vi> <vi>Well <it>put</it>!</vi> <vi>Let me <it>put</it> it another way.</vi> <vi>I think you're incompetent, <phrase>to put it bluntly</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It was a difficult experience, <phrase>to put it mildly</phrase>. [=it was a very difficult experience]</vi> <vi>She finds it hard to <phrase>put her feelings into words</phrase>. [=to say what her feelings are]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to ask (a question) or make (a suggestion) to someone <vi>Let me <it>put</it> this question to you [=let me ask you this question]: what do we do now?</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> my plan/proposal before the board of directors for consideration.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to ask a group of people to formally vote on (something) <vi>They plan on <it>putting</it> the motion/resolution to a/the vote this afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to add music to (words) <vi>She writes the lyrics and he <it>puts</it> [=<it>sets</it>] them to music.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to throw (a shot put)</dt></def> <dro><dre>I wouldn't put it past (someone)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>past</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put about (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to tell many people about (something) <vi>They <it>put about</it> the news that he was resigning. = They <it>put</it> it <it>about</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to change direction <vi>The ship <it>put about</it> and sailed back out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat or ship) to change direction <vi>a boat that can be <it>put about</it> quickly</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to get (something) across <vi>She has had trouble <it>putting</it> her message <it>across</it> to voters.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) across as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>He tries to <it>put himself across as</it> [=to make other people believe that he is] a nice guy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put a foot wrong</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>She's been <it>putting aside</it> some money for a vacation.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>put</it> a few minutes <it>aside</it> for a short meeting?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop worrying or thinking about (something) <vi>We need to <it>put</it> these problems <it>aside</it> for now and get the work done.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>put aside</it> our differences and start working together.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to guess or estimate (something) to be (something) <vi>The coroner <it>put</it> his time of death <it>at</it> 7:00. [=the coroner estimated that the time of his death was 7:00]</vi> <vi>Recent estimates <it>put</it> the number of unreported cases <it>at</it> 2,000 each year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put away</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> the pictures <it>away</it> for safekeeping.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> your notes <it>away</it>. It's time for the test.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>Her parents started <it>putting away</it> money for her education the year she was born.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to eat (a large amount of food) <vi>I used to <it>put away</it> huge meals before I went on a diet.</vi> <vi>That guy can really <phrase>put it away</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be kept in a prison or mental hospital <vi>He's a vicious criminal. I hope they <it>put</it> him <it>away</it> for the rest of his life.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>Remember to <it>put</it> the vacuum cleaner <it>back</it> in the closet after you've used it.</vi> <vi>The books had been <it>put back</it> neatly on the shelf.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to change (a planned event) to start at a later date or time <vi>They <it>put back</it> [=<it>pushed back</it>, <it>postponed</it>] the game until next week.</vi> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put back</it> from 1 p.m. to 3 p.m.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask (a person or group) to make a decision about (something) <vi>The problem of downtown parking was <it>put before</it> the mayor/council.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put</it> this question <it>before</it> the voters.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) behind you</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop worrying about or being upset by (something that happened in the past) <vi>It was a disappointing loss, but we need to <it>put it behind us</it> and focus on winning the next game.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the past <it>behind you</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put by (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to save (money) for a later time <vi>She has <it>put</it> some money <it>by</it> [=<it>put aside</it>] for emergencies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) down</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>put down (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (someone or something that you have been holding or carrying) on a table, on the floor, etc. <vi>She carefully <it>put</it> the vase <it>down</it> on the table.</vi> <vi>The police ordered him to <it>put down</it> the gun.</vi> <vi>I don't need you to carry me. <it>Put</it> me <it>down</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to a list <vi>Don't forget to <it>put down</it> milk and bread on the shopping list.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say critical or insulting things about (someone or something) <vi>He frequently <it>puts down</it> her work.</vi> <vi>Her parents are always <it>putting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>puts himself down</phrase> a lot, but he's really quite an attractive man.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-down</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write (something) :to record (something) in writing <vi>She says that the reporter <it>put</it> her quote <it>down</it> incorrectly.</vi> <vi>Every night, he <it>puts</it> his thoughts <it>down</it> in a journal.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put down</it> my thoughts on paper before I forget them.</vi> <vi>What answer did you <it>put down</it> on the test?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (an amount of money) as a first payment when you are buying something that costs a lot of money <vi>We <it>put</it> 10 percent <it>down</it> on the house. = We <it>put down</it> a 10 percent deposit on the house.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> no money <it>down</it> and pay no interest on the car until next year.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to put (something) in place on the floor or ground <vi><it>Putting down</it> [=<it>installing</it>] a new hardwood floor would greatly increase the value of your home.</vi> <vi>We <it>put down</it> a layer of mulch in the rose garden.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop (a violent or dangerous activity) by using force <vi>Federal troops were brought in to help <it>put down</it> the riot.</vi> <vi><it>put down</it> a rebellion/revolt/uprising</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to kill (an animal) in a way that causes it little pain usually because it is injured or sick <vi>They had to have their dog <it>put down</it> [=<it>put to sleep</it>] by the vet.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to end a telephone connection <vi>She said goodbye and <phrase>put down the phone</phrase>. [=<it>hung up the phone</it>]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put the phone down on him</phrase>. [=she hung up the phone while he was still talking to her]</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to formally suggest (something) as an idea to be discussed and voted on by a group of people :to propose or introduce (something) <vi><it>putting down</it> an amendment in Parliament</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to land or to cause (an airplane) to land <vi>Our plane <it>put down</it> [=<it>landed</it>] in New York around 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The pilot was forced to <it>put</it> [=<it>set</it>] the plane <it>down</it> in a field.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to place (a baby or child) in a bed to sleep <vi>He <it>put</it> the baby <it>down</it> (in her crib) for a nap.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think of (someone) as (a specified kind of person or thing) <vi>Most people <it>put</it> him <it>down as</it> [=believe that he is] a fanatic.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to write the name of (someone) on a list of people who will do or give (something) <vi>Can I <it>put you down for</it> a donation? [=can I write that you will give a donation?]</vi> <vi>Sure, <it>put me down for</it> $20.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or think that (something) happened because of (something) <vi>Let's <it>put</it> the mistake <it>down to</it> your inexperience and forget about it.</vi> <vi>The mistake was <it>put down to</it> [=<it>attributed to</it>] his inexperience.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suggest (an idea, plan, etc.) for people to think about or consider <vi>The same argument has been <it>put forth</it> by many people in the opposition.</vi> <vi>I would like to <it>put forth</it> some alternatives.</vi> <vi><it>putting forth</it> a plan/proposal/theory</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (something, such as energy) for a particular purpose <vi>She <it>put forth</it> all her energy to win the race.</vi> <vi>They <it>put forth</it> a good effort.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to produce or send out (something) by growing <vi>The trees are starting to <it>put forth</it> new leaves.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to suggest (something) for consideration :<sx>propose</sx> <vi>He <it>put forward</it> [=<it>put forth</it>] a theory about how the accident may have occurred.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) ready to be used in a certain place :<sx>install</sx> <vi>We <it>put in</it> new cabinets just last year.</vi> <vi>In order to fix the car they have to <it>put in</it> a new engine.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (a comment) to a conversation or argument <vi>She <it>put</it> a quick comment <it>in</it> about her busy schedule.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> a few words on his behalf. [=to say something that supports him]</vi> <vi>Would you mind <phrase>putting in a good word for</phrase> me? [=would you say something good about me?]</vi> <vi>You will each have a chance to <phrase>put in your two cents</phrase>. [=to express your opinion]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make an official statement, offer, or request <vi>She <it>put in</it> a plea of not guilty. [=she pleaded not guilty]</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put in</it> [=<it>make, submit</it>] a report about this.</vi> <vi>You have two weeks to <it>put in</it> [=<it>submit</it>] a claim with the insurance company.</vi> <vi>They are <it>putting in</it> [=<it>making</it>] a $300,000 offer for the house.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> [=<it>place</it>] an order for a dozen roses.</vi> <vi>Contractors have begun <it>putting in</it> bids for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to perform (a particular action) <vi>They <it>put in</it> an amazing performance last night.</vi> <vi>The prime minister <phrase>put in a call to</phrase> [=<it>called</it>] the White House.</vi> <vi>I won't be able to stay at the party long, but I'll at least try to <phrase>put in an appearance</phrase>. [=to go to the party for a short time]</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to work or do something for (an amount of time) <vi>She <it>put in</it> 10 hours at the office yesterday.</vi> <vi>She <it>put in</it> a long day at work.</vi> <vi>He has <it>put in</it> his time (in jail), and now he is a free man.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing something <vi>If we <it>put in</it> a little more effort, we could finish by this afternoon.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>in</it> his performances.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to invest (money) into (something) <vi>She <it>put</it> her money <it>in</it> stocks and bonds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what causes you to have faith, confidence, etc. <vi>He <it>puts</it> his faith <it>in</it> reason/science.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> her trust <it>in</it> God</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for (something) in an official way :to formally request (something) <vi>He <it>put in for</it> a leave of absence.</vi> <vi><it>putting in for</it> a promotion</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to enter a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put in</it> at Sydney.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing (something) <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>into</it> his performances.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put her heart into</phrase> (writing) the letter. [=she expressed her feelings in a very open and honest way]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to invest (time, money, etc.) in (something) <vi>They <it>put</it> their entire life savings <it>into</it> the company.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> a lot of money <it>into</it> (fixing up) that house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put it there</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>put her there</va></vr> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to invite someone to shake hands with you <vi><it>Put her there</it>, pal!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that (something) will happen at a later time :<sx>postpone</sx> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put off</it> until next week. = We <it>put off</it> (holding) the meeting until next week.</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call him, but I keep <it>putting</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>putting off</it> calling him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to wait <vi>I need to come up with an excuse to <it>put off</it> the bill collector.</vi> <vi>She finally called him after <it>putting</it> him <it>off</it> all week.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to dislike someone or something <vi>Don't let the restaurant's dingy appearance <it>put</it> you <it>off</it>—their food is great.</vi> <vi>I was <it>put off</it> by his rudeness.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) His rudeness <phrase>put me off him</phrase> [=made me dislike him] at once.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>off-putting</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to allow (someone) to get off a bus or other vehicle <vi>Could you <it>put</it> [=<it>let</it>] me <it>off</it> (the bus) at the next stop, please?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to dress yourself in (clothing) <vi>She <it>put on</it> her new dress.</vi> <vi><it>Put on</it> a hat and gloves.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>put</it> some clothes <it>on</it> and be right there.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to apply (something) to your face or body <vi><it>putting on</it> lipstick/mascara/lotion</vi> <vi>She <it>puts on</it> far too much makeup.</vi> <vi>We tried to <phrase>put on a happy/brave face</phrase> [=we tried to appear happy/brave] despite our concern.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to add to or increase the amount of (something) <vi>The fire was getting low and we needed to <it>put on</it> more wood.</vi> <vi>She <it>put on</it> [=<it>gained</it>] 40 pounds during her pregnancy.</vi> <vi>He's <it>put on</it> some weight recently.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause (a machine, a light, etc.) to begin to work <vi>Would you mind if I <it>put</it> [=<it>turned</it>] the TV <it>on</it>?</vi> <vi>Somebody <it>put on</it> the lights.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to be heard, seen, produced, etc. <vi><it>put on</it> a record/CD/album</vi> <vi><it>putting on</it> some music</vi> <vi>We <it>put on</it> the air-conditioning/heat in the car.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to start cooking or making (something) <vi>Let me know when to <it>put on</it> the rice.</vi> <vi>He <it>put on</it> a pot of coffee for his guests.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to produce (something that entertains people, such as a play, a party, etc.) <vi>They're <it>putting on</it> a concert.</vi> <vi>He always <it>puts on</it> a great show/performance.</vi> <vi>The town <it>puts on</it> a fireworks display every Independence Day.</vi> <vi>We are <it>putting on</it> a barbecue for everyone in the neighborhood.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say that (someone or something) is responsible for or guilty of (something) <vi>Responsibility for the accident was <it>put on</it> the other driver.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> much of the blame for his problems <it>on</it> the government.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bet (an amount of money) on (someone or something) <vi>We <it>put</it> $2 <it>on</it> the favorite to win.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> money <it>on</it> horse races</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to (a list or group of related things) <vi>She asked to have her name <it>put on</it> the list of candidates.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> the list.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> several new dishes <it>on</it> the menu.</vi> <vi>“Bartender, I'll have another beer.” “Okay, I'll <it>put</it> it <it>on</it> your bill.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say things that are not true to (someone) in a joking way :to trick or fool (someone) for amusement <vi>He said he knew the President, but I think he was just <it>putting me on</it>. [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>having me on</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you would like to speak to someone on the phone <vi>Hi Dad. Could you <it>put</it> Mom <it>on</it>? [=could you give Mom the phone so that I can speak to her?]</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> Dave <it>on</it> the phone, please.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to tell (someone) to use or do (something) <vi>Her doctor <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> medication. [=her doctor prescribed medication for her]</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>put</it> himself <it>on</it> a diet. [=to go on a diet]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (someone) information about (something) :to tell (someone) about (something that he or she did not know about before) <vi>A friend of mine <it>put</it> me <it>on to</it> this book in high school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to stop burning :<sx>extinguish</sx> <vi>She <it>put</it> the fire <it>out</it> by pouring water on it.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her cigarette in an ashtray.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from working <vi>Who <it>put out</it> [=<it>turned off</it>] the lights?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to take (something) outside and leave it there <vi>I <it>put</it> the dog <it>out</it> in the backyard before leaving the house.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> horses <it>out</it> to graze</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the trash/garbage. = (<it>Brit</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the rubbish.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to extend (something) outward <vi>I <it>put out</it> my hand and he shook it eagerly.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her arm for them to stop.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to place (something) where people may use it <vi>He always <it>put out</it> a bowl of candy for the grandchildren.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put out</it> a few extra chairs in case more people arrive.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>This small radiator <it>puts out</it> a surprising amount of heat.</vi> <vi>They will have to <it>put out</it> considerable effort to meet the deadline.</vi> <vi>It was early spring, and the trees were just starting to <it>put out</it> their leaves.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available to be bought, used, etc. <vi>She plans to <it>put out</it> a new album in March.</vi> <vi>They need to be <it>putting out</it> cars that get better gas mileage.</vi> <vi>The information was given in a pamphlet <it>put out</it> by the university's health department.</vi> <vi>Researchers recently <it>put out</it> a report/study on the issue.</vi> <vi>The police have <it>put out</it> [=<it>issued</it>] a warrant for his arrest.</vi> <vi>Someone <phrase>put the word out</phrase> [=started telling people] that the police were looking for her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to annoy or bother (someone) <vi>All the attention didn't seem to <it>put</it> her <it>out</it> at all.</vi> <vi>I'm a little <it>put out</it> that no one called to tell me they would be late.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to do extra work :to cause trouble for (someone) <vi>I hope my visit didn't <it>put</it> you <it>out</it>. [=didn't inconvenience you]</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>put</it> yourself <it>out</it> just for us.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) unconscious <vi>The anesthesia <it>put</it> him <it>out</it> for a little over three hours.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be out in baseball or cricket <vi>The runner was <it>put out</it> at second base.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>putout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with someone <vi>Did she <it>put out</it> last night?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to leave a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put out</it> to sea.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to put (something) across <vi>He <it>puts over</it> very complicated concepts in a way that his students can understand.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) over as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>She <it>puts herself over as</it> [=makes other people believe that she is] a modern, independent woman.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to lie about (something) to (someone) :to trick or deceive someone <vi>Don't try to <it>put</it> anything <it>over on</it> her. She'll see right through you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put paid to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>paid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put (someone) in mind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be accepted or done successfully <vi>They <it>put through</it> a number of reforms.</vi> <vi>tax cuts that were <it>put through</it> by former administrations</vi> <vi>I asked Human Resources to help me <it>put through</it> [=to help me get] a transfer to a different department.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay for (someone) to attend (school) <vi>She has a full-time job and is <it>putting</it> herself <it>through</it> college.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to experience (something) <vi>His doctor <it>put</it> him <it>through</it> a series of tests.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> her parents <it>through</it> a lot when she was a teenager.</vi> <vi>You've been <it>put through</it> quite an ordeal.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>put through</it> hell!</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> that truck <it>through</it> a lot when we owned it.</vi> <vi>The new software still needs to be <phrase>put through its paces</phrase> [=it still needs to be tested] before it can be made available to the public.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause a phone call from (someone) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> you <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (a phone call) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> your call <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put to death</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put together (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to create (something) by joining or gathering parts together <vi>You'll need a screwdriver to <it>put</it> the toy <it>together</it>.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> their first band <it>together</it> when they were in high school.</vi> <vi>Help me <it>put together</it> a list of what we need at the store.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> a proposal <it>together</it> to give to the committee for consideration.</vi> <vi>Her outfit was very well <it>put together</it>. [=the parts looked good together]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something is greater than the total of all the other people or things mentioned <vi>You're smarter than all of those other guys <it>put together</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add or combine (something) with (something) <vi>I never would have thought of <it>putting</it> this wine together <it>with</it> fish.</vi> <vi>The lack of rain <it>put together with</it> [=along with, combined with] the heat ruined many of the region's crops.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) in a higher position <vi>They <it>put up</it> the flag in the morning and take it down at night.</vi> <vi>Sit down. <it>Put</it> your feet <it>up</it> and relax.</vi> <vi>If you have a question, please <it>put up</it> [=<it>raise</it>] your hand.</vi> <vi>Stop! <it>Put</it> your hands <it>up</it> (over your head)!</vi> <vi>When she goes to work, she usually <it>puts</it> her hair <it>up</it> (in a ponytail).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to be on a wall, to hang from a ceiling, etc. <vi>She went around town <it>putting up</it> posters for the concert.</vi> <vi>I just <it>put up</it> new curtains.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to set or place (something) so that it stands up <vi><it>putting up</it> a tent</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a display of new products.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a “for sale” sign in front of their house.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to build (something) <vi>They're <it>putting up</it> a new office building on Main Street.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a fence</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available for people to buy or have <vi>The lamps were <it>put up</it> at auction.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>They <it>put</it> all of their possessions <it>up for</it> sale.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> the puppies <it>up for</it> adoption.</vi></un></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to provide (money, property, etc.) in order to pay for something <vi>They decided not to <it>put up</it> the money for her bail.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> the company's assets as collateral on the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as a prize <vi>The police have <it>put up</it> a $1,000 reward for information leading to his capture.</vi></dt> <sn>h</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to increase (something) :<sx>raise</sx> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> interest rates again this year.</vi></dt> <sn>i</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>It's time to <it>put up</it> [=<it>put away</it>] your toys and get ready for bed.</vi> <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put up</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>j</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to preserve (fruits, vegetables, etc.) to be used later :<sx>can</sx> <vi>Their grandmother spent the afternoon <it>putting up</it> peaches.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do (something) as a way of resisting or struggling against someone or something <vi>We're not leaving without <it>putting up</it> a fight. [=without fighting]</vi> <vi>As expected, the kids <it>put up</it> a fuss when we said it was time for bed.</vi> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> stiff resistance to any new proposals.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as an argument, a suggestion, etc. <vi>She <it>put up</it> a good/solid argument in his defense.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a proposal</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to score (points) <vi>They <it>put up</it> 20 points in the first half.</vi> <vi>She needs to <it>put up</it> big numbers [=to score a lot of points] in today's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give food and shelter to (someone) :to allow or pay for (someone) to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>Could you <it>put</it> me <it>up</it> for the night?</vi> <vi>His employers <it>put</it> him <it>up</it> at a hotel.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> our guests <it>up</it> in the spare bedroom.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>He <it>put up</it> with a friend while he was in town.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> at a hotel</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or suggest (someone) to be a candidate or competitor <vi>The party <it>put</it> her <it>up</it> (as its candidate) for governor.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> their best man to compete against the champion.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to convince (someone) to do (something stupid or foolish) <vi>His friends <it>put</it> him <it>up to</it> (playing) the prank.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you <it>up</it> to this?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up with (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (someone or something unpleasant or annoying) to exist or happen :<sx>tolerate</sx> <vi>At this school, we will not <it>put up with</it> bad behavior.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>put up with</it> much more of this.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up or shut up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to tell someone in a somewhat rude way to start doing something or to stop talking about it <vi>You've complained long enough. It's time to <it>put up or shut up</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="rap[1]"> <hw hindex="1">rap</hw> <sound><wav>rap00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈræp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>raps</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a quick hit or knock <vi>I was startled by a sharp <it>rap</it> on/against/at the window/door.</vi> <vi>He gave me a <it>rap</it> on the knee.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a statement by police or the government saying that someone has committed a crime <un>usually singular <vi>She faces a murder <it>rap</it> [=<it>charge</it>] for the death of her boyfriend.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>beat the rap <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the rap</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the blame or punishment for something <vi>He <phrase>took the rap</phrase> for his brother in order to protect him.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a complaint <it>against</it> someone or something :something that someone or something is criticized for <un>usually singular <vi>The main <it>rap against</it> him is that he isn't totally honest about what he knows.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a rap on/over/across the knuckles</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:criticism or punishment that is given in a gentle way for something that you did wrong <vi>I received <it>a rap on the knuckles</it> for missing the meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat the rap</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to avoid being sent to jail for a crime <vi>He was arrested for assault, but he <it>beat the rap</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bum rap</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:an unfair claim that someone has committed a crime or done something wrong <vi>The defendant was sent to jail on a <it>bum rap</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a criticism or bad opinion that is not deserved or fair <vi>The teenagers say they've all <phrase>gotten a bum rap</phrase> because one person damaged some property.</vi> <vi>She thinks motorboats <it>get a bum rap</it> from environmentalists.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>given a bum rap</phrase> by reviewers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>rap</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
