<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="active"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*tive</hw> <sound><wav>active01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæktɪv</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>more ac*tive; most ac*tive</sgram> <dt>:doing things that require physical movement and energy <vi>We stay/keep <it>active</it> during the cold winter months by skiing and ice skating.</vi> <vi>Despite her age, she has been able to maintain her <it>active</it> [=<it>busy</it>] lifestyle.</vi> <vi>Cats are most <it>active</it> [=<it>energetic, lively</it>] at night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>more ac*tive; most ac*tive</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:involved in the activities of a group or organization <vi>We are <it>active</it> members of our church.</vi> <vi>While many give money to the organization, only a few are <it>active</it> participants.</vi> :participating in an action or activity <vi>She was politically <it>active</it> as a volunteer for her state representative.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>They were <it>active in</it> the antiwar movement of the 1960s.</vi> <vi><it>active in</it> women's causes</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:involving action or participation <vi>They take an <it>active</it> interest in their children's education.</vi> <vi>He has taken/played a more <it>active</it> role in the production of this album.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:marked by regular action or use <vi>the bank's <it>active</it> and inactive accounts</vi> <vi>He became <phrase>sexually active</phrase> [=he began having sex] at the age of 21.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a volcano</ssl> <dt>:likely to explode violently or produce fire and hot liquid rock :capable of erupting <vi>Most volcanoes on this island are still <it>active</it> but a few are inactive.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a disease</ssl> <dt>:becoming worse or continuing to have bad effects <vi><it>active</it> tuberculosis</vi> <vi>The disease remains <it>active</it> throughout the patient's life.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:having a chemical effect especially on the body <vi>The medicine has two <it>active</it> ingredients.</vi> <vi>the <it>active</it> ingredient in/of marijuana</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:involving service in the military as a main job <vi>After two years of <phrase>active duty</phrase> [=two years of being a full-time member of the military] she entered the reserves.</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>on active duty</phrase> for two years.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:involving fighting in a war as a member of the military <vi>He saw no <phrase>active service</phrase> [=he did not fight in any battles] during his time in the army.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>on active service</phrase> in three separate wars.</vi> <vi>soldiers returning home from <it>active service</it></vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>grammar</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a verb or voice</ssl> <dt>:showing that the subject of a sentence is the one doing the action expressed by the verb <vi>“Picked” in “I picked the apples” is an <it>active</it> verb because it shows that the subject “I” is the one who picked the apples.</vi> <vi>“Hits” in “She hits the ball” is <it>active</it>, while “hit” in “The ball was hit” is passive.</vi> <snote>The <phrase>active voice</phrase> is a way of writing or speaking that uses active verbs. <vi>The sentence “The birds are singing” is written in the <it>active voice</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>compare <dxt>passive</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a verb</ssl> <dt>:expressing action rather than describing the state of something <vi>Words like “walk,” “sing,” and “eat” are <it>active</it> verbs.</vi> <vi>In the sentence “Look at this picture,” the verb “look” is <it>active</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>ac*tive*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>They participate <it>actively</it> in their church.</vi> <vi><it>actively</it> involved in a conversation</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
