<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="action"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*tion</hw> <sound><wav>action01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈækʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that a person or group does <vi>As its first official <it>action</it> [=<it>act</it>], the committee elected Ms. Jones as its president.</vi> <vi>He was critical of the government's <it>actions</it> before the war.</vi> <vi>a military <it>action</it> against another country</vi> <vi>criminal/illegal <it>actions</it></vi> <vi>She tried to explain/defend/justify her <it>actions</it>.</vi> <vi>I accept full responsibility for my <it>actions</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>take</it> <vi>The school has been asked to <it>take</it> certain <it>actions</it> to fix the problem.</vi> <vi>This is just one of the many <it>actions</it> that they could have <it>taken</it>.</vi></un> <snote>The saying <phrase>actions speak louder than words</phrase> means that the things that you do are more important than the things that you say. <vi>They say they want peace, but <it>actions speak louder than words</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:things done to achieve a particular purpose <vi>The situation demanded immediate <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>The problem may require military <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>The school took disciplinary <it>action</it> against the drunken students.</vi> <vi>They decided that no further <it>action</it> was necessary.</vi> <vi>We need to agree on a <phrase>plan of action</phrase>. [=need to agree on what we will be doing]</vi> <vi>What's the best <phrase>course of action</phrase>? [=what's the best way to proceed?]</vi> <vi>The protesters criticized the administration's <phrase>lack of action</phrase> [=<it>inaction</it>] on many issues.</vi> <un>often used with <it>take</it> <vi>We were ready to <it>take action</it>. [=to do something]</vi> <vi>Because the company failed to <it>take action</it> [=failed to act], many people were hurt.</vi> <vi>The company <it>took</it> no <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>The police are now <it>taking</it> appropriate <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>She's <phrase>all talk and no action</phrase>. [=she says that she will do things, but she does not do them]</vi></un> <snote>A <phrase>man of action</phrase> or <phrase>woman of action</phrase> is a man or woman who works in an active way to do things. <vi>He was a scholar and thinker but was also a <it>man of action</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>affirmative action</dxt> <dxt>political action committee</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:fighting that happens in a war <vi>His unit first <phrase>saw action</phrase> [=fought in a battle] on June 20th.</vi> <vi>soldiers who were killed or wounded <phrase>in action</phrase> [=<it>in battle</it>]</vi> <vi>soldiers who are <phrase>missing in action</phrase> [=soldiers who cannot be found after a battle and might have been killed, captured, or wounded]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>in action <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>the action</bnote> <dt>:the most exciting or interesting activities that are happening in a particular place <vi>The new theater places the audience closer to the center/middle of <it>the action</it>.</vi> <vi>I moved to New York City to be (a) part of <it>the action</it>.</vi> <vi>Downtown is <phrase>where the action is</phrase>. [=downtown is a very active and exciting place]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a chance or opportunity to make money <vi>Do any of you guys want to <phrase>get in on the action</phrase>? [=participate in a plan to make money]</vi> <snote><phrase>A piece of the action</phrase> or (<it>chiefly US</it>) <phrase>a cut of the action</phrase> or (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <phrase>a slice of the action</phrase> is a portion or share of the money that can be earned from something. <vi>He saw that his friends were making money illegally, and he wanted to get <it>a piece of the action</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <ssl>sometimes offensive</ssl> <dt>:sexual activity <vi>I met a girl who was ready for some <it>action</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the events that happen in a story, movie, etc. <vi>Most of the play's <it>action</it> takes place in a restaurant.</vi> <vi>the <it>action</it> [=<it>plot</it>] of the novel</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:events that happen quickly and that cause feelings of danger and excitement <vi>The movie is two hours of nonstop <it>action</it>. [=<it>excitement</it>]</vi> <vi>We went out looking for <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>That's when the <it>action</it> really starts.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>action</it> movies</vi> <vi>the film's final <it>action</it> sequence</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>live action</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used as a director's command to start filming part of a movie or television show <vi>Lights, camera, <it>action</it>!</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:the process of having a court of law make a decision about an argument <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The court dismissed the <it>action</it>. [=<it>case, lawsuit</it>]</vi> <vi>She brought/filed an <it>action</it> against the company for damages.</vi> <vi><phrase>civil actions</phrase> [=lawsuits about a person's rights]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They are threatening/considering legal <it>action</it>.</vi> <vi>bringing/taking <it>action</it> against companies for damages</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>class action</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a process in which one thing causes a change in another thing <vi>the <it>action</it> [=<it>effect</it>] of certain chemicals on the brain</vi> <vi>The medicine blocks the <it>action</it> of these proteins. [=it stops the proteins from working]</vi> <vi>The cave was formed by the <it>action</it> of an underground river.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:the way that something works or moves <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Food is swallowed by the <it>action</it> of the tongue.</vi> <vi>the <it>action</it> of the heart</vi> <vi>the mechanical <it>action</it> of a pulley</vi> <vi>the drill's twisting <it>action</it></vi> <vi>a single-<it>action</it> revolver</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>The gears meshed with a smooth <it>action</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in action</dre> <def><dt>:in the act of doing something :performing a usual job or function <vi>We came to the court to see our country's judicial system <it>in action</it>. [=<it>at work</it>]</vi> <vi>The fans have come to see their favorite players <it>in action</it>.</vi> <vi>After a two year break from baseball, he's finally <phrase>back in action</phrase>. [=he's playing baseball again]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>action <dxn>3 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into action</dre> <def><dt>:to an active state <vi>They had already put the plan <it>into action</it>. [=started using the plan]</vi> <vi>Firefighters are ready to <phrase>leap/spring/swing into action</phrase> [=quickly start working] at a moment's notice.</vi> <snote>When people or things are <phrase>called into action</phrase>, they are asked to start working or doing a particular task. <vi>As a doctor, she can be <it>called into action</it> at any time of the day.</vi> <vi>Our military unit was <it>called into action</it> at the start of the war.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of action</dre> <def><dt>:unable to perform a usual job or function :not in action <vi>He broke his leg and the doctors say that he'll be <it>out of action</it> [=<it>out of commission</it>] for at least a month.</vi> <vi>His broken leg will <phrase>put/keep him out of action</phrase> for at least a month.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="action figure"> <hw>action figure</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ures</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small usually plastic doll <snote><it>Action figures</it> are made to look like superheroes, soldiers, robots, etc.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="action-packed"> <hw>action–packed</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more action–packed; most action–packed</gram> <dt>:filled with action, danger, and excitement <vi>an <it>action-packed</it> adventure movie</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="action replay"> <hw>action replay</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -plays</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>instant replay</sx> <vi>see the winning goal again in an <it>action replay</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="action verb"> <hw>action verb</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ verbs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>grammar</sl> <dt>:a verb that expresses action <vi>“Drive” in “We often drive past their house” and “think” in “Let's think about the problem” are both <it>action verbs</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>linking verb</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="affirmative action"> <hw>affirmative action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:the practice of improving the educational and job opportunities of members of groups that have not been treated fairly in the past because of their race, sex, etc. <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>positive discrimination</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="class action"> <hw>class action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>law</sl> <dt>:a lawsuit in which many people join together to sue because they all say they were harmed by the same person or group</dt></def> <uro><ure>class–action</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>a <it>class-action</it> suit against a car company</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="industrial action"> <hw>industrial action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>job action</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="job action"> <hw>job action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:something (such as a strike or a slowing of work) done by workers to protest bad conditions, low wages, etc. <vi>The union has threatened a <it>job action</it> if wages are not increased.</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>industrial action</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="live action"> <hw>live action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a movie or scene in which actors and sets are used :a movie or scene that is not produced by animation <vi>a combination of <it>live action</it> and animation</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>live–ac*tion</ure> <sound><wav>livea01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪvˈækʃən</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>a <it>live-action</it> scene/film/sequence</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
