<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="addition"> <hw highlight="yes">ad*di*tion</hw> <sound><wav>additi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈdɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*di*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act or process of joining something to something else :the act or process of adding something <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The soup was thickened by the <it>addition of</it> cream in the last stage of cooking.</vi> <vi>The town welcomed the <it>addition of</it> three new computers to the library.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt>:the act or process of adding numbers <vi>The children learned <it>addition</it> and subtraction.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something or someone more that is included :something or someone that is added <vi>The museum's collection includes several new <it>additions</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>an <it>addition to</it> the family [=a new member of the family, such as a newborn baby]</vi> <vi>The sculpture is the newest <it>addition to</it> the museum's collection.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a part of a building that is built after the original part has been completed <vi>The <it>addition</it> expands the kitchen and adds a second bathroom.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in addition</dre> <def><dt>:as something more <un>used for adding information to a statement <vi>The city has the largest population in the country and <it>in addition</it> [=<it>also, additionally</it>] is a major shipping port.</vi> <vi>Sandwiches were served, and several salads <it>in addition</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in addition to</dre> <def><dt>:along with or together with (something or someone) <vi><it>In addition to</it> soup, several salads were served.</vi> <vi>There were six people at the meeting <it>in addition to</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
