<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="address[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ad*dress</hw> <sound><wav>addres01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈdrɛs</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ad*dress*es</if></in> <in><if>ad*dressed</if></in> <in><if>ad*dress*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to write on an envelope, package, letter, etc., the name and address of the person or business it is being sent to <vi>I've <it>addressed</it> the letter, but it still needs a stamp.</vi> <vi>The package is sealed; it just needs to be <it>addressed</it>.</vi> <vi>We spent the afternoon <it>addressing</it> invitations to all our friends.</vi> <vi>The letter was returned because it had been <it>addressed</it> incorrectly.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to speak to (a person or group) <vi>She ignored most of the people at the table, <it>addressing</it> only the man who was sitting next to her.</vi> <vi>One of the characters <it>addresses</it> the audience directly throughout the play.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use a specified name or title when speaking or writing to (someone) <un>+ <it>as</it> <vi>As children, we <it>addressed</it> him <it>as</it> “sir” [=we called him “sir”] even though he was only a few years older than us.</vi> <vi>You should <it>address</it> the queen <it>as</it> “Your Majesty.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to direct (spoken or written words) <it>to</it> someone <vi>She <it>addressed</it> her comments <it>to</it> the man [=she spoke to the man] who was sitting next to her.</vi> <vi>Most of the speaker's remarks were <it>addressed to</it> those with experience in the industry.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to give a formal speech to (a group of people) <vi>Before the awards were given, the mayor <it>addressed</it> the crowd.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give attention to (something) :to deal with (a matter, issue, problem, etc.) <vi>We're all curious about how the mayor plans to <it>address</it> the issue.</vi> <vi>Air pollution is one of the many problems being <it>addressed</it> by the scientists at the conference.</vi> <vi>The principal held a meeting to <it>address</it> the students' concerns.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>address yourself to</phrase> an issue or problem you give your attention to it. <vi>The governor is <it>addressing himself to</it> the problem of underfunded schools.</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="address[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">ad*dress</hw> <sound><wav>addres01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈdrɛs, ˈæˌdrɛs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*dress*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the words and numbers that are used to describe the location of a building and that are written on letters, envelopes, and packages so that they can be mailed to that location <vi>Write your name, <it>address</it>, and phone number in the spaces provided.</vi> <vi>Our <it>address</it> [=the address of our home] is 82 Third Street.</vi> <vi>Please deliver the package to my work <it>address</it>. [=the address of the building where I work]</vi> <vi>I forgot to put the <phrase>return address</phrase> [=the address of the person sending the letter] on the envelope.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>mail</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the letters, numbers, and symbols that are used to direct an e-mail message or to show the location of a site on the Internet <vi>an e-mail <it>address</it></vi> <vi>a Web <it>address</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a formal speech <vi>We listened to the President's inaugural <it>address</it> on the radio.</vi> <vi>She was asked to give/deliver a formal <it>address</it> at the ceremony.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>keynote address</dxt> <dxt>public address system</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>form/term of address</dre> <def><dt>:a word, name, or title that is used when speaking or writing to someone <vi>“Honey” is an affectionate <it>term of address</it> in U.S. English.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="address book"> <hw>address book</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ books</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small book in which you write the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of people you know</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a place on a computer or other device for storing e-mail addresses, phone numbers, etc.</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="forwarding address"> <hw>forwarding address</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dress*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an address that you give to someone when you move to a different place so that any mail that comes to your old address can be sent to you <vi>She didn't leave a <it>forwarding address</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="keynote address"> <hw>keynote address</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dresses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the main speech given at a gathering (such as a political convention) <vi>Many of the convention guests left after the <it>keynote address</it>.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>keynote speech</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="mailing address"> <hw>mailing address</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dresses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an address to which mail can be sent <vi>His <it>mailing address</it> [=<it>postal address</it>] is different from his home address.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="postal address"> <hw>postal address</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dresses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>mailing address</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="public address system"> <hw>public address system</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tems</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>pa <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="return address"> <hw>return address</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dress*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an address on an envelope or package that shows where the envelope or package should be returned to if it cannot be delivered <dx>see picture at <dxt>mail</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="form[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">form</hw> <sound><wav>form0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfoɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>forms</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a type or kind of something <vi>Coal is a <it>form</it> of carbon.</vi> <vi>a rare/deadly <it>form</it> of cancer</vi> <vi>a popular <it>form</it> of entertainment</vi> <vi>different <it>forms</it> of life = different life <it>forms</it> [=different types of living beings]</vi> <vi>an ancient <it>form</it> of music</vi> <vi>an art <it>form</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:one of several or many different ways in which something is seen, experienced, or produced <vi>The medicine can be taken in the <it>form</it> of a liquid or pill. = The medicine can be taken in pill or liquid <it>form</it>.</vi> <vi>His essays are now available in book <it>form</it>. [=his essays have been published in a book]</vi> <vi>the written/spoken <it>form</it> of the language</vi> <vi>Antisocial behavior can take many <it>forms</it>. [=there are many different types of antisocial behavior]</vi> <vi>Most of his wealth is in the <it>form</it> of stocks. [=most of his wealth consists of stocks]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the shape of something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>the building's massive <it>form</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a style of architecture that emphasizes <it>form</it> over function</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that can be seen only as a shape or outline <vi>The shadowy <it>forms</it> of several people were visible through the smoke.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:bodily shape :<sx>figure</sx> <vi>the human/female <it>form</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a document with blank spaces for filling in information <vi>a tax <it>form</it></vi> <vi>an application <it>form</it></vi> <vi>fill out a <it>form</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a way of behaving that is judged as proper or improper <vi>It's considered <phrase>bad/poor form</phrase> to arrive so early. = It's not considered <phrase>good form</phrase> to arrive so early. [=it is not proper to arrive so early]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a manner or style of performing <vi>an athlete with good <it>form</it></vi> <vi>She would be a better swimmer/golfer if she improved her <it>form</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:condition for performing <vi>an athlete in top <it>form</it> [=<it>shape</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe how well or badly someone is performing <vi>She was really in great <it>form</it> at the party, telling jokes and dancing.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>at the top of his form</phrase>. [=he was performing extremely well]</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) He's been playing poorly in recent months, but now he's back <phrase>on form</phrase>. [=now he's playing well again]</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) She was a little <phrase>off form</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the way in which the parts of a piece of writing or music or of a work of art are arranged <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>the <it>form</it> and content of a poem/essay</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The sonnet is a poetical <it>form</it>.</vi> <vi>symphonic <it>forms</it></vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:any one of the different ways in which a word may be written or spoken <vi>the plural/possessive <it>form</it> of a noun</vi> <vi>the inflected <it>forms</it> of a verb</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>combining form</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a grade in a British secondary school or in some American private schools <vi>students in the sixth <it>form</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as a matter of form</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is done because it is polite, usual, or required <vi>He was asked to participate only <it>as a matter of form</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>form of address</dre> <dx>see <dxt>address</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any way, shape, or form</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take form</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to develop :to start to exist or be seen <vi>a political movement that first <it>took form</it> in the 1960s</vi> <vi>The new stadium is gradually <it>taking form</it>. [=being built]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>true to form</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something or someone that is (or runs, holds, etc.) <phrase>true to form</phrase> behaves or proceeds in the usual and expected way. <vi>Her latest movie is/runs <it>true to form</it>.</vi> <vi><it>True to form</it>, he was 20 minutes late for the meeting.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
