<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="advanced"> <hw>ad*vanced</hw> <pr>ədˈvænst, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:nst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more ad*vanced; most ad*vanced</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:beyond the basic level <vi><it>advanced</it> mathematics</vi> <vi>She's taking an <it>advanced</it> course in English. = She's taking a course in <it>advanced</it> English.</vi> <vi>The school has courses for elementary, intermediate, and <it>advanced</it> students.</vi> <vi>The book explains both basic and <it>advanced</it> techniques.</vi> <vi>The job requires someone with an <phrase>advanced degree</phrase>. [=a degree (such as a master's degree or a PhD) that is higher than a bachelor's degree]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:far along in a course of progress or development: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:having developed more than others <vi>a highly <it>advanced</it> civilization [=a modern civilization]</vi> <vi>an <it>advanced</it> society</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having or using new and modern methods <vi><it>advanced</it> technology</vi> <vi>technologically <it>advanced</it> weapons</vi> <vi>The system has many <it>advanced</it> features.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having reached a bad state or condition <vi>The house was in an <it>advanced</it> state of disrepair. [=the house was in very poor condition]</vi> <vi>The disease is in an <it>advanced</it> stage.</vi> <vi>an <it>advanced</it> form of cancer</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:far along in a process of aging <vi>She began painting <phrase>at an advanced age</phrase>. [=she began painting when she was old]</vi> <vi>He is rather <phrase>advanced in age/years</phrase>. [=rather old]</vi> <vi>a man/woman <phrase>of advanced age/years</phrase> [=an old man/woman]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="advance[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ad*vance</hw> <sound><wav>advanc01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ədˈvæns, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:ns</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ad*vanc*es</if></in> <in><if>ad*vanced</if></in> <in><if>ad*vanc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move forward <vi>The car <it>advanced</it> slowly down the street.</vi> <vi>The sun slowly <it>advanced</it> across the sky.</vi> <vi>She opened the door and <it>advanced</it> cautiously into the room.</vi> <vi>Enemy soldiers are <phrase>advancing on</phrase> the city. [=they are approaching the city in order to attack it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (someone or something) forward <vi><it>advance</it> the hands of a clock</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> a pawn [=move a pawn forward in a game of chess]</vi> <vi>The film is <it>advanced</it> by an electric motor.</vi> <vi>The team <it>advanced</it> the ball steadily down the field.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go forward :to make progress <vi>Our understanding of this disease has <it>advanced</it> rapidly in recent years.</vi> <vi>The team did not <it>advance</it> beyond the first round of the play-offs.</vi> <vi>The company tries to keep up with <it>advancing</it> technology.</vi> :to continue in a process of development, aging, etc. <vi>As he <it>advanced</it> in age and stature he <it>advanced</it> in knowledge.</vi> <vi>Their children are <it>advancing</it> toward maturity.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to increase in amount or rate <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>These measures are intended to keep landlords from <it>advancing</it> [=<it>raising</it>] rents unfairly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Wages have continued to <it>advance</it>.</vi> <vi>Some stock prices have <it>advanced</it> while others have declined.</vi> <vi>Loss of memory is often a sign of <it>advancing</it> age.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to help the progress of (something) <vi>heroes whose sacrifices <it>advanced</it> the cause of freedom</vi> <vi>Volunteers have been raising money to <it>advance</it> the work of the society.</vi> <vi>They used propaganda to <it>advance</it> their cause.</vi> <vi>He was <it>advancing</it> his own interests at the expense of his friend's.</vi> :to cause or help (something) to go forward or continue <vi><it>advance</it> a plot</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (something) higher or better :to cause improvement to (something) <vi>The success of this novel will help to <it>advance</it> [=<it>enhance</it>] his reputation/status.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to raise (someone) to a higher rank or position <vi>He was <it>advanced</it> [=<it>promoted</it>] from clerk to assistant manager.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to rise to a higher rank or position <vi>The family has <it>advanced</it> to a position of influence in the community.</vi> <vi>He <it>advanced</it> quickly through the ranks.</vi> <vi>She has continued to <it>advance</it> steadily in her career.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give money to someone as a loan or before the usual time <vi><it>advance</it> a loan to someone = <it>advance</it> someone a loan</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> an employee a week's pay</vi> <vi>His publisher <it>advanced</it> him $100,000 on/for his new book.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to suggest or propose (something) for consideration or acceptance <vi><it>advance</it> a new plan/theory</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> an argument</vi> <vi>Many theories were <it>advanced</it> and rejected.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to occur more quickly <vi>a chemical used to <it>advance</it> the ripening of fruit</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (something) earlier <vi><it>advance</it> the date of the meeting</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>ad*vanc*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*vanc*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>There were more <it>advancers</it> [=stocks that increased in value] than decliners in the stock market yesterday.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="Advanced Level"> <hw>Advanced level</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ levels</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>a level</sx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
