<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="advantage"> <hw highlight="yes">ad*van*tage</hw> <sound><wav>advant01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ədˈvæntɪʤ, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:ntɪʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*van*tag*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something (such as a good position or condition) that helps to make someone or something better or more likely to succeed than others <vi>Higher ground gave the enemy the/an <it>advantage</it>.</vi> <vi>He has/enjoys an unfair <it>advantage</it> over us because of his wealth.</vi> <vi>His plan has the <it>advantage</it> of being less expensive than other options.</vi> <vi>He lacked the <it>advantages</it> of an advanced education.</vi> <vi>Speed is an <it>advantage</it> in most sports.</vi> <vi>The company's only <it>advantage</it> over the competition is its location.</vi> <vi>Applicants for this job will find that previous experience is an <it>advantage</it>.</vi> <vi>The union should be <phrase>at an advantage</phrase> [=should have an advantage] in the negotiations.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a good or desirable quality or feature <vi>Being able to set your own schedule is one of the <it>advantages</it> of owning a business.</vi> <vi>Among the <it>advantages</it> of a small college is its campus life.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disadvantage</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:benefit or gain <vi>There isn't any <it>advantage</it> in/to leaving early.</vi> <vi>She used her position for personal <it>advantage</it>. [=for personal gain; to help herself]</vi> <vi>The error was <phrase>to our advantage</phrase>. [=we were helped by the error]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disadvantage</dxt></dx> <snote>If you <phrase>turn/use something to your advantage</phrase> or <phrase>to good advantage</phrase>, you use something in a way that is helpful to you. <vi>Is there a way to <it>turn this situation to our advantage</it>? [=is there a way to exploit this situation?; is there a way to take advantage of this situation?]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>tennis</ssl> <dt>:the first point won after the score is tied at 40–40 <un>used to announce the person who has won the point <vi><it>Advantage</it> Mr. Jones.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>take advantage of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (something, such as an opportunity) in a way that helps you :to make good use of (something) <vi>We <it>took advantage of</it> the warm weather and did some yard work.</vi> <vi>They are <it>taking advantage of</it> an opportunity to travel.</vi> <vi>You should <it>take</it> (full) <it>advantage of</it> this opportunity while you can.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to ask for or expect more than is fair or reasonable from (someone) :to treat (someone who is generous or helpful) unfairly <vi>After a while, I began to think she was <it>taking advantage of</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) unfairly for personal gain <vi>He <it>took advantage of</it> [=<it>exploited</it>] my lack of knowledge.</vi> <vi>She <it>took advantage of</it> our generosity.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to advantage</dre> <def><dt>:in an attractive and appealing way <vi>The display shows off the collection <it>to</it> (good/best) <it>advantage</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="taker"> <hw>tak*er</hw> <sound><wav>taker01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈteɪkɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>tak*ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a person who takes something <vi>He's more of a giver than a <it>taker</it>. [=he likes to give rather than receive things]</vi> <vi>She's not much of a risk <it>taker</it>. [=she does not like to take risks]</vi> <vi>I'm a terrible test <it>taker</it>.</vi> <vi>a poll <it>taker</it></vi> <vi>ticket <it>takers</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a person who accepts something that is offered <vi>The class had no <it>takers</it>. [=no one took the class]</vi> <vi>I have two tickets for sale. Any <it>takers</it>?</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
