<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="advance[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ad*vance</hw> <sound><wav>advanc01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ədˈvæns, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:ns</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ad*vanc*es</if></in> <in><if>ad*vanced</if></in> <in><if>ad*vanc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move forward <vi>The car <it>advanced</it> slowly down the street.</vi> <vi>The sun slowly <it>advanced</it> across the sky.</vi> <vi>She opened the door and <it>advanced</it> cautiously into the room.</vi> <vi>Enemy soldiers are <phrase>advancing on</phrase> the city. [=they are approaching the city in order to attack it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (someone or something) forward <vi><it>advance</it> the hands of a clock</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> a pawn [=move a pawn forward in a game of chess]</vi> <vi>The film is <it>advanced</it> by an electric motor.</vi> <vi>The team <it>advanced</it> the ball steadily down the field.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go forward :to make progress <vi>Our understanding of this disease has <it>advanced</it> rapidly in recent years.</vi> <vi>The team did not <it>advance</it> beyond the first round of the play-offs.</vi> <vi>The company tries to keep up with <it>advancing</it> technology.</vi> :to continue in a process of development, aging, etc. <vi>As he <it>advanced</it> in age and stature he <it>advanced</it> in knowledge.</vi> <vi>Their children are <it>advancing</it> toward maturity.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to increase in amount or rate <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>These measures are intended to keep landlords from <it>advancing</it> [=<it>raising</it>] rents unfairly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Wages have continued to <it>advance</it>.</vi> <vi>Some stock prices have <it>advanced</it> while others have declined.</vi> <vi>Loss of memory is often a sign of <it>advancing</it> age.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to help the progress of (something) <vi>heroes whose sacrifices <it>advanced</it> the cause of freedom</vi> <vi>Volunteers have been raising money to <it>advance</it> the work of the society.</vi> <vi>They used propaganda to <it>advance</it> their cause.</vi> <vi>He was <it>advancing</it> his own interests at the expense of his friend's.</vi> :to cause or help (something) to go forward or continue <vi><it>advance</it> a plot</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (something) higher or better :to cause improvement to (something) <vi>The success of this novel will help to <it>advance</it> [=<it>enhance</it>] his reputation/status.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to raise (someone) to a higher rank or position <vi>He was <it>advanced</it> [=<it>promoted</it>] from clerk to assistant manager.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to rise to a higher rank or position <vi>The family has <it>advanced</it> to a position of influence in the community.</vi> <vi>He <it>advanced</it> quickly through the ranks.</vi> <vi>She has continued to <it>advance</it> steadily in her career.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give money to someone as a loan or before the usual time <vi><it>advance</it> a loan to someone = <it>advance</it> someone a loan</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> an employee a week's pay</vi> <vi>His publisher <it>advanced</it> him $100,000 on/for his new book.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to suggest or propose (something) for consideration or acceptance <vi><it>advance</it> a new plan/theory</vi> <vi><it>advance</it> an argument</vi> <vi>Many theories were <it>advanced</it> and rejected.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to occur more quickly <vi>a chemical used to <it>advance</it> the ripening of fruit</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (something) earlier <vi><it>advance</it> the date of the meeting</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>ad*vanc*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ad*vanc*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>There were more <it>advancers</it> [=stocks that increased in value] than decliners in the stock market yesterday.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="advance[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">advance</hw> <altpr>ədˈvæns, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:ns</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>advances</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:forward movement <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>trying to halt the enemy's <it>advance</it></vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>trying to halt the enemy's <it>advances</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:progress in the development or improvement of something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>recent <it>advances</it> in medicine</vi> <vi>a big/dramatic/huge/major/significant <it>advance</it> in technology</vi> <vi>The new system represents a considerable <it>advance</it> over the old one.</vi> <vi>There have been few <it>advances</it> made in the treatment of this disease.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There has been little <it>advance</it> made in the treatment of this disease.</vi> <vi>policies that are important for economic <it>advance</it> [=<it>advancement</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a rise in price, value, or amount <vi>The workers won wage <it>advances</it>.</vi> <vi>a yearlong <it>advance</it> in stock prices</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of speaking to someone in an effort to start a sexual relationship <un>usually plural <vi>Her unfriendly look discourages <it>advances</it>.</vi> <vi>She rebuffed/rejected his <it>advances</it>.</vi> <vi>He is accused of making unwelcome sexual <it>advances</it> to female coworkers.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:money given to someone as a loan or before the usual time of payment <vi>I need an <it>advance</it> on my salary.</vi> <vi>He was given a $100,000 <it>advance</it> on/for his new book.</vi> <vi>a cash <it>advance</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in advance</dre> <def><dt>:before something happens <vi>He knew about the change two weeks <it>in advance</it>. [=two weeks before the change occurred]</vi> <vi>There was no way to know <it>in advance</it> [=<it>ahead of time</it>] that these problems would occur.</vi> :before a future event or time <vi>We made reservations <it>in advance</it>.</vi> <vi>You should call <it>in advance</it> to make an appointment.</vi> <vi>Thank you <it>in advance</it> for your help.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>They began to make preparations several days <it>in advance of</it> [=<it>before, ahead of</it>] her arrival.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="advance[3]"> <hw hindex="3">advance</hw> <altpr>ədˈvæns, <it>Brit</it> ədˈvɑ:ns</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:made, sent, or provided at an early time <vi>an <it>advance</it> payment</vi> <vi>an <it>advance</it> warning</vi> <vi>an <it>advance</it> copy of a new book</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:going or placed before others <vi>an <it>advance</it> guard</vi> <vi>an <it>advance</it> scout</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) an <phrase>advance man/woman/team</phrase> [=a man, woman, or group whose job is to go to a place and make preparations for someone (such as a politician or an entertainer) who is coming to visit that place at a later time]</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
