<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="affair"> <hw highlight="yes">af*fair</hw> <sound><wav>affair01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈfeɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>af*fairs</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>affairs</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:work or activities done for a purpose :commercial, professional, public, or personal business <vi>The group conducts its <it>affairs</it> [=<it>business</it>] in private.</vi> <vi>We were told to arrange/settle our <it>affairs</it>. = We were told to put our <it>affairs</it> in order.</vi> <vi>handling/managing someone else's <it>affairs</it></vi> <vi>They seem to be quite pleased with the current/present <phrase>state of affairs</phrase>. [=<it>situation</it>]</vi> <vi>She's the company's director of <phrase>public affairs</phrase>. [=the person who manages a company's relationship with the public]</vi> <vi>She's an expert in <phrase>foreign affairs</phrase>. [=events and activities that involve foreign countries]</vi> <vi><phrase>world/international affairs</phrase> [=events and activities that involve different nations]</vi> <vi>After the war, the government focused on its own <phrase>domestic affairs</phrase>.</vi> <vi>They accused the U.S. of interfering in the <phrase>internal affairs</phrase> of other nations.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a matter that concerns or involves someone <vi>This has nothing to do with you. It's not your <it>affair</it>. [=<it>business, concern</it>] = It's none of your <it>affair</it>. [=<it>business</it>]</vi> <vi>How I choose to live is my <it>affair</it>, not yours.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a secret sexual relationship between two people :<sx>love affair</sx> <vi>adulterous/extramarital <it>affairs</it> between married men and single women</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>have an affair</phrase> <vi>She divorced her husband after she discovered that he was <it>having an affair</it>.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>She <it>had an affair with</it> a coworker.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a social event or activity <vi>He wants to make their wedding day an <it>affair</it> to remember. [=a special event]</vi> <vi>a simple/elaborate <it>affair</it></vi> <vi>We were invited to a black-tie <it>affair</it> [=a party in which men wear tuxedos and women wear fancy dresses] at the governor's mansion.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an event or series of events that usually involves well-known people <vi>the famous hostage <it>affair</it> of the late 1970s</vi> <vi>The public has shown little interest in the whole <it>affair</it>.</vi> <un>often used with proper names <vi>the Iran-Contra <it>affair</it> [=<it>scandal</it>]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:something made or produced :an object or thing <vi>The only bridge across the river was a flimsy <it>affair</it> of ropes and rotten wood.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="love affair"> <hw>love affair</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -fairs</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a romantic or sexual relationship especially between two people who are not married to each other <vi>His wife discovered that he was having a <it>love affair</it> [=having an affair] with another woman.</vi> <vi>Theirs was a great <it>love affair</it>. [=they were very much in love]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a feeling of great interest in and enthusiasm for something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>The book describes America's <it>love affair with</it> baseball.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
