<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="affect"> <hw highlight="yes">af*fect</hw> <sound><wav>affect02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈfɛkt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>af*fects</if></in> <in><if>af*fect*ed</if></in> <in><if>af*fect*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to produce an effect on (someone or something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to act on (someone or something) and cause a change <vi>His decisions could <it>affect</it> [=<it>influence</it>] the lives of millions of people.</vi> <vi>The accident will <it>affect</it> [=<it>influence</it>] the value of the car.</vi> <vi>We learned about the way the oceans are <it>affected</it> by the moon.</vi> <vi>This medication may <it>affect</it> your ability to drive a car. [=this medicine may make it dangerous for you to drive a car]</vi> <vi>This new evidence will <it>affect</it> the outcome of the trial.</vi> <vi>The news could adversely <it>affect</it> [=could hurt] her chances of becoming the next president.</vi> <vi>We kept the change from <it>affecting</it> [=<it>harming</it>] our friendship.</vi> <vi>The incident really <it>affected</it> my opinion of him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause strong emotions in (someone) <vi>The criticism <it>affected</it> [=<it>bothered, upset</it>] her deeply/greatly.</vi> <vi>The entire town was <it>affected</it> by their deaths. [=everyone in the town felt sad about their deaths]</vi> <vi>We were all greatly <it>affected</it> by the terrible news. [=we were all very upset by the terrible news]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause a change in (a part of the body) <vi>Paralysis <it>affected</it> his limbs. = His limbs were <it>affected</it> by/with paralysis. [=his limbs were paralyzed]</vi> <vi>The disease can <it>affect</it> your muscles.</vi> <vi>drugs that <it>affect</it> the nervous/immune system</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause illness in (someone) <vi>The condition <it>affects</it> about five million adults each year.</vi> <vi>a serious disease primarily/mainly <it>affecting</it> women over the age of 40</vi> <vi>Only men appear to be <it>affected</it> by the disease.</vi></dt> <usage>Do not confuse the verbs <it>affect</it> and <it>effect</it>. <it>Affect</it> means to act on or change someone or something. <vi>Rain <it>affected</it> [=<it>influenced</it>] their performance.</vi> <it>Effect</it> means to cause something to happen. <vi>The new president <it>effected</it> [=<it>made, caused</it>] many changes to/in the company's policies.</vi> Note that the verb <it>affect</it> and the noun <it>effect</it> are used in contexts that are similar. <vi>The weather <it>affected</it> our plans. = The weather had an <it>effect</it> on our plans. [=the weather caused us to change our plans]</vi></usage> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to pretend that a false behavior or feeling is natural or genuine <vi>She <it>affected</it> indifference [=she pretended that she did not care], though she was deeply hurt.</vi> <vi>He <it>affected</it> (a look of) surprise. [=he pretended to be surprised]</vi> <vi>She <it>affects</it> [=<it>feigns</it>] a warm friendly manner.</vi> <vi>He <it>affected</it> [=<it>faked</it>] a French accent.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
