<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="after[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">af*ter</hw> <sound><wav>after001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæftɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftə</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:following in time :at a later time <vi>Dinner was at six and we arrived shortly <it>after</it>. [=<it>thereafter</it>]</vi> <vi>He returned 20 years <it>after</it>. [=<it>later</it>]</vi> <vi>Don't tell them until <it>after</it>.</vi> <vi>I expected her then, but she arrived the week <it>after</it>.</vi> <vi>He ate lunch and left just/right/immediately <it>after</it>.</vi> <vi>I saw her again the day <it>after</it>. [=the following day]</vi> <vi>He vowed to love her forever/ever <it>after</it>. [=from that time on, forever]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="after[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">after</hw> <altpr>ˈæftɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftə</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:at a time following (something or someone) :later than (something or someone) <vi>We arrived shortly <it>after</it> six o'clock.</vi> <vi>He returned <it>after</it> 20 years.</vi> <vi>before, during, and <it>after</it> the war</vi> <vi>He left just/right/immediately/soon/shortly <it>after</it> nightfall/dark.</vi> <vi>Night fell, and soon <it>after</it> that [=soon afterward] he left.</vi> <vi>He finished the exam <it>after</it> me.</vi> <vi>I stood up <it>after</it> the judge (did). [=the judge stood up before I (did)]</vi> <vi>Call me <it>after</it> your arrival.</vi> <vi>She was going to arrive tomorrow but I'm now expecting her the day <it>after</it> tomorrow instead.</vi> <vi>She hasn't lived there since (the time) <it>after</it> the war.</vi> <vi>They earned $30,000 <it>after</it> (paying) taxes.</vi> <vi>He left <it>after</it> an hour.</vi> <vi>Let's get going! It's <it>after</it> [=<it>past</it>] 12 (o'clock).</vi> <vi>The job got easier <phrase>after a while</phrase>. [=after some time had passed]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe a time following a specified hour <vi>It's 20 (minutes) <it>after</it> 12. [=it's 20 past 12; it's 12:20]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:following and because of (something) <vi><it>After</it> all our advice, she's certain to do better. [=she's certain to do better because we have given her our advice]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:following and in spite of (something) <vi>Even <it>after</it> all our advice, she still did badly! [=she did badly even though we gave her our advice]</vi> <vi>How can you say that <it>after</it> what happened last night?</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:following (something or someone) in order or in a series <vi>It's the highest mountain <it>after</it> Mount Everest.</vi> <vi>You'll see my house just before the bank and <it>after</it> the school.</vi> <vi>The number 2 comes before 3 and <it>after</it> 1. [=2 comes between 1 and 3]</vi> <vi>My name is listed <it>after</it> yours.</vi> <vi>You go first and I'll go/follow <it>after</it> you.</vi> <vi>The children marched out <phrase>one after the other</phrase> in single file.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>after you</phrase> is used as a polite way of saying that someone should go ahead of you or do something before you do it. <vi><it>After you</it>, Madam!</vi></snote> <snote>In British English, you can say <phrase>after you with</phrase> something to ask the person who is using something to let you use it next. <vi><it>After you with</it> the pencil, please. [=I would like to use the pencil when you have finished using it]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases to describe something that happens many times or for a long period of time <vi>They have suffered misfortune <it>after</it> misfortune. [=they have suffered a long series of misfortunes]</vi> <vi>Wave <it>after</it> [=<it>upon</it>] wave was beating against the shore.</vi> <vi>She does her job <phrase>day after day</phrase> without complaining.</vi> <vi>He's done the same thing <phrase>time after time</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:trying to catch or get (something or someone) <vi>The dog ran <it>after</it> the ball. [=the dog ran to get the ball]</vi> <vi>The police went/chased <it>after</it> the escaped criminal.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>after</it> him. [=are trying to catch him]</vi> <vi>What do you think he's <it>after</it> with all his questions? [=what is he trying to achieve by asking his questions?]</vi> <snote>If people are <phrase>after you</phrase> to do something, they want you to do it and they tell you to do it repeatedly. <vi>Mom was <it>after me</it> to clean my room. [=Mom repeatedly told me to clean my room]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:following the actions or departure of (someone) <vi>She called/shouted <it>after</it> him as he walked away. [=she called/shouted at/toward him as he walked away]</vi> <vi>They made a mess and didn't clean up <it>after</it> themselves. [=they didn't clean up the mess they made]</vi> <vi>If you make a mess, don't expect me to clean up <it>after</it> you.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:with the name of (someone or something) <vi>He was called George <it>after</it> his father.</vi> <vi>She was named <it>after</it> her grandmother. [=she was given the same name as her grandmother]</vi> <vi>The game rugby was named <it>after</it> Rugby School in England, where it began.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in the manner of (someone or something) <vi>a building patterned <it>after</it> [=<it>on</it>] a cathedral</vi> <vi>(<it>formal</it>) a story <it>after</it> (the manner of) Hemingway</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:in a lower or less important position than (something) <vi>They put quality <it>after</it> quantity. [=they cared more about quantity than about quality]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:about or concerning (someone or something) <vi>I met one of your old friends and she was asking/inquiring <it>after</it> you. [=she was asking about you; she was asking how you are]</vi> <vi>She was asking <it>after</it> your health.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in spite of what was said :even though the opposite was expected <vi>They decided to go <it>after all</it>.</vi> <vi>It didn't rain <it>after all</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize something that needs to be considered <vi>It's only Tuesday, <it>after all</it>. We have plenty of time.</vi> <vi>You should apologize to her. <it>After all</it>, she is your best friend.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="after[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">after</hw> <altpr>ˈæftɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftə</altpr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><dt>:later than the time that :later than when <vi>He returned <it>after</it> 20 years had passed.</vi> <vi>The defendant stood up <it>after</it> the judge did. [=the judge stood up before the defendant did]</vi> <vi>Don't tell them until <it>after</it> they've had dinner.</vi> <vi>He left just/right/immediately/soon/shortly <it>after</it> the show ended.</vi> <vi>Call me <it>after</it> you arrive.</vi> <vi>He finished the exam <it>after</it> I did.</vi> <vi>It happened not long <it>after</it> he graduated from college.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="after[4]"> <hw hindex="4">after</hw> <altpr>ˈæftɚ, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftə</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>old-fashioned + literary</sl> <dt>:later in time <vi>in <it>after</it> [=<it>later</it>] years</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="after-sales"> <hw>af*ter–sales</hw> <sound><wav>after01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæftɚˌseɪlz, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftəˌseɪlz</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:provided to customers after a sale has been made <vi><it>after-sales</it> service and maintenance</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="after-school"> <hw>af*ter–school</hw> <sound><wav>after02ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæftɚˌsku:l, <it>Brit</it> ˈɑ:ftəˌsku:l</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:happening or done after the end of the school day <vi>She started an <it>after-school</it> job so she could buy a car.</vi> <vi><it>after-school</it> activities/programs</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="morning-after pill"> <hw>morning–after pill</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ pills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a pill that a woman takes after having sex so that she will not become pregnant</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sought-after"> <hw>sought–after</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more sought–after; most sought–after</gram> <dt>:wanted by many people and hard to get or find <vi><it>sought-after</it> antiques</vi> <vi>the most <it>sought-after</it> artists</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the entire number, quantity, or amount <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] that I have is yours.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] will be explained soon.</vi> <vi>She told us <it>all</it> about what happened.</vi> <vi>Her other books were good, but this one is the best of <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> are welcome! [=everyone is welcome]</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> enjoyed the movie. = <it>All</it> of us enjoyed the movie.</vi> <vi>Many people were invited and <it>all</it> came.</vi> <vi>His stories may be entertaining, but I don't think <it>all</it> (of them) are true.</vi> <vi>Thanks to <it>all</it> who helped out.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> of this money will be yours when I die.</vi> <vi>Not <it>all</it> of our students go on to college.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>was all (that) I could do</phrase> to keep from laughing! [=I had a hard time trying not to laugh]</vi> <vi>“Is there anything else to be done?” “No, <phrase>that's all</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He gave equal attention to <phrase>one and all</phrase>. [=to everyone]</vi> <vi><phrase>Come one, come all</phrase>. [=everyone is invited to come]</vi> <usageref>altogether</usageref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the only thing <vi>That's <it>all</it> I can do to help.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> I know is that the game was canceled. I don't know why.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>after</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>All aboard!</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aboard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all in all</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a general way :when everything is thought of or considered <vi><it>All in all</it> [=<it>in general, generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi> <vi>We did lose some money, but we got most of it back. So <it>all in all</it> things might have been a lot worse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>The cost of the repairs came to about $300 <it>all told</it>. [=<it>in all</it>] [=the total cost of the repairs was about $300]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>and all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:and everything else <vi>What with the noise outside, the fire <it>and all</it>, we got hardly any sleep.</vi> <vi>He endured everything, insults <it>and all</it>, without getting angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a response <vi>“It's really hot out!” “It is <it>and all</it>!” [=it certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>He will go anywhere <it>at all</it> to get a job.</vi> <vi>Did you find out anything <it>at all</it>?</vi></un> <un>used especially in negative statements <vi>“Did she say anything?” “No, nothing <it>at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't mind cooking <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>at all</it> what you think it is. It's something else entirely.</vi> <vi>I wasn't tired <it>at all</it>. = I wasn't <it>at all</it> tired. [=I wasn't even slightly tired]</vi> <vi>This chair is not <it>at all</it> comfortable.</vi> <vi>I didn't like it <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>That is not <it>at all</it> likely.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>not at all</phrase> is sometimes used as a polite response when someone thanks you. <vi>“Thank you for all your trouble.” “<it>Not at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>“That was very kind of you.” “<it>Not at all</it>. It was the least I could do.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your all</dre> <def><dt>:to do or give as much as you can to achieve something, to support a cause, etc. <vi>He <it>gave his all</it> for the cause. = He <it>gave his all</it> to help the cause.</vi> <vi>You'll never succeed in this business unless you <it>give (it) your all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>There were about a thousand people at the concert <it>in all</it>. [=<it>all told</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>once and for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <def><dt>:after considering or doing everything <un>used for a final general statement or judgment <vi>It won't be easy, but <it>when all is said and done</it>, we'll be glad we did it.</vi> <vi>The candidates claim to have different views but, <it>when all is said and done</it>, they're very much alike.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="another[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">another</hw> <altpr>əˈnʌðɚ</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:one more of the same kind :another one <vi>I've had one drink, but I think I'll have <it>another</it>.</vi> <vi>One copy of the letter was sent out, and <it>another</it> was placed in the files.</vi> <vi>One thief carried a gun, <it>another</it> (carried) a knife.</vi> <vi>This cup is chipped. Could you please bring me <it>another</it>?</vi> <vi>We had dinner at <it>another</it> of the city's many Italian restaurants.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:one that is different :someone or something else <vi>She's not comfortable living in <it>another's</it> house. [=in another person's house]</vi> <vi>Complaining about problems is one thing, but finding solutions to them is <it>another</it>. [=it is more difficult to find solutions to problems than to complain about them]</vi> <vi>The family seems to move from one city to <it>another</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases with <it>one</it> or (less commonly) <it>some</it> to refer to something that is not specified <vi>We all do foolish things <phrase>at one time or another</phrase>. [=<it>sometimes</it>, <it>on occasion</it>]</vi> <vi>They had to change their plans <phrase>for one/some reason or another</phrase>. [=for some reason]</vi> <vi>He vowed that he would succeed (in) <phrase>one way or another</phrase>. [=vowed that he would find a way to succeed]</vi> <vi>a lock <phrase>of one kind/sort/type or another</phrase> [=some kind/sort/type of lock]</vi> <vi>What with <phrase>one thing and another</phrase>, we still haven't finished. [=we still haven't finished because of various things that have happened]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>one another</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>one after another</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a continuing series <vi>The buses kept arriving, <it>one after another</it>.</vi> <vi><it>One</it> person <it>after another</it> walked out of the concert.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:each one in a continuing series <vi><it>One after another</it> of her friends got married and moved away.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
