<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="ahead"> <hw highlight="yes">ahead</hw> <sound><wav>ahead001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈhɛd</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in or toward the front <vi>The road stretched <it>ahead</it> for many miles.</vi> <vi>Someone was standing in the road (up) <it>ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>We knew the way <it>ahead</it> [=<it>forward</it>] was difficult, but we persevered.</vi> <vi>“Full speed <it>ahead</it>!” shouted the captain.</vi> <vi>He was looking <phrase>straight ahead</phrase>. [=directly forward]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to or toward the place where someone is going <vi>I can't leave yet. You go on <it>ahead</it>. I'll catch up later.</vi> <vi>She was delayed at the airport so she sent her bags <it>ahead</it> to the hotel.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in, into, or for the future <vi>We need to think/plan <it>ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>The past year has been successful and, looking <it>ahead</it>, we expect to do even better in the coming months.</vi> <vi>We have some hard work <it>ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>He expects to be very busy in the weeks <it>ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>We don't know what lies <it>ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>We'll pause now for a commercial. The weather report is just <it>ahead</it>. [=the weather report will be broadcast after the commercial]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in the lead in a race or competition <vi>They were trailing by 5 points earlier in the game, but now they're <it>ahead</it> [=<it>winning</it>] by 7.</vi> <vi>They scored three runs to go <it>ahead</it> by two.</vi> <vi>a politician who is <it>ahead</it> in the polls</vi> <vi>We're winning now, but we have to work hard to stay/keep <it>ahead</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:in or toward a better position <vi>I came out $20 <it>ahead</it> on the deal. [=I made a profit of $20 on the deal]</vi> <vi>He's very ambitious. He'll do anything to <phrase>get ahead</phrase>. [=to become successful]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:at an earlier time <vi>She prepared most of the food <it>ahead</it>. [=<it>ahead of time</it>]</vi> <vi>make payments <it>ahead</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ahead of"> <hw>ahead of</hw> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in, at, or to a place before (someone or something) <vi>She got <it>ahead of</it> me.</vi> <vi>Someone was standing in the road just a few yards (up) <it>ahead of</it> us.</vi> <vi>They went on <it>ahead of</it> us and by now are several miles <it>ahead of</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in the future for (someone or something) <vi>We have some hard work <it>ahead of</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:having a lead or advantage over (a competitor) <vi>The polls show that he is <it>ahead of</it> the other candidates.</vi> <vi>The company is working hard to stay one step <it>ahead of</it> the competition.</vi> <vi>They were trailing us by 5 points earlier in the game, but now they're <it>ahead of</it> us by 7.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:better than (something) <vi>The company's earnings are (way/far) <it>ahead of</it> forecasts. [=are (much) better than they were expected to be]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in a more advanced position than (someone or something) <vi>He was a year <it>ahead of</it> me in school. [=he finished school a year before I did]</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>ahead of your time</phrase> or if your ideas, creations, etc., are <phrase>ahead of their time</phrase>, you are too advanced or modern to be understood or appreciated during the time when you live or work. <vi>As a poet, he was <it>ahead of his time</it>. His poems, now regarded as classics, were unpopular when he wrote them.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:at an earlier time than (someone or something) :sooner than (someone or something) <vi>They arrived at the party a few minutes <it>ahead of</it> [=<it>before</it>] us.</vi> <vi>They're hoping to work out an agreement well <it>ahead of</it> [=<it>before</it>] the deadline.</vi> <vi>She prepared most of the food <phrase>ahead of time</phrase>. [=<it>beforehand</it>]</vi> <vi>It looks like we can finish the project <phrase>ahead of schedule</phrase>. [=earlier than planned]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="go-ahead[1]"> <hw hindex="1">go–ahead</hw> <sound><wav>goahea01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowəˌhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the go-ahead</dre> <def><dt>:permission to do something <vi>We've finally been <phrase>given the go-ahead</phrase> for the project.</vi> <vi>The company <phrase>received/got the go-ahead</phrase> to manufacture the new drug.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go ahead</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="go-ahead[2]"> <hw hindex="2">go–ahead</hw> <altpr>ˈgowəˌhɛd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:allowing a team to take the lead in a game <vi>He scored the <it>go-ahead</it> run/touchdown/goal.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>more go–ahead; most go–ahead</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:having a lot of energy and desire to try new ideas and methods <vi>a vigorous <it>go-ahead</it> company</vi></dt></def> <dxnl>see also <tag>go ahead</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="curve[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">curve</hw> <sound><wav>curve001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɚv</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>curves</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a smooth, rounded line, shape, path, etc. <vi>The dog's tail has a slight <it>curve</it>.</vi> <vi>There is a sharp/gentle <it>curve</it> coming up in the road.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a curved line on a graph that shows how something changes or is affected by one or more conditions <vi>the price <it>curve</it> in relation to inflation</vi> <vi>the population growth <it>curve</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>learning curve</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a curving line or shape of the human body and especially of a woman's body <un>usually plural <vi>The dress follows the <it>curves</it> of the body.</vi> <vi>voluptuous <it>curves</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:<sx>curveball</sx> <vi>The pitcher threw him a <it>curve</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Life has <phrase>thrown him some curves</phrase> [=<it>thrown him some curveballs</it>] over the years but he's never given up. [=he has had some difficult and unexpected problems in his life]</vi> <vi>The reporter <it>threw the actress a curve</it> [=surprised her with a difficult and unexpected question] when he asked about her past drug use.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>ahead of the curve</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>approving</sl> <dt>:faster about doing something than other people, companies, etc. <vi>The company has been <it>ahead of the curve</it> in adopting new technologies. [=has adopted new technologies faster than other companies]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>behind the curve</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:slower about doing something than other people, companies, etc. <vi>We are <it>behind the curve</it> when it comes to advances in medicine. [=we have not been keeping up with the latest advances as well as others]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="full[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">full</hw> <sound><wav>full0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfʊl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>full*er</if></in> <in><if>full*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:containing or holding as much or as many as possible <vi>a <it>full</it> bottle</vi> <vi>The disk is <it>full</it>.</vi> <vi>The plane was carrying a <it>full</it> load of passengers.</vi> <vi>The theater was <it>full</it> to capacity.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>a bottle <it>full of</it> milk</vi> <vi>a bin <it>full of</it> corn</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:not lacking anything :complete in number, amount, etc. <vi>We bought a <it>full</it> set of dishes.</vi> <vi>They waited for three <it>full</it> months.</vi> <vi>He has a <it>full</it> array of stereo equipment.</vi> <vi>The soldiers were wearing <it>full</it> combat gear.</vi> <vi>This will be his first <it>full</it> season with the team.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>a full</phrase> is often used to stress the large size of an amount. <vi>He won the match by <it>a full</it> seven strokes.</vi> <vi>It was <it>a full</it> three months before they made a decision.</vi> <vi>He's <it>a full</it> foot taller than his wife.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not limited in any way <vi>His theories have not yet found <it>full</it> acceptance.</vi> <vi>I have <it>full</it> [=<it>complete</it>] confidence in your honesty.</vi> <vi>I hope that you'll give us your <it>fullest</it> cooperation.</vi> <vi>Please give me your <it>full</it> attention.</vi> <vi>We need to take <it>full</it> advantage of this opportunity.</vi> <vi>She's expected to make a <it>full</it> recovery.</vi> <vi>They're not making <it>full</it> use of these resources.</vi> <vi>He's now a <it>full</it> member of the club. = He now has <it>full</it> membership in the club.</vi> <vi>the rights of <it>full</it> citizenship</vi> <vi>a <it>full</it> professor</vi> <vi>We're still waiting to hear the <it>full</it> story of what happened.</vi> <vi>She deserves <it>full</it> credit for meeting the deadline.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not reduced or shortened <vi>He doesn't like having to pay <it>full</it> price.</vi> <vi>We could feel the <it>full</it> impact of every bump.</vi> <vi>What is your <it>full</it> name?</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:existing or working at the highest or greatest degree :developed as much as possible <vi>The flowers were in <it>full</it> bloom.</vi> <vi>The machine was running at <it>full</it> power/speed.</vi> <vi>The factory is operating at <it>full</it> capacity.</vi> <vi>The tree has not yet reached <it>full</it> size.</vi> <vi>The stereo was at <it>full</it> volume. [=was playing as loudly as possible]</vi> <vi>After the meeting, he had a <it>fuller</it> understanding of the job.</vi> <vi>It'll be a few minutes before you feel the <it>full</it> effect of the drug.</vi> <vi>He hasn't yet realized his <it>full</it> potential as a writer.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:including many things <vi>She has a <it>full</it> range of interests. [=she is interested in many different things]</vi> <vi>The store carries a <it>full</it> line of products.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:involving many activities <vi>We have a <it>full</it> schedule of events planned.</vi> <vi>We have a <it>full</it> day of work ahead of us.</vi> :very active <vi>She lived a very <it>full</it> and satisfying life.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:having a rounded shape :not thin or narrow <vi>She has a <it>full</it> face.</vi> <vi>a woman with a <it>full</it> figure = a <it>full</it>-figured woman</vi> <vi><it>full</it> lips</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:having or containing a great number or amount <it>of</it> something <vi>The room was <it>full of</it> pictures.</vi> <vi>Despite his problems, he was still <it>full of</it> hope.</vi> <vi><it>full of</it> enthusiasm</vi> <vi>food <it>full of</it> flavor</vi> <vi>He says the charges against him are <it>full of</it> lies.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:having eaten all that is wanted <vi>No dessert for me, thank you. I'm <it>full</it>. [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>full up</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:large enough to satisfy hunger <vi>I like to start the day with a <it>full</it> breakfast.</vi> <vi>a <it>full</it> meal</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:having a large amount of material <vi>a <it>full</it> skirt/dress</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a large amount of hair <vi>He has a <it>full</it> [=<it>thick</it>] head of hair.</vi> <vi>a <it>full</it> beard</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:thinking <it>of</it> something all the time <vi>He was <it>full of</it> his own concerns.</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>full of yourself</phrase>, you think of yourself more than you should. <vi>She is certainly very <it>full of herself</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:having a strong and pleasing quality <vi>a food/wine of <it>full</it> flavor</vi> <vi>His voice is a <it>full</it>, rich baritone.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>of the moon</ssl> <dt>:appearing as a bright circle <vi>The moon is <it>full</it> tonight.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>full blast</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>full count</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>full of beans</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bean</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>full of crap/shit</dre> <def><sl>informal + offensive</sl> <dt>:not to be believed :saying things that are not true <vi>That guy is <it>full of shit</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>full of it</dre> <def><sl>informal + sometimes offensive</sl> <dt>:not to be believed <vi>His story was so exaggerated that I thought he was <it>full of it</it>.</vi> <vi>Oh, you're so <it>full of it</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>full steam/speed ahead</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is being done with as much speed and power as possible <vi>The work started slowly, but now it's <it>full steam ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>The campaign is <phrase>going full speed ahead</phrase>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have your hands full</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not playing with a full deck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>deck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the fullest</dre> <def><dt>:in a very active and energetic way <vi>She likes to live life <it>to the fullest</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>full*ness</ure> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>ful*ness</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>fullness</it> of her voice</vi> <vi>The conditioner added <it>fullness</it> to her hair.</vi> <vi>I expected it would happen <phrase>in the fullness of time</phrase>. [=it would happen eventually]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="game[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">game</hw> <sound><wav>game0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgeɪm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>games</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a physical or mental activity or contest that has rules and that people do for pleasure <vi>a card <it>game</it></vi> <vi>party <it>games</it> [=activities people do at parties for pleasure]</vi> <vi>word <it>games</it> [=games or puzzles that involve words]</vi> <vi>computer <it>games</it></vi> <vi>poker and other gambling <it>games</it></vi> <vi>Baseball is my favorite <it>game</it>. [=<it>sport</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a particular occurrence of a game <vi>Do you want to play a <it>game</it> (of tennis/cards)?</vi> <vi>She scored a goal to tie the <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>They won/lost the <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>We played a few <it>games</it> of chess.</vi> <vi>That was a good <it>game</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:one of the games that are part of a larger contest (such as a tennis match) <vi>She won the first two <it>games</it>, but lost the set and the match.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>ball game</dxt> <dxt>board game</dxt> <dxt>fun and games</dxt> <dxt>guessing game</dxt> <dxt>parlor game</dxt> <dxt>perfect game</dxt> <dxt>return game</dxt> <dxt>shell game</dxt> <dxt>video game</dxt> <tag>game of chance</tag> at <dxt>chance</dxt> <tag>game of skill</tag> at <dxt>skill</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>games</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:playful activities <vi>children playing at their <it>games</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>Games</va></svr> <dt>:an organized series of athletic contests</dt> <sd>specifically</sd> <dt>:the Olympics <vi>Let the <it>Games</it> begin.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the way someone plays in a sport <vi>They are known to play a very rough <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>She has a strong all-around <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>She needs to improve her <it>game</it> if she wants to win the championship.</vi> <vi>Champions can raise/lift their <it>game</it> [=can play better] when they're in danger of losing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a skill that is used in playing a particular game or sport <vi>a football team with a strong running/passing <it>game</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an activity that is being compared to a game or contest <vi>He's a loser in the <it>game</it> of love. [=he is not successful in romantic relationships]</vi> <vi>the <it>game</it> of life</vi> <vi>They're playing a dangerous <it>game</it> by refusing to negotiate.</vi> <vi>He's trying to <phrase>beat them at their own game</phrase>. [=he's trying to gain an advantage over them by using the same methods that they use]</vi> <vi>the <phrase>mating game</phrase> [=the effort to find a sexual partner]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>waiting game</dxt> <dxt>war game</dxt> <tag>the name of the game</tag> at <dxt>name</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a type of work :a business or profession <vi>She's spent the last 30 years in the newspaper <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>the money <it>game</it></vi> <vi>the <phrase>fight game</phrase> [=professional boxing]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>war game</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is not meant to be taken seriously <vi>Politics for her is just a <it>game</it>.</vi> <vi>Was our entire relationship just a <it>game</it> to you?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a usually dishonest or unfair plan for doing something <vi>I've seen through your little <it>game</it> and I know what you're really after!</vi> <vi>What's his <it>game</it>? [=what is his real reason for doing the things he is doing?]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>give the game away</phrase> is to make a secret plan or activity known. <vi>We can't let him know anything about it. He's too likely to <it>give the game away</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If <phrase>the game is up</phrase>, a dishonest plan or activity has been discovered and will no longer be allowed to continue. <vi>Okay, <it>the game is up</it>. [=<it>the jig is up</it>] We know you forged the letters.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:animals that are hunted <vi>wild <it>game</it></vi> <vi>small <it>game</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>game</it> bird/fish [=a bird or fish that may be legally hunted or caught]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>game preserve</phrase> [=an area of land in which hunting and fishing are carefully controlled]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>game warden</phrase> [=a person who makes sure that hunting and fishing laws are obeyed]</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The police aren't interested in these small-time drug dealers; they're after much bigger <it>game</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>big game</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>ahead of the game</dre> <def><dt>:in a position or situation in which you are likely to succeed, win, etc. <vi>The company has stayed <it>ahead of the game</it> by meeting new government standards before they go into effect.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>early/late in the game</dre> <def><dt>:at an early/late time in a game or sport <vi>She scored a goal <it>early in the game</it>. [=near the beginning of the game]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>It's too <it>late in the game</it> to change the date of the meeting. [=it's no longer reasonable to change the date; the meeting is too soon for the date to be changed]</vi> <vi>She got into the computer industry <it>early in the game</it>. [=when the industry was new]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>got game</dre> <def><dt><snote>In informal U.S. English, someone who has <it>got game</it> is very good at playing a particular game or sport, such as basketball.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head/mind games</dre> <def><dt>:actions that are meant to confuse or upset someone in order to get an advantage <vi>I couldn't handle the <it>head games</it> that came with the job anymore.</vi> <vi>She's known for playing <it>mind games</it> with her opponents.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the game</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:working as a prostitute <vi>I didn't know she was <it>on the game</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/off your game</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>on your game</it>, you are playing a sport or game well; if you are <it>off your game</it>, you are playing poorly. <vi>She's really <it>on her game</it> tonight. [=she's playing very well]</vi> <vi>Sorry I missed that shot. I'm <it>off my game</it> today. [=I'm not playing as well as I usually do]</vi> These phrases are also used figuratively. <vi>He seemed a little <it>off his game</it> during the sales presentation this morning.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play games</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to treat someone in a dishonest or unfair way in order to get an advantage <vi>Stop <it>playing games</it> (with me) and tell me what really happened!</vi> <vi>I'm trying to be honest with you. I'm not interested in <it>playing games</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to behave in a way that is not serious <vi>Let's stop <it>playing games</it> and get down to business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the only game in town</dre> <def><dt>:the only available, desirable, or valuable thing <vi>For serious home cooks, this stove is <it>the only game in town</it>. [=it is the only stove that serious home cooks should want to have]</vi> <vi>Our company is no longer <it>the only game in town</it>. [=we now have competition; another company/business is doing what we do]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="get"> <hw highlight="yes">get</hw> <sound><wav>get00001.wav</wav><wav>get00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɛt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gets</if></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>got</if> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <sound><wav>get00003.wav</wav></sound> <il>or US</il> <if>got*ten</if> <sound><wav>get00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:tn̩</pr></in> <in><if>get*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to obtain (something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to receive or be given (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> a new bicycle for his birthday.</vi> <vi>I never did <it>get</it> an answer to my question.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> a letter from my lawyer.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a phone call from her sister.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>get</it> my message?</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] a ride to town with you? [=will you give me a ride to town?]</vi> <vi>You need to <it>get</it> your mother's permission to go.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to obtain (something) through effort, chance, etc. <vi>She hasn't been able to <it>get</it> a job.</vi> <vi>It's nearly impossible to <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a reservation at that restaurant.</vi> <vi>If you want to be successful you need to <it>get</it> a good education.</vi> <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> the waiter's attention.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> a look at the thief. [=she managed to look at the thief]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to obtain the use or services of (something) <vi>It took us a while to <it>get</it> a taxi.</vi> <vi>It's hard to <it>get</it> good help these days.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to earn or gain (something) <vi>How much does he <it>get</it> [=<it>make</it>] a week?</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> $50 when I sold my old bicycle. = I <it>got</it> $50 for my old bicycle.</vi> <vi>He's <it>gotten</it> a bad reputation (for himself). = He's <it>gotten</it> himself a bad reputation.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> an “A” on my history exam!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>She <it>got</it> first prize in the essay contest.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to buy or pay for (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> (himself) a new car at a great price.</vi> <vi>“Did you <it>get</it> that dress at the mall?” “Yes, and I <it>got</it> it for only $20.”</vi> <vi>Do you <it>get</it> [=subscribe to] the local newspaper?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the next round of drinks.</vi> <vi>He offered to <it>get</it> the check, but I insisted on <it>getting</it> it myself.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> a beautiful necklace for his wife. = He <it>got</it> his wife a beautiful necklace.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go somewhere and come back with (something or someone) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> a pencil from the desk.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>get</it> anything for you? = Can I <it>get</it> you anything?</vi> <vi>Someone has to (go) <it>get</it> the boss from the airport and bring her back here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to send or take (something or someone) <it>to</it> a person or place <vi>I have to <it>get</it> an important message <it>to</it> her at once!</vi> <vi>We have to <it>get</it> him <it>to</it> the hospital immediately.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to move or go <vi>He quickly <it>got</it> himself and his luggage through customs.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> the car out of the garage.</vi> <vi>I could barely <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] the luggage into the car's trunk.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> this ring on/off my finger.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <vi>He <it>got</it> on the horse and rode away.</vi> <vi>We <it>got</it> on/off the bus.</vi> <vi>They quickly <it>got</it> [=<it>passed</it>] through customs.</vi> <vi>She never <it>got</it> out of the house last weekend.</vi> <vi>He lost weight to be able to <it>get</it> [=<it>fit</it>] into his jeans again.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> between them to keep them from fighting.</vi> <vi>Ouch! <it>Get</it> off my foot!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>When did you <it>get</it> here/there?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> home last night.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have (a feeling, an idea, etc.) <vi>I <it>got</it> a funny feeling when I saw her again.</vi> <vi>He somehow <it>got</it> the idea that I was lying to him.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> the impression that he wasn't interested.</vi> <vi>One thing led to another, and—well, <phrase>you get the picture/idea</phrase>. [=you can easily guess the rest]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become affected by (a disease) <vi>I <it>got</it> a bad cold when I was on vacation.</vi> <vi>Clean the wound carefully so you don't <it>get</it> an infection.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suffer (an injury) <vi>He <it>got</it> a broken nose in a fight.</vi> <vi>Where/how did you <it>get</it> that bruise on your leg?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or experience (something) <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> a lot of rain recently.</vi> <vi>I finally <it>got</it> a good night's sleep last night. [=I finally slept well last night]</vi> <vi>The inn doesn't <it>get</it> many visitors these days.</vi> <vi>“Do people often ask if you're Irish?” “Yes, I <it>get</it> that a lot.” [=people ask me that often]</vi> <vi><phrase>You get</phrase> [=there are] so many crazy drivers these days.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a particular reaction) <vi>That joke always <it>gets</it> a laugh.</vi> <vi>Her comments <it>got</it> an angry reaction.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make progress in some activity <vi>He hasn't <it>gotten</it> far with the essay. [=he hasn't made much progress with the essay]</vi> <vi>You won't <it>get</it> anywhere with flattery. [=you won't succeed by using flattery]</vi> <vi>At last we're <phrase>getting somewhere</phrase> (with our work)!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get ahead <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to make progress <vi>All that effort didn't really <it>get</it> us very far.</vi> <vi>Flattery will <phrase>get you nowhere</phrase>. = Flattery <phrase>won't get you anywhere</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a specified position or condition <vi>He <it>got</it> his feet wet when he stepped in a puddle.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> his nose broken in a fight. [=his nose was broken in a fight]</vi> <vi>I told you not to <it>get</it> yourself dirty.</vi> <vi>You nearly <it>got</it> us both killed!</vi> <vi>I need to <it>get</it> [=<it>have</it>] my hair cut.</vi> <vi>She finally <it>got</it> her office organized.</vi> <vi>He promised to <it>get</it> the work done quickly. [=to do the work quickly]</vi> <vi>When you're making a measurement be careful to <phrase>get it right</phrase>. [=to do it correctly]</vi> <vi>Let me <phrase>get this straight</phrase> [=let me be sure that I understand this correctly]: are you saying that you won't help us?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do something <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I can't <it>get</it> the children <it>to behave</it>.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>get</it> you <it>to understand</it> that this isn't a good idea?</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>to work</it> again.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>He <it>got</it> the computer <it>working</it> again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start <it>doing</it> something <vi>We <it>got talking</it> about old times.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>1a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or be given the chance <it>to do</it> something :to be able <it>to do</it> something <vi>She never <it>got to go</it> to college.</vi> <vi>Why do I never <it>get to drive</it> the car?</vi> <vi>She hopes she'll finally <it>get to spend</it> more time working on her garden this year.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to deal with (something that needs attention): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to answer (a telephone) <vi>Would somebody please <it>get</it> the phone?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to open (a door) <vi>If you'll <it>get</it> the door for me, I'll carry that box inside.</vi> <vi>There's someone at the door. Would you please <phrase>get it</phrase>? [=open the door and deal with the person who knocked]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to understand (something or someone) <vi>I just don't <it>get</it> the point of what you're saying.</vi> <vi>He didn't <it>get</it> the joke.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>get</it> what you mean.</vi> <vi>Oh, now I <phrase>get it</phrase>. [=<it>understand</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I just don't <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>Don't <phrase>get me wrong</phrase>. [=don't misunderstand what I am saying]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>get your drift</phrase>. [=I understand what you are saying]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I didn't quite <it>get</it> [=<it>catch</it>] his name.</vi></dt> <sn>17 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:<sx>become <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>My hands <it>got</it> dirty when I was working in the garden.</vi> <vi>I <it>get</it> very nervous when I have to speak in public.</vi> <vi>I <it>got</it> sick last week but I'm feeling better now.</vi> <vi>I just can't <it>get</it> used to this cold weather.</vi> <vi>She sent her sick friend a “<it>Get</it> Well Soon” card.</vi> <vi>I should go; it's <it>getting</it> late.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) Your daughter's <it>getting</it> quite a big girl now!</vi> <vi>We need to finish by 5 o'clock, so we'd better <phrase>get busy</phrase>. [=begin to work]</vi> <vi>You've never heard of the Internet? Come on, now. <phrase>Get with it</phrase>. [=become up-to-date in your knowledge]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>how stupid/lucky (etc.) can you get</phrase> to mean that someone or something is unusually stupid, lucky, etc. <vi>He tried to rob a policeman. <it>How stupid can you get</it>? [=he was very stupid to try to rob a policeman]</vi> <vi>Just look at that dress! <it>How tacky can you get</it>? [=that dress is very tacky]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change in a specified way as time passes <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Your daughter is <it>getting to be</it> [=is becoming] quite a big girl now!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something specified <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Once you <it>get to know</it> him, you will like him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>auxiliary verb</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>be</it> with the past participle of some verbs to form passive constructions <vi>They <it>got</it> [=<it>were</it>] married last month.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>was</it>] paid for his work.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> arrested for fraud.</vi> <vi>I nearly <it>got</it> killed.</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (a meal) <vi>We <it>got</it> dinner at an Italian restaurant last night.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare (a meal) <vi>On weekends, my wife sleeps late while I <it>get</it> breakfast.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (punishment) <vi>He <it>got</it> five years in prison for his crime.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you don't stop misbehaving you're going to <phrase>get it</phrase> when your father gets home! [=your father is going to punish you]</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to grip and hold (something or someone) <vi>The dog <it>got</it> the thief by the leg.</vi> <vi>He <it>got</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>] me around/by the neck and wouldn't let go.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find and catch (someone) <vi>The Royal Canadian Mounted Police always <it>get</it> their man! [=they always capture the man they are trying to capture]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone) <vi>The bullet <it>got</it> him in the leg.</vi></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or cause trouble for (someone) <vi>He's convinced that his ex-wife is out to <it>get</it> him.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you if it's the last thing I do!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the death of (someone) <vi>He had heart problems for many years, but it was pneumonia that <it>got</it> him in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>It really <it>gets</it> me that such a foolish man has so much influence.</vi> <vi>What <it>gets</it> me is all these delays!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2a (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) sad <vi>The end of that movie always <it>gets</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get to <dxn>2b (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be fooled or unable to think of an answer <vi>Well, you <it>got</it> [=<it>fooled, tricked</it>] me that time. That was very clever.</vi> <vi>That's a good question. <phrase>You've got me (there)</phrase>. [=I don't know the answer]</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a phone call and hear or speak to (a person or answering machine) <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get</it> [=<it>reach</it>] you (on the phone) all day!</vi> <vi>When I tried to call him I <it>got</it> his answering machine. [=the phone was answered by his answering machine]</vi></dt> <sn>28</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to receive (a radio or TV station or channel) <vi>We don't <it>get</it> this channel at home.</vi></dt> <sn>29</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce or provide (a level of performance) <vi>Our new car <it>gets</it> [=<it>delivers</it>] excellent gas mileage.</vi></dt> <sn>30</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to notice (someone or something) <vi>Did you <it>get</it> the way he looked at you?</vi> <un>often used to direct someone's attention to a person or thing that is seen as foolish, surprising, etc. <vi>Just <it>get</it> him in his new pants!</vi> <vi>She showed up at the party in—<phrase>get this</phrase>—a $3,000 designer dress!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>get about</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get above yourself</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my point has finally <it>gotten across</it> to you. [=I hope you finally understand what I am trying to say]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my point <it>across</it> to you.</vi> <vi>a politician who is trying hard to <it>get</it> his message <it>across</it> (to the voters)</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>get after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to tell (someone) repeatedly to do something <vi>His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him about doing his homework. = His parents are always <it>getting after</it> him to do his homework.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to become more successful <vi>a book about how to <it>get ahead</it> in the business world</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be or remain friendly <vi>We <it>get along</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi> <vi>My brother and my uncle don't really <it>get along</it> (with each other).</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How are you <it>getting along</it> with your work? [=how's your work coming along?]</vi> <vi>He never showed up, but we managed to <it>get along</it> [=<it>get by</it>] without him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>I really must be <it>getting along</it>. [=<it>going, leaving</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become old <vi>Her parents are <phrase>getting along in years</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to go, walk, or travel to different places <vi>She <it>gets around</it> a lot because of her job.</vi> <vi>He's having trouble <it>getting around</it> because of his sore knee.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>get round</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>get about</va></svr> <dt>:to become known by many people <vi>People will be shocked when the news about her arrest <it>gets around</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got around</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to avoid being stopped by (something) :to avoid having to deal with (something) <vi>I'm sure we can find a way to <it>get around</it> these problems.</vi> <vi><phrase>There's no getting around</phrase> the fact that the current system isn't working. [=there is no way to deny that the current system isn't working]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get around to (something)</pva> <pvl>or chiefly Brit</pvl> <pva>get round to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or deal with (something that you have not yet done or dealt with) <vi>Don't you think it's about time you <it>got around to</it> tidying your room?</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call her, but I just haven't <it>gotten around to</it> it. [=I haven't called her]</vi> <vi>Sooner or later we'll have to <it>get around to</it> the subject of taxation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach (something or someone) <vi>The valve is hard to <it>get at</it> unless you have a special tool.</vi> <vi>An angry mob tried to <it>get at</it> him but the police protected him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find out (information that is hidden or hard to know) <vi>How can we ever <it>get at</it> the truth?</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or suggest (something) in an indirect way <un>usually used as <phrase>getting at</phrase> <vi>Just what are you <it>getting at</it>? [=what are you suggesting?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>He says his teachers are always <it>getting at</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>getting on</it>] him unfairly.</vi> <vi>He's always being <it>got at</it> by his teachers.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get at it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You have a lot of work to do so you'd better <it>get at it</it>. [=<it>get to it</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go away from a place <vi>I'll be busy at work all day and I can't <it>get away</it> until tonight.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company is having problems because they've <phrase>gotten away from</phrase> the things they do best. [=they have stopped doing the things they do best]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go away from your home for a vacation <vi>I'm taking some time off because I really need to <it>get away</it> for a few days.</vi> <vi>We went on a cruise to <phrase>get away from it all</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to avoid being caught :to escape <vi>The robbers <it>got away</it> (from the police) in a fast car.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The robbers <it>got away with</it> a lot of stolen jewelry.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can't <it>get away</it> from the facts. = <phrase>There's no getting away from</phrase> the facts. [=you can't avoid or deny the facts; the facts are known and cannot be ignored]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>getaway</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be criticized or punished for (something) <vi>She's incredibly rude. I don't know how she <it>gets away with</it> it.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>There's a chance of rain, but I think I can probably <it>get away with</it> leaving my umbrella at home. [=I probably will not need my umbrella]</vi> <vi>It would be nice to have more food for the party, but I think we can <it>get away with</it> what we have. [=I think what we have is enough and will not cause problems for us]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given only slight or mild punishment for a crime or for doing something wrong <vi>The policeman stopped her for speeding but let her <it>get away with</it> just a warning.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get away with murder</tag> at <dxt>murder</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return to a place after going away <vi>When did you <it>get back</it> from your vacation?</vi> <vi>We <it>got back</it> to the office in the early afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to return to an activity, condition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Things are finally <it>getting back to</it> normal.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>get back to</it> the topic we were discussing yesterday.</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>get back to work</phrase>. [=to start working again]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get or obtain (something you have lost) again :to recover (something) <vi>He <it>got</it> his old job <it>back</it> after a long struggle.</vi> <vi>Someone stole his wallet but he <it>got</it> it <it>back</it> from the police.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get back at (someone)</pva> <pvl>or Brit</pvl> <pva>get your own back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do something bad or unpleasant to someone who has treated you badly or unfairly <vi>I'll <it>get</it> you <it>back</it> for what you did to me!</vi> <vi>After he lost his job, he vowed that he would find a way to <it>get back at</it> his old boss.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get back to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk to or write to (someone) at a later time in order to give more information, answer a question, etc. <vi>He <it>got back to</it> me (by e-mail) in a few days with a new offer.</vi> <vi>“How much will it cost?” “I'm not sure. I'll have to <it>get back to</it> you on that.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to call (someone) back on the telephone <vi>“There's someone on the phone for you, sir.” “Tell them I can't take their call now but I'll <it>get back to</it> them as soon as I can.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get back to (the) basics</dre> <dx>see <dxt>basic</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fail to do something as quickly as required or expected <vi>We've been <it>getting</it> further (and further) <it>behind</it> (schedule).</vi> <vi>We <it>got behind</it> with our car payments.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get behind (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to support (someone or something) <vi>The proposal may succeed if a few more people <it>get behind</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do enough or to do well enough to avoid failure <vi>He's doing very well in his history classes, but he's barely <it>getting by</it> in math.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be able to live or to do what is needed by using what you have even though you do not have much <vi>We don't have a lot of money, but we <it>get by</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>How can you <it>get by on</it> such a small salary?</vi></un> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>We <it>got by with</it> a minimum of clothing when we went camping.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get cracking</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>The weather was really <it>getting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Talking about politics always <it>gets</it> me <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to swallow (something) :to eat or drink (something) <vi>You'll feel better once you <it>get</it> this medicine <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to write (something) down <vi>If you have a good idea, you should <it>get</it> it <it>down</it> (in writing) so that you won't forget it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to play music or dance with skill and enthusiasm <vi>She likes to <it>get down</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) :to begin to give your attention or effort to (something) <vi>It's time to stop delaying and <it>get down to</it> work.</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>get down to business</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to talk about or describe (something) in a very simple and accurate way <vi><phrase>When you get right down to it</phrase>, this movie is just not very good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get even</dre> <dx>see <dxt>even</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get going</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave <vi>We ought to <it>get going</it> if we don't want to be late.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>You should <it>get going</it> on that assignment.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to start talking <vi>Once he <it>gets going</it> about the war you can't shut him up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to start talking <vi>Don't <it>get</it> him <it>going</it> about the war or you'll never shut him up!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to enter a place <vi>The burglar <it>got in</it> through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place <vi>The train <it>got in</it> late.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to arrive home <vi>Her husband was out late last night. He didn't <it>get in</it> until almost midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become involved in an activity <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got in</it> at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be chosen or elected for office <vi>The mayor <it>got in</it> by a very slim margin.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>It's a very good school. I hope your daughter <it>gets in</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have (someone) come to your home, business, etc., to do work <vi>We had to <it>get</it> a doctor/plumber <it>in</it> to deal with the emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do or say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get</it> a few good punches <it>in</it> before they stopped the fight.</vi> <vi>May I <phrase>get a word in</phrase> here? [=may I say something here?]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get a word in edgewise</tag> at <dxt>edgewise</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send or deliver (something) to the proper person or place <vi>Did you <it>get</it> your assignment <it>in</it> on time?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to do (something) in the amount of time that is available <vi>I was able to <it>get in</it> a few hours of reading last night.</vi> <vi>I hope we can <it>get in</it> a visit to the art museum the next time we're in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to harvest (a crop) and put it in a safe or dry place <vi>It's time to <it>get</it> the crop/harvest <it>in</it>.</vi> <vi>We'd better <it>get</it> the hay <it>in</it> before it rains.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become involved in (something) <vi>It sounds like an interesting project and I'd like to <it>get in on</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become friends with (someone) <vi>She <it>got in with</it> [=<it>fell in with</it>] a bad crowd and got into trouble.</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>get in good with</phrase> the boss. [=he got the boss to like him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (a place)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to enter (a place) <vi>The burglar <it>got into</it> the house through an unlocked window.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The train <it>got into</it> New York late last night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become involved in (an activity) <vi>The people who have become rich in this business are the ones who <it>got into</it> it at the beginning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to be interested in and to enjoy (something) <vi>It's only recently that I've really <it>gotten into</it> music.</vi> <vi>I tried reading the book, but I just couldn't <it>get into</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted or to cause (someone) to be accepted as a student, member, etc. <vi>I hope your daughter <it>gets into</it> the school.</vi> <vi>I hope you <it>get</it> your daughter <it>into</it> the school.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become involved or to cause (someone) to become involved in (something bad, such as trouble or a fight) <vi>He <it>got into</it> a lot of trouble when he was a teenager.</vi> <vi>They <it>got into</it> an argument.</vi> <vi>His friends <it>got</it> him <it>into</it> trouble.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll tell you what happened, but I don't want to <it>get into</it> [=<it>go into</it>] all the reasons for why it happened.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>got into (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to affect the behavior of (someone) <un>used to say that someone is behaving in an unusual way and you don't know why <vi>I don't know what has <it>gotten into</it> him lately.</vi> <vi>She never used to be so rude to people. <phrase>What got into her?</phrase> [=why is she behaving this way?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get lost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get lucky</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lucky</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get moving</dre> <dx>see <dxt>move</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave at the start of a journey <vi>We <it>got off</it> early on our camping trip.</vi> <un>often used figuratively in the phrase <phrase>get off to a good/bad (etc.) start</phrase> <vi>He and I <it>got off to a bad start</it>, but now we get along well.</vi> <vi>The project <it>got off to a slow start</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>get off on the right/wrong foot</tag> at <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be punished for a crime :to be judged not guilty of a crime <vi>He's been arrested several times, but he always <it>gets off</it>.</vi> :to help (someone) to be judged not guilty <vi>His lawyer <it>got</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be given or to help (someone) to be given only a slight punishment for a crime <vi>She <it>got off</it> lightly.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He <it>got off with</it> a light sentence.</vi> <vi>His lawyer tried to <it>get</it> him <it>off with</it> a light sentence.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>It was a bad accident. You're lucky that you <it>got off with</it> just a broken leg—you could have been killed!</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being on or against someone or something <vi><it>Get off</it>—you're hurting me!</vi> <vi>I took the subway and <it>got off</it> at the downtown station.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>5a</dxn> <dxn>b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop talking about (something) or to cause (someone) to stop talking about (something) <vi>We somehow <it>got off</it> (the subject of) work and started talking about our personal lives.</vi> <vi>I tried to change the subject, but I couldn't <it>get</it> her <it>off</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off work</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to finish working and leave the place where you work <vi>I <it>get off</it> early on Fridays.</vi> <vi>I <it>got off work</it> early last Thursday so I could see the parade.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write and send (a letter, an e-mail message, etc.) <vi>I'll <it>get</it> the letter <it>off</it> (to them) tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to shoot (something) from a gun <vi>The policeman <it>got off</it> [=<it>fired</it>] several shots before the criminal escaped.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He managed to <it>get off</it> a few good jokes in his speech.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to fall asleep or to help (someone, such as a baby) to fall asleep <vi>I had just <it>got off</it> [=<it>dropped off</it>] when the doorbell rang. = I had just <phrase>got off to sleep</phrase> when the doorbell rang.</vi> <vi>I just <it>got</it> the baby <it>off to sleep</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have an orgasm or to cause (someone) to have an orgasm</dt> <sn>9</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal + sometimes disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy or be excited by (something) especially in a sexual way <vi>He's one of those guys who seem to <it>get off on</it> making other people feel guilty.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <phrasev><pva>get off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone) :to begin a sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>She found out he'd <it>gotten off with</it> another woman.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>tell someone where to get off</phrase> is to criticize or disagree with someone in a very direct and angry way. <vi>I was sick of listening to his constant complaints, so I <it>told him where to get off</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>don't know where someone gets off</phrase> (doing something), you are angry because someone has done something that is not right. <vi>I <it>don't know where he gets off</it> telling me what to do. = <phrase>Where does he get off</phrase> telling me what to do? [=he has no right to tell me what to do]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you. I'll let you <it>get on with</it> your work.</vi> <vi>You need to stop feeling sorry for yourself and just <phrase>get on with your life</phrase>. [=return to doing the things you do in your normal life]</vi> <vi>This introduction is taking forever. I wish they'd just <phrase>get on with it</phrase>. [=stop delaying and get to the interesting or important part]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to be or remain friendly :to get along <vi>They've never really <it>got on</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>We <it>get on</it> well enough, but we're not really close friends.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make progress while doing something <vi>How is your daughter <it>getting on</it> in/at school?</vi> <vi>We can <it>get on</it> [=<it>get along, get by, manage</it>] just fine without them.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to achieve greater success :to get ahead <vi>an ambitious young woman trying to <it>get on</it> in business</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“These files need to be organized.” “I'll <it>get on</it> it right away.”</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) repeatedly <vi>His boss has been <it>getting on</it> him about the quality of his work.</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>getting on his case</phrase> about cleaning his room. [=she's always telling him to clean it]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it on</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US slang</ssl> <dt>:to have sex</dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on in years</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to grow old <vi>My grandmother is <it>getting on</it> [=<it>aging</it>] a bit, but she's still very active.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become late <vi>It's <it>getting on</it>, and we really ought to go.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get on for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to move toward becoming (a specified age, time, etc.) <vi>He's <it>getting on for</it> 70. [=he's approaching 70; he is nearly 70]</vi> <vi>It was <it>getting on for</it> noon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get onto</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>get on to</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to start to do or deal with (something) <vi>“We need someone to send out the invitations.” “I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get on</it>] it right away.”</vi> :to start to talk about something <vi>How did we <it>get onto</it> this topic?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get onto (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get on to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to speak to or write to (someone) about a particular problem, job, etc. <vi>I'll <it>get onto</it> [=<it>get in touch with</it>] the doctor/plumber straightaway and see if he'll come round.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave or escape from a place, a vehicle, etc. <vi>He was trapped in the burning building/car, but he was somehow able to <it>get out</it> (of it) alive.</vi> <un>used as an angry way to tell someone to leave <vi><it>Get out</it>! I never want to see you again!</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or help (someone) to leave or escape <vi>The firemen managed to <it>get</it> him <it>out</it> (of the burning building) alive.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) from storage so that it can be used <vi>It's raining. I'd better <it>get out</it> the umbrella.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go to places outside your home for social occasions, events, etc. <vi>You spend too much time at home. You need to <it>get out</it> more.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become known <vi>Their secret <it>got out</it>.</vi> <vi>Word <it>got out</it> that she was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say (something) by making an effort <vi>He managed to <it>get out</it> a few words before he collapsed.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to show that you are surprised by something or do not believe it <vi>“They gave the job to Jane.” “<it>Get out</it>!” = “<phrase>Get out of here</phrase>!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get out of (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone or something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to avoid doing (something) or to help (someone) to avoid doing (something) <vi>I didn't want to go to the lecture, but I couldn't <it>get out of</it> it.</vi> <vi>He tried to <it>get out of</it> doing his homework.</vi> <vi>My sister said she could <it>get</it> me <it>out of</it> going to the party if I really didn't want to go</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having (a habit) or to cause (someone) to stop having (a habit) <vi>I used to exercise every day, but I <it>got out of</it> the habit.</vi> <vi>All the extra work I've been doing has <it>gotten</it> me <it>out of</it> the habit of exercising.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop being in or involved in (something) or to cause (someone or something) to stop being in or involved in (something) <vi>The company has decided to <it>get</it> (itself) <it>out of</it> the computer business.</vi> <vi>She <it>got</it> her money <it>out of</it> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something) from (something or someone) <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> the gun <it>out of</it> the suspect's hand.</vi> <vi>The police officer <it>got</it> a confession <it>out of</it> the suspect.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to gain (something) from (something) <vi>What do you hope to <it>get out of</it> this experience?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop being controlled or bothered by (something, such as a problem or feeling) <vi>You need to <it>get over</it> [=<it>overcome</it>] your fear of being lied to.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy about (something) <vi>She's disappointed about their decision, but she'll <it>get over</it> it eventually.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that you are very surprised or impressed by something <vi>I just can't <it>get over</it> how much weight you've lost!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become healthy again after (an illness) <vi>He had a bad cold, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> it completely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop feeling unhappy after ending a relationship with (someone) <vi>He broke up with his girlfriend a couple of months ago, and he still hasn't <it>gotten over</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get (something) over with</va></svr> <dt>:to cause or experience the end of (something) :to finish (something) <vi>I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over</it>! = I just want to <it>get</it> this ordeal <it>over with</it>! = I just want to <phrase>get</phrase> this ordeal <phrase>over and done with</phrase>! [=I want this ordeal to end]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get over (something)</va></svr> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to express (something) clearly so that it is understood <vi>I don't know if I was able to <it>get</it> my message <it>over</it> [=<it>across</it>] to them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get real</dre> <dx>see <dxt>real</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rid of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get rolling</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roll</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get round</dre> <dx>see <dxt>get around <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>best</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get the better of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get there</dre> <def><dt>:to reach a goal :to do what you are trying to do <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we'll <it>get there</it> eventually. [=we'll make a profit eventually]</vi> :to come closer to reaching a goal <vi>We haven't made a profit yet, but we're <it>getting there</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to finish a job or activity <vi>When you <it>get through</it> (with that job), I've got something else for you to do.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or finish (something, such as an amount of work) <vi>We <it>got through</it> [=<it>covered</it>] all of the material that we wanted to cover.</vi> <vi>There's still a lot of paperwork to be <it>gotten through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to complete or to help (someone) to complete (a test, an exam, etc.) successfully <vi>She studied hard and <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] her exams.</vi> <vi>The extra hours of study are what <it>got</it> her <it>through</it> her exams.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pass through or beyond something that blocks you or slows you down <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting through</it> to the flood victims.</vi> :to cause (something) to pass through or beyond something <vi>Traffic was very heavy, but we managed to <it>get</it> our truck <it>through</it> (it).</vi> <vi>Rescuers are having trouble <it>getting</it> supplies <it>through</it> to the flood victims.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have the experience of living through (something that is difficult, dangerous, etc.) <vi>It was a very difficult time in our marriage, but we <it>got through</it> it.</vi> <vi>I don't know how those early settlers managed to <it>get through</it> [=<it>survive</it>] the winter.</vi> :to help (someone) to live through (something) <vi>It was pure determination that <it>got</it> them <it>through</it> that crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] all the money he inherited in just a few years.</vi> <vi>They <it>got through</it> [=<it>went through</it>] three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be clearly expressed to and understood by someone <vi>I hope my message has finally <it>gotten through to</it> you. [=I hope you finally understand my message]</vi> <vi>I think my message finally <it>got through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through to (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (something) through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to express something clearly so that it is understood by (someone) <vi>I've talked to him many times, but I just can't seem to <it>get through to</it> him.</vi> <vi>I hope I've finally <it>gotten</it> my message <it>through to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a successful telephone call to someone <vi>I tried to call home but I couldn't <it>get through</it>.</vi> <vi>Where were you? I've been trying to <it>get through to</it> you (on the phone) all day!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>get through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be accepted or approved by an official group <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] and eventually became a law.</vi> <vi>The bill finally <it>got through</it> [=<it>passed</it>] Congress and eventually became a law.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to start (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>She sometimes <it>gets to worrying</it> over her health.</vi> <vi>We <it>got to talking</it> about old times.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to deal with (something) <vi>The letter is on my desk, but I haven't <it>gotten to</it> it yet.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>get to</it> the accounts as soon as I can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>All these delays are starting to <it>get to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel sad <vi>The movie's sad ending really <it>got to</it> me.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get <dxn>26b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to change or influence the behavior of (someone) wrongly or illegally by making threats, paying money, etc. <vi>The witness changed his story. Someone must have <it>gotten to</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get to (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go to or reach (somewhere) <vi>We <it>got to</it> the station/airport just in time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to meet and spend time together <vi>I'd like to <it>get together</it> with you soon.</vi> <vi>He often <it>gets together</it> with his friends after work.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to have a sexual or romantic relationship <vi>He and his wife first <it>got together</it> in college.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (people) to meet or to have a relationship <vi>Their shared interest in photography is what <it>got</it> them <it>together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept something <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The two sides have been unable to <it>get together on</it> a new contract.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get together (things or people)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (things or people) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to collect (things) or gather (people) into one place or group <vi>He <it>got together</it> [=<it>assembled</it>] a great art collection.</vi> <vi>The government <it>got together</it> a group of experts to study the problem.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>get together</it> [=<it>obtain</it>] the money we need to buy a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get your act together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get yourself together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get it together</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>get your life together</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to live in a good and sensible way :to stop being confused, foolish, etc. <vi>His life got much better when he stopped drinking and <it>got his act together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to function in a skillful or effective way <vi>The company finally <it>got its act together</it> and started making a profit this year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to sleep</dre> <def><dt>:to start sleeping :to fall asleep <vi>She finally <it>got to sleep</it> after midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get to work</dre> <def><dt>:to start working <vi>We need to stop delaying and <it>get to work</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>get up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to rise or to cause (someone) to rise after lying or sleeping in a bed <vi>I <it>got up</it> [=got out of bed] early this morning.</vi> <vi>I woke up early but I didn't <it>get up</it> till later.</vi> <vi>The alarm clock <it>got</it> me <it>up</it> earlier than usual.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stand up <vi>He <it>got up</it> to greet her when she entered the room.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>get up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to produce (something, such as courage) in yourself by trying or making an effort <vi>He couldn't <it>get up</it> the courage to ask her out on a date.</vi> <vi>She was so tired she could hardly <it>get up</it> the energy to make dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prepare or organize (something that involves a group of people) <vi>They're trying to <it>get up</it> a petition to have the movie theater reopened.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>get it up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to get an erection</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get up on the wrong side of the bed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get what's coming to you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get wind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your goat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have got</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="go[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">go</hw> <sound><wav>go000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>goes</if> <sound><wav>go000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊz</pr></in> <in><if>went</if> <sound><wav>go000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>gone</if> <sound><wav>gone0001.wav</wav><wav>go000003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:n</pr></in> <in><if>go*ing</if> <sound><wav>go000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a place <vi>He <it>went</it> to the window and looked out at the yard.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes</it> to the office every morning and comes home in the evening.</vi> <vi>I'm tired. Let's <it>go</it> home.</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> downstairs to the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The train <it>goes</it> from New York to Chicago.</vi> <vi>Halt! <phrase>Who goes there</phrase>? [=who is there?; who is coming this way?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to travel to and stay in (a place) for a particular amount of time <vi>I <it>went</it> with my family to Rome last year.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going to</it> Iowa for a week.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move or travel in a particular way or for a particular distance <vi>The car was <it>going</it> too fast.</vi> <vi>How much farther do we have to <it>go</it>?</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> a long way to see him.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> many miles that day.</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> straight for two blocks, then <it>go</it> right/left at the light.</vi> <vi>The street is blocked, so we'll have to <it>go</it> around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their relationship doesn't seem to be <it>going</it> anywhere. [=doesn't seem to be making any progress]</vi> <vi><phrase>Where do we go from here</phrase>? [=what do we do now?]</vi> <vi>We've accomplished a lot, but we still have <phrase>a long way to go</phrase>. [=we have much more to do]</vi> <vi>She has a lot of talent. If she works hard, she should <phrase>go far</phrase>. [=she should be very successful]</vi> <vi>These changes will <phrase>go a long way</phrase> toward solving the dispute.</vi> <vi>Would you <phrase>go so far</phrase> as to call them dishonest? [=would you say that they are dishonest?]</vi> <vi>This time you've <phrase>gone too far</phrase>! [=you've done something that cannot be allowed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move to or be at a place (such as an office or school) for work, study, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> church on Sunday.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> work from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</vi> <vi>Their son is <it>going to</it> college in Florida. [=he is attending a college in Florida]</vi> <vi>He <it>went to</it> prison for his crimes.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something that involves moving or traveling to a place <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're <it>going on</it> vacation next week.</vi> <vi>The thieves <it>went on</it> a crime spree.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>The neighbors <it>went running</it> [=the neighbors ran] when they heard the screams.</vi> <vi>I like to <it>go walking/swimming/shopping</it>. [=I like to walk/swim/shop]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>go for <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or travel to a place for a particular purpose <vi>I <it>went</it> to see them last week.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> to see a movie last night. = We <it>went</it> to a movie last night.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> to the wedding? [=do you plan to attend the wedding?]</vi> <vi>I may <it>go</it> to see them next week. = I may <it>go</it> and see them next week. = (<it>US</it>) I may <it>go</it> see them next week.</vi> <snote>In informal spoken English, <phrase>go and</phrase> is used to emphasize a following verb. It usually expresses anger or annoyance. <vi>Now you've <it>gone and</it> ruined it!</vi> <vi>They <it>went and</it> changed it!</vi> <vi><it>Go and</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>go</it> by itself is also sometimes used this way. <vi>Why did you have to <it>go</it> ruin it?!</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to engage in (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>Don't <it>go telling</it> everyone what happened. [=don't tell everyone what happened]</vi> <vi>He <it>went blabbing</it> the news all over the place.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>It's getting late. I should <it>go</it> now.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>going</it> when the phone rang.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave a job, position, etc. <vi>Pack up your desk and <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>She's retiring soon, and it'll be sad for all of us to see her <it>go</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to lie or move along a particular route or in a particular direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>goes</it> from the town to the lake.</vi> <vi>His land <it>goes</it> almost all the way down to the river.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> my way? [=are you going in the same direction that I'm going in?]</vi> <vi>The car <it>went</it> the length of the street and then turned around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She <it>went</it> the conventional route [=she did the conventional thing] by going straight to college after high school.</vi> <vi>He has always <phrase>gone his own way</phrase>. [=he has always done the things he wants to do instead of the things that most people do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to provide a way to get to a place <vi>That door <it>goes</it> to the cellar. [=you can get to the cellar by going through that door]</vi> <vi>Where does this road <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be sent <vi>The message <it>went</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be lost, used, or spent <vi>I don't know where the money <it>goes</it>.</vi> <vi>I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they're <it>gone</it>. = (<it>Brit</it>) I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they've <it>gone</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>all</it> <vi>The money was <it>all gone</it> by Friday. = <it>All</it> (of) the money was <it>gone</it> by Friday.</vi> <vi>“Is there any ice cream left?” “No, it's <it>all gone</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to die <vi>She <it>went</it> peacefully at about midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The time/day seemed to <it>go</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen in a particular way <vi>The evening <it>went</it> well/badly.</vi> <vi>She worked hard to make the party <it>go</it> according to plan.</vi> <vi><phrase>The way things are going</phrase> [=if things keep happening this way], I may get laid off.</vi> <vi>We lost the game, but <phrase>that's the way it/life goes</phrase>. [=it is a fact that bad or disappointing things will happen sometimes]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to talk or ask about how you are feeling <vi>“How are things <it>going</it>? = How's everything <it>going</it>? = How's it <it>going</it>?” “Everything's <it>going</it> well/fine/great.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be given up, thrown away, etc. <vi>I want to keep these, but that one can <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>These old boxes <phrase>have got to go</phrase>. = These old boxes <phrase>have to go</phrase>. [=we have to get rid of these old boxes]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be sold <vi>The house <it>went</it> for a good price.</vi> <vi>The cabinets <it>go</it> for about $400.</vi> <vi>The painting will <it>go</it> to the highest bidder</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be willing to pay a certain price for something <vi>I'll <it>go</it> as high as $100, but not over that.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail or become weak because of use, age, etc. <vi>His hearing has started to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>The batteries in the flashlight are <it>going</it> and will have to be changed.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break because of force or pressure <vi>The dam/roof is weakening and it could <it>go</it> at any time.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>Everyone's here, so I think we're ready to <it>go</it>. = (<it>US, informal</it>) I think we're <phrase>good to go</phrase>. [=I think we're ready to start]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get going</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the result of a contest, election, decision, etc. <vi>The election <it>went</it> in her favor. [=she won the election]</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went</it> against him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to work in the usual or expected way <vi>I couldn't get the car to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I kept working on the engine until I finally got it <it>going</it>. [=I finally got it to work/run]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>keep going</tag> at <dxt>keep</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>18 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to become <un>used to describe a change <vi>The building has <it>gone</it> condo. [=the building has become a condominium]</vi> <vi>British currency <it>went</it> decimal in 1971.</vi></un> <un>used especially to describe a change that is not wanted <vi>The tire <it>went</it> flat.</vi> <vi>The bread has <it>gone</it> stale.</vi> <vi>The company <it>went</it> bankrupt.</vi> <vi>Everything keeps <it>going</it> wrong.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change <vi>The leaves here <it>go</it> from green to red in the fall.</vi> <vi>The situation <it>went</it> from bad to worse.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe someone's or something's condition <vi>I like to <it>go</it> barefoot in the summer.</vi> <vi>There was nothing to eat, so we had to <it>go</it> hungry.</vi> <vi>My letters have <it>gone</it> unanswered. [=have not been answered]</vi> <vi>Her excellent work has not <it>gone</it> unnoticed/unappreciated. [=someone has noticed/appreciated her excellent work]</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make a particular movement <vi>Can you <it>go</it> like this with your eyebrows? [=can you move your eyebrows like this?]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to talk about a story, song, etc. <vi>I can't remember how the story <it>goes</it>. [=I can't remember what happens in the story]</vi> <vi>The story/rumor/legend <it>goes</it> that he left home poor and came back rich.</vi> <vi>The tune <it>goes</it> like this.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to fit in or through a space <vi>Will these clothes <it>go</it> in your suitcase? [=is there enough room for these clothes in your suitcase?]</vi> <vi>The box was too big to <it>go</it> [=<it>fit</it>] through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a usual or proper place or position :<sx>belong</sx> <vi>These books <it>go</it> on the top shelf.</vi> <vi>Where do your keys <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have authority :to require you to do what is said or demanded <vi><phrase>What she says goes</phrase>! [=she is the boss; you have to do what she tells you to do]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use the toilet <vi>One of the children said he had to <it>go</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go to the bathroom</tag> at <dxt>bathroom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to make a sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The bell <it>went</it> and the class came to an end.</vi> <vi>The music was <it>going</it> full blast. [=the music was being played as loud as possible]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The gun <it>went</it> bang.</vi> <vi>The cow <it>went</it> “moo.”</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say (something) <un>used in describing what people said in a conversation <vi>So she <it>goes</it>, “Did you write this?” and I <it>go</it>, “Mind your own business!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a sports team or player</ssl> <dt>:to have a specified record <vi>The team <it>went</it> 11–2 last season. [=the team won 11 games and lost 2 games last year]</vi> <vi>The shortstop <it>went</it> two for four in yesterday's game. [=the shortstop had two hits in four times at bat in yesterday's game]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything goes</dre> <def><dt>:anything is acceptable :there are no rules for behavior, dress, etc. <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <it>anything goes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as (someone or something) goes</dre> <def><dt><un>used to compare someone or something with someone or something else of the same kind <vi><it>As lectures go</it>, it was very interesting.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be available <vi>There <it>are</it> no jobs <it>going</it> right now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going to</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about what will happen or could happen <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> be cold tomorrow. [=it will be cold tomorrow]</vi> <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> rain: if you don't take an umbrella, you<it>'re going to</it> get soaked.</vi> <vi>I <it>am</it> not <it>going to</it> tolerate [=I won't tolerate] any more bad behavior!</vi> <vi>I <it>was</it> just <it>going to</it> call him. [=I was about to call him]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>gonna</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go about (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) <vi>I'd like to fix this old radio but I don't know how to <it>go about</it> (doing) it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>Despite the threat of war, most people are just quietly <phrase>going about their business</phrase>. [=most people are just doing the things that they usually do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go a bundle on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bundle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to follow and try to stop or catch (someone) <vi>When the boy ran out the door, his mother quickly <it>went after</it> him.</vi> <vi>The police <it>went after</it> the escaped criminal.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to find and punish (someone) <vi>The government is <it>going after</it> people who cheat on their taxes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something or someone) <vi>If you want the job, you should just <it>go after</it> it.</vi> <vi>She accused her friend of <it>going after</it> her husband.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not agree with (something) <vi>I won't do anything that <it>goes against</it> my conscience/beliefs/principles.</vi> <vi>values that <it>go against</it> those of society</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to oppose (someone or something) <vi>He was surprised when some of his former supporters <it>went against</it> him.</vi> <vi>He was reluctant to <it>go against</it> his parents' wishes. [=he was reluctant to do something that his parents did not want him to do]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to compete against (a player or team) in a contest or game <vi>The Red Sox will be <it>going against</it> the Yankees in tonight's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not be good for (someone) :to not produce the result that is wanted by (someone) <vi>Everything seemed to be <it>going against</it> her but she didn't give up hope.</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went against</it> the defendant. [=the verdict was not in favor of the defendant]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do or begin to do something <vi>Instead of waiting for approval, they just <it>went ahead</it> and started working on the project.</vi> :to do something after planning to do it or after getting permission to do it <vi>Despite the bad weather, they decided to <it>go ahead</it> with the party.</vi> <vi>My boss told me to <it>go ahead</it> (with the work).</vi> <vi>“Could I sit here?” “Sure, <it>go</it> (right) <it>ahead</it>.”</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more cake.” “Oh, <it>go ahead</it>. It won't kill you.”</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go-ahead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to happen or proceed <vi>Despite the weather, the party <it>went ahead</it> as planned.</vi> <vi>After a brief delay, the work is now <it>going ahead</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before the other person or group that is with you <vi>I'll <it>go</it> (on) <it>ahead</it> and make sure that everything's ready when you arrive.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <def><dt>:to do something with as much effort as possible <vi>When he has a party, he likes to <it>go all out</it>. [=have a big and expensive party]</vi> <vi>Her company always <it>went all out</it> [=did everything possible] to make the customer happy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-out</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all the way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue or proceed <vi>The project is <it>going along</it> smoothly.</vi> <vi>On this job there's a lot to learn—but I'm sure you'll pick it up as you <it>go along</it>.</vi> <vi>He was just making up the story as he <it>went along</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel with someone <vi>They were going to the fair so I asked whether I could <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I asked whether I could <it>go along with</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept what other people want <vi>We tried to convince him to support us but he refused to <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> us.</vi> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> our plan.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be part of something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes along with</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ape</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ape</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>go round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to go to different places <vi>She and her friends <it>go around</it> (together) to lots of clubs. = She <it>goes around</it> with her friends to lots of clubs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place that is nearby <vi>I <it>went round</it> [=<it>went over</it>] <it>to</it> his flat.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way a person often dresses or behaves <vi>She <it>goes around</it> (dressed) in a miniskirt.</vi> <vi>You can't <it>go around</it> treating people so rudely.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go or pass from one person to another person <vi>There's a rumor <it>going around</it> (the office) that the boss is about to get fired.</vi> <vi>An amusing story is <it>going around</it>.</vi> <vi>There's a nasty cold <it>going around</it>: I hope you don't catch it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be long enough to pass all the way around (something or someone) <vi>This belt isn't long enough to <it>go around</it> (my waist).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>If people want something and there is <phrase>enough/plenty to go around</phrase>, there is enough for all of the people who want it or need it. <vi>There aren't <it>enough jobs to go around</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>what goes around comes around</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that if you treat other people badly you will eventually be treated badly by someone else</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>They <it>went at</it> each other viciously.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to fight or argue <vi>Our neighbors were arguing again last night. They <it>went at it</it> for almost an hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make an effort to do or deal with (something) <vi>They had to <it>go at</it> the problem from many different angles before they finally solved it.</vi> <vi>It was a tough job, and I was impressed by the energetic way he <it>went at</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place or person <vi>She angrily told him to <it>go away</it> and stop bothering her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for a period of time <vi>They're <it>going away</it> on vacation.</vi> <vi>After graduating from high school, he <it>went away</it> to college.</vi> <vi>a <it>going-away</it> present/party [=a present/party for someone who is leaving to live, study, or travel in a distant place]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop existing or happening :to end <vi>I just wish there was some way to make the pain <it>go away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I forgot my purse and had to <it>go back</it> for it.</vi> <vi>What was it like to <it>go back</it> after so many years?</vi> <vi>After college she <it>went back</it> home.</vi> <vi><it>Go back</it> inside! You'll catch cold.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin doing something again <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>I turned off the alarm and <it>went back to</it> sleep.</vi> <vi>He waved hello, then <it>went</it> right <it>back to</it> work.</vi> <vi>She <it>went back to</it> eating her dinner.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>there's no going back</phrase> means that you have done or decided something and cannot change it. <vi>I've already signed the contract, so <it>there's no going back</it> now.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to have existed for a particular amount of time or since a particular period <vi>These ruins <it>go back</it> hundreds of years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a tradition that <it>goes back</it> [=<it>dates back</it>] <it>to</it> colonial times</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have known each other for a particular amount of time <vi>We <it>go back</it> 30 years.</vi> <vi>He and I <phrase>go back a long way</phrase>. = He and I <phrase>go way back</phrase>. [=he and I have known each other for many years]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to think or talk about something from the past <vi>To fully understand the issues, we have to <it>go back</it> a few years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'd like to <it>go back to</it> your earlier comment. [=I'd like to discuss it further]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go back on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>She <it>went back on</it> her promise to help us. [=she failed to keep her promise]</vi> <vi>I would never <it>go back on</it> my word.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to happen or exist at an earlier time than (someone) <vi>We owe a great debt of gratitude to those who <it>went before</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be considered by (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>The contestants will <it>go before</it> the judges tomorrow.</vi> <vi>The case <it>went before</it> the court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go beyond</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go beyond (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do more than (something) <vi>She <it>went beyond</it> the call of duty. [=she did more than was required]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>go beyond</it> merely talking about the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The morning seemed to <it>go by</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi> <vi>Many years have <it>gone by</it> since the last time I saw her.</vi> <vi>They have many happy memories of days <it>gone by</it>. [=bygone days, days/times in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be guided or directed by (something, such as a rule) <vi>That's a good rule to <it>go by</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion from (something) <vi>She may be guilty but we have very little evidence to <it>go by</it>.</vi> <vi>You can't always <it>go by</it> appearances. [=you can't always judge people or things by the way they look]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (a name)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be known by (a name) <vi>His name is Edwin but he <it>goes by</it> Ed. [=people call him Ed]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go by (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go somewhere in order to visit someone <vi>I <it>went by</it> (her house) to see her after school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall or crash to the ground <vi>The airplane <it>went down</it> when one of its engines caught fire.</vi> <vi>The boxer took a punch and <it>went down</it> hard.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to sink into the water <vi>The ship <it>went down</it> after hitting an iceberg.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go down</it> soon.</vi> <vi>The quality of his work has been <it>going down</it>.</vi> <vi>She had a fever yesterday, but it <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become less or smaller <vi>It may take a few hours for the swelling to <it>go down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become less bright <vi>The lights <it>went down</it> [=the lights were turned down] as the movie started.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to stop being visible in the sky :to set <vi>The sun comes up in the morning and <it>goes down</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to eat or drink something <vi>The medicine <it>went down</it> easily. [=it was easy to swallow the medicine]</vi> <vi>I took a sip but it <it>went down</it> the wrong way. [=I choked on my drink]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to accept or agree to something <vi>His suggestion didn't <it>go down</it> [=<it>go over</it>] very well with his boss. [=his boss didn't like his suggestion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to lose or fail <vi>Last year's champion <it>went down</it> in the first round of the tournament this year.</vi> <vi>The regime finally <it>went down</it> [=<it>fell</it>] in a wave of popular protest.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>of a computer, system, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The network <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to be remembered or talked about as an important person, event, etc. <vi>He will <it>go down</it> as one of the greatest leaders this country has ever known.</vi> <vi>His name will <phrase>go down in history</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be sent to prison <vi>He <it>went down</it> [=went to jail] for six years for the robbery.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to travel to a place (especially one that is nearby or to the south) <vi>I need to <it>go down</it> to the store for milk.</vi> <vi>We <it>went down</it> south to visit relatives.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to happen <vi>We need to find out what's <it>going down</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>going on</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to perform oral sex on (someone)</dt> <sn>14</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>He <it>went down with</it> [=<it>caught</it>, <it>came down with</it>] measles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go easy, go easy on/with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go figure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>My dog <it>went for</it> the intruder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something) <vi><it>go for</it> the prize</vi> <vi>If you want to achieve success, you have to stop hesitating and just <phrase>go for it</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to accept or agree to (something, such as a plan or suggestion) <vi>I asked her to lend us some money, but she wouldn't <it>go for</it> it. [=she wouldn't agree to lend us money]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to like or be attracted to (someone or something) <vi>When I see how she looks at him, I can tell she really <it>goes for</it> him.</vi> <vi>I don't really <it>go for</it> modern art.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>could go for</phrase> [=I would like] a cup of coffee right now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relate to or apply to (someone or something) <vi>The rule <it>goes for</it> you, too. [=the rule also applies to you]</vi> <vi>“I'd like ice cream for desert.” “That <it>goes for</it> me too.” [=I'd like ice cream too]</vi> <vi>The economy here has been growing stronger, and <phrase>the same goes for</phrase> [=the same is true for] many other areas.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a price)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be sold for (a particular price) <vi>The painting <it>went for</it> more than a million dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a walk, a drive, etc.)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do an activity (such as walking or driving a car) that usually involves going somewhere <vi>She <it>went for</it> a walk/stroll after dinner.</vi> <vi>On Saturday mornings we like to <it>go for</it> a drive out in the countryside.</vi> <vi>Would anyone like to <it>go for</it> a swim?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>have something going for you</phrase>, you have a talent, skill, etc., that helps you. <vi>She's not as young as some of the other athletes, but experience helps, and she <it>has that going for</it> her. [=she has an advantage because of her experience]</vi> <vi>You should be more confident in yourself. You <phrase>have a lot going for you</phrase>! [=you have many talents, abilities, etc.]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go great guns</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become hidden by a cloud <vi>The afternoon got cooler after the sun <it>went in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to like or be interested in (something) <vi>She doesn't <it>go in for</it> sports.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help pay for (something, such as a present) <vi>Are you going to <it>go in on</it> the gift for her?</vi> <vi>We all <it>went in on</it> the gift together. [=we all gave some money towards buying the gift]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to join (someone) in a business, project, etc. <vi>His brother-in-law <it>went in with</it> him on his new business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to start to be in (a different state or condition) <vi>After she lost her job she <it>went into</it> a deep depression. [=she became very depressed]</vi> <vi>The criminal has <phrase>gone into hiding</phrase>. [=the criminal is hiding]</vi> <vi>After losing the election, she <phrase>went into seclusion</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go into effect</tag> at <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to start to move in (a different and usually bad way) <vi>The car <it>went into</it> a skid. [=the car began to skid]</vi> <vi>The plane <it>went into</it> a tailspin.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) as a job or career <vi>He wants to <it>go into</it> the priesthood. [=he wants to become a priest]</vi> <vi>Their daughter is planning to <it>go into</it> medicine. [=to be a doctor; to get a job in the medical field]</vi> <vi>Both his sons have <it>gone into</it> the army. [=joined the army]</vi> <vi>His dream is to <phrase>go into business</phrase> for himself. [=to start his own business]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll try to tell the story without <it>going into</it> too many details. = I'll try not to <it>go into</it> too much detail.</vi> :to talk about the details of (something) <vi>Having <it>gone into</it> the causes of the French Revolution, the book then discusses its effects.</vi> <vi>“I've had a long day.” “What happened?” “I'll tell you later. I don't feel like <it>going into</it> it right now.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to get information about (something) <un>usually used as <it>(be) gone into</it> <vi>A problem like that should really <it>be gone into</it> [=<it>looked into</it>] carefully.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be used for (something) <vi>Lots of time, energy, and money have <it>gone into</it> (completing) the project.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt><un>used to say how many times a number can be multiplied to produce a larger number <vi>6 <it>goes into</it> 18 three times. [=18 divided by 6 equals 3]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go it alone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a bomb</ssl> <dt>:to explode <vi>The building was evacuated before the bomb <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a gun</ssl> <dt>:to shoot <vi>The gun <it>went off</it> accidentally.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of an alarm</ssl> <dt>:to begin to make a sudden loud noise <vi>I woke up when the alarm <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The lights in the building suddenly <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place for a new place <vi>He <it>went off</it> to join the army after graduating from high school.</vi> <vi>She <it>went off</it> to America.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to occur or happen <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen a particular way <vi>The party <it>went off</it> well. [=the party was a success]</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> poorly.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin shouting at someone in an angry way <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>Her boss <it>went off on</it> her because she was late again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop liking (someone or something) <vi>She used to like him but now she's <it>gone off</it> him completely.</vi> <vi>My boss has <it>gone off</it> the idea, so it's been cancelled.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (a spouse, partner, etc.) for someone else <vi>He left his wife and <it>went off with</it> [=<it>ran off with</it>] some young thing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something that belongs to someone else) away with you :<sx>steal</sx> <vi>Someone <it>went off with</it> my pencil/wallet.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to continue on a journey <vi>We stopped briefly in Detroit, and then <it>went on</it> to Chicago.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue as time passes <vi>Life <it>goes on</it>.</vi> <vi>How much longer will the meeting <it>go on</it>? [=<it>last</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to continue doing something <vi>She <it>went on</it> working [=she continued to work] after everyone else had stopped.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to continue talking <vi>He <it>went on</it> (and on) about how unfairly he had been treated. [=he talked about it for a long time]</vi> :to talk too much or too long about something <vi>She's always <it>going on</it> about the importance of a good diet.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to continue to be in the same situation or relationship <vi>We can't <it>go on</it> like this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before another person or group that is with you <vi>You <it>go on</it> (ahead). I'll come later.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to do or say something else after you have finished doing or saying something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He accepted the nomination and <it>went on to</it> win the election.</vi> <vi>After I finished reading the first book I immediately <it>went on to</it> the next one.</vi> <vi>He <it>went on to</it> say that further tax increases would be necessary.</vi> <vi>Everyone expected that she would <phrase>go on to greater things</phrase>. [=that she would become very successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>What's <it>going on</it>?</vi> <vi>No one knows exactly what <it>went on</it> during their private meeting.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>goings-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>went on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion or conclusion from something <un>used in the phrase <phrase>to go on</phrase> <vi>There's very little evidence <it>to go on</it>. [=there's very little evidence that can be used to form an opinion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to urge someone to do something <vi><it>Go on</it> (and try it): you might actually like it!</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more ice cream.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>! It won't hurt you to have a little more.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to express disbelief <vi>“I used to be a spy.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>.”</vi> <vi>A spy? <phrase>Go on with you</phrase>, then. [=I don't believe you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>go on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) often or repeatedly <vi>Quit <it>going on at</it> me all the time!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>going on</tag> at <dxt>going</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go one better</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to achieve more :to move to a higher or better level <vi>She qualified for the finals, then <it>went one better</it> and took first place.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go (someone or something) one better</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do better or more than (someone or something) :to outdo (someone or something) <vi>The company has <it>gone</it> its competitors <it>one better</it> by offering new customers a special discount.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for an activity <vi>I'm <it>going out</it> for a walk. I'll be back soon.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going out</it> to get some lunch.</vi> <vi>On Saturday nights he <it>goes out</it> drinking with his friends.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be sent from a person or place <vi>The message <it>went out</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi> <vi>Word has <it>gone out</it> that snow is expected.</vi> <vi><phrase>Our thoughts and prayers go out to</phrase> all the victims of this tragedy. [=we are thinking of and praying for all the victims of this tragedy]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being popular or fashionable <vi>That hairstyle <it>went out</it> years ago.</vi> <vi>Short skirts have <phrase>gone out of fashion</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to meet someone for a romantic social activity :to go on a date with someone <vi>They <it>went out</it> a couple of times, but it was never serious.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with someone <vi>I've been <it>going out</it> with her for quite a while now. = We've been <it>going out</it> for quite a while now.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The electricity suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to stop shining or burning <vi>The fire/candle <it>went out</it>.</vi> <vi>All the lights suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to try to become a member of a team, group, etc. <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>He <it>went out for</it> football last year. = He <it>went out for</it> the football team last year.</vi> <vi>She <it>went out</it> [=<it>tried out</it>] <it>for</it> the school play.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of the tide</ssl> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>The tide is <it>going out</it> [=(more formally) <it>ebbing</it>] now.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be broadcast on the radio, television, etc. <vi>A distress call <it>went out</it> three hours ago.</vi> <un>often + <it>over</it> <vi>Warnings about the approaching storm <it>went out over</it> the radio.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a particular place or person <vi>He <it>went over</it> and stood by the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over</it> and hugged her.</vi> <vi>I think I see Jane. Let's <it>go over</it> and say hello.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> her and hugged her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change sides in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>After several years of supporting us, he <it>went over to</it> our competitors.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to be accepted or received in a particular way <vi>He tried to make a joke but it <it>went over</it> badly. [=no one thought his joke was funny]</vi> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well <it>with</it> the boss. [=the boss didn't like her proposal]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think about (something) carefully <vi>He <it>went over</it> all the arguments before making up his mind.</vi> <vi>We <it>went over</it> the accident again and again in our minds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look at or study (something) again in order to correct it, learn it, etc. <vi>The students were told to <it>go over</it> their essays.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go over</it> the instructions.</vi> <vi>an actress <it>going over</it> her lines</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go the distance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>distance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to start to talk or think about something <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>“Do you remember when we were dating?” “Let's not <it>go there</it>.” = “I don't want to <it>go there</it>.” = “Don't <it>go there</it>.” [=I don't want to talk about that]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to study or look at (something) in a careful way <vi>The book <it>goes through</it> every detail of the French Revolution.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go through</it> the plan one more time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look in or at (something) in order to find something :to search in or through (something) <vi>I found him <it>going through</it> my closet.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to experience (something) <vi>He's <it>going through</it> a painful divorce.</vi> <vi>I understand what you're <it>going through</it>.</vi> <vi>In order to learn the job well, you have to <it>go through</it> several months of training.</vi> <vi>The book has already <it>gone through</it> four editions. [=the publishers have already released four editions of the book]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>went through</it> all the money he inherited.</vi> <vi>They <it>went through</it> three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to occur throughout (something) <vi>A note of despair <it>goes through</it> the narrative. [=there is a note of despair throughout the narrative]</vi> <snote>If something (such as an idea or a song) is <phrase>going through your head/mind</phrase>, you are thinking about it or remembering it. <vi>I don't know what was <it>going through her mind</it> [=I don't know what her thoughts were; I don't know why she did this] when she agreed to help him.</vi> <vi>That song keeps <it>going through my head</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>It took him about an hour to <it>go through</it> his usual morning routine.</vi> <vi>Before we practice the next section, let's <it>go through</it> the chorus once again.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go through the motions</tag> at <dxt>motion</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>Something (such as a law or contract) that <phrase>goes through</phrase> is officially accepted and approved. <vi>The bill is expected to <it>go through</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The proposed deal failed to <it>go through</it>.</vi> <vi>The bill <phrase>went through Congress/Parliament</phrase> [=was passed by Congress/Parliament] without difficulty and soon became law.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something that you have thought or talked about) <vi>He was always threatening to quit his job, but I never thought he'd actually <it>go through with</it> it. [=I never thought he would actually do it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to be in (a particular state, condition, or situation) <vi>You need to <phrase>go to sleep</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The countries <phrase>went to war</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be given to (someone or something) <vi>First prize <it>went to</it> the team from Chicago.</vi> <vi>The property will <it>go to</it> his wife if he dies before she does.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (trouble or expense)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to do something that causes you (trouble or expense) <vi>You shouldn't <it>go to all this trouble</it> just for me.</vi> <vi>They <it>went to a lot of expense</it> [=they spent a lot of money] to make sure that the job was done correctly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be suited to or appropriate for each other <vi>The tie and his suit <it>go together</it> well.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship <vi>They've been <it>going together</it> for several years.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to show/prove</dre> <def><dt>:to help show or prove something <vi>Her success <phrase>goes to show</phrase> that if you work hard, you can make your dreams come true.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go toward(s)</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go toward(s) (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help pay for (something) <vi>My extra income is <it>going towards</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>Your donations will <it>go toward</it> better sanitation for refugees.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to sink below the surface of the water <vi>The ship <it>went under</it> after being struck by a torpedo.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail :to not succeed <vi>The company has been losing money and is in danger of <it>going under</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a higher level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go up</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become brighter <vi>The lights <it>went up</it> [=the lights were turned up] when the movie ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be built <vi>A new store is <it>going up</it> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place (especially one that is to the north) <vi>We <it>went up to</it> the lake for the weekend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with (someone) :to date (someone) <vi>I've been <it>going with</it> her for quite a while now.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go out <dxn>4b (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>go together <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be suitable for or appropriate with (something) <vi>The skirt she's wearing doesn't really <it>go with</it> [=<it>match</it>] her blouse.</vi> <vi>The tie <it>goes</it> (well) <it>with</it> his suit.</vi> <vi>Do you think this wine will <it>go</it> well <it>with</it> dinner?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go together <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to exist or occur as a necessary part of (something) <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes with</it> it.</vi> <vi>There are a lot of responsibilities that <it>go with</it> starting your own business.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go with the territory</tag> at <dxt>territory</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or use (someone or something) <vi>After thinking about who to offer the job to, they decided to <it>go with</it> the more experienced candidate.</vi> <vi>The golfer <it>went with</it> an iron off the tee. [=the golfer used an iron for her tee shot]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go without</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go without</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go without (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not have (something) :to live or continue without having (something) <vi>How long can you <it>go without</it> sleeping/sleep?</vi> <vi>If you can't afford a new car, you'll just have to <it>go without</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>here goes (nothing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>here</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>here/there you go (again)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is happening again or in the same way that it has happened before <vi><it>There you go</it>, making a big deal out of nothing.</vi> <vi>When I saw his name in the headlines I thought, “<it>Here we go again</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how goes it?</dre> <def><dt><un>used as an informal greeting <vi>Hi Paul. <it>How goes it</it>? [=how are you?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ready, set, go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ready</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>there go/goes</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is no longer available or possible <vi>Look at that traffic jam! <it>There goes</it> our only chance of arriving on time. [=our only chance of arriving on time is gone/lost]</vi> <vi>It's supposed to rain this weekend, so <it>there go</it> our plans for a barbecue. [=we won't be able to have a barbecue]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:still remaining <vi>There are only three more days <it>to go</it> until my birthday!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:sold to be taken away and eaten somewhere else <vi>“I'd like a hamburger.” “For here or <it>to go</it>?” “<it>To go</it>.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="head[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">head</hw> <sound><wav>head0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>heads</if> <il>or in sense 7</il> <if>head</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body containing the brain, eyes, ears, nose, and mouth <vi>She patted the dog on the <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>He nodded his <it>head</it> in agreement.</vi> <vi>The ceiling's low—watch your <it>head</it>!</vi> <vi><it>head</it> injuries</vi> <vi>They were covered <phrase>from head to foot/toe</phrase> in mud. [=they were completely covered in mud]</vi> <vi>He has a <phrase>full head of hair</phrase>. [=he has a full amount of hair on his head]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>talking head</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person's mental ability :mind or intellect <vi>You shouldn't let your heart rule your <it>head</it>. [=you should be guided by reason and not by your emotions]</vi> <vi>She did some quick calculations <phrase>in her head</phrase>. [=without writing anything; mentally]</vi> <vi>I keep hearing that song <it>in my head</it>. = That song keeps running through my <it>head</it>. = I can't get that song <phrase>out of my head</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It never even <phrase>entered my head</phrase> to run for office. [=I never thought of running for office]</vi> <vi>The problem is <phrase>all in his head</phrase>. [=the problem is not real; he's just imagining it]</vi> <vi>Don't go <phrase>putting ideas in/into his head</phrase>. [=don't cause him to have ideas or suspicions that he would not have himself]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>put that idea out of your head</phrase>. [=you should stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>She always says the first thing that <phrase>comes/pops into her head</phrase>. [=the first thing that she thinks of]</vi> <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <phrase>use our heads</phrase>. [=think carefully]</vi> <vi>That guy should <phrase>have his head examined</phrase>. = That guy is <phrase>not right in the head</phrase>. [=that guy is crazy]</vi> <vi>You need a <phrase>cool/calm head</phrase> [=an ability to remain calm] to deal with someone like him.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>clear head</phrase> [=an ability to think clearly]</vi> <snote>If you have <phrase>a good head on your shoulders</phrase>, you are intelligent and have good judgment. <vi>You don't have to worry about her—she's got <it>a good head on her shoulders</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>When you <phrase>get/take it into your head</phrase> to do something, you suddenly decide to do it in a way that seems foolish or surprising. <vi>He's <it>taken it into his head</it> to try skydiving.</vi> <vi>I somehow <it>got it into my head</it> to run for public office.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get it into your head</phrase> that something is true, you begin to believe something even though there is no good reason for believing it. <vi>She's somehow <it>gotten it into her head</it> that I don't like her. [=she believes that I don't like her although I do like her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who has a specified mental or emotional quality <vi>A fight was avoided when <phrase>cooler heads prevailed</phrase>. [=when calmer or less angry people were able to convince others not to fight]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hothead</dxt> <dxt>sorehead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a distance equal to the length of a head <vi>The horse won the race by a <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a <it>head</it> taller than you.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the front side of a coin :the side of a coin that shows a picture of a person's head <vi>the <it>head</it> of a penny</vi> <un>usually used in the plural to refer to one of the two choices you can make when a coin is thrown in the air to decide something <vi>I call <it>heads</it>.</vi> <vi>Is it <it>heads</it> or tails? [=did the coin land with heads or tails facing up?]</vi> <vi>It landed <it>heads</it> up.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>tail <dxn>3</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>head</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:individual animals <vi>100 <it>head</it> of cattle</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an end of something that is like a head in shape or position <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She placed the pillows at the <it>head of</it> the bed.</vi> <vi>We arrived early so that we'd be at the <it>head</it> [=<it>front</it>] <it>of</it> the line.</vi> <vi>The chairman sat at the <it>head of</it> the table.</vi> <vi>the <it>head</it> [=<it>top</it>] <it>of</it> a nail/pin/screw</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an object that hits or touches something else <vi>a grinding <it>head</it></vi> <vi>the hammer's <it>head</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a spear</vi> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a golf club</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>arrowhead</dxt> <dxt>spearhead</dxt> <dxt>warhead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the position of being a leader <vi>She's <phrase>at the head of</phrase> her class. [=she is the best student in her class]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who leads or directs a group or organization <vi>Have you met the new department <it>head</it>?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She is the <it>head of</it> our sales division.</vi> <vi><it>heads of</it> families/households</vi> <vi><phrase>heads of state</phrase> [=leaders of countries]</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the restaurant's <it>head</it> cook</vi> <vi>the team's <it>head</it> coach</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>head teacher</sx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a tight mass of leaves or flowers on a plant <vi>The flower <it>heads</it> on the plant are very large.</vi> <vi>a <it>head</it> of cabbage/lettuce</vi> <vi>a <it>head of</it> garlic</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where a stream or river begins <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>head</it> of the Nile</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:pressure caused by the water or steam in a machine <snote>When an engine has a <phrase>full head of steam</phrase>, it has built up a full amount of power. This phrase is often used figuratively to describe something that is moving forward in a fast and powerful way. <vi>The project started slowly, but now we have a <it>full head of steam</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the bubbles that form on the top of some liquids (such as beer) <un>usually singular <vi>the foamy <it>head</it> on a beer</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the point at which a situation becomes very serious or when action is required <vi>Things <phrase>came to a head</phrase> when the workers threatened to go on strike.</vi> <vi>These new revelations <phrase>brought</phrase> the scandal <phrase>to a head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small, inflamed area on the skin with a spot in the middle <dx>see also <dxt>blackhead</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a big/swelled head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an overly high opinion of yourself <vi>All those compliments have given him a <it>big head</it>. [=have made him very conceited]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>a head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a price on someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>price</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bang heads together</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>butt heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>butt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get it through someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to learn and remember something <vi>She's finally <it>gotten it through their heads</it> that she doesn't eat meat.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get it through your head</dre> <def><dt>:to accept or understand (something) <vi>He can't seem to <it>get it through his head</it> that I'm not interested in working with him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your head round</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to understand (something) <vi>She couldn't <it>get her head round</it> why he had to leave.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to discuss something with a person who is higher in rank than someone else <vi>He <it>went over his supervisor's head</it> to complain about the policy to the company's president. [=he complained about the policy to the company's president rather than his supervisor]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of an alcoholic drink</ssl> <dt>:to make you feel drunk <vi>I just had one glass of wine, but it <phrase>went straight to my head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make you believe that you are better than other people <vi>He has never let his fame <it>go to his head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a head for</dre> <def><dt>:to have an ability to understand or deal with (something) <vi>She's always <it>had a</it> (good) <it>head for</it> business.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) He <phrase>has a head for heights</phrase>. [=he is not afraid of heights; being up high does not bother him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/get your head (screwed) on right/straight</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to think or act in a smart and sensible way <vi>She's young, but it's clear that she <it>has her head screwed on right</it>.</vi> <vi>You think that's a good idea? You need to <it>get your head screwed on straight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head and shoulders above</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone or something is much better than others <vi>They <phrase>are/stand head and shoulders above</phrase> the competition.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head in the sand</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>bury/have/hide (etc.) your head in the sand</phrase>, you ignore something unpleasant that you should be dealing with. <vi>He can't just <it>bury his head in the sand</it> every time there's a problem.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head over heels</dre> <def><dt>:very deeply in love <vi>We were <it>head over heels</it> (in love).</vi> <vi>He <phrase>fell head over heels for</phrase> some girl he met at school.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>went head over heels for</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heads roll</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that <phrase>heads will roll</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>heads are going to roll</phrase>, you mean that people will be severely punished or will lose their jobs because of something that has happened. <vi>When the boss finds out about the mistake, <it>heads will roll</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the nail on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold up your head</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold your head (up) high</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be proud :to not feel ashamed <vi>Even though they lost the game, they can still <it>hold up their heads</it> because they tried their best.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head</dre> <def><dt>:to remain calm <vi>She has shown that she can <it>keep her head</it> in a crisis.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head above water</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid financial failure while having money problems <vi>We have so much debt that we're barely able to <it>keep our heads above water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head down</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in a quiet way that does not attract attention <vi>a politician who is <it>keeping his head down</it> and trying to avoid controversy</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock some sense into someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock (something) on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your head</dre> <def><dt>:to become very upset or angry <vi>He <it>lost his head</it> and said some things he regrets.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not make head or/nor tail of</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>not make heads or/nor tails (out) of</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be unable to understand (something) <vi>I <it>couldn't make heads or tails of</it> her reaction.</vi> <vi>His handwriting was so bad that we <it>couldn't make heads or tails out of</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the top of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>off your head</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:crazy or foolish <vi>He's not just eccentric—he's completely <it>off his head</it>!</vi> <vi>He's gone <it>off his head</it> over some girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with the upper and lower parts of your body reversed in position <vi>Can you <phrase>stand on your head</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or into great disorder <vi>News of the discovery <phrase>turned</phrase> the scientific world <phrase>on its head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you will be blamed for something <vi>If we miss our deadline, it will be <it>on your head</it>. [=it will be your fault]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to act or think in a reasonable and controlled way because of drunkenness or strong emotion <vi>He was (drunk) <it>out of his head</it>. [=he was extremely drunk]</vi> <vi>Her parents were <it>out of their heads</it> with worry [=were extremely worried and upset] when she didn't come home on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over your head</dre> <def><dt>:beyond your understanding or ability <vi>The technical details were <it>over my head</it>. [=too complicated for me to understand]</vi> <vi>That joke went right <it>over my head</it>. [=I did not get that joke]</vi> <vi>We realized after we started the business that we were (in) <it>over our heads</it>. [=we were trying to do something that was too difficult]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>per head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>per head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick/raise your head above the parapet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>parapet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your heads together</dre> <def><dt>:to think of a solution to a problem with another person <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <it>put our heads together</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rear/raise its ugly head</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something bad <it>rears/raises its ugly head</it>, it suddenly becomes obvious or causes trouble. <vi>Inflation threatened to <it>rear its ugly head</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be confused about something and unable to understand the reason for it <vi>His odd behavior left us all <it>scratching our heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) your head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) very loudly or for a long time <vi>She was <it>screaming her head off</it>.</vi> <vi>You can <it>shout your head off</it> at him, but he still won't listen.</vi> <vi>If they saw me dressed like this, they'd <it>laugh their heads off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>shake your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two heads are better than one</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is easier for two people who help each other to solve a problem than it is for one person to solve a problem alone</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn heads</dre> <def><dt>:to attract attention or notice <vi>The car's sleek design is bound to <it>turn heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
