<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="alive"> <hw highlight="yes">alive</hw> <sound><wav>alive001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈlaɪv</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having life :living :not dead <vi>It feels great to be <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>The patient was barely <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>The sheriff was ordered to find the killer and bring him back <it>alive</it>.</vi> <vi>She must be the happiest woman <it>alive</it>. [=the happiest woman in the world]</vi> <vi>He managed to <phrase>stay alive</phrase> for a week without any food.</vi> <vi>The patient is being <phrase>kept alive</phrase> by artificial means.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:continuing to exist <vi>an old tradition that is still <it>alive</it></vi> <vi>We tried to keep the organization <it>alive</it> [=<it>active</it>] despite having fewer members.</vi> <vi>We need to keep hope <it>alive</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not yet defeated :still having a chance to win or succeed <vi>The legislation is still <it>alive</it> in the Senate. [=the legislation has not been defeated yet]</vi> <vi>The team needs to win tonight in order to stay <it>alive</it> in the play-offs.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>more alive; most alive</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:filled with life and energy <vi>I love to sail because it makes me feel so <it>alive</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her face was <it>alive with</it> joy/happiness.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:filled with activity <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>flower gardens <it>alive with</it> bees [=filled with the activity of many bees]</vi> <vi>The city streets are <it>alive</it> [=<it>busy</it>] <it>with</it> shoppers.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>alive and kicking</dre> <def><dt>:healthy and active <vi>She ran a marathon late in life, just to prove she was still <it>alive and kicking</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>After years of slow earnings, the industry is now <it>alive and kicking</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>alive and well</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:living and healthy <vi>She found out that her aunt is <it>alive and well</it> and living in Arizona.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:still popular :continuing to be used <vi>Many of the old traditions are still <it>alive and well</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>alive to</dre> <def><dt>:aware of (something) :able to notice (something) <vi>Recovering from his illness has made him more <it>alive to</it> the beauty of life.</vi> <vi>We need to be <it>alive</it> [=<it>sensitive</it>] <it>to</it> new opportunities for our business to grow.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (something) alive</dre> <def><dt>:to make (something) seem more real or interesting <vi>The play <it>brings the old fairy tale alive</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come alive</dre> <def><dt>:to become lively: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to become excited and filled with energy <vi>The crowd <it>came alive</it> when the singer appeared on stage.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become filled with activity <vi>This neighborhood is quiet during the day, but it <it>comes alive</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to become exciting or appealing <vi>In her kitchen, Italian food <it>comes alive</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat (someone or something) alive</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>skin (someone) alive</dre> <dx>see <dxt>skin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="eat"> <hw highlight="yes">eat</hw> <sound><wav>eat00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈi:t</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>eats</if></in> <in><if>ate</if> <sound><wav>eat00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈeɪt, <it>Brit</it> ˈɛt, ˈeɪt</pr></in> <in><if>eat*en</if> <sound><wav>eat00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈi:tn̩</pr></in> <in><if>eat*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to take food into your mouth and swallow it <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You'll feel better if you <it>eat</it> something.</vi> <vi>I <it>ate</it> a big breakfast so I'm not very hungry.</vi> <vi>Let's grab a bite to <it>eat</it>. = Let's get something to <it>eat</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been trying <phrase>to watch what I eat</phrase>. [=to be more careful about eating healthy foods and not eating too much]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'm hungry. Let's <it>eat</it>.</vi> <vi>They like to <it>eat</it> at home.</vi> <vi>It's important to <phrase>eat right</phrase>. [=to eat healthy foods]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>eat out</phrase> is to dine at a restaurant rather than at home. <vi>We like to <it>eat out</it> on Fridays.</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>eat in</phrase> is to dine at home. <vi>Let's <it>eat in</it> tonight.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to gradually destroy, use, or take away something :to wear something away <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>away</it> <vi>The rocks were <it>eaten away</it> by erosion.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>into, away at</it>, or <it>at</it> <vi>Marketing costs <it>ate into</it> their profits.</vi> <vi>The acids were <it>eating away at</it> the metal finish.</vi> <vi>The failure of his business has <it>eaten away at</it> his confidence.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to bother or annoy (someone) <vi>What's <it>eating</it> you?</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be eating out of someone's hand</dre> <def><dt>:to be completely controlled by someone <vi>He had them <it>eating out of his hand</it>. [=he controlled them completely]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat a horse</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat crow</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>eat humble pie</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to admit that you were wrong or accept that you have been defeated <vi>He was forced to <it>eat crow</it> when the company fired him.</vi> <vi>They had to <it>eat humble pie</it> when the rumors they were spreading were proved false.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat light</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat (someone or something) alive</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of insects</ssl> <dt>:to bite (someone or something) many times <vi>The mosquitoes were <it>eating us alive</it>. [=we were being bitten frequently by many mosquitoes]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to badly defeat or harm someone or something <vi>Their competitors are going to <it>eat them alive</it> if they don't cut their prices.</vi> <vi>If this story gets out, the press will <it>eat him alive</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat someone's or something's lunch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lunch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to tell someone to start or continue eating <vi><it>Eat up</it>! Your dinner is getting cold.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>eat up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>eat (something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to eat all of (something) <vi><it>Eat</it> your dinner <it>up</it> before it gets cold.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use up (time, resources, etc.) <vi>This project has been <it>eating up</it> a large part of the budget.</vi> <vi>Your savings may be <it>eaten up</it> by inflation.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>A person who is <phrase>eaten up</phrase> with or by jealousy, bitterness, etc., cannot escape that feeling and is made unhappy by it. <vi>He was <it>eaten up</it> with envy of his brother's success.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>eat (something) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to enjoy (something) greatly <vi>I thought the speech was stupid, but the audience <it>ate it up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat up the clock</dre> <dx>see <dxt>clock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat your fill</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fill</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eat your heart out</dre> <def><dt>:to be jealous <vi>“<it>Eat your heart out</it>,” he jokingly told his friend before getting on his new boat.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eat your words</dre> <def><dt>:to take back what you have said :to admit that you were wrong about something <vi>She said she would <it>eat her words</it> if the wedding was called off.</vi> <vi>They promised success, but if things don't get better soon, they may have to <it>eat their words</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have your cake and eat it too</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>have your cake and eat it</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>cake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>I'll eat my hat</dre> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something will not happen or cannot be true <vi>If he wins the election, <it>I'll eat my hat</it>! [=I don't believe he has any chance to win the election]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the proof of the pudding is in the eating</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pudding</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>eat*able</ure> <sound><wav>eatabl01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈi:ɾəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>eatable</it> [=(more commonly) <it>edible</it>] plant</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>eat*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>eat*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a picky <it>eater</it> [=someone who dislikes many kinds of food]</vi> <vi>a big <it>eater</it> [=someone who eats a lot]</vi></utxt></uro> <syns><sc>eat</sc>, <sc>consume</sc>, and <sc>devour</sc> mean to chew and swallow food. <sc>eat</sc> is a general word that can apply to any manner of taking in food. <vi><it>Eat</it> your dinner.</vi> <sc>consume</sc> suggests completely eating something up so that none is left. <vi>By noon they had <it>consumed</it> all of their food supplies.</vi> <sc>devour</sc> suggests eating quickly and greedily. <vi>The hungry children <it>devoured</it> the grapes.</vi></syns></entry>

	<entry id="skin[2]"> <hw hindex="2">skin</hw> <altpr>ˈskɪn</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>skins</if></in> <in><if>skinned</if></in> <in><if>skin*ning</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to remove the skin of (an animal, fruit, or vegetable) <vi>The hunter <it>skinned</it> the rabbit and prepared it for cooking.</vi> <vi><it>Skin</it> [=(more commonly) <it>peel</it>] the tomatoes/peppers.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to scrape or rub off some of the skin from (a body part) <vi>I <it>skinned</it> my knee when I fell.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>keep your eyes skinned</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>skin (someone) alive</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to punish (someone) severely <vi>Mom is going to <it>skin</it> me <it>alive</it> when she finds out about the broken window.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="well[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">well</hw> <altpr>ˈwɛl</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>better</if></in> <in><if>best</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in good health :<sx>healthy</sx> <vi>The children are <it>well</it> again.</vi> <vi>He is not <it>well</it>. = He is not a <it>well</it> man.</vi> <vi>I don't feel very <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>You don't look so <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <phrase>get well soon</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:in a good or satisfactory state <vi>I hope all is <it>well</it> with you and your family.</vi> <vi>We almost didn't make it here, but <phrase>all's well that ends well</phrase>. [=we can forget about how unpleasant or difficult it was because everything ended in a good way]</vi> <vi>I should have <phrase>left/let well (enough) alone</phrase> [=I should not have tried to make the situation better], but instead I tried to help and only made things worse.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:wise, sensible, or reasonable <vi>It might be <it>well</it> [=it might be a good idea] for you to leave now.</vi> <vi>It would be <phrase>as well</phrase> for you to get some rest. [=you should get some rest]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>alive and well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alive</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all very well</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>all well and good</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that something may seem proper, good, or reasonable by itself but that there are other things that also have to be considered <vi><phrase>It's all very well</phrase> your telling me to take it easy, but I have a deadline to meet!</vi> <vi>They say we have to improve our schools. <phrase>That's all very well</phrase>, but the question is, how can we find the money to do it?</vi> <vi>It is <it>all well and good</it> that you have been enjoying yourself, but you have to start saving your money.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just as well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>just</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>very well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>very</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
