<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="allow"> <hw highlight="yes">al*low</hw> <sound><wav>allow001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈlaʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>al*lows</if></in> <in><if>al*lowed</if></in> <in><if>al*low*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to permit (something) :to regard or treat (something) as acceptable <vi>a religion that does not <it>allow</it> divorce</vi> <vi>They don't <it>allow</it> smoking in this hotel.</vi> <vi>I want to change my schedule, but my boss won't <it>allow</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to permit (someone) to have or do something <vi>He <it>allowed</it> her to leave. [=he let her leave]</vi> <vi>My boss wouldn't <it>allow</it> me to change my schedule.</vi> <vi>They don't <it>allow</it> people to smoke in this hotel.</vi> <vi>He <it>allows</it> himself (to have) many luxuries.</vi> <un>used in the phrase <phrase>allow me</phrase> to make a polite offer to help someone <vi><it>Allow me</it> to get/open the door for you.</vi> <vi>If you're going to remodel your kitchen, <it>allow me</it> to offer a few suggestions.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to permit (someone) to go or come in, out, etc. <vi>Women were not <it>allowed</it> in/into the club.</vi> <vi>The hospital doesn't <it>allow</it> visitors after 8 p.m.</vi> <vi>Those children are too young to be <it>allowed</it> (to go) out at night.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to make it possible for someone or something to have or do something <vi>Her experience <it>allows</it> her to handle difficult situations easily. [=she can handle difficult situations easily because of her experience]</vi> <vi>Her schedule doesn't <it>allow</it> her any time to run errands.</vi> <vi>The system <it>allows</it> you to transfer data easily from one computer to another.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make it possible for something to happen <vi>Occasional gaps <it>allow</it> passage through the mountains.</vi> <vi>a password that <it>allows</it> access to the system</vi> <vi>The system <it>allows</it> the easy transfer of data from one computer to another. = The system <it>allows</it> data to be transferred easily from one computer to another.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to fail to prevent something or someone from being, becoming, or doing something <vi>They <it>allowed</it> the garden to become overgrown with weeds.</vi> <vi>These conditions should never have been <it>allowed</it> to develop.</vi> <vi>I was surprised to see that she had <it>allowed</it> herself to become so fat. [=that she had become so fat]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to include (a quantity of time, money, etc.) as an appropriate amount <vi>When you're planning your day you should <it>allow</it> an hour for lunch.</vi> <vi>Their parents <it>allowed</it> five dollars for each child as spending money.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>allow</it> (ourselves) enough time to get the job done properly.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to accept (something) <vi>The judge decided to <it>allow</it> the evidence.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to admit (something) <vi>His job played a more important part in his life than his biographer <it>allows</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>that</it> or (<it>US, informal</it>) <it>as how</it> <vi>She <it>allowed that</it> the work was hard. = She <it>allowed as how</it> the work was hard. [=she admitted that the work was hard]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to let an opposing team or player have or score (a goal, a hit, etc.) <vi>The pitcher <it>allowed</it> five hits and three runs in the first two innings.</vi> <vi><it>allow</it> a goal</vi> <vi>The defense has not <it>allowed</it> a touchdown in the past three games.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>allow for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>allow for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to think about or plan for (something that will or might happen in the future) <vi>When purchasing property, the company should <it>allow for</it> possible future growth/expansion.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to consider (something) when you make a calculation <vi>The total distance, <it>allowing for</it> detours, is about 10 miles.</vi> <vi>If you <it>allow for</it> inflation, he's actually earning less money now than he was 10 years ago. [=the value of the money he earns now is less than that of the money he earned 10 years ago because of inflation]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (something) possible <vi>The design of the system <it>allows for</it> [=<it>allows, permits</it>] easy upgrades.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>allow of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>allow of (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to make (something) possible <vi>The evidence <it>allows of</it> [=<it>allows, permits</it>] two possible interpretations.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>al*low*able</ure> <sound><wav>allowa01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈlawəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>allowable</it> behavior</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
