<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="ancient"> <hw>an*cient</hw> <sound><wav>ancien02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈeɪnʃənt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more an*cient; most an*cient</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:very old :having lived or existed for a very long time <vi>The people in the village still observe the <it>ancient</it> customs/traditions of their ancestors.</vi> <vi>a grove of <it>ancient</it> oak trees</vi> <un>often used in an exaggerated way to describe an old machine, person, etc. <vi>We got a ride in an <it>ancient</it> truck.</vi> <vi>an <it>ancient</it> barn</vi> <vi>I never thought I'd feel <it>ancient</it> at age 31.</vi> <vi>She finally decided to replace her <it>ancient</it> computer with something more modern and up to date.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:of, coming from, or belonging to a time that was long ago in the past <vi>The practice was more common in <it>ancient</it> times than it is now.</vi> <vi>life in <it>ancient</it> Egypt/Rome/Greece/China</vi> <vi>the gods of the <it>ancient</it> Romans</vi> <vi><it>ancient</it> artifacts</vi> <vi>She studied both <it>ancient</it> and modern history.</vi> <snote>In informal use, something that happened long ago and that is not important any more is <phrase>ancient history</phrase>. <vi>Our relationship is <it>ancient history</it>.</vi> <vi>Forget about the problems we've had in the past. They're <it>ancient history</it>.</vi></snote> <synref>old</synref></dt></def> <uro><ure>an*cient*ly</ure> <sound><wav>ancie01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈeɪnʃəntli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a drink that was used <it>anciently</it> [=in ancient times] as a love potion</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="history"> <hw highlight="yes">his*to*ry</hw> <sound><wav>histor15.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɪstəri</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>his*to*ries</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the study of past events <vi>I studied <it>history</it> in college.</vi> <vi>a professor of medieval/American <it>history</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>natural history</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:events of the past <vi>They were one of the greatest teams in <it>history</it>.</vi> <vi>the dawn of recorded <it>history</it> [=the beginning of the time when important events in the past were written down]</vi> <vi>These problems have occurred throughout (human) <it>history</it>.</vi> <vi>It was one of the most destructive storms in modern/recent <it>history</it>.</vi> <vi>It was a period in American <it>history</it> when most people lived and worked on farms.</vi> <vi>Her discoveries have earned her a place in <it>history</it>. [=she will be remembered in the future because of her discoveries]</vi> <vi>How will <it>history</it> judge the policies of the current administration? [=how will the policies be regarded in the future?]</vi> <vi><phrase>History has shown</phrase> that such attempts have always failed. [=such attempts have always failed in the past]</vi> <vi>They believe that they will succeed because <phrase>history is on their side</phrase>. [=because other people have succeeded in the past in similar situations]</vi> <vi>You can't <phrase>rewrite history</phrase>. [=you can't change what has happened in the past]</vi> <vi>A talent scout spotted her behind the counter at a soda fountain and <phrase>the rest is history</phrase>. [=the rest of the story about her success is well-known]</vi> <vi>They won the championship last year. Will <phrase>history repeat itself</phrase> this year? [=will the same thing happen again?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:past events that relate to a particular subject, place, organization, etc. <vi>He gave us a tour of the building and told us about the company's <it>history</it>. [=about how the company began and how it has developed over time]</vi> <vi>The company has been successful throughout its <it>history</it>. [=throughout the entire time of its existence]</vi> <vi>Nothing like this has occurred before in the company's 20-year <it>history</it>. [=in the 20 years that the company has existed]</vi> <vi>There is quite a bit of <it>history</it> [=much has happened] in this old house.</vi> <vi>The <it>history</it> of space exploration is a fascinating topic.</vi> <vi>The school can <phrase>trace its history</phrase> back to the early 19th century. [=the school has existed since the early 19th century]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a written record of important events that have happened since the beginning of something <vi>He wrote a well-known <it>history</it> of the British empire.</vi> <vi>The book begins with a brief/short <it>history</it> of the Internet.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an established record of past events, actions, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>The patient has no (prior) <it>history</it> of heart problems. [=she has not had heart problems in the past]</vi> <vi>The prisoner has a <it>history</it> of violence. [=the prisoner has been violent in the past]</vi> <vi>a patient's <phrase>medical history</phrase> [=a record of past medical problems and treatments]</vi> <vi>a worker's <phrase>employment history</phrase> [=a record of jobs that a worker has had]</vi> <vi>It's hard to buy a car if you don't have any <phrase>credit history</phrase>. [=if you have not borrowed and repaid money in the past]</vi> <vi>They have a <phrase>family history</phrase> of heart disease. [=many people in their family have suffered from heart disease in the past]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:someone or something that is finished <vi>Their winning streak was <it>history</it>. [=their winning streak was finished/over]</vi> <vi>His boss told him that if he was late one more time, he would be <it>history</it>. [=he would be fired]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>ancient history</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ancient</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go down in history</dre> <def><dt>:to be remembered as a very important person or event <vi>The discovery of the structure of DNA will <it>go down in history</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make history</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that is very important or famous and that will be remembered as part of history <vi>They <it>made history</it> by discovering the structure of DNA.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
