<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="and"> <hw highlight="yes">and</hw> <sound><wav>and00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈænd, ənd, ən</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to join words or groups of words <vi>We have ice cream <it>and</it> cake for dessert.</vi> <vi>He's feeling strong <it>and</it> healthy.</vi> <vi>She answered quickly <it>and</it> confidently.</vi> <vi>He swerved <it>and</it> avoided an accident.</vi> <vi>She's the club's secretary <it>and</it> treasurer.</vi> <vi>He walked into the room <it>and</it> sat down at the table.</vi> <vi>an actor who is tall, dark, <it>and</it> handsome</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:added to :plus <vi>2 <it>and</it> 2 equals 4.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe an action that is repeated or that occurs for a long time <vi>The dog barked <it>and</it> barked.</vi> <vi>She cried <it>and</it> cried.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to repeat a word for emphasis <vi>You <it>and</it> you alone are responsible for correcting these errors.</vi> <vi>There were hundreds <it>and</it> hundreds of people there.</vi> <vi>The project is becoming more <it>and</it> more expensive.</vi> <vi>The work is getting harder <it>and</it> harder.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe actions that occur at the same time <vi>They walked <it>and</it> talked.</vi> <vi>We sat <it>and</it> waited for hours.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe an action that occurs after another action <vi>They drove five miles <it>and</it> stopped to eat.</vi> <vi>He promised to come <it>and</it> didn't.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe an action that occurs after and is caused by another action <vi>I told him to go <it>and</it> he went.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used after <it>go, come, try, write</it>, etc., to indicate the purpose of an action <vi>Why don't you go/come <it>and</it> see her? [=go/come to see her]</vi> <vi>I'll try <it>and</it> do it. [=I'll try to do it]</vi> <vi>Promise that you'll write <it>and</it> tell me [=write to tell me] about your vacation.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a choice <vi>You have to choose between him <it>and</it> me.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to start a new sentence or clause that continues or adds to a previous sentence or clause <vi>These problems have been occurring for many years, as everyone acknowledges. <it>And</it> of course they are going to continue unless something is done.</vi> <vi>Critics of the administration—<it>and</it> there many of them—have objected to the new plan.</vi> <vi>“Well, I've spoken to him…” “<it>And</it>?” “<it>And</it> he said yes!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt><un>used after <it>hundred</it> and <it>thousand</it> when saying a number aloud <vi>a/one hundred <it>and</it> twenty-four [=124]</vi> <vi>two thousand <it>and</it> sixty-five [=2,065]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used when saying aloud a number that is followed by a fraction <vi>seven <it>and</it> three quarters [=7<frac>3/4</frac>]</vi> <vi>One <it>and</it> a half years have passed since then. = A year <it>and</it> a half has passed since then.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the point where two streets meet or cross <vi>a restaurant located at (the corner of) Main Street <it>and</it> First Avenue</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="all[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the entire number, quantity, or amount <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] that I have is yours.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] will be explained soon.</vi> <vi>She told us <it>all</it> about what happened.</vi> <vi>Her other books were good, but this one is the best of <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> are welcome! [=everyone is welcome]</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> enjoyed the movie. = <it>All</it> of us enjoyed the movie.</vi> <vi>Many people were invited and <it>all</it> came.</vi> <vi>His stories may be entertaining, but I don't think <it>all</it> (of them) are true.</vi> <vi>Thanks to <it>all</it> who helped out.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> of this money will be yours when I die.</vi> <vi>Not <it>all</it> of our students go on to college.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>was all (that) I could do</phrase> to keep from laughing! [=I had a hard time trying not to laugh]</vi> <vi>“Is there anything else to be done?” “No, <phrase>that's all</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He gave equal attention to <phrase>one and all</phrase>. [=to everyone]</vi> <vi><phrase>Come one, come all</phrase>. [=everyone is invited to come]</vi> <usageref>altogether</usageref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the only thing <vi>That's <it>all</it> I can do to help.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> I know is that the game was canceled. I don't know why.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>after</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>All aboard!</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aboard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all in all</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a general way :when everything is thought of or considered <vi><it>All in all</it> [=<it>in general, generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi> <vi>We did lose some money, but we got most of it back. So <it>all in all</it> things might have been a lot worse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>The cost of the repairs came to about $300 <it>all told</it>. [=<it>in all</it>] [=the total cost of the repairs was about $300]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>and all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:and everything else <vi>What with the noise outside, the fire <it>and all</it>, we got hardly any sleep.</vi> <vi>He endured everything, insults <it>and all</it>, without getting angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a response <vi>“It's really hot out!” “It is <it>and all</it>!” [=it certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>He will go anywhere <it>at all</it> to get a job.</vi> <vi>Did you find out anything <it>at all</it>?</vi></un> <un>used especially in negative statements <vi>“Did she say anything?” “No, nothing <it>at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't mind cooking <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>at all</it> what you think it is. It's something else entirely.</vi> <vi>I wasn't tired <it>at all</it>. = I wasn't <it>at all</it> tired. [=I wasn't even slightly tired]</vi> <vi>This chair is not <it>at all</it> comfortable.</vi> <vi>I didn't like it <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>That is not <it>at all</it> likely.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>not at all</phrase> is sometimes used as a polite response when someone thanks you. <vi>“Thank you for all your trouble.” “<it>Not at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>“That was very kind of you.” “<it>Not at all</it>. It was the least I could do.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your all</dre> <def><dt>:to do or give as much as you can to achieve something, to support a cause, etc. <vi>He <it>gave his all</it> for the cause. = He <it>gave his all</it> to help the cause.</vi> <vi>You'll never succeed in this business unless you <it>give (it) your all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>There were about a thousand people at the concert <it>in all</it>. [=<it>all told</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>once and for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <def><dt>:after considering or doing everything <un>used for a final general statement or judgment <vi>It won't be easy, but <it>when all is said and done</it>, we'll be glad we did it.</vi> <vi>The candidates claim to have different views but, <it>when all is said and done</it>, they're very much alike.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="Bob"> <hw>Bob</hw> <pr>ˈbɑ:b</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>and Bob's your uncle</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is easy to do or use <vi>Just complete the form, pay the fee, <it>and Bob's your uncle</it>! [=and there you go]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="change[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">change</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃeɪnʤ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>changes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act, process, or result of changing: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of becoming different or of causing someone or something to become different <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There has been little if any <it>change</it> in her daily routine.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't be afraid of <it>change</it>. <it>Change</it> is a natural part of life.</vi> <vi>The terms of this contract are subject to <it>change</it> without notice. [=the terms can be changed at any time]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The years have brought many <it>changes</it> to the town's economy.</vi> <vi>We need to make some <it>changes</it> in/to the system.</vi> <vi>Many voters believe that it's time for a <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>We've had to make a slight <it>change</it> in the schedule.</vi> <vi>There has been a <it>change</it> in/to our plans. = There's been a <phrase>change of plan</phrase>. [=we have changed our plans]</vi> <vi><phrase>a change for the better</phrase> [=an improvement]</vi> <vi><phrase>a change for the worse</phrase></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sea change</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of replacing one thing with another <vi>a <it>change</it> of address/name</vi> <vi><it>changes</it> of mood/attitude/tone</vi> <vi>I enjoy the <phrase>change of seasons</phrase> every year. [=I enjoy seeing the seasons change from winter to spring, etc.]</vi> <vi>The car needs an <phrase>oil change</phrase>. [=needs to have the old, dirty oil removed and replaced with clean oil]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of moving from one plane, train, etc., to another in order to continue a journey <vi>If you take this flight you'll need to make a <it>change</it> (of planes) in Chicago. [=you'll need to change planes in Chicago]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is different from what is usual or expected <vi>We've been so busy that a quiet day at home was a welcome <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>We eat at home a lot, so dining out sometimes is/makes a nice <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) So you've done the cooking for once in your life! Well, that <phrase>makes a change</phrase>!</vi> <vi>I've been stuck here in the city for months. I could really use <phrase>a change of scene/scenery</phrase>. = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) I could really use a <phrase>change of air</phrase>. [=I would like to go somewhere else for a time]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>for a change <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:smaller bills or coins that are given for a larger bill <vi>Have you got <it>change</it> for a $10 bill?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the money returned when a payment is more than the amount needed <vi>It cost $9 and I gave you $10, so I should be getting $1 in <it>change</it>.</vi> <vi>“It costs $9.” “Here's $10. You can <phrase>keep the change</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Can you <phrase>make change</phrase> for a twenty? [=can you give me change if I pay with a $20 bill?]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:money in the form of coins <vi>I've got a $10 bill and about $3 in <it>change</it>. [=<it>coins</it>]</vi> <vi>a pocketful of <phrase>loose change</phrase></vi> <vi>The beggar asked us if we had any <phrase>spare change</phrase>. [=a small amount of money that we did not need]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>change purse</dxt> <dxt>small change</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>money</sx> <un>used in the phrase <phrase>chunk of change</phrase> <vi>She inherited a large/hefty/nice <it>chunk of change</it> [=a large amount of money] from her aunt.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a clean set of clothes that someone can wear if they are needed <vi>For a weekend in the country you'll need several <it>changes</it> of clothes.</vi> <vi>The only extra clothes he took with him were a pair of socks and a <it>change</it> of underwear.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>changeup</sx> <vi>The batter struck out on a straight <it>change</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the change</bnote> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:<sx>change of life</sx> <vi>women who are going through <it>the change</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and change</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:and a very small additional amount <vi>There's only six minutes <it>and change</it> left in the game. [=there's only a little more than six minutes left in the game]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for a change</dre> <def><dt>:as something different from what is usual <vi>Let's eat out <it>for a change</it>.</vi> <vi>Why don't you help me out <it>for a change</it> instead of me always helping you?!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ring the changes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ring</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="count[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">count</hw> <sound><wav>count001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkaʊnt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>counts</if></in> <in><if>count*ed</if></in> <in><if>count*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to add (people or things) together to find the total number <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Count</it> the plates on the table.</vi> <vi>She made sure to <it>count</it> her change.</vi> <vi><it>Count</it> how many fingers I am holding up.</vi> <vi>He <it>counted</it> seven deer in the field.</vi> <vi>When it comes to books, I have <phrase>too many to count</phrase>. [=I have a lot of books]</vi> <vi>She is <phrase>counting calories</phrase>. [=she counts the number of calories in the food she eats so that she won't eat too much]</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She was <it>counting up</it> the money in the envelope.</vi> <vi>All the votes were <it>counted up</it>, and he was the winner.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>There are 10 days left until the end of school, <it>counting</it> from today.</vi> <vi>Keep <it>counting</it> until there are no more left to count.</vi> <vi>Don't interrupt me. I'm <it>counting</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to say numbers in order <vi>Can your daughter <it>count</it> yet?</vi> <vi>The teacher taught the students to <it>count</it> by 10s. [=to say “10, 20, 30, etc.”]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> or <it>up to</it> <vi>My son can <it>count to</it> one hundred.</vi> <vi>He <it>counted up to</it> 10 and then stopped.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to include (someone or something) in a total <vi>She <it>counts</it> [=<it>numbers</it>] several musicians among her friends. [=her friends include musicians]</vi> <vi>There will be 150 people at the wedding, not <it>counting</it> children.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be accepted or allowed officially <vi>There was a penalty on the play, so the goal does not <it>count</it>. [=the goal is not allowed]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to consider or regard (someone or something) in a specified way <vi>I <it>count</it> myself lucky.</vi> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>I don't <it>count</it> him <it>as</it> my friend anymore.</vi> <vi>She was <it>counted as</it> absent from school that day.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be considered or regarded <it>as</it> something <vi>A laptop computer <it>counts as</it> a piece of luggage on the plane.</vi> <vi>The job is so easy that it hardly <it>counts as</it> work. [=it can hardly be considered to be work]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have value or importance <vi>Every vote <it>counts</it>.</vi> <vi>He played well in the play-offs, when it really <it>counted</it>. [=<it>mattered</it>]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>My effort in class has to <it>count for</it> something!</vi> <vi>Her promises don't <it>count for</it> much. [=his promises don't have much value]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to be considered in a specified way when a person or thing is being judged <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His experience <it>counts</it> in his favor. [=his experience is a good thing that is in his favor]</vi> <vi>His lack of experience <it>counts</it> against him.</vi> <vi>A wrong answer on the quiz will not <it>count</it> against [=will not hurt] your final grade.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>counted</it> his lack of job experience against him.</vi> <vi>A wrong answer on the quiz will not be <it>counted</it> against your final grade.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and counting</dre> <def><dt>:with more to come <vi>He is 47 years old <it>and counting</it>.</vi> <vi>They have been in business for 50 years <it>and counting</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to count numbers in a reverse order from higher numbers to lower ones <vi>He <it>counted down</it> from 10 to 1.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count down (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>count (something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay close attention to the number of (days, miles, etc.) that remain until a particular moment or event is reached <vi>He is <it>counting down</it> the days left in the school year. [=he is eagerly looking forward to the end of the school year]</vi> <vi>We were <it>counting down</it> the miles as we approached our destination.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <def><dt>:to count how many people are present at a place <vi>The coach <it>counted heads</it> before the bus left.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>count (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to plan to include (someone) in an activity :to consider (someone) as one of the people who will be doing something <vi>“Do you want to go to the beach with us?” “Yes! <it>Count</it> me <it>in</it>!”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to count numbers that are spaced a certain number apart <vi>The students <it>counted off</it> by twos. [=counted 2, 4, 6, 8, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to list (something) out loud <vi>She <it>counted off</it> all the things she wanted to do.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>count on/upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to trust (someone) :to rely or depend on (someone) to do something <vi>He isn't someone you can <it>count on</it> all the time.</vi> <vi>I am <it>counting on</it> you to help me through this difficult time.</vi> <vi>She is <it>counted on</it> [=<it>trusted</it>] as a leader.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to expect (someone) to do something <vi>I wouldn't <it>count on</it> him to win the match.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to expect (something) to happen <vi>My parents might loan me some money, but I can't <it>count on</it> it.</vi> <vi>She is <it>counting on</it> a big tax refund this year.</vi> <vi>The kids are <it>counting on</it> going to the movies. Don't disappoint them!</vi> <vi>They were not <it>counting on</it> getting a flat tire on the way to the restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>count (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not include (someone) in an activity <vi>If you are looking for people to help you clean the house today, <it>count</it> me <it>out</it>. [=don't include me; I won't be helping you]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>count (someone or something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count out (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that (someone or something) cannot win or succeed <vi>Don't <it>count out</it> our team just yet. They could still win.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count the cost</dre> <def><dt>:to feel the bad effects of a mistake, accident, etc. <vi>He was careless and now he's <it>counting the cost</it>. = Now he's <it>counting the cost</it> of his carelessness.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count toward/towards</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>count toward/towards (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>count (something) toward/towards (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have value as a credit or payment in relation to (something) <vi>The credits you earned for this class <it>count toward</it> your degree. [=they are added to the total number of credits you have earned for your degree]</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) counted toward/towards</it> <vi>Fifty dollars will <it>be counted towards</it> [=<it>credited to</it>] your next bill.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>count your blessings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blessing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count your chickens before they hatch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chicken</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>stand up and be counted</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>who's counting?</dre> <def><sl>informal + humorous</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not care about how large a number is <vi>Tomorrow's my 80th birthday, but <it>who's counting</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="everything"> <hw highlight="yes">ev*ery*thing</hw> <sound><wav>everyt01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛvriˌθɪŋ</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:every thing there is :all that exists <vi>People will buy <it>everything</it> she paints.</vi> <vi>I didn't agree with <it>everything</it> he said.</vi> <vi>What do you buy for the man who has <it>everything</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:all that is related to a particular subject <vi>Tell us <it>everything</it> that happened.</vi> <vi>He denied <it>everything</it> about the incident.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>everything from (something) to (something)</phrase> is used to show the wide range of things that are included in something. <vi>The company makes <it>everything from golf tees to diapers</it>.</vi> <vi>Her paintings have been called <it>everything from childish to brilliant</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:all that is important <vi>To him, money is <it>everything</it>. [=he only cares about money]</vi> <vi>She means <it>everything</it> to me.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the things that are happening in a person's life <vi>How's <it>everything</it>?</vi> <vi><it>Everything</it> is fine.</vi> <vi>We're pretty happy with <it>everything</it> right now.</vi> <snote>Phrases like <phrase>How's everything?</phrase> and <phrase>How's everything going?</phrase> are used, especially in U.S. English, as informal ways to say “How are you?”</snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>and everything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:and other things like that <vi>I like being out in the forest with all the birds and trees <it>and everything</it>.</vi> <vi>He has a lot on his mind, what with his health problems <it>and everything</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry everything before you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>carry</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="forth"> <hw>forth</hw> <sound><wav>forth001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfoɚθ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>literary</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:out into notice or view :<sx>out</sx> <vi>a flow of lava bursting <it>forth</it> from the earth</vi> <vi>The snow is gone and the flowers are ready to spring <it>forth</it>.</vi> <vi>He went <it>forth</it> to spread the news.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:onward or forward in time or place <vi>She stretched <it>forth</it> her hands in prayer.</vi> <vi><phrase>from that day forth</phrase> [=from that time onward]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and so forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>so</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bring forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bring</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>call</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>put</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sally forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sally</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set forth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>set</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>back and forth</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="half[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">half</hw> <sound><wav>half0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhæf, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑ:f</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>halves</if> <sound><wav>half0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhævz, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑvz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:one of two equal or nearly equal parts into which something can be divided <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She broke each cookie into <it>halves</it>.</vi> <vi>“Which <it>half</it> do you want?” “I'll take the smaller <it>half</it>.”</vi> <vi>Two <it>halves</it> make a whole.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The price has been reduced <phrase>by half</phrase>. [=by 50 percent; by an amount that is equal to one half of the original]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>better half</dxt> <dxt>other half</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:either of the two equal periods of playing time in sports like football and basketball <vi>The team fell behind in the first <it>half</it> but rallied in the second <it>half</it> to win the game.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the half</bnote> <dt>:the time when the first half of a game ends <vi>The score was tied at <it>the half</it>. [=at halftime]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:half a pint of a drink (such as beer) <vi>“What's yours?” “A <it>half</it> of lager, please.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>and a half</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used in measurements of time, distance, weight, etc., to indicate one half of the unit of measurement <vi>My daughter is two and a <it>half</it> (years old). [=two years and six months old]</vi> <vi>The fish was a foot <it>and a half</it> long. [=one foot and six inches long]</vi> <vi>ten <it>and a half</it> pounds [=ten pounds and eight ounces]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that something is very good, large, difficult, etc. <vi>That was a meal <it>and a half</it>! [=that was a very big meal]</vi> <vi>Renovating a house is a job <it>and a half</it>. [=is a very difficult job]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by halves</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in an incomplete way <un>used in negative statements to say that someone does things with a lot of energy and effort <vi>She never does anything <it>by halves</it>—it's all or nothing!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go halves</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>go half and half</va></vr> <def><dt>:to share the cost of something equally <vi>We decided to <it>go halves</it> (with each other) on the expenses.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in half</dre> <def><dt>:into two equal parts :into two halves <vi>She cut the apple <it>in half</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the half of it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that a situation is even worse than you think it is or than it seems to be <vi>“It sounds like you've been having some problems.” “You don't know <it>the half of it</it>!”</vi> <vi>Sales are down but that's only <it>the half of it</it>—the company is closing several stores.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too…by half</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has too much of a particular quality usually in a way that is annoying <vi>an arrogant politician who is <phrase>too clever by half</phrase></vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="how[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">how</hw> <sound><wav>how00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhaʊ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in what manner or way <vi><it>How</it> and where did you meet him?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> shall I address the President?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> will we pay for the trip?</vi> :by what means <vi>“<it>How</it> did you get here?” “By bus.”</vi> <vi>“<it>How</it> did she die?” “She had cancer.”</vi> <vi><it>How</it> do you know that?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> did you find us?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> could you have known?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:for what reason :<sx>why</sx> <vi><it>How</it> did you happen to move here?</vi> <vi>“Is it going to rain?” “<phrase>How should/would I know</phrase>?” [=I don't know]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to what degree, extent, or amount <un>used before an adjective or adverb <vi><it>How</it> handsome is he?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> much longer do we have to wait? = <it>How</it> much longer is the wait?</vi> <vi>I don't know <it>how</it> good the service is at the new restaurant.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure <it>how</it> old he is.</vi> <vi>It's a pity <it>how</it> rarely we see each other.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis before an adjective <vi><it>How</it> old he is! [=he is very old]</vi> <vi><it>How</it> wonderful/strange/awful!</vi> <vi><it>How</it> kind of you to ask!</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) <it>How</it> cool is that! [=that is really cool]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt><un>used to ask if someone feels good, bad, happy, sad, etc. <vi>“<it>How</it> are you?” “Very well, thank you.”</vi> <vi>“<it>How</it> are you doing?” “Okay, I guess.”</vi> <vi>“<it>How</it> is your mother these days?” “Much better.”</vi> <vi><it>How</it> do you feel? = <it>How</it> are you feeling?</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>how do you do <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to ask if something is good, bad, etc. <vi><it>How's</it> the new job? [=do you like your new job?]</vi> <vi><it>How</it> are things at home?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> did they do/perform [=did they do/perform well or badly] in the tournament?</vi> <vi><it>How</it> was the play?</vi> <vi><phrase>How do you like</phrase> the soup? = <it>How</it> is the soup? [=do you like the soup?; is the soup good?]</vi> <vi>I can bring it over tomorrow. <phrase>How's that</phrase>? [=is that all right?]</vi> <vi>Let me get you another blanket. There, <phrase>how's that</phrase>? [=is that comfortable?; is that better?]</vi> <vi>He will send a check. <phrase>How will that be</phrase>? = <phrase>How would it be</phrase> if he sent you a check? [=would it be acceptable if he sent you a check?]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>and how</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used for emphasis <vi>Prices are going up, <it>and how</it>! [=prices are going up very quickly]</vi> <vi>“Will you be glad when it's over?” “<it>And how</it>!” [=I will be very glad when it's over]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as how</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>that</sx> <vi>I don't know <it>as how</it> your plan would be any better than mine.</vi> <vi><phrase>Seeing as how</phrase> things were getting worse [=because things were getting worse], she decided to do something.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>, <it>informal</it>) She <phrase>allowed as how</phrase> the situation was serious. [=she admitted that the situation was serious]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how about</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:does that include (someone) :what about <vi>“We're all going to the beach.” “<it>How about</it> Kenny?”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to show that you are very impressed by someone or something <vi>He won again! <it>How about</it> that guy! [=isn't that guy amazing/impressive?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>how about that</bnote> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt><un>used to show that you are surprised or pleased by something <vi>He won again! <it>How about that</it>! [=what good news!; isn't that great?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>also US (informal)</vl> <va>how's about</va></svr> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to make a suggestion about what could be done <vi>We'll need to talk about this again. <it>How about</it> (meeting) next month?</vi> <vi><it>How about</it> [=<it>what about</it>] driving to the coast for the weekend?</vi> <vi><it>How about</it> another game? [=would you like to play another game?]</vi> <vi>What should we do tonight? <it>How about</it> (seeing) a movie?</vi> <vi><it>How's about</it> some more pie?</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to ask someone to give you something <vi><it>How about</it> a couple of dollars until payday? [=can you loan me a couple of dollars until payday?]</vi> <vi><it>How's about</it> (offering me) a drink?</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to ask if someone will do something <vi>Well, <phrase>how about it</phrase>, are you coming?</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to ask someone to tell you something in response to what you have just said <vi>I like skiing and hiking. <phrase>How about you?</phrase> [=what sports do you like?]</vi> <vi>I'm ready to go. <it>How about you?</it> [=are you ready, too?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how can/could</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to show you think that someone has done or said something shocking or wrong <vi>“We don't need his help anyway.” “<it>How can</it> you say that?!” [=it is very wrong of you to say that]</vi> <vi><it>How could</it> she just walk away from her children like that?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to express doubt that something will happen, is possible, etc. <vi><it>How could</it> I (ever/possibly) leave this job?</vi> <vi><it>How can</it> I (ever/possibly) thank you? [=I can never thank you enough; I am extremely grateful to you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>how could you</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to show disappointment in someone's actions, thoughts, words, etc. <vi>You threw away my gift? Oh, <it>how could you</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how come</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to ask why something has happened, is true, etc. <vi>“He said he's not going.” “<it>How come</it>?” [=why isn't he going?]</vi> <vi><it>How come</it> you're here so early? [=why are you here so early?]</vi> <vi><it>How come</it> no one told me?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how dare you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dare</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>how do you do</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:<sx>hello</sx> <un>used especially when you are first introduced to someone <vi><it>How do you do</it>, Miss Smith?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how do you like that</dre> <def><dt><un>used for emphasis or to show surprise or disapproval <vi>He's moving to Hawaii? Well, <it>how do you like that</it>! [=that's a surprise]</vi> <vi>She canceled at the last minute. <it>How do you like that</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how goes it?</dre> <dx>see <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>how's everything (going)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>everything</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>how so</dre> <def><dt>:in what way :why do you think that <vi>“This room looks different.” “<it>How so</it>?” [=in what way does it look different?]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how's that (again)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>what</sx> <un>used to request that something be repeated or explained again <vi><it>How's that</it>? [=what did you say?] I didn't hear you.</vi> <vi>I don't understand. <it>How's that again</it>?</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how's that for</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used for emphasis to describe someone or something you think is very impressive <vi>He won first prize! <it>How's that for</it> a guy who almost didn't enter the contest at all!</vi> <vi>They took care of everything for us. <it>How's that for</it> hospitality? [=that was very hospitable]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how will/would</dre> <def><dt><un>used to express doubt that something will happen or is possible <vi><it>How will</it> we (ever) get everything done on time?</vi> <vi><it>How would</it> he manage without her? [=I don't know if he will be able to manage without her; I doubt he will manage without her]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="like[2]"> <hw hindex="2">like</hw> <altpr>ˈlaɪk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>likes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something that you like, approve of, or enjoy <un>usually plural <vi>my <it>likes</it> and dislikes</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>like</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
