<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="anger[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">an*ger</hw> <sound><wav>anger02w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæŋgɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a strong feeling of being upset or annoyed because of something wrong or bad :the feeling that makes someone want to hurt other people, to shout, etc. :the feeling of being angry <vi>He couldn't hide his <it>anger</it> with/at us.</vi> <vi>You could hear the <it>anger</it> in his voice.</vi> <vi>The group expressed/vented its <it>anger</it> over/about the company's arrogance.</vi> <vi>He said that he had/felt no <it>anger</it> towards the person who shot him.</vi> <vi>He never raised his voice in <it>anger</it>.</vi> <vi>She was shaking/trembling in/with <it>anger</it>.</vi> <vi>He is not easily moved to <it>anger</it>. [=he does not become angry easily]</vi></dt></def> <syns><sc>anger</sc>, <sc>rage</sc>, <sc>fury</sc>, and <sc>wrath</sc> mean a strong feeling caused by displeasure. <sc>anger</sc> is a general word that applies to many different levels of emotion that may or may not be shown. <vi>She kept her <it>anger</it> inside herself.</vi> <sc>rage</sc> suggests loss of control because of great anger. <vi>They were screaming with <it>rage</it>.</vi> <sc>fury</sc> suggests a violent anger. <vi>In their <it>fury</it> they smashed all the dishes.</vi> <sc>wrath</sc> is a slightly old-fashioned word that suggests a desire to punish someone or to get revenge for something. <vi>In his <it>wrath</it> the king ordered the rebels executed.</vi></syns></entry>

	<entry id="anger[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">anger</hw> <altpr>ˈæŋgɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>angers</if></in> <in><if>angered</if></in> <in><if>anger*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to make (someone) angry <vi>They were shocked and <it>angered</it> by the company's arrogance.</vi> <vi>He was <it>angered</it> to learn that he had been fired.</vi> <vi>It <it>angered</it> me that she would say something like that.</vi> <vi>He's a gentle man who's not easily <it>angered</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
