<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="any[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">any</hw> <sound><wav>any00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛni</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a person or thing that is not particular or specific <vi>Ask <it>any</it> man you meet, and he will tell you the same thing.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> one of them could have answered the question.</vi> <vi>You can return the product if <it>any</it> defect appears within the first six months.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> plan (at all) is better than no plan.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> [=<it>every</it>] child knows that. [=all children know that]</vi> <vi>He is as good as <it>any</it> other pitcher in the league.</vi> <vi>We can meet <it>any</it> day but Monday.</vi> <vi>You could have seen him <it>any</it> afternoon last week.</vi> <vi>The recipe uses a large amount of pepper, and <phrase>not just any</phrase> pepper, but a special blend imported from India.</vi> <vi>You have to be a member to go there. They won't let <phrase>just any</phrase> person in.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an amount greater than zero or none</un> <un>usually used in negative statements, in questions, and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>You haven't eaten <it>any</it> salad. [=no salad has been eaten]</vi> <vi>I can't find <it>any</it> stamps.</vi> <vi>Don't pay <it>any</it> attention to him.</vi> <vi>There is hardly <it>any</it> difference between the two teams.</vi> <vi>They dropped by without <it>any</it> warning.</vi> <vi>We don't want there to be <it>any</it> misunderstandings.</vi> <vi>The company has denied <it>any</it> [=<it>all</it>] responsibility for the accident.</vi> <vi>There are <phrase>few if any</phrase> [=few or no] details about the accident.</vi> <vi>Do you have <it>any</it> money?</vi> <vi>He asked if/whether you had <it>any</it> money.</vi> <vi>If there are <it>any</it> errors, report them to me. = Report <it>any</it> errors to me.</vi> <vi>If you can give me <it>any</it> help, I'd appreciate it. = I'd appreciate <it>any</it> help you can give me.</vi></un></dt> <usage><it>Some</it> is used instead of <it>any</it> in positive statements. <vi>I have <it>some</it> money.</vi> It is sometimes used instead of <it>any</it> in questions and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it>. <vi>Do you have <it>some</it> money?</vi> <vi>If I had <it>some</it> money, I would spend it on books.</vi></usage></def> <dro><dre>any moment</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moment</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <dx>see <dxt>old</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at any cost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>by any chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go to any length/lengths</dre> <dx>see <dxt>length</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any case</dre> <dx>see <dxt>case</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any event</dre> <dx>see <dxt>event</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="any[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">any</hw> <altpr>ˈɛni</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:any one of the people or things in a group <vi>She asked if there were <it>any</it> present who needed assistance.</vi> <vi>The movie's opening scene is as powerful as <it>any</it> I've ever watched.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi><it>Any of</it> them could answer the question.</vi> <vi>He is taller than <it>any of</it> the other boys.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:any amount <vi>“I'd like some more coffee.” “I'm sorry, but there isn't <it>any</it> left.”</vi> <vi>Is there <it>any</it> [=<it>some</it>] left?</vi> <vi>I'll see if there's <it>any</it> [=<it>some</it>] left.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>You have not eaten <it>any of</it> your salad.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="any[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">any</hw> <altpr>ˈɛni</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:to the least amount or degree <vi>The food there is never <it>any</it> good.</vi> <vi>He won't be <it>any</it> happier there than he was here.</vi> <vi>I could not walk <it>any</it> farther.</vi> <vi>Do you want <it>any</it> [=<it>some</it>] more pizza?</vi> <vi>I can't eat <it>any</it> more pizza.</vi> <vi>If you want <it>any</it> [=<it>some</it>] more pizza, it's in the fridge.</vi> <vi>(<it>US, informal</it>) You certainly aren't helping me <it>any</it>. [=<it>at all</it>]</vi> <vi>We can't ignore these problems <phrase>any longer</phrase>. [=<it>anymore</it>] [=we must stop ignoring these problems]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="day"> <hw highlight="yes">day</hw> <sound><wav>day00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdeɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>days</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a period of 24 hours beginning at midnight :one of the seven time periods that make up a week <vi>We're open seven <it>days</it> a week, 365 <it>days</it> a year.</vi> <vi>Payment is due on the first <it>day</it> of every month.</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> is (it) today?” “Tuesday.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> [=<it>date</it>] is Friday?” “It's the 28th.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> of the week is the 28th?” “It's a Friday.”</vi> <vi>He spent five <it>days</it> in the hospital.</vi> <vi>She left on Thursday and came back four <it>days</it> later.</vi> <vi>The baby is due (to be born) in three <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>That was the happiest <it>day</it> of my life.</vi> <vi>Parenthood gets better every <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>We'll be finished in a <it>day</it> or two. = We'll be finished in a couple of <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It rained for a <it>day</it> and a half. [=it rained for about 36 hours]</vi> <vi>The office is closed for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I call him every (single) <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow is another <it>day</it>. [=there will be more opportunities to do things tomorrow]</vi> <vi>a <it>day</it> of celebration/mourning [=a day for people to celebrate/mourn]</vi> <vi>Take one pill two times <phrase>a day</phrase>. [=each day]</vi> <vi>She works eight hours <it>a day</it>.</vi> <vi>It costs 10 dollars <it>a day</it> to park there.</vi> <vi>The party is <phrase>the day after tomorrow</phrase>. = The party is in two <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It happened <phrase>the day before yesterday</phrase>. = It happened two <it>days</it> ago.</vi> <vi>Sometimes they didn't speak to each other for <phrase>days on end</phrase>. [=several days]</vi> <vi><phrase>From that day forth/forward</phrase> [=(less formally) <it>from then on</it>], I was determined to do better.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>do not look a day over</phrase> a particular age, you appear to be that age. <vi>“Today's my 50th birthday.” “Really? I'm surprised. You <it>don't look a day over</it> 40.” [=you don't look any older than 40 years old]</vi></snote> <snote>If you say that someone is a particular age <phrase>if he/she is a day</phrase>, you mean that the person is that age or older. <vi>The man she's dating is 60 <it>if he's a day</it>. [=he is at least sixty years old]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the time of light between one night and the next :the part of the day when light from the sun can be seen <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What a beautiful summer <it>day</it>!</vi> <vi>a cold/wet/rainy <it>day</it></vi> <vi>The shortest <it>day</it> of the year is usually December 22, and June 22 is usually the longest.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He sleeps during the <it>day</it> [=<it>daytime</it>] and works at night.</vi> <vi>You can call me any time, <it>day</it> or night.</vi> <vi>These animals are mostly active during the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I work during the <it>day</it>. [=I work days]</vi> <vi>She's a student <phrase>by day</phrase> [=during the day] and a waitress by night.</vi> <vi>I woke at (the) <phrase>break of day</phrase>. [=(more commonly) <it>dawn, daybreak, sunrise</it>]</vi> <vi><phrase>day workers</phrase> [=people who work during the day]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>night</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of the day when people are usually most active and when most businesses are open <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>I like to start my <it>day</it> with a cup of coffee. [=I like to drink a cup of coffee as soon as I wake up]</vi> <vi>We decided to rent a car for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>How was your <it>day</it>?</vi> <vi>By the end of the <it>day</it>, we were all exhausted.</vi> <vi>Our neighbors play their loud music <phrase>at all hours of the day</phrase>. [=throughout the day]</vi> <vi>Let's go to bed. We have an <phrase>early day</phrase> [=we will get out of bed early] tomorrow.</vi> <vi>I needed to relax after a <phrase>long day</phrase> at work/school. [=after working/being at school for a long time]</vi> <vi>“Thank you, ma'am. <phrase>Have a nice day</phrase>!”</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I'll be gone <phrase>all day</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It rained <phrase>all day long</phrase>.</vi> <snote>People sometimes say that they <phrase>can't wait all day</phrase> or <phrase>don't have all day</phrase> when they are in a hurry and need someone to move or act more quickly. These phrases are usually used in a rude way. <vi>Hurry up! I <it>can't wait all day</it>! = I <it>don't have all day</it>. = I <it>haven't got all day</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hours during a day when a person works or goes to school or when a company does business <vi>I put in four twelve-hour <it>days</it> [=<it>workdays</it>] this week.</vi> <vi>She makes about 50 dollars a/per <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>He was late for his first <it>day</it> on the job.</vi> <vi>They collected a full <it>day</it>'s pay for half a <it>day</it>'s work.</vi> <vi>We had a busy couple of <it>days</it> at the store.</vi> <vi>We have a short <it>day</it> tomorrow. [=we have to work fewer hours tomorrow than usual]</vi> <vi>The school committee is pushing for a longer school <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow's our last <it>day</it> of school (for the school year).</vi> <vi>Please allow 14 <phrase>business days</phrase> [=days when most businesses are open; weekdays that are not holidays] for delivery.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>all in a day's work</phrase> for someone, it is part of a person's typical work. <vi>Solving violent crimes is <it>all in a day's work</it> for these police detectives.</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>take a/the day off</phrase> is to decide not to work on a particular day. <vi>He <it>took the day off</it> to go fishing.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the day on which something specified happens or is expected to happen <vi>It rained on their wedding <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>day</it> of his birth</vi> <vi>This Sunday is <phrase>family day</phrase> [=a day for families especially with young children] at the amusement park.</vi> <vi>If you've been waiting for the perfect skiing conditions, <phrase>today's the day</phrase>. [=the conditions are perfect today]</vi> <vi>So, when's <phrase>the big day</phrase>? When are you getting married?</vi> <vi>Did you ever think you'd <phrase>see the day</phrase> when he would apologize? [=did you believe he would ever apologize?]</vi> <vi>I never thought I would <phrase>live to see the day</phrase> when you would graduate from college. [=I did not think I would live long enough to see you graduate]</vi> <vi>Let her have her <phrase>day in court</phrase> [=let her defend herself in a court of law] before you pass judgment on her.</vi> <vi>This is <phrase>your lucky day</phrase>. [=a day when something good happens to you]</vi> <snote>If a day <phrase>is your day</phrase>, something good will happen to you on that day. <vi>You never know. Maybe today will <it>be my day</it>. [=maybe I will succeed, win, etc., today]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry you lost. I guess it just <it>wasn't your day</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>People sometimes use the phrase <phrase>that'll be the day</phrase> to say that they think something will not happen. <vi>“Do you think he'll ever admit he made a mistake?” “<it>That'll be the day</it>!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular period of time <vi>She was the most talented actress of her <it>day</it>. [=during the time when she lived and worked as an actress]</vi> <vi><phrase>In my day</phrase> [=when I was young], boys asked girls out on dates, not the other way around.</vi> <vi>Life was simpler <it>in my grandmother's day</it>, but it wasn't easier.</vi> <vi>We sell books dating from 1875 to <phrase>the present day</phrase>. [=<it>today</it>]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He often spoke about his <it>days</it> as a soldier.</vi> <vi>I was quite an athlete in my younger <it>days</it>. [=when I was young]</vi> <vi>The practice dates back to the <it>days</it> of ancient Rome.</vi> <vi>the olden <it>days</it></vi> <vi>my college <it>days</it> [=when I was in college]</vi> <vi>the <it>days</it> of stagecoaches [=when stagecoaches were used]</vi> <vi>In those <it>days</it> many factory workers were children.</vi></un> <snote>The saying <phrase>those were the days</phrase> is sometimes used to say that a period of time in the past was pleasant and often better than the present time. <vi>When I was a kid, we spent our summers at the beach. <it>Those were the days</it>!</vi> <vi>In the 1960s, everything seemed possible. Those were <phrase>the good old days</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) the livelong day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>livelong</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any day now</dre> <def><dt>:within the next few days :<sx>soon</sx> <vi>We're expecting a phone call from him <it>any day now</it>. [=in the near future]</vi> <vi><it>Any day now</it>, the decision could be made.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the end of the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call it a day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>call</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry/win the day</dre> <def><dt>:to win or be successful <vi>The “no” vote <it>carried the day</it>. [=<it>prevailed</it>]</vi> <vi>We believe that truth and justice will <it>carry/win the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day after day</dre> <def><dt>:for several days without stopping or changing <vi>She wore the same pants <it>day after day</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Day after day</it>, we hear the same complaints from our customers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day and night</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>night and day</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:all the time :without stopping <vi>We've been working on it <it>day and night</it>. = We've been working on it <it>night and day</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:complete or total <vi>The difference between them is <it>day and night</it>. = The difference between them is <it>night and day</it>. [=they are completely different]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day by day</dre> <def><dt>:in small amounts every day <vi><it>Day by day</it>, the situation is becoming more complex.</vi> <vi>She felt herself growing stronger <it>day by day</it>. [=every day]</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>take it/things day by day</phrase>, you make progress in a slow and careful way by dealing with each day as it comes. <vi>He hopes to make a full recovery after his surgery, but right now he's just <it>taking it day by day</it>. [=<it>taking it one day at a time</it>, <it>taking each day as it comes</it>]</vi> <vi>I don't know if our relationship is going to work out. I'm <it>taking things day by day</it> at this point.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day in, day out</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>day in and day out</va></vr> <def><dt>:every day for many days :for a long time without stopping or changing <vi>She does the same thing at her job <it>day in</it>, <it>day out</it>.</vi> <vi>It can be difficult to spend all of your time with one person <it>day in and day out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>days are numbered</dre> <dx>see <dxt>number</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>early days (yet)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>early</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every dog has its day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for a rainy day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rainy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from day to day</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>His opinions seem to change <it>from day to day</it>. [=<it>from one day to the next</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>day-to-day</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from one day to the next</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>She changes her mind <it>from one day to the next</it>. [=<it>from day to day</it>]</vi> :as one day becomes another day <vi>You never know <it>from one day to the next</it> what's going to happen to you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the time of day</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to pay attention to someone <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>No one would <it>give us the time of day</it>.</vi> <vi>I needed their help, but they wouldn't <it>give me the time of day</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>glory days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>glory</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have seen/known better days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in all your born days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the cold light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in this day and age</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time in history <vi>Computers are essential to getting work done <it>in this day and age</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>It's unbelievable that <it>in this day and age</it> people are still dying from hunger.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>it is not every day</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something happens very rarely <vi><it>It's not every day</it> that I get to meet the President.</vi> <vi>Go ahead and spend the extra money. <it>It's not every day</it> that you get married.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>late in the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>late</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's day</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's day to be pleasant or happy <vi>Thanks for the compliment. You've really <it>made my day</it>!</vi> <vi>It <it>made my day</it> to see his smiling face.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of the day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:served in a restaurant as a special item on a particular day <vi>What's the fish/vegetable <it>of the day</it>?</vi> <vi>Our soup <it>of the day</it> [=<it>du jour</it>] is vegetable beef.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:of a particular period of time <vi>What were some of the popular movies <it>of the day</it>? [=that were popular during that time]</vi> <vi>the important issues <it>of the day</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at some time in the future <vi><it>One day</it>, it'll happen. You'll see.</vi> <vi>People may <it>one day</it> [=<it>someday</it>] be able to take vacations to the moon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:on a day in the past <vi>I went to her house <it>one day</it> and had lunch with her.</vi> <vi><it>One day</it>, we had a terrible argument.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the day</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:on the day that an event happens <vi>I know we seem a bit disorganized now, but we'll be all right <it>on the day</it>.</vi> <vi>Whether we win or not depends on which players are healthy <it>on the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>some day</dre> <def><dt>:at some time in the future :<sx>someday</sx> <vi><it>Some day</it> I may be rich enough to own two houses.</vi> <vi>I'd like to return there <it>some day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take each day as it comes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take one day at a time</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>take it/things one day at a time</va></vr> <def><dt>:to deal with each day's problems as they come instead of worrying about the future <vi>There's no way to know what the future will bring, so just <it>take each day as it comes</it> and hope for the best.</vi> <vi><it>Take one day at a time</it> and don't expect things to change overnight.</vi> <vi>It's important to <it>take things one day at a time</it> so you don't feel too overwhelmed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the other day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>other</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>these days</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time <vi>It seems that everyone has a cell phone <it>these days</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>What kind of music are you listening to <it>these days</it>?</vi> <vi><it>These days</it>, she has a very busy social life.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>one of these days</phrase> means at some time in the future. <vi><it>One of these days</it>, [=<it>one day</it>] I'm going to buy myself a boat.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>those days</dre> <def><dt>:a period of time in the past <vi>Remember when we were kids and life was easy? Well, <it>those days</it> are gone.</vi> <vi><phrase>In those days</phrase>, women weren't allowed to own property.</vi> <vi>No one knew <it>in those days</it> what caused the disease.</vi> <snote>If it is (<phrase>just) one of those days</phrase>, it is a day in which many bad or unpleasant things happen. <vi>It's <it>just one of those days</it> when everything seems to go wrong.</vi> <vi>I missed the bus and sprained my ankle; it was <it>one of those days</it> when nothing was going right.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the day</dre> <def><dt>:to exactly a specified number of years <vi>It's been 100 years <it>to the day</it> since their great discovery.</vi> <vi>Soon after their wedding, almost a year <it>to the day</it>, they got divorced.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to this day</dre> <def><dt>:up to now :continuing until today <vi><it>To this day</it>, I still don't know what happened.</vi> <vi>The belief persists <it>to this day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="minute[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">min*ute</hw> <sound><wav>minute01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmɪnət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>min*utes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a unit of time equal to 60 seconds :one 60th of an hour <vi>Bake the cake for 25–30 <it>minutes</it>.</vi> <vi>We waited for several <it>minutes</it>, but no one came to the door.</vi> <vi>He can run a six-<it>minute</it> mile. [=he can run a mile in six minutes]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a brief period of time :<sx>moment</sx> <vi>I saw him a <it>minute</it> ago.</vi> <vi>Dinner will be ready in just a few <it>minutes</it>.</vi> <vi>One <it>minute</it> it was sunny, the next it was pouring rain.</vi> <vi>Could I have a <it>minute</it> of your time? = Do you have a <it>minute</it>? = Could I speak to you for a <it>minute</it>? [=could I speak to you briefly?]</vi> <vi>I'm coming, just give me a <it>minute</it>. [=wait for me]</vi> <vi>It was an excellent show. I enjoyed every <it>minute</it> of it. [=I enjoyed all of it]</vi> <vi>I'll explain that <phrase>in a minute</phrase>. [=shortly, soon]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>last minute</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the distance that can be traveled in a minute <vi>My house is just a few <it>minutes</it> from here.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>minutes</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:an official record of what was said and done in a meeting <vi>The secretary read the <it>minutes</it> of the last meeting.</vi> <vi>The secretary took the <it>minutes</it> [=recorded in writing what happened] during the meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:one of 60 equal parts into which a degree can be divided for measuring angles <vi>42 degrees and 30 <it>minutes</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a laugh a minute</dre> <dx>see <dxt>laugh</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any minute</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something could happen (<phrase>at</phrase>) <phrase>any minute</phrase> (<phrase>now</phrase>), it could happen very soon. <vi>The bus should be here <it>any minute now</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm expecting a phone call <it>any minute</it>.</vi> <vi>Things could change <it>at any minute</it>. [=<it>at any moment</it>]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at/on a minute's notice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>notice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from minute to minute</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>from one minute to the next</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>minute by minute</va></vr> <def><dt>:very quickly as time passes <vi>Things kept changing <it>from minute to minute</it>. [=<it>from moment to moment</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold/hang on a minute</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>wait/just a minute</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to tell someone to wait or to stop for a brief time <vi>“Aren't you finished yet?” “<it>Hold on a minute</it>. I'm almost done.”</vi> <vi><it>Hang on a minute</it>—I didn't hear you. Could you repeat what you said?</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to express surprise or disbelief <vi>Hey, <it>wait a minute</it>! That's not what you said yesterday!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just this minute</dre> <dx>see <dxt>just</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not for a/one minute</dre> <def><dt>:at no time :not at all :<sx>never</sx> <vi>I did <it>not</it> believe her <it>for one minute</it>. = <it>Not for one minute</it> did I believe her. [=I never believed her]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the minute</dre> <def><dt>:as soon as <vi>Please call me <it>the minute</it> you get home.</vi> <vi>I knew <it>the minute</it> (that) I saw it that I had to have this dress.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>this minute</dre> <def><dt>:right now :<sx>immediately</sx> <vi>Stop it <it>this minute</it>!</vi> <vi>I have to have the report <it>this minute</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the minute</dre> <def><dt>:exactly or precisely <vi>The buses were on time <it>to the minute</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>up-to-the-minute</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>within minutes</dre> <def><dt>:within a very short amount of time <vi>We called an ambulance and it arrived <it>within minutes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="moment"> <hw highlight="yes">mo*ment</hw> <sound><wav>moment01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmoʊmənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>mo*ments</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a very short period of time <vi>The sunshine that was here a <it>moment</it> [=<it>minute, second</it>] ago is gone.</vi> <vi>The sun was shining. <it>Moments</it> later, it began to rain.</vi> <vi>It was a <it>moment</it> before she realized what had happened.</vi> <vi>She stopped for a <it>moment</it> and peeked into the window.</vi> <vi>It should only take a <it>moment</it> to fix the problem.</vi> <vi>Do you have a (spare) <it>moment</it>? [=do you have some free time so we can talk to each other briefly?]</vi> <vi>I'm very busy and I don't have a <it>moment</it> to spare.</vi> <vi>The doctor arrived <phrase>not a moment too soon</phrase>. [=the doctor arrived just in time to help]</vi> <vi>I'll explain that <phrase>in a moment</phrase>. [=shortly, soon]</vi> <vi>The crowd observed a <phrase>moment of silence</phrase> [=a short period of silent thought or prayer] for those who died in the tragedy.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular time :a precise point in time <vi>One <it>moment</it> it was sunny; the next it was pouring rain.</vi> <vi>We enjoyed every <it>moment</it> of the play. [=we enjoyed all of the play]</vi> <vi>The <it>moment</it> for us to act has arrived.</vi> <vi>The <it>moment</it> is ripe for action. [=this is the right time for action]</vi> <vi>War seemed unavoidable at that <it>moment</it> in history.</vi> <vi>She knew exactly the right <it>moment</it> to ask for a raise.</vi> <vi>We had an exciting vacation. There was <phrase>never a dull moment</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the present time <vi><phrase>At the moment</phrase> [=<it>right now, at the current time</it>] she is working on a novel.</vi> <vi>We aren't prepared <phrase>at this moment</phrase> [=<it>at this time</it>, <it>now</it>] to say what our plans are.</vi> <vi><phrase>As of this moment</phrase> [=<it>as of now, right now</it>], there's nothing you can do.</vi> <snote>Something that is true <phrase>for the moment</phrase> is true now but might not be true for long. <vi><it>For the moment</it>, it is the world's largest city. [=it is the world's largest city now, but that may not be true much longer]</vi> <vi>He's staying out of trouble <it>for the moment</it>.</vi> <vi><it>For the moment</it>, at least, I had the room to myself.</vi></snote> <snote>Someone or something that is <phrase>of the moment</phrase> is very popular at a particular time. <vi>the vacation destination <it>of the moment</it> [=the vacation destination that is now most popular]</vi> <vi>the man/woman <it>of the moment</it> [=the man/woman who is now very popular and admired]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a time of importance or success <vi>She took the time to relish her <it>moment</it> of triumph.</vi> <vi>He's not the best player on the team, but he <phrase>has his moments</phrase>. [=he has times when he is extremely good, successful, etc.]</vi> <vi>It was a <phrase>defining moment</phrase> for him.</vi> <vi>It was a <phrase>crowning moment</phrase> in his presidency.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>any moment</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something could happen <phrase>(at) any moment (now)</phrase>, it could happen very soon. <vi>He could lose his temper <it>at any moment</it>.</vi> <vi>The war could begin <it>at any moment</it>.</vi> <vi>She should be arriving <it>at any moment now</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at/on a moment's notice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>notice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from moment to moment</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>from one moment to the next</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>moment by moment</va></vr> <def><dt>:very quickly as time passes <vi>The weather kept changing <it>from one moment to the next</it>. = The weather kept changing <it>from moment to moment</it>. [=<it>from minute to minute</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold/hang on a moment</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>wait/just a moment</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to tell someone to wait or to stop for a brief time <vi>“Aren't you finished yet?” “<it>Hold on a moment</it>. I'm almost done.”</vi> <vi><it>Hang on a moment</it>—I don't understand.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>moment of truth</dre> <def><dt>:the time when you have to do or decide something <vi>The <it>moment of truth</it> came early, when we had to decide whether to stay or go.</vi> <vi>It was her <it>moment of truth</it>, when she needed to show that she had the talent to succeed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not for a/one moment</dre> <def><dt>:at no time :not at all <vi>I did <it>not</it> believe her <it>for one moment</it>. [=I never believed her]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of moment</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:having importance <vi>an event <it>of</it> great <it>moment</it> [=a very important event]</vi> <vi>There is no news <it>of</it> any <it>moment</it> to report.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the spur of the moment</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spur</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the last moment</dre> <def><dt>:the latest possible time :the last minute <vi>Our flight was canceled at <it>the last moment</it>.</vi> <vi>She finished her paper at <it>the last moment</it>.</vi> <vi>Many people wait until <it>the last</it> (possible) <it>moment</it> before shopping for Christmas presents.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the moment</dre> <def><dt>:as soon as <vi><it>The moment</it> the cameras are turned off, he is able to relax.</vi> <vi>Everything stops <it>the moment</it> she walks in the room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>within moments</dre> <def><dt>:very quickly :within a very short amount of time <vi><it>Within moments</it>, dozens of people had gathered.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="old[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">old</hw> <sound><wav>old00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈoʊld</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>old*er</if></in> <in><if>old*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:having lived for many years :not young <vi>He's an <it>old</it> man now.</vi> <vi>a little <it>old</it> lady</vi> <vi>She was helping an <it>old</it> [=(more politely) <it>elderly</it>] woman cross the street.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about or ask about a person's age <vi>He looks <it>old</it> for his age. [=he looks older than he really is]</vi> <vi>She's <it>older</it> than she looks. [=she has a young appearance]</vi> <vi>He's dating an <it>older</it> woman. [=a woman who is older than he is]</vi> <vi>I wasn't <it>old</it> enough [=I was too young] to vote in the last election.</vi> <vi>“How <it>old</it> is your daughter?” “She's almost six.”</vi> <vi>Their <it>oldest</it> [=<it>eldest</it>] child is 18 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>My sister's three years <it>older</it> than me.</vi> <vi>She lived to the <phrase>ripe old age</phrase> of 85.</vi> <vi>He joked that he was <phrase>as old as the hills</phrase>. [=very old]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a specified age <vi>He's 30 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>a nine-month-<it>old</it> baby</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:having existed or been in use for a long time :not new <vi>We rented an <it>old</it> black-and-white movie.</vi> <vi><it>old</it> newspapers/magazines</vi> <vi>a beautiful <it>old</it> house</vi> <vi>There's an <it>old</it> saying that good fences make good neighbors.</vi> <vi>an <it>old</it> family tradition</vi> <vi>a new approach to an <it>old</it> problem</vi> <vi>She wore a T-shirt and an <it>old</it> pair of jeans.</vi> <vi>I wish you would stop wearing that dirty <it>old</it> hat!</vi> <vi>The hotel was <it>old</it> and dingy.</vi> <vi>the <it>oldest</it> known civilization in the region</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having existed for a specified amount of time <vi>The house we live in is 50 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>a 400-year-<it>old</it> castle</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:belonging to, used by, or known by someone in the past <vi>We went back to visit our <it>old</it> neighborhood.</vi> <vi>I met one of my <it>old</it> [=<it>former</it>] professors at the library.</vi> <vi>one of his <it>old</it> cars</vi> <vi>I made a lot less money at my <it>old</it> job.</vi> <vi>That's their <it>old</it> number. The new number is 555-4397.</vi> <vi>She is now just a shadow of her <it>old</it> self. [=she is not the person she was in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has been your friend, enemy, etc., for a long time <vi>I had lunch with an <it>old</it> friend of mine. [=a friend I have known for a very long time]</vi> <vi>They're <it>old</it> enemies.</vi> <vi>Spaghetti is an <it>old</it> favorite in our home.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:done or experienced many times <vi>Do we have to go through that <it>old</it> routine again?</vi> <vi>Grandpa tells the <phrase>same old</phrase> stories over and over again.</vi> <vi>When she brought up the <it>same old</it> argument, I just stopped listening.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used for emphasis after adjectives like <it>big, good</it>, etc. <vi>We had a big <it>old</it> party in her honor.</vi> <vi>You poor <it>old</it> thing. You must be exhausted!</vi> <vi><phrase>Good old</phrase> Joe. He's always helping people in need.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe someone or something that is not special or specific <vi>I don't care where I sleep. <it>Any old</it> couch will do.</vi> <vi>She won't drink <it>any old</it> tea; it has to be her favorite kind.</vi> <vi>You'll have to park <it>any old</it> way [=any way] you can.</vi> <vi>Give me beer over champagne <phrase>any old day</phrase> (of the week).</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chip off the old block</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for old times' sake</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>old boy/chap/man/etc.</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to address a man <vi>Don't worry, <it>old chap</it>, it'll be all right.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>old boy</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>good old boy</dxt></dxnl> <syns><sc>old</sc>, <sc>ancient</sc>, <sc>antique</sc>, and <sc>archaic</sc> describe things that existed or were used in the past. <sc>old</sc> is the most common and general of these words and can refer to either the recent past or to the distant past. <vi>This is one of my <it>old</it> sweaters.</vi> <vi>The neighborhood has many <it>old</it> houses that were built more than 200 years ago.</vi> <sc>ancient</sc> refers to things that happened or existed in the very distant past and that may or may not exist today. <vi>an <it>ancient</it> custom</vi> <vi>the <it>ancient</it> pyramids of Egypt</vi> <sc>antique</sc> refers to things, such as toys, machines, and pieces of furniture, that have been kept from the past and that are often valuable. <vi>She collects <it>antique</it> furniture.</vi> <sc>archaic</sc> refers to things, such as words or ways of behaving, that belong to a much earlier time and that are no longer used. <vi>The play used <it>archaic</it> language to convey a sense of the past.</vi> <vi>an <it>archaic</it> tradition</vi></syns></entry>

	<entry id="port[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">port</hw> <sound><wav>port0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpoɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ports</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a town or city where ships stop to load and unload cargo <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Boston is a major U.S. <it>port</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The ship is now in <it>port</it> but will be leaving <it>port</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a place where ships can find shelter from a storm <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The ship reached the <it>port</it> safely.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The ship spent two days in <it>port</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>any port in a storm</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that you will use anyone or anything for comfort, help, etc., when you are in a bad situation <vi>“I know she's lonely, but I can't believe she's going out with that guy.” “Well, you know what they say: <it>any port in a storm</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>port</dxt> <dxt>port</dxt> <dxt>port</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="slice[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">slice</hw> <altpr>ˈslaɪs</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>slices</if></in> <in><if>sliced</if></in> <in><if>slic*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to cut something with a sharp object (such as a knife) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>sliced</it> the lemon in half.</vi> <vi>He <it>sliced</it> the board in two. [=he cut the board into two pieces]</vi> <vi>He <it>sliced</it> open his finger while cleaning the fish.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The knife <it>sliced</it> through the cake easily.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>His jokes <it>sliced</it> [=<it>cut</it>] through the tension in a room.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cut (something) into pieces or slices <vi>She <it>sliced</it> the bread/tomato/pie.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>He <it>sliced up</it> a banana.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) smaller by removing part of it <vi>The university <it>sliced</it> [=<it>cut</it>] the research budget in half.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to hit or kick (a ball or shot) in a way that causes it to curve :to hit a slice <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>(<it>golf</it>) She <it>sliced</it> her drive into the rough.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>(<it>golf</it>) The ball <it>sliced</it> into the rough.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to move quickly and easily through something (such as air or water) <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>through</it> <vi>The ship's hull <it>sliced through</it> the waves.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The conductor <it>sliced</it> the air with his arms.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>any way you slice it</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>no matter how you slice it</va></vr> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that the truth of a statement is not changed or affected by the way you describe or think about a situation <vi>Losing is disappointing <it>no matter how you slice it</it>. [=losing is always disappointing]</vi> <vi><it>Any way you slice it</it>, online commerce is here to stay.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>slice and dice</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:to divide something into many small parts especially so you can use the result for your own purposes <vi>You can <it>slice and dice</it> the data any way you want.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>slice off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>slice off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>slice (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) by cutting :to cut off (something) with a sharp object (such as a knife) <vi><it>Slice off</it> the excess fat after you cook the steak.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The salesperson <it>sliced</it> 10 percent <it>off</it> of the cost of the car.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the best/greatest thing since sliced bread</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe something or someone that you think is very good, useful, etc. <vi>He thinks wireless Internet access is <it>the greatest thing since sliced bread</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>sliced</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>thinly <it>sliced</it> beef</vi> <vi><it>sliced</it> bread</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>slic*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>slic*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a bread <it>slicer</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="storm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">storm</hw> <sound><wav>storm001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈstoɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>storms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an occurrence of bad weather in which there is a lot of rain, snow, etc., and often strong winds <vi>The sky got dark and it looked like a <it>storm</it> was coming.</vi> <vi>A <phrase>storm was brewing</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We made it home before the <phrase>storm struck/broke</phrase>. [=before the <it>storm</it> began]</vi> <vi>I went out for a walk and got <phrase>caught in a storm</phrase>. [=I was outside when the storm began]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dust storm</dxt> <dxt>electrical storm</dxt> <dxt>electric storm</dxt> <dxt>firestorm</dxt> <dxt>hailstorm</dxt> <dxt>ice storm</dxt> <dxt>rainstorm</dxt> <dxt>sandstorm</dxt> <dxt>snowstorm</dxt> <dxt>thunderstorm</dxt> <dxt>tropical storm</dxt> <dxt>windstorm</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a sudden occurrence of something in large amounts <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> publicity</vi> <vi>The speaker was greeted with a <it>storm of</it> applause.</vi> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> punches</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>brainstorm</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a situation in which many people are angry, upset, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>His racial comments <phrase>kicked/whipped/stirred up a storm</phrase> in the newspapers. [=newspapers criticized his racial comments very strongly]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>storm of</it> controversy/protest</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>any port in a storm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>port</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a storm in a teacup</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a situation in which people are very angry or upset about something that is not important <vi>The whole controversy turned out to be <it>a storm in a teacup</it>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>a tempest in a teapot</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take (something) by storm</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to quickly become very successful or popular in (a particular place) or among (a particular group) <vi>The writer has <it>taken</it> the literary world <it>by storm</it>.</vi> <vi>The new fashion has <it>taken</it> London <it>by storm</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to attack and capture (a place) suddenly by using a lot of force or a large number of people <vi>The soldiers <it>took</it> the castle <it>by storm</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the calm/lull before the storm</dre> <def><dt>:a period of quiet that comes before a time of activity, excitement, violence, etc. <vi>The college was quiet that morning, but it was <it>the calm before the storm</it>. Thousands of students would arrive later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up a storm</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is being done with a lot of energy or enthusiasm <vi>They danced/sang <it>up a storm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was cooking <it>up a storm</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>weather the storm</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>ride out the storm</va></vr> <def><dt>:to deal with a difficult situation without being harmed or damaged too much <vi>Newspapers have <it>weathered the storm</it> of online information by providing news online themselves.</vi> <vi>It was a difficult time but they managed to <it>ride out the storm</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
