<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="appear"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*pear</hw> <sound><wav>appear01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpiɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ap*pears</if></in> <in><if>ap*peared</if></in> <in><if>ap*pear*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to seem to be something :to make someone think that a person or thing has a particular characteristic :<sx>look</sx> <sx>seem</sx> <vi>She <it>appears</it> angry.</vi> <vi>“Is she angry?” “So it <it>appears</it>.” = “So it would <it>appear</it>.” = “It <it>appears</it> so.”</vi> <vi>“Is she pleased?” “It <it>appears</it> not.” = “It would <it>appear</it> not.”</vi> <vi>She <it>appears</it> a nice enough person.</vi> <vi>Although everything <it>appeared</it> normal to me [=although I thought everything was normal], something was wrong.</vi> <vi>Winning the election <it>appears</it> unlikely at this point.</vi> <vi>Things are not always as they <it>appear</it>. [=they are not always what you think they are]</vi> <vi>It <it>appears</it> to us [=we think] that something should be done.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She <it>appeared to be</it> angry.</vi> <vi>She <it>appears to be</it> a nice enough person.</vi> <vi>Everyone <it>appeared to have</it> a good time. = They all <it>appeared to enjoy</it> themselves.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to become visible :to begin to be seen <vi>One by one, the stars <it>appeared</it> in the sky.</vi> <vi>The sun began to <it>appear</it> from behind the clouds.</vi> <vi>The airplanes seemed to <it>appear</it> out of nowhere.</vi> <vi>Her grandfather often <it>appears</it> to her in her dreams. [=she often sees her grandfather in her dreams]</vi> <vi>The storm disappeared as suddenly as it had <it>appeared</it>.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disappear</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at a place :to show up <vi>The cat <it>appears</it> at our kitchen door every morning.</vi> <vi>One of the guests <it>appeared</it> a few minutes late.</vi> <vi>He <it>appeared</it> a little before eight last night.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disappear</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to exist <vi>The disease first <it>appeared</it> in the late 1970s.</vi> <vi>This new technology first <it>appears</it> in Europe in the early 20th century.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disappear</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be seen or heard by the public: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to go where you can be seen to give a speech, answer questions, etc. <un>often + <it>before</it> <vi>I was invited to <it>appear before</it> a meeting of teachers to talk about the school system.</vi> <vi><it>appearing before</it> a group of reporters</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to work as an actor or performer in a movie, on the radio, etc. <vi>The two actors <it>appeared</it> [=<it>performed</it>] together in the film.</vi> <vi>He has <it>appeared</it> on many radio and television shows.</vi> <vi>She <it>appeared</it> in her first Broadway musical last year.</vi> <vi>Several guest musicians <it>appeared</it> on his latest album.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to be published or made available to the public <vi>The story <it>appeared</it> on the front page of the newspaper.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>We got a lot of phone calls after the story <it>appeared in</it> the newspaper.</vi> <vi>Her papers have <it>appeared in</it> several different scientific journals.</vi> <vi>The book <phrase>appeared in print</phrase> [=was published] again a few years ago.</vi> <vi>The word first <it>appeared in print</it> in 1782.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go in front of a person or group that has authority (such as a judge or council) especially in order to answer questions <vi>I <it>appeared</it> in front of the committee during its last meeting.</vi> <vi>She was instructed to <it>appear</it> in court the next morning.</vi> <vi>She <it>appeared</it> before the judge.</vi> <vi>He will be <it>appearing</it> as a witness at the trial.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
