<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="appeal[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ap*peal</hw> <sound><wav>appeal01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpi:l</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*peals</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a quality that causes people to like someone or something <vi>I can't understand the <it>appeal</it> of skydiving. [=I can't understand why some people like it]</vi> <vi>Music never held much <it>appeal</it> [=<it>attraction</it>] for him.</vi> <vi>Her jokes are quickly losing their <it>appeal</it>.</vi> <vi>The movie has great <it>appeal</it> to/for adults as well as children. [=adults and children like the movie]</vi> <vi>the wide/broad/mass/universal <it>appeal</it> of the artist's work</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sex appeal</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a serious request for help, support, etc. <vi>They made a desperate <it>appeal</it> [=<it>plea</it>, <it>entreaty</it>] for help.</vi> <vi>His <it>appeals</it> to his father for money were ignored.</vi> <vi>The mayor made an <it>appeal</it> to the people of the city to stay calm.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an attempt to make someone do or accept something as right or proper by saying things that are directed at a person's feelings, attitudes, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>The author makes an <it>appeal to</it> the reader's emotions.</vi> <vi>an <it>appeal to</it> reason</vi> <vi>an <it>appeal to</it> the intellect</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:an organized effort to raise money <vi>We made a donation during the school's annual <it>appeal</it>.</vi> <vi>She helped to organize/launch an <it>appeal</it> on behalf of the homeless.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a process in which a decision is studied and accepted or rejected by a higher court or by someone in authority <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>My lawyer said the court's decision wasn't correct and that we should file for an <it>appeal</it>.</vi> <vi>lodge an <it>appeal</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Her conviction was thrown out <phrase>on appeal</phrase>. [=a higher court decided that she should not have been convicted]</vi> <vi>The case is currently <phrase>under appeal</phrase>. [=the case is currently being reviewed by a higher court]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>court of appeals</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="appeal[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">appeal</hw> <altpr>əˈpi:l</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>appeals</if></in> <in><if>appealed</if></in> <in><if>appeal*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be liked by someone :to be pleasing or attractive <it>to</it> someone <vi>The movie <it>appeals to</it> adults as well as (<it>to</it>) children. [=adults and children like the movie]</vi> <vi>music that <it>appeals to</it> a wide variety of people</vi> <vi>The idea of going to college <it>appealed to</it> him greatly. [=the idea was very appealing to him]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to ask for something (such as help or support) in a serious way <vi>The government <it>appealed</it> for calm.</vi> <vi>desperate people who are <it>appealing</it> for help</vi> <vi>The government <it>appealed</it> to the people to stay calm.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to make someone do or accept something as right or proper by saying things that are directed at a person's feelings, attitudes, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>We got them to join by <it>appealing to</it> their sense of duty and honor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make a formal request for a higher court or for someone in authority to review and change a decision <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>appealed</it>, arguing that there was not enough evidence to convict him.</vi> <vi>She lost the case and <it>appealed</it> the following month.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) We plan to <phrase>appeal against</phrase> the court's decision.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> (<it>US</it>) <vi>We plan to <it>appeal</it> the court's decision.</vi> <vi>The ruling can be <it>appealed</it> within 30 days.</vi> <vi>(<it>baseball</it>) The runner was called out at home plate but the manager <it>appealed</it> the umpire's decision.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="sex appeal"> <hw>sex appeal</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the quality of being sexually attractive <vi>an actor with a lot of <it>sex appeal</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="snob appeal"> <hw>snob appeal</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:a quality that makes something attractive to people who are snobs <vi>Expensive cars have <it>snob appeal</it>.</vi> <vi>old foreign films with <it>snob appeal</it></vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>snob value</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="appeals court"> <hw>appeals court</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>appeal court</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ courts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>law</sl> <dt>:<sx>court of appeals <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="court of appeals"> <hw>court of appeals</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>court of appeal</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>courts of appeals</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>law</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a court that studies the decisions made by a lower court and decides if they were correct <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>appeals court</cat> (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>appeal court</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>Court of Appeals</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:any one of 13 courts in the U.S. below the Supreme Court <vi>the 9th/Ninth Circuit <it>Court of Appeals</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>Court of Appeal</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the highest court in Britain below the House of Lords</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
