<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="appearance"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*pear*ance</hw> <sound><wav>appear02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈpirəns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*pear*anc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:the way that someone or something looks <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The room has a neat/fresh/clean <it>appearance</it>. [=<it>look</it>]</vi> <vi>The general <it>appearance</it> of the house is quite good.</vi> <vi>The museum restored the painting to its original <it>appearance</it>.</vi> <vi>lotions that improve your skin's <it>appearance</it> and texture</vi> <vi>It minimizes the <it>appearance</it> of wrinkles. [=it makes wrinkles more difficult to see]</vi> <vi>You shouldn't judge a man by his <it>appearance</it>.</vi> <vi>Have you noticed any changes in her <it>appearance</it>?</vi> <vi>He's very proud of his <phrase>physical appearance</phrase>. [=the way he looks]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He is still very youthful <phrase>in appearance</phrase>. [=he still looks very young]</vi> <vi>They are very similar <it>in appearance</it>. [=they look the same]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of looking that is not true or real <vi>He appears to be happy, but <it>appearances</it> can be deceptive/deceiving.</vi> <vi>Their expensive home created a false <it>appearance</it> of success and happiness.</vi> <vi>The furniture <phrase>has the appearance</phrase> of being made by hand. [=the furniture was not made by hand but it looks/appears as if it was]</vi> <vi><phrase>Despite appearances</phrase>, her company is very successful. = <phrase>Appearances to the contrary</phrase>, her company is very successful. [=her company is very successful even though it does not appear to be]</vi> <vi>She is only attending the banquet <phrase>for the sake of appearances</phrase>. [=because people think that she should attend]</vi> <vi>He was, <phrase>to/by all (outward) appearances</phrase>, a happily married man. [=he seemed to be a happily married man, but he wasn't]</vi> <vi>Their meetings tend to <phrase>take on the appearance of</phrase> [=to look like] family gatherings.</vi> <vi>His white beard <phrase>gave him the appearance of</phrase> an old man. [=made him look like an old man]</vi> <vi>The playground <phrase>gives every appearance of</phrase> being a safe place for children [=the playground appears to be a safe place for children], but a tragic accident occurred there recently.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the action of appearing :the fact that something or someone arrives or begins to be seen <un>usually singular <vi>The <it>appearance</it> of buds on the trees tells us that spring has arrived.</vi> <vi>We were surprised by the <it>appearance</it> of smoke in the distance.</vi> <vi>I wasn't expecting him to come and was surprised by his sudden <it>appearance</it>. [=I was surprised when he suddenly appeared/arrived]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the time when something begins to exist or is seen for the first time <un>usually singular <vi>The <it>appearance</it> [=<it>creation</it>] of the Internet has changed our culture in many ways.</vi> <vi>The technology made its first <it>appearance</it> [=appeared for the first time] in the early 1980s.</vi> <vi>Before the <it>appearance</it> of the telephone, people sent messages by telegraph.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an act of being seen or heard by the public as an actor, politician, athlete, etc. <vi>He has announced that this will be his final/last <it>appearance</it> with the band. [=the last time that he will perform in public with the band]</vi> <vi>This is her first <it>appearance</it> [=the first time that she has competed] at/in the national championships.</vi> <un>often used with <it>make</it> <vi>She is <it>making</it> her first <it>appearance</it> at/in the national championships.</vi> <vi>Tonight, he is <it>making</it> his first <phrase>public appearance</phrase> since winning the award.</vi> <vi>He'll be <it>making</it> a special <phrase>guest appearance</phrase> [=performing as a guest] on the popular television show next fall.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the formal act of going in front of a person or group to speak, answer questions, etc. <vi>One man has been convicted of the crime, and two others are awaiting <phrase>court appearances</phrase>. [=waiting to go to court]</vi> <un>often + <it>before</it> <vi>He is awaiting his <it>appearance before</it> a judge.</vi> <vi>She made an <it>appearance before</it> Congress last year.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>keep up appearances</dre> <def><dt>:to hide something bad by pretending that nothing is wrong <vi>Although they were getting a divorce, my parents thought it was important to <it>keep up appearances</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make an appearance</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>put in an appearance</va></vr> <def><dt>:to go to an event, gathering, etc., usually for a short period of time <vi>The candidate <it>made an appearance</it> at the rally.</vi> <vi>The governor <it>put in an appearance</it> at the party.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
