<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="apply"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*ply</hw> <sound><wav>apply001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈplaɪ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ap*plies</if></in> <in><if>ap*plied</if></in> <in><if>ap*ply*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to ask formally for something (such as a job, admission to a school, a loan, etc.) usually in writing <vi>For further information, <it>apply</it> to the address below.</vi> <vi>I <it>applied</it> in writing to several different companies.</vi> <vi>You must have a high school diploma for this job. High school dropouts <phrase>need not apply</phrase>.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>I <it>applied for</it> several jobs and was offered one.</vi> <vi>Anyone can <it>apply for</it> membership.</vi> <vi>We <it>applied</it> to the bank <it>for</it> a loan.</vi> <vi>To <it>apply for</it> our credit card, just fill out this form and send it to us.</vi> <vi>Many high school students have begun <phrase>applying for college</phrase>. [=asking to be accepted as students at colleges or universities by filling out and sending applications]</vi></un> <un>sometimes followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Anyone can <it>apply to become</it> a member.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put or spread (something) on a surface, a part of the body, etc. <vi>After <it>applying</it> a thin layer of paint to the wall and letting it dry, <it>apply</it> another coat.</vi> <vi>We <it>applied</it> the ointment to the cut.</vi> <vi>I washed my face and <it>applied</it> fresh makeup.</vi> <vi>Fertilizer was <it>applied</it> to the lawn every two weeks.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (force, pressure, etc.) to have an effect or to be felt <vi>He was able to stop the bleeding by <it>applying</it> pressure to the cut. [=by pressing on/against the cut]</vi> <vi>He knows how to <it>apply</it> [=<it>use, exert</it>] pressure to get what he wants.</vi> <vi>The police should have been able to deal with the situation without <it>applying</it> [=<it>using</it>] force.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use (an idea, method, law, etc.) in a particular situation <vi>Try to solve the math problems by <it>applying</it> the formulas/methods that we learned in class.</vi> <vi>They <it>applied</it> a new technique to solve an old problem.</vi> <vi>We can handle these problems effectively if we <it>apply</it> the lessons learned from past experiences.</vi> <vi>They <it>apply</it> what they learned in school to their everyday lives.</vi> <vi>The law has not been <it>applied</it> fairly. [=has not been used in a fair way]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (the brakes of a vehicle) to work <vi>Take your foot off the gas pedal and slowly <it>apply</it> the brakes.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have an effect on someone or something <vi>The rule no longer <it>applies</it>.</vi> <vi>The same principle <it>applies</it> [=can be used] when you are trying to lose weight.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The ban <it>applies</it> [=<it>relates, pertains</it>] <it>to</it> all guns that are not used for hunting.</vi> <vi>These rules <it>apply to</it> everyone in the school. [=everyone in the school must obey these rules]</vi> <vi>This <it>applies</it> equally <it>to</it> men and (<it>to</it>) women.</vi> <vi>The rule doesn't <it>apply to</it> you, so don't worry about it.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to use a word, name, etc., to describe someone or something <un>usually + <it>to</it></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The term “baby boomer” usually <it>applies to</it> people who were born immediately after World War II.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The author <it>applies</it> the name/label <it>to</it> corrupt politicians.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) applied</it> <vi>The term “baby boomer” <it>is</it> usually <it>applied to</it> people who were born immediately after World War II.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>apply yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to make yourself work hard in order to complete something successfully <vi>If you <it>apply yourself</it>, you might be able to finish the project on time.</vi> <vi>She <it>applied herself</it> to learning the language.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
