<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="application"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*pli*ca*tion</hw> <sound><wav>applic05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌæpləˈkeɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*pli*ca*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a formal and usually written request for something (such as a job, admission to a school, a loan, etc.) <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We've made an <it>application</it> for certification. [=we have applied to be certified]</vi> <vi>Our loan <it>application</it> has been approved/denied.</vi> <vi>Anyone interested in running for office must file/submit an <it>application</it> by August 1st.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>If you'd like to be considered for the job, please send us a <phrase>letter of application</phrase> that gives your experience and qualifications.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a document that is used to make a formal request for something <vi>Please fill out this <it>application</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of applying something: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of putting something on a surface, a part of the body, etc. <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The <it>application</it> of heat often helps sore muscles.</vi> <vi>I prefer using the lotion because of its ease of <it>application</it>. [=because it is easy to apply]</vi> <vi>Repeated <it>application</it> of fertilizer will help the grass become green and healthy.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Repeated <it>applications</it> of fertilizer will help the grass become green and healthy.</vi> <vi>The cut should be treated with a generous/liberal <it>application</it> of ointment.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the use of an idea, method, law, etc., in a particular situation or for a particular purpose <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Strict <it>application</it> of the rules is necessary in this case.</vi> <vi>the <it>application</it> of new information</vi> <vi>learning about the creative <it>application</it> [=<it>use</it>] of new technology</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He teaches his students about the practical <it>applications</it> [=<it>uses</it>] of technology.</vi> <vi>I think it is a fair <it>application</it> of the law.</vi> <vi><it>applications</it> of science to everyday life</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the use of a word, name, etc., to describe someone or something <vi>the <it>application</it> of the term “baby boomer” to people who were born right after World War II</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the ability to be used for practical purposes <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The technique has wide/limited <it>application</it>. [=it can/cannot be used for a large number of practical purposes]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The tool has a number of <it>applications</it>. = The tool has a wide range of <it>applications</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:a computer program that performs a particular task (such as word processing) <vi>How many <it>applications</it> is your computer currently running?</vi> <vi><it>applications</it> software</vi> <ca>called also (<it>chiefly US, informal</it>) <cat>app</cat></ca></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:effort made to work hard in order to complete something successfully <vi>She succeeded because of <it>application</it> and intelligence.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
