<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="area"> <hw highlight="yes">ar*ea</hw> <sound><wav>area0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈerijə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ar*eas</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a part or section within a larger place :<sx>region</sx> <vi>Settlers came to this <it>area</it> from the east.</vi> <vi>The group visited the <it>area</it> during a hunting trip.</vi> <vi>in the <it>area</it> surrounding the lake</vi> <vi>The storm caused damage in many <it>areas</it> along the coast.</vi> <vi>a bird found only in remote <it>areas</it> of the U.S.</vi> <vi>in many <it>areas</it> of the world</vi> <vi>He is the metropolitan <it>area's</it> most popular politician.</vi> <vi>urban and rural <it>areas</it></vi> <vi>He lived in an unfashionable <it>area</it> of the city.</vi> <vi>a residential <it>area</it></vi> <vi>One of our representatives will be in your <it>area</it> [=<it>neighborhood</it>] next week.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a section of space within a building, room, etc. <vi>She set aside a work <it>area</it> in the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The dining <it>area</it> has extra windows.</vi> <vi>We were asked to wait in the reception <it>area</it>.</vi> <vi>The park had several picnic <it>areas</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a part of the surface of something (such as a person's body or a piece of cloth) <vi>Choose a small <it>area</it> of the fabric to test first.</vi> <vi>The patient was having pain in the shoulder/abdominal <it>area</it>. = The patient was having pain in the <it>area</it> of the shoulder/abdomen.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a field of activity or study <vi>The discovery has opened up new <it>areas</it> of/for research.</vi> <vi>The budget continues to be a major <it>area</it> of concern.</vi> <vi>a problem <it>area</it></vi> <vi>the whole <it>area</it> of foreign policy</vi> <vi>She wants the government to provide more help in the <it>area</it> of health care.</vi> <vi>Your question falls outside my <it>area</it> of expertise.</vi> <vi>There are still some <it>areas</it> of disagreement between the two sides.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>gray area</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:the amount of space inside a shape, surface, region, room, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The students learned how to calculate the <it>area</it> of a triangle.</vi> <vi>a circle with an <it>area</it> of 500 square meters</vi> <vi>The park has an <it>area</it> of 2 square miles.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a circle that is 500 square meters in <it>area</it></vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) The nightclub provided enough <it>area</it> [=<it>room, space</it>] for a dance floor.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in the area of</dre> <def><dt>:close to (an amount) <vi>The project will cost (somewhere) <it>in the area of</it> $50,000.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="area code"> <hw>area code</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ codes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a number that represents each telephone service area in a country (such as the U.S. or Canada) <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>dialling code</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="catchment area"> <hw>catch*ment area</hw> <sound><wav>catch01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃmənt-, ˈkɛtʃmənt-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:the area from which water flows into a river, stream, etc.</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:the area that a school, hospital, etc., provides a service to</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="disaster area"> <hw>disaster area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an area where there has been a major disaster (such as a flood, tornado, or earthquake) and where people can receive special help from the government (such as money to rebuild homes or emergency supplies) <vi>After the hurricane, the state was declared a <it>disaster area</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a place that is very messy or dirty <vi>His office is a <it>disaster area</it>. How can he find anything in all this clutter?</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="gray area"> <hw>gray area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an area or situation in which it is difficult to judge what is right and what is wrong <vi>There are no <it>gray areas</it> in the rules.</vi> <vi>a legal <it>gray area</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="local area network"> <hw>local area network</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -works</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>computers</sl> <dt>:a network that allows the computers in a small area (such as an office) to share equipment (such as printers) and data <ca>called also <cat>LAN</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="no-go area"> <hw>no–go area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:an area that is dangerous or where people are not allowed to go <vi>He reported from one of the city's <it>no-go areas</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Religion is a <it>no-go area</it> when you talk with her.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="rest area"> <hw>rest area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -eas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:an area next to a highway where people can stop to rest, use the bathroom, get food, etc. <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>rest stop</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="service area"> <hw>service area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>rest area</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="staging area"> <hw>staging area</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ areas</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place where soldiers gather and military equipment is prepared before a mission</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
