<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="arrangement"> <hw highlight="yes">ar*range*ment</hw> <sound><wav>arrang03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈreɪnʤmənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ar*range*ments</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the way that things or people are organized for a particular purpose or activity :the way that things or people are arranged <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They changed the <it>arrangement</it> of furniture in the room.</vi> <vi>the dictionary's alphabetical <it>arrangement</it> [=<it>ordering</it>] of words</vi> <vi>the collection and <it>arrangement</it> of data</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a chronological <it>arrangement</it> of historical events</vi> <vi>We tried several different <it>arrangements</it> of the parts/components/elements.</vi> <vi>Having my brother and his wife living nearby was an ideal <it>arrangement</it> for our family.</vi> <vi>The family had very unusual living <it>arrangements</it>.</vi> <vi>“What were your sleeping <it>arrangements</it>?” “I slept on the bed while he slept on the floor.”</vi> <vi>We'll have to change the seating <it>arrangements</it> for the dinner party.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that is done to prepare or plan for something in the future <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually plural <vi>She has her secretary handle all of her travel <it>arrangements</it>.</vi> <vi>He helped his mother with his father's funeral <it>arrangements</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used with <it>make</it> <vi>The city <it>made</it> special <it>arrangements</it> [=<it>preparations</it>] for the Queen's visit.</vi> <vi>All of the <it>arrangements</it> have been <it>made</it> in advance.</vi> <vi>They <it>made arrangements</it> to meet each other at the restaurant.</vi> <vi>We provide breakfast and dinner, but you <it>make</it> your own <it>arrangements</it> for lunch.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Her job includes <it>arrangement</it> of her boss's travel plans.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a usually informal agreement <vi>There was an unusual political <it>arrangement</it> between the two countries.</vi> <vi>business/financial <it>arrangements</it></vi> <vi>I'm sure we can come to some <it>arrangement</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Our band has an <it>arrangement with</it> the club's manager.</vi> <vi>The company made an <it>arrangement with</it> the college to supply all of its computers.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something made by putting things together and organizing them <vi>a flower/floral <it>arrangement</it> = an <it>arrangement</it> of flowers</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>music</ssl> <dt>:a piece of music that has been changed so that it can be performed by particular types of voices or instruments <vi>orchestral/vocal <it>arrangements</it></vi> <vi>an <it>arrangement</it> for the guitar</vi> <vi>a rock <it>arrangement</it> of an old blues song</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
