<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="arrange"> <hw highlight="yes">ar*range</hw> <sound><wav>arrang01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈreɪnʤ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ar*rang*es</if></in> <in><if>ar*ranged</if></in> <in><if>ar*rang*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move and organize (things) into a particular order or position <vi>She <it>arranged</it> her pictures on her desk.</vi> <vi>He <it>arranged</it> some fresh fruit neatly on a plate.</vi> <vi><it>arranging</it> flowers in a vase</vi> <vi>The books were <it>arranged</it> according to their subject. = The books were <it>arranged</it> by subject.</vi> <vi>We <it>arranged</it> and rearranged the order several times.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give a particular order or position to the parts of (something) <vi>They <it>arranged</it> [=<it>organized</it>] the room around a fireplace.</vi> <vi>She <it>arranged</it> her hair on top of her head.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to organize the details of something before it happens :to plan (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Don't worry: I'll <it>arrange</it> [=<it>take care of</it>, <it>deal with</it>] everything.</vi> <vi>All of the details have been <it>arranged</it> [=<it>taken care of</it>, <it>dealt with</it>] in advance.</vi> <vi>Please <it>arrange</it> a meeting with your partners.</vi> <vi><it>arrange</it> a funeral</vi> <vi>I think we can <it>arrange</it> a deal.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>arrange</it> our schedules so that we can meet for lunch.</vi> <vi>They <it>arranged</it> their daughter's marriage when she was a child. [=they chose who she would marry]</vi> <vi>You'll need to <it>arrange</it> transportation from the airport.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>You'll need to <it>arrange for</it> transportation from the airport.</vi> <vi>She <it>arranged for</it> a car to pick us up at our house.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>arrange for</it> us to meet your friend?</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>I can <it>arrange to have</it> the day off from work.</vi> <vi>They <it>arranged to meet</it> each other at the restaurant.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>music</ssl> <dt>:to change (a song, a musical, etc.) so that it can be performed by particular voices or instruments <vi>He <it>arranged</it> her last two albums.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
