<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="art"> <hw highlight="yes">art</hw> <sound><wav>art00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>arts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:something that is created with imagination and skill and that is beautiful or that expresses important ideas or feelings <vi>a piece of modern/contemporary <it>art</it></vi> <vi>It's a remarkable picture, but is it <it>art</it>?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>op-art</dxt> <dxt>performance art</dxt> <dxt>pop art</dxt> <dxt>work of art</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:works created by artists :paintings, sculptures, etc., that are created to be beautiful or to express important ideas or feelings <vi>the <it>art</it> [=<it>artwork</it>] of Salvador Dalí</vi> <vi>The museum has a large collection of folk <it>art</it>.</vi> <vi>African/Japanese/Mayan <it>art</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>art</it> history</vi> <vi><it>art</it> objects</vi> <vi>an <it>art</it> museum/gallery</vi> <vi>an <it>art</it> collector/lover</vi> <vi>She prefers <it>art</it> films to Hollywood blockbusters.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>arts and crafts</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the methods and skills used for painting, sculpting, drawing, etc. <vi>He studied <it>art</it> in college.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>an <it>art</it> teacher/program</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an activity that is done to create something beautiful or to express important ideas or feelings <vi>She studied the <it>art</it> of drawing/painting/dance.</vi> <vi>dance, drama, and other <it>art</it> forms</vi> <vi>the performing/visual/graphic <it>arts</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fine art</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the arts</bnote> <dt>:painting, sculpture, music, theater, literature, etc., considered as a group of activities done by people with skill and imagination <vi>She's a patron of <it>the arts</it>.</vi> <vi>He wants the government to increase its funding for <it>the arts</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>performing arts</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a skill that someone learns through experience or study <un>usually singular <vi>He never learned the <it>art</it> of making friends. [=he never learned how to make friends]</vi> <vi>She's a master of the <it>art</it> of conversation. [=she is very good at conversation]</vi> <vi>There's an <it>art</it> to cooking that comes only with practice.</vi> <vi>Writing letters has become something of a <phrase>lost art</phrase>. [=not many people write letters any more]</vi></un> <snote>If you <phrase>raise/elevate something to an art (form)</phrase> you are known for doing something or having something (such as a personal quality). This phrase is often used in an ironic or joking way to describe qualities or abilities that are not admired. <vi>He seems to have <it>elevated stupidity to an art form</it>. [=he is very stupid]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an activity that requires special knowledge or skill <vi>Shipbuilding is both an <it>art</it> and a science.</vi> <vi>the <it>art</it> of navigation</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>martial art</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>arts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:areas of study (such as history, language, and literature) that are intended to develop the mind in a general way :<sx>liberal arts</sx> <vi>a bachelor of <it>arts</it></vi> <vi>the College of <it>Arts</it> and Sciences</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="art deco"> <hw>art de*co</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>Art Deco</va> <sound><wav>artde01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɑɚtˈdɛkoʊ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a style of art, design, and architecture that uses bold lines and simple shapes <snote>Art Deco was popular in the U.S. and Europe in the 1920s and 1930s. <vi>an <it>Art Deco</it> vase/building</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="art house"> <hw>art house</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ houses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a movie theater that shows mostly foreign movies and movies that are made by small companies :a building where art films are shown <ca>called also <cat>art theater</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="art nouveau"> <hw>art nou*veau</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>Art Nouveau</va> <sound><wav>artno01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌɑɚtnuˈvoʊ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a style of art, design, and architecture that uses curving lines and shapes that look like leaves and flowers <snote>Art Nouveau was popular in the U.S. and Europe in the late 1800s. <vi>an <it>Art Nouveau</it> lamp</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="art theater"> <hw>art theater</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ter</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>art house</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="black art"> <hw>black art</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ arts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a skill or ability that seems mysterious or magical <un>often used humorously <vi>She's trying to master the <it>black art</it> of setting up a computer network.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>the black arts</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>black magic</sx> <vi>She practices <it>the black arts</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="fine art"> <hw>fine art</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ arts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a type of art (such as painting, sculpture, or music) that is done to create beautiful things <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a collector of <it>fine art</it></vi> <wsgram>plural</wsgram> <vi>She studies painting in the department of <it>fine arts</it>.</vi> <vi>We saw the sculpture at the Museum of <it>Fine Arts</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:an activity that requires skill and care <vi>the <it>fine art</it> of gourmet cooking</vi> <un>often used in a humorous or ironic way <vi>He has mastered the <it>fine art</it> of flattery.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="martial art"> <hw>martial art</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ arts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:any one of several forms of fighting and self-defense (such as karate and judo) that are widely practiced as sports <vi>He was trained in the <it>martial arts</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>martial artist</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ists</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="op-art"> <hw>op–art</hw> <pr>ˈɑ:pˈɑɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:paintings, drawings, etc., made up of lines and shapes that are repeated and often placed in such a way that they look as though they are moving</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="performance art"> <hw>performance art</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a type of art that is created in front of or presented to an audience by the artist</dt></def> <uro><ure>performance artist</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ists</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
