<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="article[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ar*ti*cle</hw> <sound><wav>articl01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚtɪkəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ar*ti*cles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a piece of writing about a particular subject that is included in a magazine, newspaper, etc. <vi>a magazine/newspaper <it>article</it></vi> <vi>I just read an interesting <it>article</it> on/about the city's early history.</vi> <vi>He has published numerous <it>articles</it> in scholarly journals.</vi> <vi>an encyclopedia <it>article</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a particular kind of object <vi>an <it>article</it> [=<it>piece</it>] of clothing</vi> <vi>domestic/household <it>articles</it></vi> <vi><it>articles</it> [=<it>pieces</it>] of furniture</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>For many people it is an <phrase>article of faith</phrase> [=something that is believed without being questioned or doubted] that the economy will begin to improve soon.</vi> <vi>A lot of people pretend to be cowboys, but he's <phrase>the genuine article</phrase>. [=he's a real cowboy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a separate part of a legal document that deals with a single subject <vi><it>Article</it> 3 of the U.S. Constitution</vi> <vi>The company amended its <it>articles</it> of incorporation.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>grammar</ssl> <dt>:a word (such as <it>a, an</it>, or <it>the</it>) that is used with a noun to show whether or not the noun refers to a specific person or thing <dx>see also <dxt>definite article</dxt> <dxt>indefinite article</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="article[2]"> <hw hindex="2">article</hw> <altpr>ˈɑɚtɪkəl</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>articles</if></in> <in><if>arti*cled</if></in> <in><if>arti*cling</if></in> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to work for a group of lawyers, architects, etc., while you are learning to become a lawyer, architect, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>articled</it> at the famous law firm many years ago.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>usually used as <it>(be) articled to</it> <vi>She <it>was articled to</it> a firm of engineers.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>articled</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>articled</it> clerk</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="definite article"> <hw>definite article</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ articles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>grammar</sl> <dt>:the word <it>the</it> used in English to refer to a person or thing that is identified or specified</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a word that is used in a similar way in another language <dx>compare <dxt>indefinite article</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="indefinite article"> <hw>indefinite article</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -cles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the word <it>a</it> or <it>an</it> used in English to refer to a person or thing that is not identified or specified <vi>In “I gave a book to the boy” the word “a” is an <it>indefinite article</it> and the word “the” is a definite article.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a word that has a similar use in another language</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="leading article"> <hw>leading article</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ articles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>editorial</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="faith"> <hw highlight="yes">faith</hw> <sound><wav>faith001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfeɪθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>faiths</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:strong belief or trust in someone or something <vi>His supporters have accepted his claims with blind/unquestioning <it>faith</it>.</vi> <vi>Our <it>faith</it> in the government has been badly shaken by the recent scandals.</vi> <vi>His parents have always <phrase>had faith in</phrase> him. = His parents have never <phrase>lost faith in</phrase> him. [=his parents have always believed that he is a person who deserves to be trusted and who will succeed]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>have no faith</phrase> in politicians. = I <phrase>put/have little faith in</phrase> politicians. [=I do not trust politicians]</vi> <vi>Lending him the money to start his own business was an <phrase>act of faith</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It requires a giant <phrase>leap of faith</phrase> for us to believe that she is telling the truth.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad faith</dxt> <dxt>good faith</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:belief in the existence of God :strong religious feelings or beliefs <vi>religious <it>faith</it></vi> <vi>Nothing is more important to her than her <it>faith</it> in God.</vi> <vi>She says that her <it>faith</it> has given her the courage to deal with this tragedy.</vi> <vi>He says he has <phrase>found faith</phrase>. [=he has begun to believe in God or has developed strong religious beliefs]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a system of religious beliefs :<sx>religion</sx> <vi>people of all <it>faiths</it></vi> <vi>the Christian/Jewish/Muslim <it>faith</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>accept/take (something) on faith</dre> <def><dt>:to accept (something) as true without proof or evidence that it is true <vi>I'm not willing to <it>take her statements on faith</it>.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>accept it on faith</it> that he knows the truth.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an article of faith</dre> <def><dt>:something that is believed without being questioned or doubted <vi>For many it is an <it>article of faith</it> that the economy will begin to improve soon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break faith with</dre> <def><dt>:to stop supporting or being loyal to (someone) :to betray (someone) <vi>He has accused the government of <it>breaking faith with</it> its supporters.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep faith with</dre> <def><dt>:to continue supporting or being loyal to (someone) <vi>He has <it>kept faith with</it> his old political allies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep the faith</dre> <def><dt>:to continue to believe in, trust, or support someone or something when it is difficult to do so <vi>The team has been playing poorly, but its devoted fans have <it>kept the faith</it>. [=they have continued to support the team]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
