<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="as[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">as</hw> <sound><wav>as000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæz, əz</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to the same degree or amount <vi>He has a lot of time but I don't have <it>as</it> much. [=I have less time than he has]</vi> <vi>He has many books, but I have <phrase>just as</phrase> many. [=I have the same amount of books that he has]</vi> <vi>He was angry, but she was <it>just as</it> angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt><un>used to introduce an example <vi>various trees, <it>as</it> [=<it>such as</it>] oaks and pines</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="as[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">as</hw> <altpr>ˈæz, əz</altpr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt><un>used to make comparisons <vi>The fabric was soft <it>as</it> silk. [=the softness of the fabric was like the softness of silk]</vi></un> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>as…as</phrase> <vi>The fabric was <it>as</it> soft <it>as</it> silk.</vi> <vi>He is every bit <it>as</it> clever <it>as</it> she (is).</vi> <vi>There are <it>as</it> many books here <it>as</it> (there are) there.</vi> <vi>That was <it>as</it> delicious a meal <it>as</it> your last one (was). = That was a meal <it>as</it> delicious <it>as</it> your last one (was).</vi> <vi><it>as</it> hard <it>as</it> a rock [=very hard]</vi> <vi><it>as</it> clear <it>as</it> crystal [=completely clear]</vi> <vi><it>as</it> white <it>as</it> snow [=snow-white, pure white]</vi> <vi>He is <it>as</it> brave <it>as</it> he is loyal.</vi> <vi>Her second book is twice <it>as</it> long <it>as</it> her first one.</vi> <vi>He's not <it>as</it> old <it>as</it> he claims to be.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in negative phrases with <it>so</it> <vi>He's not <it>so</it> old <it>as</it> he claims to be.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in the phrase <phrase>as…as</phrase> to say when something should be done, how often something should happen, etc. <vi>Come back <it>as</it> often <it>as</it> you like.</vi> <vi>If you're going to look for a new job, you should do it <phrase>as soon/early/quickly as possible</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:in the way that <vi>The letter “k” is sometimes silent, <it>as</it> it is in “knee.”</vi> <vi>In the word “macho” the “ch” should be pronounced <it>as</it> (it is) in “China,” not <it>as</it> (it is) in “Chicago.”</vi> <vi>Knowing him <it>as</it> I do [=because I know him well], I'm not surprised by his decision.</vi> <vi>Do (it) <it>as</it> I do.</vi> <vi>I'll do it <it>as</it> I planned (to).</vi> <vi>Sometimes a noun comes from a verb (<it>as</it> “publisher” comes from “publish”) and sometimes a verb comes from a noun (<it>as</it> “edit” comes from “editor”).</vi> <vi><phrase>As it happens</phrase>, I know his brother. [=I happen to know his brother]</vi> <vi>We planned a picnic but, <phrase>as it happened</phrase>, it rained that day. [=it happened to rain that day]</vi> <vi>We arrived late and, <phrase>as it turned out</phrase>, all the tickets were already sold. [=we learned that all the tickets were already sold when we arrived late]</vi> <vi>He seemed to be having a midlife crisis, <it>as</it> many men do. = <phrase>As is the case</phrase> with many men, he seemed to be having a midlife crisis.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to introduce a statement which indicates that something being mentioned was known, expected, etc. <vi>He won the election, <it>as</it> you know. = <it>As</it> you know, he won the election.</vi> <vi><it>As</it> was only to be expected, the election was very close.</vi> <vi>He is a foreigner, <it>as</it> is evident from his accent.</vi> <vi>It rained that day, <it>as</it> often happens.</vi> <vi>Just <it>as</it> I suspected/thought! You've been drinking!</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases with <it>same</it> <vi>He works in the <it>same</it> building <it>as</it> my brother. [=he and my brother work in the same building]</vi> <vi>I've got shoes the <it>same as</it> his. = I've got the <it>same</it> type of shoes <it>as</it> he has. [=my shoes and his shoes are the same]</vi> <vi>He was fooled the <it>same as</it> I was. [=he and I were both fooled]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:while or when <vi>She spilled the milk just <it>as</it> she was getting up.</vi> <vi>I met him <it>as</it> I was leaving.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:regardless of the degree to which :<sx>though</sx> <vi>Unaccustomed <it>as</it> I am to public speaking [=although I am unaccustomed to public speaking], I'd like to say a few words now.</vi> <vi>Improbable <it>as</it> it seems, it's still true. = (<it>chiefly US</it>) <it>As</it> improbable <it>as</it> it seems, it's still true. [=although it seems improbable, it's still true]</vi> <vi><phrase>Much as</phrase> I respect him [=although I respect him very much], I still have to disagree with him on this point. = (<it>chiefly US</it>) <phrase>As much as</phrase> I respect him, I still have to disagree with him on this point.</vi> <vi><phrase>Try as he might</phrase> [=no matter how hard he tried], he couldn't do it.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:for the reason that :<sx>because</sx> <vi>She stayed home <it>as</it> she had no car.</vi> <vi><it>As</it> I'm a pacifist, I'm against all wars.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate that one relationship is like another relationship <vi>A puppy is to a dog <it>as</it> a kitten is to a cat.</vi> <vi>Two is to four <it>as</it> eight is to sixteen.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>so</it> or <it>such</it> to indicate the result or effect of something <vi>The evidence is <it>such as</it> to leave no doubt of his guilt. [=the evidence leaves no doubt of his guilt]</vi> <vi>He is <it>so</it> clearly guilty <it>as</it> to leave no doubt.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>so as <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>as against</dre> <def><dt>:in comparison to (something) <vi>The government's foreign policy is approved by 54 percent of men <it>as against</it> 48 percent of women.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as for</dre> <def><dt>:with regard to :<sx>concerning</sx> <vi>He's here. <it>As for</it> the others, they'll arrive later. [=the others will arrive later]</vi> <vi>He was a nice enough person, but <it>as for</it> his suggestions, I found them unhelpful.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as from</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt><un>used to indicate the time or date when something begins <vi>The new law takes effect <it>as from</it> [=<it>as of</it>] July 1.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as if</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>as though</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the way it would be if <vi>The plane looked <it>as if</it> it was going to crash.</vi> <vi>He was as sad <it>as if</it> he had lost his last friend.</vi> <vi>The dog wagged its tail <it>as if</it> to say “Welcome back!” = The dog wagged its tail <it>as if</it> it was/were saying “Welcome back!”</vi> <vi>The day seemed <it>as though</it> it would never end. = It seemed <it>as though</it> the day would never end.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:as someone would do if <vi>He ran <it>as if</it> ghosts were chasing him.</vi> <vi>He had his hands together <it>as though</it> in prayer.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in spoken phrases to say that something is not true, will not happen, etc. <vi>“She's afraid you might try to take the job yourself.” “<phrase>As if I ever would</phrase>!” [=I never would]</vi> <vi>“He'll never come back, you know!” “<phrase>As if I cared</phrase>!” [=I don't care]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <it>as if</it> is sometimes used informally as an interjection to say that something suggested or claimed is impossible or very unlikely. <vi>“He thinks you like him.” “<it>As if</it>!” [=I don't like him at all; there is no chance that I would like him]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as is</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:in the present condition without any changes <vi>The car is being sold <it>as is</it>.</vi> <vi>She bought the clock at an auction <it>as is</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as it is</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the present condition <vi>Leave everything exactly/just <it>as it is</it>. [=how it is, the way it is]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:with the situation that exists now <vi>We have enough to do <it>as it is</it> [=<it>already</it>] without your latest orders!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as it were</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a statement is true or accurate in a certain way even if it is not literally or completely true <vi>His retirement was, <it>as it were</it> [=<it>so to speak</it>], the beginning of his real career.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as of</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate the time or date when something begins <vi>The new law takes effect <it>as of</it> July 1.</vi> <vi><it>As of</it> July 1, prices will rise.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as to</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>about</sx> <vi>I'm at a loss <it>as to</it> how to explain the error. [=I don't know how to explain the error]</vi> <vi>There is disagreement <it>as to</it> the causes of the fire.</vi> <vi>I remained uncertain <it>as to</it> the value of his suggestions.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>according to</sx> <sx>by</sx> <vi>The eggs are graded <it>as to</it> size and color.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as was</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>formerly</sx> <sx>originally</sx> <un>used after a former name <vi>Myanmar—Burma <it>as was</it> [=Myanmar, which was formerly called Burma]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>so as</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate the purpose of something <vi>He defended himself <it>so as</it> [=<it>in order</it>] to prove his innocence.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>as <dxn>7 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="as[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">as</hw> <altpr>ˈæz, əz</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate how a person or thing appears, is thought of, etc. <vi>They regarded/described the situation <it>as</it> (being) a disaster.</vi> <vi>Don't think of it <it>as</it> (being) a setback—think of it <it>as</it> (being) a challenge!</vi> <vi>Many people now regard him <it>as</it> a traitor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the condition, role, job, etc., of someone or something <vi>Then she spoke <it>as</it> a child [=she was a child when she spoke then], but now she is speaking <it>as</it> an adult.</vi> <vi>He has a job <it>as</it> an editor.</vi> <vi>The policeman disguised himself <it>as</it> a beggar.</vi> <vi>Some people were surprised by his election <it>as</it> Governor.</vi> <vi>The critics praised his performance <it>as</it> Othello.</vi> <vi>I like her both <it>as</it> a poet and <it>as</it> a novelist.</vi> <vi><it>As</it> a pacifist, I'm against all wars.</vi> <vi>Everyone rose <phrase>as one</phrase>. [=everyone rose together]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="a[1]"> <hw hindex="1">a</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>A</va> <sound><wav>a0000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈeɪ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>a's</if> <il>or</il> <if>as</if> <il>or</il> <if>A's</if> <il>or</il> <if>As</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the first letter of the English alphabet <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a word that begins with an <it>a</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a word that begins with <it>a</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a musical note or key referred to by the letter A :the sixth tone of a C-major scale <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>play/sing an <it>A</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a song in the key of <it>A</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a grade that is given to a student for doing excellent work <vi>She got an <it>A</it> on the exam.</vi> <vi>He's an <phrase>A student</phrase>. [=a student who gets A's for his schoolwork]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt><un>used to refer to the first of two or more people, places, or things that are being considered <vi>If <it>A</it>, B, and C divide the coins equally, how many does each person get?</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>an A for effort</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effort</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>exhibit A</dre> <dx>see <dxt>exhibit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from A to Z</dre> <def><dt>:including everything <vi>The book is titled “Home Repairs <it>From A to Z</it>.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from (point) A to (point) B</dre> <def><dt>:from one place to another <vi>I don't care about the scenery. I'm only interested in getting <it>from A to B</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="against"> <hw highlight="yes">against</hw> <sound><wav>agains01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈgɛnst</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in opposition to (someone or something) <vi>Everyone was <it>against</it> them. [=everyone opposed them]</vi> <vi>We must continue the struggle for justice and <it>against</it> injustice.</vi> <vi>She voted <it>against</it> the proposal.</vi> <vi>You're either for/with me or <it>against</it> me! [=you either support me or oppose me]</vi> <vi>He spoke <it>against</it> appeasing the enemy.</vi> <vi>The U.S. fought <it>against</it> Germany in World Wars I and II. = The U.S. and Germany fought <it>against</it> each other in World Wars I and II.</vi> <vi>Some people were for the proposal but others were <it>against</it> it.</vi> <vi>There's a law <it>against</it> doing that.</vi> <vi>His parents were angry when they learned he had borrowed the car <phrase>against their wishes</phrase>. [=he borrowed the car even though they did not want him to]</vi> <vi><phrase>Against my advice</phrase>, she quit her job. [=she quit her job even though I advised her not to]</vi> <vi>He was being held <phrase>against his will</phrase>. [=he was being kept in a place by force even though he wanted to leave]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in competition with (someone or something) <vi>two runners racing <it>against</it> each other</vi> <vi>It's the Yankees <it>against</it> [=<it>versus</it>] the Red Sox tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the person or thing that is affected or harmed by something <vi>He denies the charges that have been made <it>against</it> him.</vi> <vi>The evidence <it>against</it> him is very convincing.</vi> <vi>The war was a crime <it>against</it> humanity.</vi> <vi>Someone has been making threats <it>against</it> her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not agreeing with or allowed by (something, such as a law) <vi>You can't do that. It's <it>against</it> the law. [=the law does not allow it]</vi> <vi>Touching the ball with your hands is <it>against</it> the rules.</vi> <vi>I won't do it. It's <it>against</it> my principles. [=my principles don't allow it; I believe that it is wrong]</vi> <vi>They were acting <it>against</it> tradition. [=acting in a way that did not agree with tradition]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not helping or favoring (someone) <vi>Everything was/went <it>against</it> them. [=everything that happened was unfavorable to them]</vi> <vi>Her appearance is/counts <it>against</it> her. [=her appearance does not help her; people form a bad opinion of her because of her appearance]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:as a reason for disliking (someone or something) <vi>I <phrase>have nothing against</phrase> him. [=I don't dislike him; I have no reason for disliking him]</vi> <vi>We disagree about many things, but I don't <phrase>hold it/that against</phrase> you. [=I don't dislike you because of it/that]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that one thing is being compared with another <vi>Profits are up this year <it>against</it> last year. [=profits are higher this year than they were last year]</vi> <vi>The yen rose/fell <it>against</it> the dollar.</vi> <vi>a graph that plots height <it>against</it> weight</vi> <vi>We will weigh/balance the risk <it>against</it> the possible benefit. [=we will compare the risk with the possible benefit]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:as a defense or protection from (something) <vi>He built a crude hut as a shelter <it>against</it> [=<it>from</it>] the cold.</vi> <vi>injections <it>against</it> flu</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in preparation for (something) <vi>saving <it>against</it> [=<it>for</it>] an uncertain future</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to describe hitting or touching something or someone <vi>I accidentally knocked/hit my head <it>against</it> the shelf.</vi> <vi>The waves were beating <it>against</it> [=<it>on</it>] the shore.</vi> <vi>She accidentally brushed <it>against</it> him as she walked by.</vi> <vi>The ladder was leaning <it>against</it> the wall.</vi> <vi>She was resting her head <it>against</it> the side of the chair.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:in a direction opposite to the movement of (something) <vi>They were sailing <it>against</it> the wind.</vi> <vi>swimming <it>against</it> the current/tide</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:with the background of (something) <vi>The tree looked beautiful when viewed <it>against</it> the dark sky.</vi> <vi>Her colorful coat stood out <it>against</it> the dull colors of the room.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:as a charge on (something) <vi>The purchase was charged <it>against</it> [=<it>to</it>] her account. [=the amount of money needed for the purchase was added to the amount owed in her account]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as against</dre> <dx>see <dxt>as</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>over against</dre> <dx>see <dxt>over</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>up against</dre> <dx>see <dxt>up</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="always"> <hw highlight="yes">al*ways</hw> <sound><wav>always01.wav</wav><wav>always01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑ:lˌweɪz</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:at all times :on every occasion :in a way that does not change <vi>He <it>always</it> tries, but he doesn't <it>always</it> succeed.</vi> <vi>It's <it>always</it> a pleasure to see you.</vi> <vi>I can <it>always</it> tell when he's upset.</vi> <vi>He's <it>always</it> [=<it>constantly</it>] looking for ways to make money.</vi> <vi>She's almost <it>always</it> smiling.</vi> <vi>This area is <it>always</it> filled with tourists.</vi> <vi>You should <it>always</it> (remember to) wear your seat belt.</vi> <vi>The holidays are <it>always</it> a very busy time for us. = (<it>less commonly</it>) The holidays <it>always</it> are a very busy time for us.</vi> <vi>Things won't <it>always</it> go as planned.</vi> <vi>You're <it>always</it> welcome to stay with us.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>never</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:at all times in the past <vi>He has <it>always</it> been a good friend to me.</vi> <vi>They didn't <it>always</it> get along so well. [=they get along now, but they didn't like each other in the past]</vi> <vi>It hasn't <it>always</it> been easy for him. [=difficult or sad things have happened to him]</vi> <vi>He could <it>always</it> make me angry. = He <it>always</it> could make me angry. [=he often made me angry]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:throughout all time :for a very long time: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:forever into the future <vi>I'll remember you <it>always</it>. [=forever]</vi> <vi>You'll <it>always</it> be my best friend. = You're my best friend, and you <it>always</it> will be.</vi> <vi>Life won't <it>always</it> be this easy.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:forever in the past :from the beginning of the time that can be remembered <vi>I've <it>always</it> loved you.</vi> <vi>I <it>always</it> thought they'd get married some day, but they never did.</vi> <vi>Isn't that what you've <it>always</it> wanted?</vi> <vi>She <it>always</it> wanted to be famous.</vi> <vi>It has <it>always</it> been my goal to have my own business.</vi> <vi>He's <it>always</it> been a firm believer in hard work. = He's a firm believer in hard work, and he <it>always</it> has been.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:often, frequently, or repeatedly <vi>We <it>always</it> tell people not to arrive too early.</vi> <vi>My parents <it>always</it> told me not to speak to strangers.</vi> <un>often used to describe repeated behavior that is annoying <vi>She's <it>always</it> calling me by the wrong name.</vi> <vi>Must you <it>always</it> be so rude?!</vi> <vi>He <it>always</it> tells such funny stories. = He's <it>always</it> telling such funny stories.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to suggest another possibility <vi>If we don't win today, there's <it>always</it> tomorrow. [=we might win tomorrow]</vi></un> <un>usually used after <it>can</it> or <it>could</it> <vi>If she doesn't answer the phone now, you <it>can/could always</it> try (calling) again later.</vi> <vi>If you don't have enough money now, you <it>can always</it> use your credit card.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>as always</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something was expected because it always happens <vi><it>As always</it>, dinner was delicious. [=dinner was delicious, as it always is]</vi> <vi>Your children, <it>as always</it>, were very well-behaved. [=your children were well-behaved, as they always are]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="anything"> <hw highlight="yes">any*thing</hw> <sound><wav>anythi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛniˌθɪŋ</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a thing of any kind <vi>We were allowed to do <it>anything</it> we wanted to.</vi> <vi>If you're not sure what to say, just say <it>anything</it> that comes to mind.</vi> <vi>She didn't say <it>anything</it> at all. [=she said nothing at all]</vi> <vi>That dog will eat almost/nearly/practically/virtually <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>We didn't talk about <it>anything</it> much.</vi> <vi>The new stadium is spectacular. There's never been <it>anything</it> like it.</vi> <vi>She never does <it>anything</it> but complain. [=all she does is complain]</vi> <vi>I'll do <it>anything</it> I can to help.</vi> <vi>They were ready for <it>anything</it> (that might happen).</vi> <vi>You can't tell him <it>anything</it> about computers. He thinks he's an expert.</vi> <vi>I can't think of her as <it>anything</it> but a good friend. [=I can only think of her as a good friend]</vi> <vi>He'll do <it>anything</it> for a laugh.</vi> <vi>I'd do/give <it>anything</it> to see her again.</vi> <vi>He won't take <it>anything</it> from anyone. [=he won't allow anyone to mistreat him, to be rude to him, etc.]</vi> <vi>She ate hardly <it>anything</it>. [=she ate almost nothing]</vi> <vi>He said he was sorry, but that doesn't really mean <it>anything</it>.</vi> <vi>I don't have <it>anything</it> against them. [=I don't have any reason for disliking them]</vi> <vi>She thought it was funny but I didn't see <it>anything</it> funny about it. [=I didn't think it was funny at all]</vi> <vi>They've been doing <phrase>everything and anything</phrase> to finish on time. = They've been doing <phrase>anything and everything</phrase> to finish on time.</vi> <vi>The problems were caused by lack of time <phrase>as much as anything</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <phrase>anything goes</phrase>. [=anything is acceptable; there are no rules that have to be followed]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>something</sx> <un>used in questions <vi>Would you like <it>anything</it> else?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> wrong?</vi> <vi>Is there <it>anything</it> (good/interesting) on TV tonight?</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) Do you want some pretzels <phrase>or anything</phrase>? [=or a similar thing]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything but</dre> <def><dt>:not at all <vi>He looked <it>anything but</it> happy. [=he looked very unhappy]</vi> <vi>Though he said he was happy, he looked <it>anything but</it> (happy).</vi> <vi>This problem is <it>anything but</it> new.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>anything like</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at all like <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>anything near</va></svr> <dt>:in any way :at all <un>used in negative statements <vi>He doesn't look <it>anything like</it> his brother.</vi> <vi>The movie wasn't <it>anything like/near</it> what I expected it to be. [=the movie was completely different from what I expected it to be]</vi> <vi>We don't have <it>anything like/near</it> enough time. [=we don't have nearly enough time]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:as any person or thing <un>used to make a statement more forceful <vi>He was (<it>as</it>) calm <it>as anything</it>. [=he was very calm]</vi> <vi>It was as obvious <it>as anything</it> [=it was extremely obvious] that she didn't want to go.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for anything</dre> <def><dt>:for any reason <un>used in negative statements <vi>I like my life, and I wouldn't change it <it>for anything</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if anything</dre> <dx>see <dxt>if</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like anything</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very much :very forcefully <vi>It was raining <it>like anything</it>. [=it was raining very hard]</vi> <vi>She was hoping <it>like anything</it> that the weather would be good.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than anything</dre> <def><dt>:very much :very badly <vi>I wanted to believe her <it>more than anything</it> [=I very much wanted to believe her], but I couldn't.</vi> <vi><it>More than anything</it> (in the world), I'd like to visit Paris again. [=the thing I most want to do is to visit Paris again]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="arm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">arm</hw> <sound><wav>arm00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>arms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:either one of the two long body parts that join the top of your body at the shoulder and that end at the hand or wrist <vi>He has big, strong, muscular <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>She broke her left <it>arm</it>. = Her left <it>arm</it> was/got broken.</vi> <vi>He hurt his throwing/pitching <it>arm</it> [=the arm that he uses to throw/pitch a ball] in the last game.</vi> <vi>She put/threw her <it>arms</it> around him. [=she hugged him]</vi> <vi>She had a newspaper tucked under her <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was carrying a bag of groceries in each <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He gave/offered his <it>arm</it> to her, and she took it. [=she held onto his arm]</vi> <vi>She grabbed my <it>arm</it>. = She grabbed me by the <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was standing there with his <it>arms</it> crossed/folded.</vi> <vi>She stood with her <it>arms</it> outstretched. = She stood with her <it>arms</it> wide open.</vi> <vi>She sat cradling the baby in her <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her since she was <phrase>a babe in arms</phrase>. [=a baby who is too young to walk and has to be held]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her in/into his arms</phrase> [=he embraced her] and kissed her passionately.</vi> <vi>She found him <phrase>in the arms of</phrase> [=being embraced by] another woman.</vi> <vi>He showed up at the party with a young woman <phrase>on his arm</phrase>. [=holding his arm]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her (by the) arm</phrase> and they walked in to dinner.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the part of a piece of clothing (such as a shirt or coat) that covers the arm :<sx>sleeve</sx> <vi>The jacket's <it>arms</it> are too tight. = The jacket is too tight in the <it>arms</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a part of a piece of furniture (such as a chair or couch) that gives support for a person's arm <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the sofa</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>armchair</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:a long thin piece that is connected to the main part of a machine, structure, etc., and that looks or moves like a human arm <vi>the robot's mechanical <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the machine's robotic <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the record player</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long and narrow area of water <vi>an <it>arm</it> of the sea</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the part of a group or organization that performs a specific job or function <un>usually singular <vi>the organization's political <it>arm</it> [=the part of the organization that deals with politics]</vi> <vi>It is the most powerful <it>arm</it> [=<it>division</it>] of the organization.</vi> <vi>the military <it>arm</it> of the government</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a person's ability to throw a ball <un>usually singular <vi>Their pitcher's got a great <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>a strong/weak <it>arm</it></vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>an arm and a leg</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a very large amount of money <vi>It's a reliable car, and it doesn't cost <it>an arm and a leg</it>. [=it isn't too expensive]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>arm in arm</dre> <def><dt>:next to each other with the arm of one person linked at the elbow to the arm of another person <vi>an elderly couple walking down the street <it>arm in arm</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a shot in the arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as long as someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>long</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at arm's length</dre> <def><dt>:from a distance that is the length of a person's arm <vi>It's best to view the painting <it>at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>holding a candle <it>at arm's length</it></vi> <snote>To <phrase>keep someone or something at arm's length</phrase> is to avoid being very close to or friendly with someone or something. <vi>Since going to college, he has <it>kept his old friends at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>They no longer trust her and are <it>keeping her at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>kept the group at arm's length</it> until now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chance your arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your right arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>give</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the long arm of the law</dre> <def><dt>:the ability of the police to find and catch people who commit crimes <vi><it>The long arm of the law</it> finally caught up with him [=the police caught him] 30 years later.</vi> <vi>So far, she's been able to escape <it>the long arm of the law</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>twist someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twist</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with open arms</dre> <def><dt>:in a very kind and friendly way <vi>We were welcomed back <phrase>with open arms</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>arm</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="best[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>well</ct></cx> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the best way :in a way that is better than all others <vi>The sauce is <it>best</it> served/eaten/enjoyed cold.</vi> <vi>His cooking is <it>best</it> described as spicy. = It can <it>best</it> be described as spicy.</vi> :with the most success or benefit <vi>They work <it>best</it> under pressure.</vi> <vi>That's what we do <it>best</it>!</vi> <vi>We need to think about how <it>best</it> to fix this problem.</vi> <vi>This is a job <it>best</it> left to the professionals. [=it's better/best to allow professional workers to do this job]</vi> <vi>Some things are <it>best</it> left unsaid. [=it's better/best not to talk about some things]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to the greatest degree or extent :<sx>most</sx> <vi>That's the one we liked (the) <it>best</it>.</vi> <vi>The work should be done by the people who are <it>best</it> able to do it.</vi> <vi>She's <it>best</it> suited to life in the city.</vi> <vi>He is <it>best</it> known for his invention of the lightbulb.</vi> <vi>The museum features some of the <it>best</it>-known examples of this style of painting.</vi> <vi>the industry's <it>best</it>-kept secret</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as best you can</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the best (that) you can</va></vr> <def><dt>:as well, skillfully, or accurately as you can <vi>She answered their questions <it>as best she could</it>. [=as well as she could]</vi> <vi>You don't have to do it perfectly. Just do it <it>the best you can</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>had best</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>had best</it> do something, you should do it. <vi><it>You'd best</it> get ready for school. [=you'd better get ready for school; you should get ready for school]</vi> <vi><it>Had</it>n't you <it>best</it> get ready for school?</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="boot[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">boot</hw> <sound><wav>boot0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbu:t</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>boots</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a covering usually of leather or rubber for the entire foot and the lower part of the leg <vi>You'll need a pair of warm <it>boots</it> for winter.</vi> <vi>It's been snowing, so you'd better wear your <it>boots</it>.</vi> <vi>hiking <it>boots</it> [=boots worn for hiking]</vi> <vi>riding <it>boots</it> [=boots worn for horseback riding]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>shoe</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>booted</dxt> <dxt>cowboy boot</dxt> <dxt>hobnail boot</dxt> <dxt>ski boot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a forceful kick with the foot <vi>She gave the ball a <it>boot</it>, and it landed on the other side of the field.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the boot</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a sudden dismissal from a job <vi>He <phrase>got the boot</phrase> [=<it>got fired</it>] for talking to the press about company secrets.</vi> <vi>I heard they <phrase>gave her the boot</phrase>. [=they fired her; they told her she could no longer work for them]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the trunk of a car</dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:<sx>denver boot</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>as tough as old boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tough</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lick someone's boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the boot is on the other foot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to boot</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>besides</sx> <sx>also</sx> <vi>He's smart, funny, and handsome <it>to boot</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too big for your boots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>big</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to put the boot in</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to treat someone in a cruel or critical way</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to kick someone again and again</dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>bossy-boots</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
