<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="aside[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">aside</hw> <sound><wav>aside001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsaɪd</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to or toward the side <vi>He stepped <it>aside</it> and let her pass.</vi> <vi>She drew <it>aside</it> the curtains. = She drew the curtains <it>aside</it>.</vi> <vi>He threw/tossed his coat <it>aside</it>.</vi> <vi>Please stand <it>aside</it>.</vi> <vi>She laid/set the book <it>aside</it>.</vi> <vi>He elbowed people <it>aside</it> as he moved through the crowd.</vi> <vi>He took/drew her <it>aside</it> to speak to her privately.</vi> <vi>Someone grabbed him and pulled/pushed him <it>aside</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their objections were swept/brushed <it>aside</it>. [=were quickly dismissed or disregarded]</vi> <vi>The old methods have been cast/thrown <it>aside</it> [=have been abandoned] in favor of new ones.</vi> <vi>Leaving/Putting <it>aside</it> the question of money for the moment, we need to come up with a workable schedule.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>put</it> or <it>set</it> to describe something that is being kept or saved for a future use <vi>She's been <it>setting/putting</it> money <it>aside</it> [=has been saving money] for school.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>set aside</it> a thousand acres for use as a park.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is not included in a statement that follows <vi>Dangerous appearances <it>aside</it>, these animals are really very gentle and friendly. [=these animals are friendly despite their dangerous appearances]</vi> <vi>Such minor problems <it>aside</it> [=except for such minor problems], the movie is a very entertaining thriller.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>aside from</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:not including (something) :with the exception of (something) <vi><it>Aside from</it> [=<it>apart from, except for</it>] a few pieces of bread, the food is gone.</vi> <vi>The movie has been praised by most people, <it>aside from</it> a few critics who have called its happy ending trite and predictable.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in addition to (something) :<sx>besides</sx> <vi><it>Aside from</it> being well written, the book is also beautifully illustrated</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="aside[2]"> <hw hindex="2">aside</hw> <altpr>əˈsaɪd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>asides</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a comment spoken by a character in a play that is heard by the audience but is supposedly not heard by other characters on stage</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a comment that is spoken quietly to someone so that it cannot be heard by other people who are present <vi>She made a joke about the food in a muttered/whispered <it>aside</it> to her husband.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a comment or discussion that does not relate directly to the main subject being discussed <vi>The book includes several lengthy <it>asides</it> about the personal lives of scientists involved in the project.</vi> <vi>In his speech he mentioned her contributions almost as an <it>aside</it>, despite the fact that she was the one who came up with the idea originally.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="set-aside"> <hw>set–aside</hw> <sound><wav>setasi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛtəˌsaɪd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>set–asides</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is saved and used for a particular purpose</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a program that requires jobs, money, etc., to be saved for people who have not been given as much as others in the past <vi>minority <it>set-asides</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a plan in the European Union in which farmers are paid not to grow a certain crop on a piece of land so that the price for that crop will not decrease too much</dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of land on which the crop is not grown</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brush[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">brush</hw> <altpr>ˈbrʌʃ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>brushes</if></in> <in><if>brushed</if></in> <in><if>brush*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to clean or smooth (something) with a brush <vi><it>brush</it> your teeth/hair</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put (something) on or onto something with a brush <vi><it>Brush</it> some butter onto the fish before cooking it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) with a brush or with a quick movement of your hand, fingers, etc. <vi><it>Brush</it> the dirt off your pants.</vi> <vi>The camera showed him <it>brushing</it> [=<it>wiping</it>] away a tear.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to touch gently against (something) when going past it <vi>Leaves <it>brushed</it> my cheek.</vi> <vi>The two men <phrase>brushed shoulders</phrase> [=touched at the shoulders] as they walked past each other.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to move quickly past someone without stopping or paying attention <vi>The governor <it>brushed</it> by/past the reporters.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>brush aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>brush (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>brush aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to treat (something) as not important :to ignore or dismiss (something) <vi>He <it>brushed aside</it> [=<it>brushed off</it>] questions about his son's arrest.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>brush off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>brush (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>brush off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to treat (something) as not important :to refuse to deal with or talk about (something) in a serious way <vi>The company <it>brushed off</it> [=<it>brushed aside</it>] reports that it couldn't pay its bills.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>brush (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>brush off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to respond to (someone) in a rude way that shows you are not interested in what is being asked for or suggested <vi>I asked him for some help, but he just <it>brushed</it> me <it>off</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>brush-off</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>brush up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>brush up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>brush up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to improve your skill at (something) or increase your knowledge of (something) <vi>My Spanish is very rusty. I need to <it>brush up</it> before I go on my vacation to Mexico.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>brush up</it> my Spanish.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I need to <it>brush up on</it> my Spanish.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cast[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cast</hw> <sound><wav>cast0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈkɑ:st</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>casts</if></in> <in><if>cast</if></in> <in><if>cast*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to throw or move (something) in a forceful way <vi><it>cast</it> [=<it>throw, toss</it>] a stone</vi> <vi>Seaweed was <it>cast</it> up by the waves.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to throw (a fishing line, hook, etc.) into the water by using a fishing pole</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to send or direct (something) in the direction of someone or something <vi>He <it>cast</it> a glance toward the door. [=he glanced at the door]</vi> <vi>The witch <it>cast</it> [=<it>put</it>] a spell on him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send (something) out or forward <vi>The fire <it>casts</it> [=<it>gives off</it>] a warm glow.</vi> <vi>The tree <it>cast</it> a long shadow on the lawn.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The trial <it>casts</it> a harsh light on [=reveals bad things about] the banking industry.</vi> <vi>Their argument <phrase>cast a pall</phrase> on the party. [=gave the party an unhappy mood]</vi> <vi>The incident <phrase>casts doubt</phrase> on her honesty.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (a vote) formally <vi>How many votes were <it>cast</it>?</vi> <vi><it>cast</it> a ballot</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to assign roles for (a play, movie, etc.) to actors <vi><it>cast</it> a play</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to assign (an actor or actress) a role in a film, play, etc. <vi>She was <it>cast</it> as a college professor who becomes a spy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>typecast</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to shape (a substance) by pouring it into a mold and letting it harden <vi>The metal was <it>cast</it> into candlesticks.</vi> <vi>molds used for <it>casting</it> steel</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form (something, such as a sculpture) by casting metal, plaster, etc. <vi>The statue will be <it>cast</it> in bronze.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to arrange (something) into parts or into a proper form <vi>He <it>cast</it> the story in the form of a diary.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think of (someone or something) in a particular way <vi>The war was <it>cast</it> as a battle against terrorism.</vi> <vi>Health care issues are often <it>cast</it> in economic terms.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cast about/around for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast about/around for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look in many places for (something) <vi>They <it>cast about for</it> new ways to make money on the farm.</vi> <vi>She is still <it>casting around for</it> [=<it>seeking</it>] someone to watch her son while she is at work.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast a (dark) cloud</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloud</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast adrift</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (a boat) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat) to float on the water without being tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>a small lifeboat <it>cast adrift</it> in the open sea</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (someone) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to float on the water in a boat that is not tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>They <it>were cast adrift</it> in a small, leaky boat.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>I <it>was cast adrift</it> in a sea of confusion.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast aside (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) aside</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop thinking about (something) <vi>She tried to <it>cast aside</it> her worries and enjoy the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aspersions</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aspersions</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast away (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone) away</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (someone) alone somewhere (such as on an island) as a result of a storm, shipwreck, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be) cast away</it> <vi>The crew <it>was cast away</it> on a desert island.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>castaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast caution to the wind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>caution</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast light on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast lots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get rid of (something) <vi>The snake <it>casts off</it> [=<it>sheds</it>] its skin.</vi> <vi>They wanted to <it>cast off</it> their fears.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>castoff</dxt> <dxt>cast-off</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to untie the rope that is holding a boat near the land <vi>We decided to <it>cast off</it> and head out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to remove stitches from a knitting needle in a way that does not cause them to become loose <vi>When I finish this row, can you show me how to <it>cast off</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to place stitches on a knitting needle <vi>I was having trouble <it>casting on</it>, but I think I have it now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone or something) to go away <vi>He was <it>cast out</it> of [=expelled from] the tribe.</vi> <vi>They tried to <it>cast out</it> the spirits from the haunted house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast pearls before swine</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pearl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your eye over</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your lot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your mind back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your net wide</dre> <dx>see <dxt>net</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the die is cast</dre> <dx>see <dxt>die</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="joke[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">joke</hw> <altpr>ˈʤoʊk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>jokes</if></in> <in><if>joked</if></in> <in><if>jok*ing</if></in> <def><dt>:to say things that are meant to cause laughter :to make jokes about someone or something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My friends would <it>joke</it> about the uniform I had to wear at work.</vi> <vi>She <it>joked</it> about the possibility of losing her job.</vi> <vi>I thought he was <it>joking</it> when he said he might quit, but it turned out that he really meant it.</vi> <vi>Don't take it seriously: I was only <it>joking</it>.</vi> <vi>She spent a few minutes <it>joking</it> with reporters after giving her speech.</vi> <vi>“The report is to be done by tomorrow.” “<phrase>You're joking</phrase>.” = “<phrase>You must be joking</phrase>.” [=you must be kidding; what you say is very surprising or hard to believe]</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>no joking matter</phrase>. [=it is no joke; it is a serious matter]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>joked</it> that she could always get work as a truck driver if she lost her job.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>joking aside</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>joking apart</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to introduce a serious statement that follows a humorous statement <vi>It looks like this is a job for Superman! But <it>joking aside</it>, this is a serious problem and we're going to need help.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>jok*ing*ly</ure> <sound><wav>joke0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈʤoʊkɪŋli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <gram>more jok*ing*ly; most jok*ing*ly</gram> <utxt><vi>She spoke <it>jokingly</it> about the possibility of losing her job.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="lay[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">lay</hw> <sound><wav>lay00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈleɪ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>lays</if></in> <in><if>laid</if> <sound><wav>lay00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈleɪd</pr></in> <in><if>lay*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to place (someone or something) down gently in a flat position <vi><it>Lay</it> the fabric carefully on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>laid</it> a gentle hand on her shoulder.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid</it> the baby in his crib for a nap.</vi> <vi>He says that he never <phrase>laid a finger/hand on</phrase> her. [=that he never touched her]</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi>He <it>laid</it> the newspaper <it>down</it> on the desk.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid</it> the baby down for his nap.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>lay down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) into position on or along a surface :to build or set (something) on or in the ground or another surface <vi>When will they <it>lay</it> the foundation for the addition?</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> tracks for the new railroad</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> pipe/cable/lines</vi> <vi><it>laying</it> bricks</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi><it>laying down</it> a new road/carpet</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We are <phrase>laying the groundwork/foundation</phrase> [=providing conditions] for additional research.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to spread (something) over a surface <vi><it>lay</it> plaster/paint</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> wallpaper</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:<sx>bury <sxn>1</sxn></sx>a <vi>They <it>laid</it> him in his grave.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be in a flat position on a surface :<sx>lie</sx> <vi>The book was <it>laying</it> on the table.</vi> <snote>The use of <it>lay</it> to mean “lie” occurs commonly in informal speech but it is regarded as an error by many people.</snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to beat or strike (something) down with force <vi>The wheat was <phrase>laid flat</phrase> by the wind and rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change the condition of something in a specified way <vi>The mountainside has been <phrase>laid bare</phrase> by loggers. [=all the trees on the mountainside have been cut down by loggers]</vi> <vi>He <it>laid bare</it> his soul. = He <it>laid</it> his soul <it>bare</it>. [=he revealed his most private thoughts and feelings]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>laid himself open</phrase> to criticism [=he exposed himself to criticism] with his remarks.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>of a bird, insect, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to produce (an egg) outside of the body :to push (an egg) out of the body <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>birds that typically <it>lay</it> only two eggs per year</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>old chickens that no longer <it>lay</it></vi> <dx>see also <tag>lay an egg</tag> at <dxt>egg</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>make, place</it>, or <it>put</it> in various phrases <vi>She has <phrase>laid plans</phrase> [=she has made plans] to cut the staff down to just 15 people.</vi> <vi>Even the <phrase>best-laid plans</phrase> [=the most carefully made plans] sometimes go wrong.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>lays great stress/emphasis</phrase> on good manners. [=she stresses/emphasizes good manners very much]</vi> <vi>The author <phrase>lays the blame/responsibility</phrase> for the state of the environment squarely on the government. [=the author blames the government for the state of the environment]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) ready :to prepare (something) <vi><it>lay</it> a trap</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> a fire in the fireplace</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Places were <it>laid</it> (at the table) for three people. [=silverware, glasses, and napkins were put on the table for three people who will be eating there]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) <it>lay</it> [=<it>set</it>] the table for a meal</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to risk losing (money) if your guess about what will happen is wrong :<sx>bet</sx> <vi><it>lay</it> money on a race</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal + offensive</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with someone <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>get laid</phrase> <vi>All he cares about is <it>getting laid</it>. [=having sex]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>lay aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to place (something) to one side <vi>She <it>laid aside</it> [=<it>put aside, set aside</it>] the book she had been reading and turned on the TV.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Plans for a new school have been <it>laid aside</it>. [=<it>put aside, set aside</it>]</vi> <vi>It's time for all of us to <it>lay aside</it> old prejudices.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>lay</it> our differences <it>aside</it> so that we can learn to work together.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) for special or future use :to reserve or save (something) :to keep (something) for special or future use <vi>She has been able to <it>lay aside</it> [=<it>put aside</it>] a few dollars each week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay by (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (something) for special or future use <vi>She has been able to <it>lay by</it> [=<it>lay aside</it>] a few dollars each week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay charges</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to accuse someone officially of doing something illegal <vi>Police are deciding whether to <it>lay charges</it> (against her).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay claim to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>claim</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to clearly state (a rule, standard, guideline, etc.) <vi>The company has <it>laid down</it> strict new safety standards.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop using (something) <vi>At noon, we <it>laid down</it> the rakes and rested for a while.</vi> <vi>The strikers <it>laid down</it> their tools.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (a weapon) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay down (a weapon)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to put (a weapon) down and stop fighting <vi>The police ordered the criminals to <it>lay down</it> their weapons.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay down your life</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give up your life for a good purpose :to die for a good cause <vi>heroes who <it>laid down their lives</it> to preserve our nation</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay down the law</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a strong statement about what someone is or is not allowed to do <vi>The agreement <it>lays down the law</it> (to everyone) on what the group allows.</vi> <vi>When she came home after midnight, her father <it>laid down the law</it>: if she came home that late again, she would not be allowed to watch TV for a week.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>lay <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get and store (a supply of something) for future use <vi>They <it>laid in</it> [=<it>laid up</it>] canned goods for the winter.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay into (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to angrily attack or criticize (someone or something) <vi>The coach really <it>laid into</it> us for playing so carelessly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay it on the line</dre> <dx>see <dxt>line</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop employing (someone) because there is not enough work <vi>The company has had to <it>lay off</it> most of the staff.</vi> <vi>Costs have increased and many workers have been <it>laid off</it>. [=<it>let go</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>layoff</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay off (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop doing, using, eating, or drinking (something) <vi>You should <it>lay off</it> the late nights. [=you should stop staying up so late]</vi> <vi>My doctor advised me to <it>lay off</it> caffeine.</vi> <vi>He's a much nicer person since he <it>laid off</it> the booze. [=since he stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>I need to <it>lay off</it> fatty foods and lose some weight.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to leave someone alone :to stop annoying someone <vi>I wish you'd just <it>lay off</it>!</vi> <vi><it>Lay off</it> me! [=stop bothering me]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to spread (something) over a surface <vi>Try to <it>lay</it> the grout <it>on</it> the surface evenly.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>(<it>informal</it>) My parents have been <it>laying</it> a lot of guilt <it>on</it> me. [=have been saying things that make me feel guilty]</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you have something to tell me, just <it>lay</it> it <it>on</it> me. [=just tell me]</vi> <vi>He <it>laid</it> the flattery <it>on</it> pretty heavily.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid on</it> a fake southern accent. [=she spoke with a southern accent although she doesn't usually speak that way]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to provide (something) for someone <vi>If a lot of people want to come, more coaches will be <it>laid on</it> for them.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay it on (thick)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to speak in a way that is exaggerated and not sincere <vi>You should compliment her cooking but don't <it>lay it on too thick</it> or she'll know you don't mean it.</vi> <vi>He <it>laid it on</it> pretty heavily and pretended to be interested in what she said.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) on a surface in a carefully arranged way <vi>The wires were <it>laid out</it> along the floor.</vi> <vi>Brochures were <it>laid out</it> on a table.</vi> <vi>She was <it>laying out</it> the cheese and crackers for the guests.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrange (something) in a particular pattern or design <vi>The garden was <it>laid out</it> in a formal pattern.</vi> <vi>Much of Manhattan is <it>laid out</it> in the form of a grid.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>layout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to plan the details of (something) <vi>She's been hired to <it>lay out</it> [=<it>map out</it>] the election campaign.</vi> <vi>The work for tomorrow is all <it>laid out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to explain the details of (something) <vi>He <it>laid out</it> the reasons for his decision.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to spend (money) <vi>The city <it>laid out</it> millions of dollars for the new stadium.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>outlay</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone's body) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (someone's body)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prepare (someone's dead body) so that it can be seen by family and friends before it is buried <vi>They <it>laid</it> him <it>out</it> in a plain coffin.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make (someone) unconscious :to knock (someone) out <vi>He <it>laid</it> his opponent <it>out</it> with a hard right to the jaw.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a stop in the middle of a journey <vi>Our flight to Italy <it>laid over</it> in Madrid for several hours.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stop in the middle of a journey <un>usually used as <it>(be) laid over</it> <vi>We <it>were laid over</it> in Madrid for several hours.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>layover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay siege to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>siege</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay (someone) to rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay to rest (something)</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>lay (something) to rest</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to store (something) <vi><it>lay up</it> [=<it>lay in</it>] grain for the winter</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take (something) out of active use or service <vi>We <it>laid up</it> the boat for the winter.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stay at home or in bed because of illness or injury <vi>The flu <it>laid him up</it> for two weeks.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) laid up</it> <vi>He <it>was laid up</it> for six weeks with a bad back.</vi> <vi>He <it>was laid up</it> by the flu.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay waste to</dre> <def><dt>:to cause very bad damage to (something) <vi>The fire <it>laid waste to</it> the land. [=the fire caused great destruction to the land]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay your hands on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the goose that lays the golden egg</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goose</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="pull[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">pull</hw> <sound><wav>pull0001.wav</wav><wav>pull0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpʊl</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>pulls</if></in> <in><if>pulled</if></in> <in><if>pull*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to hold onto and move (someone or something) in a particular direction and especially toward yourself <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the door open and ran out.</vi> <vi>The cat will scratch you if you keep <it>pulling</it> its tail.</vi> <vi>Make a knot in the rope and <it>pull</it> it tight.</vi> <vi><it>Pull</it> the baby's chair closer to the table.</vi> <vi>She <it>pulled</it> the blanket over her head.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>We tried pushing and <it>pulling</it> but couldn't get the couch to move.</vi> <vi>Grab the end of the rope and <it>pull</it> as hard as you can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (something) by gripping it and using force <vi>We spent the morning in the garden <it>pulling</it> weeds.</vi> <vi>I accidentally <it>pulled</it> one of the buttons off my shirt.</vi> <vi>The dentist said I have to have two teeth <it>pulled</it>. [=<it>extracted</it>]</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the cork (out) and poured the wine.</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the plug out of the socket.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something you are holding or something that is attached to you) to move with you as you go in a particular direction <vi>Horses <it>pull</it> carriages around the park.</vi> <vi>She was <it>pulling</it> a wagon behind her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to move or be directed toward something <vi>The colors <it>pull</it> [=<it>draw</it>] the eye toward the center of the painting.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a car, train, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to move from or to a particular place <vi>The car <it>pulled</it> out of the driveway.</vi> <vi>The train <it>pulled</it> into the station [=arrived at the station] right on time.</vi> <vi>I made it to the bus stop just when the bus was <it>pulling</it> away/out. [=was leaving]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move a vehicle from or to a particular place <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Look both ways before <it>pulling</it> out (into traffic).</vi> <vi>It's a tight squeeze, so be careful <it>pulling</it> in.</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> into the parking space.</vi> <vi>We'll have to <it>pull</it> off the highway.</vi> <vi>She <it>pulled</it> away from the curb and into traffic.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He slowly <it>pulled</it> the car into traffic.</vi> <vi><it>Pull</it> the car into the garage.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a car, wheel, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to move to the left or right instead of straight ahead when traveling forward <vi>I need to get the alignment of the car fixed because when I drive it <it>pulls</it> [=<it>drifts</it>] to the right/left.</vi> <vi>The wheel <it>pulls</it> left.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to move (your body or a part of your body) in a particular direction or to a particular position <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She wore her hair <it>pulled</it> back in a ponytail.</vi> <vi>At my age, it can be hard to <it>pull</it> yourself up from the couch.</vi> <vi>I tried to grab his hand but he <it>pulled</it> it away.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>When I leaned over to kiss her, she <it>pulled</it> away.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (a trigger, lever, etc.) in order to operate a device or machine <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the trigger, but the gun didn't fire.</vi> <vi>She dropped in a quarter and <it>pulled</it> the slot machine's lever.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to move a boat through water using oars :<sx>row</sx> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The crew <it>pulled</it> toward shore.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The crew <it>pulled</it> the boat toward shore.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove (someone or something) from a place or situation <vi>The pitcher was <it>pulled</it> (from the game) [=was taken out of the game] in the third inning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take (something) away <vi>The police <it>pulled</it> his driver's license for drunk driving. = He had his license <it>pulled</it> for drunk driving.</vi> <vi>The project was well-funded until a few companies <it>pulled</it> [=<it>withdrew</it>] their sponsorship.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (a weapon) out of a pocket or other hidden place <vi>He went into the store and <it>pulled</it> a gun on the cashier. [=took out a gun and pointed it at the cashier]</vi> <vi>Somone <it>pulled</it> a knife on him and threatened to stab him.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>They <it>pulled</it> [=<it>carried out</it>] a robbery.</vi> <vi>I <it>pulled</it> [=<it>worked</it>] two double shifts at the restaurant this week.</vi> <vi>She loved to <it>pull</it> [=<it>play</it>] tricks/jokes on her brother.</vi> <vi>Don't you ever <it>pull</it> a crazy stunt like that again!</vi> <vi>To finish my paper for class, I had to <phrase>pull an all-nighter</phrase>. [=stay awake all night working]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hurt (a muscle, tendon, or ligament) by stretching it too much <vi>She <it>pulled</it> [=<it>strained</it>] a muscle in her back when she tried to reach the top shelf.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to hit (a ball) toward the left from a right-handed swing or toward the right from a left-handed swing <vi>(<it>baseball</it>) He <it>pulled</it> the ball down the left-field line.</vi> <vi>(<it>golf</it>) She <it>pulled</it> her drive into the rough.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>push</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave like (a particular person) <vi>Whenever anyone forgot where they had parked the car, we'd say they “<it>pulled</it> a Dave.” [=they did something that Dave often does]</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to attract (someone) sexually <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He had a brief affair with a girl he <it>pulled</it> in a bar.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She's wearing a short skirt hoping it will help her <it>pull</it> tonight.</vi></dt> <snotebox>In addition to the phrases shown below, <it>pull</it> occurs in many idioms that are shown at appropriate entries throughout the dictionary. For example, <it>pull a face</it> can be found at <sc>face</sc>, <it>pull someone's leg</it> can be found at <sc>leg</sc>, and <it>pull the wool over someone's eyes</it> can be found at <sc>wool</sc>.</snotebox></def> <dro><dre>pull a fast one</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to deceive or trick someone <vi>Be careful. Someone might try to <it>pull a fast one</it> on you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to take the lead in a race, competition, contest, etc. <vi>The two runners were side by side until one <it>pulled ahead</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>pulled ahead</it> in the race.</vi> <vi>He has <it>pulled ahead</it> of the other candidates in the election polls.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull apart</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to be separated into parts or pieces by pulling <vi>The rolls <it>pull apart</it> easily.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (something) apart</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull apart (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to separate or break (something) into parts or pieces <vi>She <it>pulled</it> the rolls <it>apart</it> with her hands.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>His gambling problem is <it>pulling</it> the family <it>apart</it>. [=is destroying the family]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (people or animals) apart</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull apart (people or animals)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to separate (people or animals) in order to stop a fight <vi>Customers stepped in and <it>pulled</it> the two men <it>apart</it>. [=separated the two men who were fighting]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pull (someone) aside</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (someone) to one side away from other people for a private conversation <vi>The reporter <it>pulled</it> me <it>aside</it> and asked if I knew who was in charge.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pull at (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to hold onto and pull (something) repeatedly <vi>When she gets nervous, she <it>pulls at</it> [=<it>pulls on</it>] her ear.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to breathe in the smoke from (a cigarette, pipe, etc.) <vi>He rocked back and forth, <it>pulling at</it> [=<it>pulling on</it>] his pipe.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to begin to move farther ahead in a race, competition, contest, etc. <vi>They <it>pulled away</it> in the second half and won the game easily.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>In the final lap, he <it>pulled away from</it> the other cars and won.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to decide not to do something that you had intended to do or started to do <vi>The buyers of the house <it>pulled back</it> [=<it>pulled out</it>] at the last minute.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull back (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone or something) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move back from a place or position or to cause (someone or something) to move back from a place or position <vi>The soldiers were outnumbered and were forced to <it>pull back</it>. [=<it>retreat, withdraw</it>]</vi> <vi>The general <it>pulled</it> his army <it>back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull back (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to score (a goal, point, etc.) so that you are not as far behind in a game as you were before <vi>They were behind 2–0 but they <it>pulled back</it> a goal [=they scored a goal to make the score 2–1] early in the second half.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) down</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move (something) down <vi>I <it>pulled down</it> the shade.</vi> <vi>He always wears his baseball cap <it>pulled down</it> over his eyes.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to destroy (a building) completely <vi>The wreckers <it>pulled down</it> [=<it>demolished</it>] the building.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (something) smaller in amount or number :to reduce or lower (something) <vi>The rumors that the company was filing for bankruptcy <it>pulled</it> stock prices <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull down (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become sad or depressed <vi>The loss really <it>pulled</it> the team <it>down</it>. [=brought the team down]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull down (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to earn (a particular and usually large amount of money) <vi>He <it>pulls down</it> [=<it>makes, pulls in</it>] more than a million dollars a year.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get (something) <vi>The show has <it>pulled down</it> high ratings.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pull for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say or show that you hope (someone or something) will succeed, get well, etc. <vi>I hope you're feeling better soon. We're all <it>pulling for</it> you (to get well).</vi> <vi>I'm <it>pulling</it> [=<it>rooting</it>] <it>for</it> the home team.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to arrive at a place and come to a stop <vi>“When are our guests coming?” “I think they just <it>pulled in</it>.”</vi> <vi>The train <it>pulled in</it> on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull in (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone or something) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attract (someone or something) <vi>We hope the display will <it>pull</it> customers <it>in</it> from the street.</vi> <vi>She's trying to <it>pull in</it> more votes.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull in (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>pull (something) in</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to earn (a particular and usually large amount of money) <vi>After just a couple of years at the firm, she was <it>pulling in</it> [=<it>pulling down, making</it>] more than $100,000.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (someone) to a police station :to arrest (someone) <vi>The police <it>pulled</it> him <it>in</it> for questioning.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>pull off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) from something else :to take off (something) <vi>He <it>pulled off</it> the covers of the bed.</vi> <vi>She <it>pulled</it> her boots <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do (something difficult) successfully <vi>We were doubtful the plan would work, but he managed to <it>pull</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>The team <it>pulled off</it> a win/upset.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to hold onto and pull (something) repeatedly <vi>When she gets nervous, she <it>pulls on</it> [=<it>pulls at</it>] her ear.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to breathe in the smoke from (a cigarette, pipe, etc.) <vi>He rocked back and forth, <it>pulling on</it> [=<it>pulling at</it>] his pipe.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull on (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) on</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to dress yourself in (clothing) <vi>She quickly <it>pulled on</it> [=<it>put on</it>] her clothes/sweater.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to decide not to do something that you had intended to do or started to do <vi>The buyers of the house <it>pulled out</it> at the last minute.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave a place or position or to cause (someone or something) to leave a place or position <vi>The invading army was outnumbered and was forced to <it>pull out</it>. [=<it>withdraw</it>]</vi> <vi>Military leaders have decided to <it>pull</it> the troops <it>out</it> of the war zone.</vi> <vi>Organizations are <it>pulling out</it> of the country [=are leaving the country] due to threats of civil war.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pullout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move a vehicle to the side of the road and stop <vi>Let's <it>pull over</it> and look at the map.</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the car <it>over</it> to look at the map.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull over (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone or something) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (a driver or vehicle) to move to the side of the road and stop <vi>He was <it>pulled over</it> (by the police) for speeding.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to survive a serious illness, injury, operation, etc. <vi>We sat in the hospital waiting room praying that he would <it>pull through</it>. [=<it>live</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get through a difficult situation <vi>I'm sure that the company will <it>pull through</it>, just as it has in difficult times in the past.</vi> <vi>It was a bad time for my family, but we managed to <it>pull through</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (someone or something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help (someone or something) to continue to live or succeed in a dangerous or difficult situation <vi>His determination <it>pulled</it> him <it>through</it>.</vi> <vi>Outside financial help is needed to <it>pull</it> the company <it>through</it> its troubles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to work together as a group in order to get something done <vi>It was amazing to see so many people <it>pull together</it> to help the poor.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull together (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (someone or something) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (people or things) together and organize them in order to make or do something <vi>She managed to <it>pull</it> a team of researchers <it>together</it>.</vi> <vi>He started his research by <it>pulling together</it> all the available data.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull together (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (something) by bringing together different things <vi>The chef <it>pulled together</it> a menu of American and Italian cuisine.</vi> <vi>The boss asked her to <it>pull</it> a brief sales report <it>together</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (yourself) together</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become calm again :to control your emotions and behavior after you have been very upset, emotional, etc. <vi>I know you're upset, but you need to <it>pull yourself together</it>. [=<it>calm down</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move (something) up <vi>I <it>pulled up</it> the shade.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move (something) forward or into a position where it can be seen, used, etc. <vi><it>Pull up</it> a chair and make yourself comfortable.</vi> <vi>Give me a moment to <it>pull up</it> your file on the computer.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>pull up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop a vehicle at a particular place <vi>We <it>pulled up</it> in front of the house.</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled up</it> next to me at the stoplight.</vi> <vi>He <it>pulled</it> the car <it>up</it> in front of the house.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop suddenly before completing something <vi>A muscle spasm caused him to <it>pull up</it> halfway through the race.</vi> <vi>She started to answer and then <phrase>pulled up short</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>pull (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) severely for doing something <vi>Her boss <it>pulled</it> her <it>up</it> for/on being late.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="put[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">put</hw> <sound><wav>put00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpʊt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>puts</if></in> <in><if>put</if></in> <in><if>put*ting</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular place or position <vi>She <it>put</it> [=<it>placed, set</it>] the plant near the window.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the car in the garage.</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> the keys on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his arms around her and held her tight.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to go into or through something in a forceful way <vi>He fell and accidentally <it>put</it> his hand through a window.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be in a particular place or send (someone) to a particular place <vi>The illness <it>put</it> her in the hospital for three days.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her in prison for forgery.</vi> <vi>Her parents decided to <it>put</it> her in a special school for deaf children.</vi> <vi>If she drove 55 mph for 20 minutes, that would <it>put</it> her about halfway there by now.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to show that (someone or something) is in a particular place <vi>The evidence/report <it>puts</it> the defendant at the scene of the crime. [=it shows that the defendant was at the scene of the crime]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to write (something) with a pen or pencil in or on something <vi>Don't forget to <it>put</it> your signature on the check.</vi> <vi>He <it>put</it> his phone number on a napkin.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> a circle around the correct answer.</vi> <vi>I wrote that the answer was option B. What did you <it>put</it>?</vi> <vi>She had always dreamed of writing a novel, but she never actually <phrase>put pen to paper</phrase>. [=started writing]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a particular state or condition <vi>Not exercising <it>puts</it> you at greater risk of developing heart disease.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the TV on channel 5, please.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you in charge/command/control?</vi> <vi>I told her some jokes to <it>put</it> her in/into a good mood.</vi> <vi>His careless spending <it>put</it> him in/into debt.</vi> <vi>Their actions have <it>put</it> them in serious danger.</vi> <vi>Her reassuring words <phrase>put us at ease</phrase>. [=made us feel calm and relaxed]</vi> <vi><phrase>Put</phrase> that idea <phrase>out of your mind</phrase>. [=stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>They said they shot the injured horse to <phrase>put</phrase> it <phrase>out of its misery</phrase>. [=so that it would not continue to suffer]</vi> <vi>They have <phrase>put</phrase> their competitors <phrase>out of business</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The new technology could <phrase>put him out of a job</phrase>. = It could <phrase>put him out of work</phrase>. [=it could make him lose his job]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>putting</phrase> the children <phrase>to bed</phrase>. [=helping them get into their beds]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do work or perform a task <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>put</it> the kids <it>to</it> work cleaning the basement.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) <vi>They are ready to <it>put</it> the plan in action/motion.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> an idea into action/effect/practice</vi> <vi>The new weapon was immediately <phrase>put to use</phrase> by the military.</vi> <vi>I don't need this camera, but maybe you can <phrase>put it to good use</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to cause (something) to have an effect on someone or something <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>puts</it> [=<it>places</it>] great emphasis <it>on</it> the need for new leadership. [=he strongly emphasizes the need for new leadership]</vi> <vi>She has been <it>putting</it> pressure <it>on</it> us to finish the project early.</vi> <vi>Another child would <it>put</it> a heavy strain <it>on</it> their finances. [=would strain their finances very much]</vi> <vi>A special tax/duty/surcharge was <it>put on</it> luxury items.</vi> <vi>They want to <it>put</it> a limit <it>on</it> government spending.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to say or express (something) <vi>As she <it>put</it> it, “You can't please everyone.”</vi> <vi>How should I <it>put</it> this? I don't think you're cut out for this job.</vi> <vi>Well <it>put</it>!</vi> <vi>Let me <it>put</it> it another way.</vi> <vi>I think you're incompetent, <phrase>to put it bluntly</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It was a difficult experience, <phrase>to put it mildly</phrase>. [=it was a very difficult experience]</vi> <vi>She finds it hard to <phrase>put her feelings into words</phrase>. [=to say what her feelings are]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to ask (a question) or make (a suggestion) to someone <vi>Let me <it>put</it> this question to you [=let me ask you this question]: what do we do now?</vi> <vi>I <it>put</it> my plan/proposal before the board of directors for consideration.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to ask a group of people to formally vote on (something) <vi>They plan on <it>putting</it> the motion/resolution to a/the vote this afternoon.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to add music to (words) <vi>She writes the lyrics and he <it>puts</it> [=<it>sets</it>] them to music.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to throw (a shot put)</dt></def> <dro><dre>I wouldn't put it past (someone)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>past</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put about (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to tell many people about (something) <vi>They <it>put about</it> the news that he was resigning. = They <it>put</it> it <it>about</it> that he was resigning.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to change direction <vi>The ship <it>put about</it> and sailed back out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) about</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat or ship) to change direction <vi>a boat that can be <it>put about</it> quickly</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put across</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) across</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put across (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to get (something) across <vi>She has had trouble <it>putting</it> her message <it>across</it> to voters.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) across as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>He tries to <it>put himself across as</it> [=to make other people believe that he is] a nice guy.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put a foot wrong</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>She's been <it>putting aside</it> some money for a vacation.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>put</it> a few minutes <it>aside</it> for a short meeting?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop worrying or thinking about (something) <vi>We need to <it>put</it> these problems <it>aside</it> for now and get the work done.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>put aside</it> our differences and start working together.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to guess or estimate (something) to be (something) <vi>The coroner <it>put</it> his time of death <it>at</it> 7:00. [=the coroner estimated that the time of his death was 7:00]</vi> <vi>Recent estimates <it>put</it> the number of unreported cases <it>at</it> 2,000 each year.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put away</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> the pictures <it>away</it> for safekeeping.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> your notes <it>away</it>. It's time for the test.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to save or keep (something, such as money) to be used at a later time <vi>Her parents started <it>putting away</it> money for her education the year she was born.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to eat (a large amount of food) <vi>I used to <it>put away</it> huge meals before I went on a diet.</vi> <vi>That guy can really <phrase>put it away</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put away (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be kept in a prison or mental hospital <vi>He's a vicious criminal. I hope they <it>put</it> him <it>away</it> for the rest of his life.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>Remember to <it>put</it> the vacuum cleaner <it>back</it> in the closet after you've used it.</vi> <vi>The books had been <it>put back</it> neatly on the shelf.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to change (a planned event) to start at a later date or time <vi>They <it>put back</it> [=<it>pushed back</it>, <it>postponed</it>] the game until next week.</vi> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put back</it> from 1 p.m. to 3 p.m.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask (a person or group) to make a decision about (something) <vi>The problem of downtown parking was <it>put before</it> the mayor/council.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put</it> this question <it>before</it> the voters.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put behind</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) behind you</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop worrying about or being upset by (something that happened in the past) <vi>It was a disappointing loss, but we need to <it>put it behind us</it> and focus on winning the next game.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> the past <it>behind you</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put by (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to save (money) for a later time <vi>She has <it>put</it> some money <it>by</it> [=<it>put aside</it>] for emergencies.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) down</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>put down (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (someone or something that you have been holding or carrying) on a table, on the floor, etc. <vi>She carefully <it>put</it> the vase <it>down</it> on the table.</vi> <vi>The police ordered him to <it>put down</it> the gun.</vi> <vi>I don't need you to carry me. <it>Put</it> me <it>down</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to a list <vi>Don't forget to <it>put down</it> milk and bread on the shopping list.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say critical or insulting things about (someone or something) <vi>He frequently <it>puts down</it> her work.</vi> <vi>Her parents are always <it>putting</it> her <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>puts himself down</phrase> a lot, but he's really quite an attractive man.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-down</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to write (something) :to record (something) in writing <vi>She says that the reporter <it>put</it> her quote <it>down</it> incorrectly.</vi> <vi>Every night, he <it>puts</it> his thoughts <it>down</it> in a journal.</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put down</it> my thoughts on paper before I forget them.</vi> <vi>What answer did you <it>put down</it> on the test?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (an amount of money) as a first payment when you are buying something that costs a lot of money <vi>We <it>put</it> 10 percent <it>down</it> on the house. = We <it>put down</it> a 10 percent deposit on the house.</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> no money <it>down</it> and pay no interest on the car until next year.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to put (something) in place on the floor or ground <vi><it>Putting down</it> [=<it>installing</it>] a new hardwood floor would greatly increase the value of your home.</vi> <vi>We <it>put down</it> a layer of mulch in the rose garden.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop (a violent or dangerous activity) by using force <vi>Federal troops were brought in to help <it>put down</it> the riot.</vi> <vi><it>put down</it> a rebellion/revolt/uprising</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to kill (an animal) in a way that causes it little pain usually because it is injured or sick <vi>They had to have their dog <it>put down</it> [=<it>put to sleep</it>] by the vet.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to end a telephone connection <vi>She said goodbye and <phrase>put down the phone</phrase>. [=<it>hung up the phone</it>]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put the phone down on him</phrase>. [=she hung up the phone while he was still talking to her]</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to formally suggest (something) as an idea to be discussed and voted on by a group of people :to propose or introduce (something) <vi><it>putting down</it> an amendment in Parliament</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to land or to cause (an airplane) to land <vi>Our plane <it>put down</it> [=<it>landed</it>] in New York around 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The pilot was forced to <it>put</it> [=<it>set</it>] the plane <it>down</it> in a field.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to place (a baby or child) in a bed to sleep <vi>He <it>put</it> the baby <it>down</it> (in her crib) for a nap.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to think of (someone) as (a specified kind of person or thing) <vi>Most people <it>put</it> him <it>down as</it> [=believe that he is] a fanatic.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) down for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to write the name of (someone) on a list of people who will do or give (something) <vi>Can I <it>put you down for</it> a donation? [=can I write that you will give a donation?]</vi> <vi>Sure, <it>put me down for</it> $20.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) down to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say or think that (something) happened because of (something) <vi>Let's <it>put</it> the mistake <it>down to</it> your inexperience and forget about it.</vi> <vi>The mistake was <it>put down to</it> [=<it>attributed to</it>] his inexperience.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suggest (an idea, plan, etc.) for people to think about or consider <vi>The same argument has been <it>put forth</it> by many people in the opposition.</vi> <vi>I would like to <it>put forth</it> some alternatives.</vi> <vi><it>putting forth</it> a plan/proposal/theory</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (something, such as energy) for a particular purpose <vi>She <it>put forth</it> all her energy to win the race.</vi> <vi>They <it>put forth</it> a good effort.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to produce or send out (something) by growing <vi>The trees are starting to <it>put forth</it> new leaves.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to suggest (something) for consideration :<sx>propose</sx> <vi>He <it>put forward</it> [=<it>put forth</it>] a theory about how the accident may have occurred.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) ready to be used in a certain place :<sx>install</sx> <vi>We <it>put in</it> new cabinets just last year.</vi> <vi>In order to fix the car they have to <it>put in</it> a new engine.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to add (a comment) to a conversation or argument <vi>She <it>put</it> a quick comment <it>in</it> about her busy schedule.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> a few words on his behalf. [=to say something that supports him]</vi> <vi>Would you mind <phrase>putting in a good word for</phrase> me? [=would you say something good about me?]</vi> <vi>You will each have a chance to <phrase>put in your two cents</phrase>. [=to express your opinion]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make an official statement, offer, or request <vi>She <it>put in</it> a plea of not guilty. [=she pleaded not guilty]</vi> <vi>I need to <it>put in</it> [=<it>make, submit</it>] a report about this.</vi> <vi>You have two weeks to <it>put in</it> [=<it>submit</it>] a claim with the insurance company.</vi> <vi>They are <it>putting in</it> [=<it>making</it>] a $300,000 offer for the house.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>put in</it> [=<it>place</it>] an order for a dozen roses.</vi> <vi>Contractors have begun <it>putting in</it> bids for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to perform (a particular action) <vi>They <it>put in</it> an amazing performance last night.</vi> <vi>The prime minister <phrase>put in a call to</phrase> [=<it>called</it>] the White House.</vi> <vi>I won't be able to stay at the party long, but I'll at least try to <phrase>put in an appearance</phrase>. [=to go to the party for a short time]</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to work or do something for (an amount of time) <vi>She <it>put in</it> 10 hours at the office yesterday.</vi> <vi>She <it>put in</it> a long day at work.</vi> <vi>He has <it>put in</it> his time (in jail), and now he is a free man.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing something <vi>If we <it>put in</it> a little more effort, we could finish by this afternoon.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>in</it> his performances.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to invest (money) into (something) <vi>She <it>put</it> her money <it>in</it> stocks and bonds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what causes you to have faith, confidence, etc. <vi>He <it>puts</it> his faith <it>in</it> reason/science.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> her trust <it>in</it> God</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ask for (something) in an official way :to formally request (something) <vi>He <it>put in for</it> a leave of absence.</vi> <vi><it>putting in for</it> a promotion</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to enter a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put in</it> at Sydney.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>put (something) into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (a certain amount of energy or effort) when doing (something) <vi>He <it>puts</it> a lot of energy <it>into</it> his performances.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>put her heart into</phrase> (writing) the letter. [=she expressed her feelings in a very open and honest way]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to invest (time, money, etc.) in (something) <vi>They <it>put</it> their entire life savings <it>into</it> the company.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> a lot of money <it>into</it> (fixing up) that house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put it there</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>put her there</va></vr> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to invite someone to shake hands with you <vi><it>Put her there</it>, pal!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that (something) will happen at a later time :<sx>postpone</sx> <vi>The meeting has been <it>put off</it> until next week. = We <it>put off</it> (holding) the meeting until next week.</vi> <vi>I've been meaning to call him, but I keep <it>putting</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>putting off</it> calling him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to wait <vi>I need to come up with an excuse to <it>put off</it> the bill collector.</vi> <vi>She finally called him after <it>putting</it> him <it>off</it> all week.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to dislike someone or something <vi>Don't let the restaurant's dingy appearance <it>put</it> you <it>off</it>—their food is great.</vi> <vi>I was <it>put off</it> by his rudeness.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) His rudeness <phrase>put me off him</phrase> [=made me dislike him] at once.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>off-putting</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to allow (someone) to get off a bus or other vehicle <vi>Could you <it>put</it> [=<it>let</it>] me <it>off</it> (the bus) at the next stop, please?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to dress yourself in (clothing) <vi>She <it>put on</it> her new dress.</vi> <vi><it>Put on</it> a hat and gloves.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>put</it> some clothes <it>on</it> and be right there.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to apply (something) to your face or body <vi><it>putting on</it> lipstick/mascara/lotion</vi> <vi>She <it>puts on</it> far too much makeup.</vi> <vi>We tried to <phrase>put on a happy/brave face</phrase> [=we tried to appear happy/brave] despite our concern.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to add to or increase the amount of (something) <vi>The fire was getting low and we needed to <it>put on</it> more wood.</vi> <vi>She <it>put on</it> [=<it>gained</it>] 40 pounds during her pregnancy.</vi> <vi>He's <it>put on</it> some weight recently.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause (a machine, a light, etc.) to begin to work <vi>Would you mind if I <it>put</it> [=<it>turned</it>] the TV <it>on</it>?</vi> <vi>Somebody <it>put on</it> the lights.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to be heard, seen, produced, etc. <vi><it>put on</it> a record/CD/album</vi> <vi><it>putting on</it> some music</vi> <vi>We <it>put on</it> the air-conditioning/heat in the car.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to start cooking or making (something) <vi>Let me know when to <it>put on</it> the rice.</vi> <vi>He <it>put on</it> a pot of coffee for his guests.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to produce (something that entertains people, such as a play, a party, etc.) <vi>They're <it>putting on</it> a concert.</vi> <vi>He always <it>puts on</it> a great show/performance.</vi> <vi>The town <it>puts on</it> a fireworks display every Independence Day.</vi> <vi>We are <it>putting on</it> a barbecue for everyone in the neighborhood.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to say that (someone or something) is responsible for or guilty of (something) <vi>Responsibility for the accident was <it>put on</it> the other driver.</vi> <vi>He <it>puts</it> much of the blame for his problems <it>on</it> the government.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bet (an amount of money) on (someone or something) <vi>We <it>put</it> $2 <it>on</it> the favorite to win.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> money <it>on</it> horse races</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (someone or something) to (a list or group of related things) <vi>She asked to have her name <it>put on</it> the list of candidates.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> the list.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> several new dishes <it>on</it> the menu.</vi> <vi>“Bartender, I'll have another beer.” “Okay, I'll <it>put</it> it <it>on</it> your bill.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say things that are not true to (someone) in a joking way :to trick or fool (someone) for amusement <vi>He said he knew the President, but I think he was just <it>putting me on</it>. [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>having me on</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>put-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you would like to speak to someone on the phone <vi>Hi Dad. Could you <it>put</it> Mom <it>on</it>? [=could you give Mom the phone so that I can speak to her?]</vi> <vi><it>Put</it> Dave <it>on</it> the phone, please.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to tell (someone) to use or do (something) <vi>Her doctor <it>put</it> her <it>on</it> medication. [=her doctor prescribed medication for her]</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>put</it> himself <it>on</it> a diet. [=to go on a diet]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (someone) information about (something) :to tell (someone) about (something that he or she did not know about before) <vi>A friend of mine <it>put</it> me <it>on to</it> this book in high school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to stop burning :<sx>extinguish</sx> <vi>She <it>put</it> the fire <it>out</it> by pouring water on it.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her cigarette in an ashtray.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from working <vi>Who <it>put out</it> [=<it>turned off</it>] the lights?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to take (something) outside and leave it there <vi>I <it>put</it> the dog <it>out</it> in the backyard before leaving the house.</vi> <vi><it>putting</it> horses <it>out</it> to graze</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the trash/garbage. = (<it>Brit</it>) Don't forget to <it>put out</it> the rubbish.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to extend (something) outward <vi>I <it>put out</it> my hand and he shook it eagerly.</vi> <vi>She <it>put out</it> her arm for them to stop.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to place (something) where people may use it <vi>He always <it>put out</it> a bowl of candy for the grandchildren.</vi> <vi>We should <it>put out</it> a few extra chairs in case more people arrive.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>This small radiator <it>puts out</it> a surprising amount of heat.</vi> <vi>They will have to <it>put out</it> considerable effort to meet the deadline.</vi> <vi>It was early spring, and the trees were just starting to <it>put out</it> their leaves.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available to be bought, used, etc. <vi>She plans to <it>put out</it> a new album in March.</vi> <vi>They need to be <it>putting out</it> cars that get better gas mileage.</vi> <vi>The information was given in a pamphlet <it>put out</it> by the university's health department.</vi> <vi>Researchers recently <it>put out</it> a report/study on the issue.</vi> <vi>The police have <it>put out</it> [=<it>issued</it>] a warrant for his arrest.</vi> <vi>Someone <phrase>put the word out</phrase> [=started telling people] that the police were looking for her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to annoy or bother (someone) <vi>All the attention didn't seem to <it>put</it> her <it>out</it> at all.</vi> <vi>I'm a little <it>put out</it> that no one called to tell me they would be late.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to do extra work :to cause trouble for (someone) <vi>I hope my visit didn't <it>put</it> you <it>out</it>. [=didn't inconvenience you]</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>put</it> yourself <it>out</it> just for us.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) unconscious <vi>The anesthesia <it>put</it> him <it>out</it> for a little over three hours.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be out in baseball or cricket <vi>The runner was <it>put out</it> at second base.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>putout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with someone <vi>Did she <it>put out</it> last night?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a boat or ship</ssl> <dt>:to leave a harbor or port <vi>The ship <it>put out</it> to sea.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be clearly understood :to put (something) across <vi>He <it>puts over</it> very complicated concepts in a way that his students can understand.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (yourself) over as (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (yourself) to appear to be (a particular type of person) <vi>She <it>puts herself over as</it> [=makes other people believe that she is] a modern, independent woman.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) over on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to lie about (something) to (someone) :to trick or deceive someone <vi>Don't try to <it>put</it> anything <it>over on</it> her. She'll see right through you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put paid to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>paid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put (someone) in mind of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to be accepted or done successfully <vi>They <it>put through</it> a number of reforms.</vi> <vi>tax cuts that were <it>put through</it> by former administrations</vi> <vi>I asked Human Resources to help me <it>put through</it> [=to help me get] a transfer to a different department.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to pay for (someone) to attend (school) <vi>She has a full-time job and is <it>putting</it> herself <it>through</it> college.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to experience (something) <vi>His doctor <it>put</it> him <it>through</it> a series of tests.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> her parents <it>through</it> a lot when she was a teenager.</vi> <vi>You've been <it>put through</it> quite an ordeal.</vi> <vi>I've been <it>put through</it> hell!</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> that truck <it>through</it> a lot when we owned it.</vi> <vi>The new software still needs to be <phrase>put through its paces</phrase> [=it still needs to be tested] before it can be made available to the public.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone or something) through</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put through (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause a phone call from (someone) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> you <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (a phone call) to be sent to another person's phone <vi>Please hold while I <it>put</it> your call <it>through</it> (to the manager).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put to death</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put together (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to create (something) by joining or gathering parts together <vi>You'll need a screwdriver to <it>put</it> the toy <it>together</it>.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> their first band <it>together</it> when they were in high school.</vi> <vi>Help me <it>put together</it> a list of what we need at the store.</vi> <vi>She <it>put</it> a proposal <it>together</it> to give to the committee for consideration.</vi> <vi>Her outfit was very well <it>put together</it>. [=the parts looked good together]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something is greater than the total of all the other people or things mentioned <vi>You're smarter than all of those other guys <it>put together</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) together with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add or combine (something) with (something) <vi>I never would have thought of <it>putting</it> this wine together <it>with</it> fish.</vi> <vi>The lack of rain <it>put together with</it> [=along with, combined with] the heat ruined many of the region's crops.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) in a higher position <vi>They <it>put up</it> the flag in the morning and take it down at night.</vi> <vi>Sit down. <it>Put</it> your feet <it>up</it> and relax.</vi> <vi>If you have a question, please <it>put up</it> [=<it>raise</it>] your hand.</vi> <vi>Stop! <it>Put</it> your hands <it>up</it> (over your head)!</vi> <vi>When she goes to work, she usually <it>puts</it> her hair <it>up</it> (in a ponytail).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to be on a wall, to hang from a ceiling, etc. <vi>She went around town <it>putting up</it> posters for the concert.</vi> <vi>I just <it>put up</it> new curtains.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to set or place (something) so that it stands up <vi><it>putting up</it> a tent</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a display of new products.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> a “for sale” sign in front of their house.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to build (something) <vi>They're <it>putting up</it> a new office building on Main Street.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a fence</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to make (something) available for people to buy or have <vi>The lamps were <it>put up</it> at auction.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>They <it>put</it> all of their possessions <it>up for</it> sale.</vi> <vi>They <it>put</it> the puppies <it>up for</it> adoption.</vi></un></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to provide (money, property, etc.) in order to pay for something <vi>They decided not to <it>put up</it> the money for her bail.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> the company's assets as collateral on the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as a prize <vi>The police have <it>put up</it> a $1,000 reward for information leading to his capture.</vi></dt> <sn>h</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to increase (something) :<sx>raise</sx> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> interest rates again this year.</vi></dt> <sn>i</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to return (something) to the place where it belongs <vi>It's time to <it>put up</it> [=<it>put away</it>] your toys and get ready for bed.</vi> <vi>He washed, dried, and <it>put up</it> the dishes after dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>j</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to preserve (fruits, vegetables, etc.) to be used later :<sx>can</sx> <vi>Their grandmother spent the afternoon <it>putting up</it> peaches.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do (something) as a way of resisting or struggling against someone or something <vi>We're not leaving without <it>putting up</it> a fight. [=without fighting]</vi> <vi>As expected, the kids <it>put up</it> a fuss when we said it was time for bed.</vi> <vi>They are likely to <it>put up</it> stiff resistance to any new proposals.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) as an argument, a suggestion, etc. <vi>She <it>put up</it> a good/solid argument in his defense.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> a proposal</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to score (points) <vi>They <it>put up</it> 20 points in the first half.</vi> <vi>She needs to <it>put up</it> big numbers [=to score a lot of points] in today's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give food and shelter to (someone) :to allow or pay for (someone) to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>Could you <it>put</it> me <it>up</it> for the night?</vi> <vi>His employers <it>put</it> him <it>up</it> at a hotel.</vi> <vi>We <it>put</it> our guests <it>up</it> in the spare bedroom.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stay in someone's home, a hotel, etc., for the night <vi>He <it>put up</it> with a friend while he was in town.</vi> <vi><it>putting up</it> at a hotel</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>put up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or suggest (someone) to be a candidate or competitor <vi>The party <it>put</it> her <it>up</it> (as its candidate) for governor.</vi> <vi>They <it>put up</it> their best man to compete against the champion.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>put (someone) up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to convince (someone) to do (something stupid or foolish) <vi>His friends <it>put</it> him <it>up to</it> (playing) the prank.</vi> <vi>Who <it>put</it> you <it>up</it> to this?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up with (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (someone or something unpleasant or annoying) to exist or happen :<sx>tolerate</sx> <vi>At this school, we will not <it>put up with</it> bad behavior.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>put up with</it> much more of this.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>put up or shut up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to tell someone in a somewhat rude way to start doing something or to stop talking about it <vi>You've complained long enough. It's time to <it>put up or shut up</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="set[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">set</hw> <sound><wav>set00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɛt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>sets</if></in> <in><if>set</if></in> <in><if>set*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to put (something) in a place or position <vi><it>Set</it> your books (down) on the table.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>set</it> some extra chairs around the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>set</it> the ladder against the wall and walked away.</vi> <vi>I remember <it>setting</it> my bag right here.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put (something) into the surface of something <vi>They <it>set</it> the bricks along the walkway.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) set</it> <vi>The posts <it>are set</it> firmly in the ground.</vi> <vi>The tiles <it>are set</it> into the wall.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to attach (something, such as a jewel) to a piece of jewelry or other decoration <vi>The jeweler can <it>set</it> the stone several different ways.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) set</it> <vi>Her wedding ring <it>is set</it> [=<it>inlaid</it>] with seven diamonds.</vi> <vi>a diamond <it>set</it> in a simple gold band</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause the action of (a film, story, etc.) to happen in a certain place or during a certain time <un>often used as <it>(be) set</it> <vi>The play <it>is set</it> in Verona, Italy. [=the action of the play takes place in Verona]</vi> <vi>The novel <it>is set</it> in 1943.</vi> <vi>a novel <it>set</it> during World War II</vi> <vi>The story <phrase>is set against</phrase> (the backdrop of) the Second World War. [=the story takes place during the Second World War]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) ready to be used :to put (something) in a position to be used <vi>He turned off the car and <it>set</it> the parking brake.</vi> <vi>Rangers will <it>set</it> a trap to catch the bear.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put plates, forks, spoons, knives, etc., on a table before serving a meal <vi>Would you please <it>set</it> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>lay</it>] the table?</vi> <vi>We <it>set</it> an extra place at the table for our guest.</vi> <vi>The table was <it>set</it> for two. [=it had two place settings]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a clock) to show a particular time <vi>We <it>set</it> the clocks ahead one hour for daylight saving time.</vi> :to cause the controls of (a clock or other device) to be in a particular position <vi>The alarm was <it>set</it> for 7:00 a.m. = The alarm was <it>set</it> to go off at 7:00 a.m.</vi> <vi>I <it>set</it> the timer for/to twenty minutes.</vi> <vi><it>Set</it> the oven to 350 degrees.</vi> <vi>In the winter, she <it>sets</it> the thermostat at/to 68 degrees.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to decide on or choose (something) <vi>I <it>set</it> a goal (for myself) to lose 15 pounds by the end of the year.</vi> <vi>The company must meet certain conditions <it>set</it> by the government in order to stay in business.</vi> <vi>She will be <it>setting</it> the agenda for this afternoon's meeting.</vi> <vi><it>setting</it> boundaries/limits/rules</vi> <vi>NASA has not yet <it>set</it> [=<it>named</it>] the date for the shuttle launch.</vi> <vi>He has <phrase>set his sights on</phrase> becoming [=he has decided to try to become] the next president.</vi> <vi>We don't have enough time to do everything. We have to <phrase>set priorities</phrase>. [=to decide which things are most important to do]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give (a particular price or value) to something <vi>An antiques appraiser <it>set</it> the value of the chair at $500.</vi> <vi>If you <it>set</it> your prices too high, no one will buy your products.</vi> <vi>Her bail was <it>set</it> at $10,000. = The judge <it>set</it> (her) bail at $10,000. [=the judge decided that she will have to pay $10,000 or stay in jail until her trial]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (a high value or importance) to something <vi>They <it>set</it> a high value on their privacy. [=they value their privacy very highly]</vi> <vi>Our family <phrase>sets great store by/on</phrase> tradition. [=our family believes that tradition is very important]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to be accepted as an example, rule, etc. :to establish (a standard, trend, etc.) for others to follow or try to copy <vi>They are improving the safety of their vehicles and <it>setting</it> a higher standard for other companies (to follow).</vi> <vi>His style of directing has <it>set</it> a new trend in moviemaking. [=other directors are copying his way of making movies]</vi> <vi>His behavior <phrase>sets a good/bad example</phrase> for the rest of the children.</vi> <vi>The ruling is likely to <phrase>set a precedent</phrase> for how future cases are decided. [=future cases will be decided based on this case]</vi> <vi>Her lighthearted question <phrase>set the tone</phrase> for the rest of the interview. [=it gave the rest of the interview a light and easy feeling]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to establish (a record) as the performance or achievement that is the best of its kind <vi>She <it>set</it> a record for the most sales in the company's history. [=she made more sales for the company than anyone else ever had]</vi> <vi>He <it>set</it> the world record for/in the 100-meter dash.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a specified condition <vi>The slaves were <it>set</it> free.</vi> <vi>He made a raft and <it>set</it> it afloat in the river.</vi> <vi>They <phrase>set</phrase> the house <phrase>on fire</phrase>. = They <phrase>set fire to</phrase> the house. = (more formally) They <it>set</it> the house afire/aflame/ablaze. [=they caused the house to begin burning]</vi> <vi>I wish I knew how to <phrase>set your mind at ease</phrase>. [=to help you stop worrying]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>set him right/straight</phrase> about what happened. [=she told him that he was wrong and explained what really happened]</vi> <vi>We should <phrase>set our own house in order</phrase> [=correct the way we do things] before we criticize them.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to start doing something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We have no idea what <it>set</it> [=<it>got</it>] her crying.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Her question <it>set</it> me <it>to</it> wondering if I had made the right decision.</vi> <vi>They are ready to <phrase>set</phrase> the plan <phrase>in motion</phrase>. [=they are ready to cause the plan to start happening]</vi> <vi>The plan has been <it>set in motion</it>.</vi> <vi>Sources say that the governor has <phrase>set the wheels in motion</phrase> for a run for the presidency. [=the governor has started to run for president]</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He immediately <phrase>set to work</phrase> [=started working] on the project.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to give (someone) a particular job :to require someone to do (a task) <vi>My boss <it>set</it> me to organizing the files.</vi> <vi>She <it>set</it> [=<it>assigned</it>] her students the task of writing a three-page report.</vi> <vi><it>setting</it> homework for the children</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to move down in the sky and go below the horizon <vi>We sat on the beach and watched the sun <it>set</it>.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>rise <dxn>5</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put and hold (your jaw, mouth, etc.) firmly into a certain position <vi>She crossed her arms, <it>set</it> her jaw, and refused to answer any questions.</vi> <vi>He <it>set</it> his lips firmly.</vi></dt> <sn>13 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a liquid</ssl> <dt>:to become thick or hard <vi>The gelatin needs a few hours to <it>set</it>.</vi> <vi>My nail polish is still <it>setting</it>.</vi> <vi>a quick-<it>setting</it> cement</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become permanent <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you don't wash your shirt right away, the stain will <it>set</it>. [=you will not be able to remove the stain]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Hot water will <it>set</it> the stain.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:to put (a broken bone) into its normal position so it can heal <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Doctors <it>set</it> her broken leg last week.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The bones will take several weeks to <it>set</it>. [=grow together]</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give a particular style to (someone's hair) by wetting it, putting it in curlers or clips, and drying it <vi>She gets her hair <it>set</it> and styled twice a week.</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to type or print (a word, sentence, etc.) in a particular form or style <vi>a word <it>set</it> in italics</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to add music to (words) :to create (music) to accompany words <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>She wrote the lyrics, and he <it>set</it> them <it>to</it> music.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>set about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>set about (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to do (something) <vi>They <it>set about</it> (the task of) creating a new Web site.</vi> <un>sometimes followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>They <it>set about to create</it> a new Web site.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (something) against (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to compare (something) to (something else) <vi>Let's <it>set</it> the advantages <it>against</it> the disadvantages.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) set against</it> <vi>The challenges of fixing the problem now must <it>be set against</it> the dangers of waiting until later to act.</vi> <vi>The fines were small when <it>set against</it> the company's huge annual profits.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>set <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to list (something) as an expense in order to reduce (income for which you must pay tax) <vi>You can <it>set</it> your mortgage payments <it>against</it> your rental income.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (yourself) against (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decide that you do not support (something or someone) :to be or become opposed to (something or someone) <vi>She <it>set herself against</it> the prevailing beliefs of the time.</vi> <vi>He has <it>set himself against</it> (joining) them.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone) against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to disagree with or oppose (someone) <vi>The incident <it>set</it> brother <it>against</it> sister.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set apart</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone or something) apart</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be a quality that makes (someone or something) better than or different from other people or things <un>usually + <it>from</it> <vi>What <it>set</it>s her <it>apart</it> (<it>from</it> the other teachers) is her great passion for her work.</vi> <vi>His great height <it>set</it> him <it>apart from</it> the other men in his family.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (something) apart</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep or save (something) for a particular purpose <un>often used as <it>(be) set apart</it></un> <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>A few acres of the city <it>were set apart for</it> a park.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>set (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move (something) to the side because you are not working on it, dealing with it, etc. <vi>Mix the dry ingredients in a small bowl and <it>set</it> the mixture <it>aside</it>.</vi> :to wait until later to use or deal with (something) <vi>I've <it>set</it> your memo <it>aside</it> for now but I'll read it this afternoon.</vi> <vi>The committee <it>set aside</it> discussion of the proposal until their next meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep or save (something) for a particular purpose <vi>The hotel <it>set aside</it> [=<it>set apart</it>] 20 rooms for the guests of the bride and groom.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>set</it> some money <it>aside</it> for our vacation.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop thinking about, talking about, or being affected by (something) <vi>They decided to <it>set aside</it> their differences and work together.</vi> <vi><it>Setting aside</it> the fact that the meal was extremely expensive, dinner was very enjoyable.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to change or reverse (a legal decision, conviction, etc.) <vi>The verdict was <it>set aside</it> [=<it>overturned</it>] by the court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (something or someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set back (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make the progress of (something or someone) slower or more difficult :to cause (something or someone) to go back to an earlier or worse condition <vi>A recent lack of funding has <it>set back</it> research on the disease.</vi> <vi>If the law is reversed, it will <it>set</it> us <it>back</it> 20 years. [=it will undo 20 years of progress]</vi> <vi><it>setting back</it> progress</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone) back</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>cost</sx> <vi>A new suit will <it>set</it> you <it>back</it> at least $200.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>set down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to create or establish (a rule, requirement, etc.) <vi>All participants must follow the guidelines <it>set down</it> [=<it>established</it>] by the organization.</vi> <vi>Once she <it>sets down</it> the rules, there's no changing her mind.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to record (something) by writing it down <vi>She took out her notebook and started <it>setting down</it> her thoughts.</vi> <vi>When an idea for a song comes to me, I <it>set</it> it <it>down</it> on paper.</vi> <vi><it>setting</it> an agreement <it>down</it> in writing</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to land (an airplane) on the ground or water <vi>We had to <it>set</it> the plane <it>down</it> in a field.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (someone) to get off a bus, airplane, etc. <vi>I asked the taxi driver to <it>set</it> me <it>down</it> [=<it>drop me off</it>, (<it>US</it>) <it>let me off</it>] in front of the library.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set foot in/on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set forth</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to begin a journey <vi>We will <it>set forth</it> [=<it>set out</it>] at dawn.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set forth (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set (something) forth</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to explain or describe (something) in an organized way <vi>The author <it>sets forth</it> [=<it>states</it>] the book's premise in its first two pages.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set forward</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>set (something) forward</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set forward (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to explain or describe (something) so that it can be considered <vi>She has <it>set forward</it> [=<it>presented</it>] an ambitious plan to fix the nation's health-care system.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to begin to be present, seen, etc. <un>used of something unpleasant or unwanted that often lasts for a long time <vi>The kids should go outside and play before the rain <it>sets in</it> again.</vi> <vi>An infection <it>set in</it> after the surgery.</vi> <vi>Reality was starting to <it>set in</it>. [=become obvious] We were not going to win.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set in stone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set loose</dre> <dx>see <tag>let loose</tag> at <dxt>loose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin traveling in a particular direction <vi>We <it>set off</it> for home.</vi> <vi>They <it>set off</it> in a different direction.</vi> <vi>In the first chapter, the hero <it>sets off</it> on a long voyage across the ocean.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set off (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>set (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to start or happen <vi><it>set off</it> an explosion</vi> <vi>Her comments <it>set off</it> [=<it>touched off</it>] a chain of events that led to two people losing their jobs.</vi> <vi>The incident <it>set off</it> a debate about how public land should be used.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>set off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set (something) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin making noise <vi>The thick smoke <it>set off</it> the school's fire alarms.</vi> <vi>Your watch will probably <it>set</it> the metal detectors <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (fireworks, a bomb, etc.) to explode <vi>They were accused of <it>setting off</it> the bomb that destroyed the building.</vi> <vi>It was <it>set off</it> by remote control.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (something) easy to see or notice <vi>The blue in your sweater <it>sets off</it> [=<it>accents</it>] your eyes.</vi> <vi>Bright yellow police tape <it>set off</it> the area where the crime occurred.</vi> <vi>a quote <it>set off</it> by quotation marks</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to suddenly start yelling, crying, laughing, etc. <vi>I wonder what <it>set</it> her <it>off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>set (someone or something) on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (a person or animal) suddenly attack (someone) <vi>Police dogs were <it>set on</it> the protesters.</vi> <vi>She <it>set</it> her friends <it>on</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to begin traveling in a particular direction <vi>We got out of the car and <it>set out</it> for the nearest gas station.</vi> <vi>They <it>set out</it> toward the east.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to start doing something :to begin an activity or effort with a particular plan or purpose <vi>She <it>set out</it> with the goal of going to the Olympics.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She accomplishes whatever she <it>sets out</it> [=<it>intends</it>] <it>to do</it>.</vi> <vi>I never <it>set out to hurt</it> you. [=I was not trying to hurt you]</vi> <vi>He <it>set out to become</it> a lawyer but ended up teaching history instead.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to explain or describe (something) <vi>In the article, the group <it>sets out</it> the role of parents in a child's education.</vi> <vi>He <it>set out</it> the basic argument between the two groups.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move and organize (a group of things) so that they can be seen or used <vi>We'll need to <it>set</it> a few extra chairs <it>out</it> for our guests.</vi> <vi>They <it>set out</it> maps and travel brochures for the tourists to take.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set pen to paper</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pen</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set sail</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sail</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set the pace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set the record straight</dre> <dx>see <dxt>record</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set the scene</dre> <dx>see <dxt>scene</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set the stage</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stage</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set to</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to begin doing something in an active and serious way <vi>We <it>set to</it> and soon finished the work.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to prepare for something by putting things where they need to be <vi>We have one hour left to <it>set up</it> for the party.</vi> <vi>We had better start <it>setting up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>set up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set (something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to create or establish (something) for a particular purpose <vi>A panel needs to be <it>set up</it> to investigate the issue.</vi> <vi>She hopes that in a few years she can <it>set up</it> a private practice of her own.</vi> <vi>A foundation was <it>set up</it> for people with the disease.</vi> <vi>The church <it>set up</it> a school for the city's homeless children.</vi> <vi>The hikers <phrase>set up camp</phrase> [=they prepared an area where they could sleep outside] just before sunset.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrange and plan (an event or activity) <vi>I'll ask my secretary to <it>set up</it> a meeting with our clients.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>set up</it> a time to get together.</vi> <vi>He was the one who <it>set up</it> the bank robbery.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to put (something) in an upright position <vi>They <it>set up</it> flags along the street for the parade.</vi> <vi>Help me <it>set</it> the tent <it>up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to make (a machine, system, etc.) ready to be used <vi>They <it>set up</it> the movie camera next to the door.</vi> <vi>This computer wasn't <it>set up</it> to run so many programs at one time.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>set up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be in a bad situation or to appear guilty <vi>Those aren't his drugs. Someone must have <it>set</it> him <it>up</it>! [=framed him; made it look like the drugs were his]</vi> <vi>He claimed he was <it>set up</it> by the police.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to help (someone) feel healthy and full of energy <vi>She says that daily exercise has <it>set</it> her <it>up</it> to face the challenges of getting old.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to give (someone) a job, a place to live, etc. <vi>She <it>set</it> me <it>up</it> in a great apartment in the city.</vi> <vi>He <it>set</it> his son <it>up</it> with a job at his company.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to do something that makes it likely or possible for (someone) to do, get, or experience something <vi>The team's excellent defense <it>set</it> them <it>up</it> to score the winning touchdown.</vi> <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>I think you're just <it>setting</it> yourself <it>up for</it> a big disappointment. [=you're expecting something that won't happen and you will be disappointed when it doesn't]</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to meet someone in order to start a romantic relationship <vi>“How did you first meet your husband?” “My best friend <it>set</it> us <it>up</it>.”</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>She wants to <it>set</it> him <it>up with</it> her sister.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>set (yourself) up as (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to try to make people believe that you are (something) <vi>She has <it>set herself up as</it> the best alternative to the current administration.</vi> <vi>He <it>sets himself up as</it> a defender of the people, but he's really only interested in getting more power.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>also</vl> <va>set up as (something)</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>set up in (something)</va></svr> <dt>:to start your own business <vi>She <it>set</it> (<it>herself</it>) <it>up as</it> a wedding planner. [=she began working as a wedding planner]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>set up in business</phrase> after finishing college.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>setup</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set up house</dre> <dx>see <dxt>house</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>set (someone or something) upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone or something) <un>often used as <it>(be) set upon</it> <vi>The protesters <it>were set upon</it> by police dogs.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set up shop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set your heart on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set your mind to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>set your teeth on edge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tooth</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
