<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="assume"> <hw highlight="yes">as*sume</hw> <sound><wav>assume01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈsu:m</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>as*sumes</if></in> <in><if>as*sumed</if></in> <in><if>as*sum*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to think that something is true or probably true without knowing that it is true <vi>I <it>assumed</it> he was coming, so I was surprised when he didn't show up.</vi> <vi>“Is he coming?” “So I <it>assume</it>.” = “I <it>assume</it> so.”</vi> <vi>I think we can safely <it>assume</it> that he's coming. = I think it's safe to <it>assume</it> that he's coming.</vi> <vi>She <it>assumed</it> from his expression that he was confused.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>assume</it> [=<it>suppose</it>] (that) she rejects your invitation. What will you do then? = <it>Assuming</it> (that) she rejects your invitation, what will you do? [=what will you do if she rejects your invitation?]</vi> <vi>We'll be arriving around noon. That's <it>assuming</it> that our flight is on time.</vi> <vi>The study <it>assumes</it> that the problem develops after birth. [=the study does not consider the possibility that the problem may begin before birth]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to begin (a role, duty, etc.) as a job or responsibility <vi>She <it>assumed</it> the presidency. = She <it>assumed</it> the position of president.</vi> <vi><it>assume</it> [=<it>take</it>] office</vi> <vi>The king <it>assumed</it> the throne when he was very young.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take or begin to have (power, control, etc.) in a job or situation <vi>He is ready to <it>assume</it> [=<it>take</it>] control of the organization.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin to have (a particular appearance or quality) <vi>The last game of the season <it>assumes</it> much greater importance now. [=it becomes much more important now]</vi> <vi>Their financial problems <it>assumed</it> huge proportions. [=grew to be very serious]</vi> <vi>The sky gradually <it>assumed</it> [=<it>took on</it>] an otherworldly glow.</vi> <vi>Under certain conditions, the chemical will <it>assume</it> the appearance of ice.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to make yourself have (an appearance that does not show your true feelings) in order to deceive someone <vi>She immediately <it>assumed</it> a look of innocence. [=she had an expression on her face that made her look innocent, even though she wasn't]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to place yourself in (a particular position or posture) <vi>She <it>assumed</it> a sitting position [=she sat down] on the floor.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to accept (a responsibility, debt, etc.) <vi>When they purchased the company they had to <it>assume</it> [=<it>take on</it>] its debts.</vi> <vi><it>assume</it> liability</vi> <vi>The city <it>assumes</it> greater financial risk with that plan.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
