<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="at"> <hw highlight="yes">at</hw> <sound><wav>at000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæt, ət</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the place where someone or something is <vi>We're staying <it>at</it> a hotel.</vi> <vi>The kitchen is <it>at</it> the back of the house.</vi> <vi>He was sitting <it>at</it> the table.</vi> <vi>They left for Cambridge early and arrived <it>at</it> [=<it>in</it>] Cambridge before noon.</vi> <vi>The party will be <it>at</it> Susan's house. = The party will be <it>at</it> Susan's.</vi> <vi>Ann works <it>at</it> [=<it>in</it>] a library.</vi> <vi>We met <it>at</it> a party.</vi> <vi>They live <it>at</it> opposite ends of town.</vi> <vi>They met <it>at</it> [=<it>on</it>] a street corner in a town.</vi> <vi>“Is your father <it>at</it> home?” [=is your father home?] “No, he's working late <it>at</it> the office.”</vi> <vi>She met us <it>at</it> the door.</vi> <vi>He was standing <it>at</it> [=next to] the window.</vi> <vi>There were 200 people <it>at</it> the wedding. [=200 people attended the wedding]</vi> <vi>Their older son has graduated, but their younger son is still <it>at</it> school. [=is still attending school]</vi> <vi>Who was <it>at</it> the controls when the accident occurred?</vi></un></dt> <snotebox>The word <phrase>at</phrase> is used in speech in e-mail addresses. <vi>“Can I e-mail you?” “Sure. Our e-mail address is ‘comments <it>at</it> Merriam-Webster dot com.’”</vi> In writing, the symbol @ is used instead. <vi>comments@Merriam-Webster.com</vi></snotebox> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the person or thing toward which an action, motion, or feeling is directed or aimed <vi>She pointed her gun <it>at</it> the target.</vi> <vi>He's angry <it>at</it> his brother.</vi> <vi>His anger is directed <it>at</it> his brother.</vi> <vi>She shouted (words of) abuse <it>at</it> me.</vi> <vi>He looked directly <it>at</it> me.</vi> <vi>They laughed <it>at</it> him.</vi> <vi>She grabbed <it>at</it> my arm. [=she tried to grab my arm]</vi> <vi>He poked <it>at</it> his food.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate something that is being tried or attempted <vi>I made an attempt <it>at</it> persuading him to go.</vi> <vi>I took a shot <it>at</it> doing it myself. [=I tried to do it myself]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:because of or in reaction to (something) <vi>They laughed <it>at</it> my joke.</vi> <vi>She's furious <it>at</it> how slowly the investigation is proceeding.</vi> <un>used to indicate the cause of an action, feeling, etc. <vi>I was greatly surprised <it>at</it> [=<it>by</it>] the result. [=the result surprised me greatly]</vi> <vi>He enlisted in the army <it>at</it> his father's urging. [=because his father urged him to]</vi> <vi>She visited the museum <it>at</it> my suggestion.</vi> <vi>They came here <it>at</it> our invitation.</vi> <vi>You can act <it>at</it> your own discretion.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an activity <vi>He's very serious when he's <it>at</it> work. [=when he's working]</vi> <vi>children who are <it>at</it> play [=children who are playing]</vi> <vi>She's good <it>at</it> (playing) chess. [=she plays chess well]</vi> <vi>I'm bad <it>at</it> cooking. [=I'm a bad cook, I do not cook well]</vi> <vi>She's doing very well <it>at</it> her studies.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a situation or condition <vi>I'm not <it>at</it> liberty to discuss that.</vi> <vi><it>at</it> rest</vi> <vi>two nations that are <it>at</it> war</vi> <vi>people who are <it>at</it> risk</vi> <vi>He is now <it>at</it> peace.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate position on a scale or in a series <vi>The temperature is <it>at</it> 90 degrees.</vi> <vi>He was driving <it>at</it> almost 80 miles an hour.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a rate <vi>They sell <it>at</it> [=<it>for</it>] a dollar a dozen. [=each dozen costs one dollar]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an age or time <vi>He plans to retire <it>at</it> (age) 65.</vi> <vi>He called us <it>at</it> (about/exactly) 9 o'clock on July 24.</vi> <vi><it>at</it> dawn/noon/sunset/night</vi> <vi>I still think of her <it>at</it> certain moments/times.</vi> <vi>He was president of the company <it>at</it> (the time of) his death.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate the method by which something is done <vi>The property was sold <it>at</it> auction.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>at best</phrase>, <phrase>at worst</phrase>, etc., to indicate a possible result or condition that is considered best, worst, etc. <vi>The company will make a small profit <it>at best</it> this year. [=it is not possible that the company will earn anything better/more than a small profit]</vi> <vi>We might be 5 or 10 minutes late <it>at worst</it>. [=we will not be more than 5 or 10 minutes late]</vi> <vi>We should arrive by noon <it>at the latest</it>. [=we should not arrive later than noon]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>at its best</phrase>, <phrase>at its worst</phrase>, etc., to indicate that something or someone is as good, bad, etc., as possible <vi>This is baseball <it>at its best</it>.</vi> <vi>He's often rude, and last night he was <it>at his worst</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at it</dre> <def><dt>:doing some activity <vi>I didn't expect her to have started working yet, but she was already (hard) <it>at it</it> when I arrived. [=she was already working (hard) when I arrived]</vi> <vi>My neighbors are always arguing, and they were <it>at it</it> again last night. [=they were arguing again last night]</vi> <vi>Since we're cleaning the kitchen, we should wash the floor <phrase>while we're at it</phrase>. [=we should wash the floor when we clean the kitchen]</vi> <vi>“I'm going to the store to buy a newspaper.” “<it>While you're at it</it>, could you get some milk?”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at that</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>where it's at</dre> <dx>see <dxt>where</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>where (someone) is at</dre> <dx>see <dxt>where</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="all[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">all</hw> <altpr>ˈɑ:l</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the entire number, quantity, or amount <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] that I have is yours.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> [=<it>everything</it>] will be explained soon.</vi> <vi>She told us <it>all</it> about what happened.</vi> <vi>Her other books were good, but this one is the best of <it>all</it>.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> are welcome! [=everyone is welcome]</vi> <vi>We <it>all</it> enjoyed the movie. = <it>All</it> of us enjoyed the movie.</vi> <vi>Many people were invited and <it>all</it> came.</vi> <vi>His stories may be entertaining, but I don't think <it>all</it> (of them) are true.</vi> <vi>Thanks to <it>all</it> who helped out.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> of this money will be yours when I die.</vi> <vi>Not <it>all</it> of our students go on to college.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>was all (that) I could do</phrase> to keep from laughing! [=I had a hard time trying not to laugh]</vi> <vi>“Is there anything else to be done?” “No, <phrase>that's all</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He gave equal attention to <phrase>one and all</phrase>. [=to everyone]</vi> <vi><phrase>Come one, come all</phrase>. [=everyone is invited to come]</vi> <usageref>altogether</usageref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the only thing <vi>That's <it>all</it> I can do to help.</vi> <vi><it>All</it> I know is that the game was canceled. I don't know why.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>after all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>after</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>All aboard!</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aboard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all in all</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a general way :when everything is thought of or considered <vi><it>All in all</it> [=<it>in general, generally, for the most part</it>], I like the way things have gone.</vi> <vi>We did lose some money, but we got most of it back. So <it>all in all</it> things might have been a lot worse.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all told</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>The cost of the repairs came to about $300 <it>all told</it>. [=<it>in all</it>] [=the total cost of the repairs was about $300]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>and all</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:and everything else <vi>What with the noise outside, the fire <it>and all</it>, we got hardly any sleep.</vi> <vi>He endured everything, insults <it>and all</it>, without getting angry.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to emphasize a response <vi>“It's really hot out!” “It is <it>and all</it>!” [=it certainly is]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to make a statement or question more forceful <vi>He will go anywhere <it>at all</it> to get a job.</vi> <vi>Did you find out anything <it>at all</it>?</vi></un> <un>used especially in negative statements <vi>“Did she say anything?” “No, nothing <it>at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't mind cooking <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>at all</it> what you think it is. It's something else entirely.</vi> <vi>I wasn't tired <it>at all</it>. = I wasn't <it>at all</it> tired. [=I wasn't even slightly tired]</vi> <vi>This chair is not <it>at all</it> comfortable.</vi> <vi>I didn't like it <it>at all</it>.</vi> <vi>That is not <it>at all</it> likely.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>not at all</phrase> is sometimes used as a polite response when someone thanks you. <vi>“Thank you for all your trouble.” “<it>Not at all</it>.”</vi> <vi>“That was very kind of you.” “<it>Not at all</it>. It was the least I could do.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>for</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all I know</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <dx>see <dxt>care</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your all</dre> <def><dt>:to do or give as much as you can to achieve something, to support a cause, etc. <vi>He <it>gave his all</it> for the cause. = He <it>gave his all</it> to help the cause.</vi> <vi>You'll never succeed in this business unless you <it>give (it) your all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all</dre> <def><dt>:including everything or everyone <un>used to indicate a total <vi>There were about a thousand people at the concert <it>in all</it>. [=<it>all told</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>once and for all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>once</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>that is all</dre> <dx>see <dxt>that</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>when all is said and done</dre> <def><dt>:after considering or doing everything <un>used for a final general statement or judgment <vi>It won't be easy, but <it>when all is said and done</it>, we'll be glad we did it.</vi> <vi>The candidates claim to have different views but, <it>when all is said and done</it>, they're very much alike.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="any[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">any</hw> <sound><wav>any00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛni</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a person or thing that is not particular or specific <vi>Ask <it>any</it> man you meet, and he will tell you the same thing.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> one of them could have answered the question.</vi> <vi>You can return the product if <it>any</it> defect appears within the first six months.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> plan (at all) is better than no plan.</vi> <vi><it>Any</it> [=<it>every</it>] child knows that. [=all children know that]</vi> <vi>He is as good as <it>any</it> other pitcher in the league.</vi> <vi>We can meet <it>any</it> day but Monday.</vi> <vi>You could have seen him <it>any</it> afternoon last week.</vi> <vi>The recipe uses a large amount of pepper, and <phrase>not just any</phrase> pepper, but a special blend imported from India.</vi> <vi>You have to be a member to go there. They won't let <phrase>just any</phrase> person in.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate an amount greater than zero or none</un> <un>usually used in negative statements, in questions, and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it> <vi>You haven't eaten <it>any</it> salad. [=no salad has been eaten]</vi> <vi>I can't find <it>any</it> stamps.</vi> <vi>Don't pay <it>any</it> attention to him.</vi> <vi>There is hardly <it>any</it> difference between the two teams.</vi> <vi>They dropped by without <it>any</it> warning.</vi> <vi>We don't want there to be <it>any</it> misunderstandings.</vi> <vi>The company has denied <it>any</it> [=<it>all</it>] responsibility for the accident.</vi> <vi>There are <phrase>few if any</phrase> [=few or no] details about the accident.</vi> <vi>Do you have <it>any</it> money?</vi> <vi>He asked if/whether you had <it>any</it> money.</vi> <vi>If there are <it>any</it> errors, report them to me. = Report <it>any</it> errors to me.</vi> <vi>If you can give me <it>any</it> help, I'd appreciate it. = I'd appreciate <it>any</it> help you can give me.</vi></un></dt> <usage><it>Some</it> is used instead of <it>any</it> in positive statements. <vi>I have <it>some</it> money.</vi> It is sometimes used instead of <it>any</it> in questions and in statements with <it>if</it> or <it>whether</it>. <vi>Do you have <it>some</it> money?</vi> <vi>If I had <it>some</it> money, I would spend it on books.</vi></usage></def> <dro><dre>any moment</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moment</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <dx>see <dxt>old</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at any cost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>by any chance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go to any length/lengths</dre> <dx>see <dxt>length</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any case</dre> <dx>see <dxt>case</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in any event</dre> <dx>see <dxt>event</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="arm[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">arm</hw> <sound><wav>arm00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑɚm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>arms</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:either one of the two long body parts that join the top of your body at the shoulder and that end at the hand or wrist <vi>He has big, strong, muscular <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>She broke her left <it>arm</it>. = Her left <it>arm</it> was/got broken.</vi> <vi>He hurt his throwing/pitching <it>arm</it> [=the arm that he uses to throw/pitch a ball] in the last game.</vi> <vi>She put/threw her <it>arms</it> around him. [=she hugged him]</vi> <vi>She had a newspaper tucked under her <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was carrying a bag of groceries in each <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He gave/offered his <it>arm</it> to her, and she took it. [=she held onto his arm]</vi> <vi>She grabbed my <it>arm</it>. = She grabbed me by the <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>He was standing there with his <it>arms</it> crossed/folded.</vi> <vi>She stood with her <it>arms</it> outstretched. = She stood with her <it>arms</it> wide open.</vi> <vi>She sat cradling the baby in her <it>arms</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her since she was <phrase>a babe in arms</phrase>. [=a baby who is too young to walk and has to be held]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her in/into his arms</phrase> [=he embraced her] and kissed her passionately.</vi> <vi>She found him <phrase>in the arms of</phrase> [=being embraced by] another woman.</vi> <vi>He showed up at the party with a young woman <phrase>on his arm</phrase>. [=holding his arm]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>took her (by the) arm</phrase> and they walked in to dinner.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the part of a piece of clothing (such as a shirt or coat) that covers the arm :<sx>sleeve</sx> <vi>The jacket's <it>arms</it> are too tight. = The jacket is too tight in the <it>arms</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a part of a piece of furniture (such as a chair or couch) that gives support for a person's arm <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the sofa</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>armchair</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:a long thin piece that is connected to the main part of a machine, structure, etc., and that looks or moves like a human arm <vi>the robot's mechanical <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the machine's robotic <it>arm</it></vi> <vi>the <it>arm</it> of the record player</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long and narrow area of water <vi>an <it>arm</it> of the sea</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the part of a group or organization that performs a specific job or function <un>usually singular <vi>the organization's political <it>arm</it> [=the part of the organization that deals with politics]</vi> <vi>It is the most powerful <it>arm</it> [=<it>division</it>] of the organization.</vi> <vi>the military <it>arm</it> of the government</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a person's ability to throw a ball <un>usually singular <vi>Their pitcher's got a great <it>arm</it>.</vi> <vi>a strong/weak <it>arm</it></vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>an arm and a leg</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a very large amount of money <vi>It's a reliable car, and it doesn't cost <it>an arm and a leg</it>. [=it isn't too expensive]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>arm in arm</dre> <def><dt>:next to each other with the arm of one person linked at the elbow to the arm of another person <vi>an elderly couple walking down the street <it>arm in arm</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a shot in the arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as long as someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>long</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at arm's length</dre> <def><dt>:from a distance that is the length of a person's arm <vi>It's best to view the painting <it>at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>holding a candle <it>at arm's length</it></vi> <snote>To <phrase>keep someone or something at arm's length</phrase> is to avoid being very close to or friendly with someone or something. <vi>Since going to college, he has <it>kept his old friends at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>They no longer trust her and are <it>keeping her at arm's length</it>.</vi> <vi>The government has <it>kept the group at arm's length</it> until now.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chance your arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give your right arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>give</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the long arm of the law</dre> <def><dt>:the ability of the police to find and catch people who commit crimes <vi><it>The long arm of the law</it> finally caught up with him [=the police caught him] 30 years later.</vi> <vi>So far, she's been able to escape <it>the long arm of the law</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>twist someone's arm</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twist</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with open arms</dre> <def><dt>:in a very kind and friendly way <vi>We were welcomed back <phrase>with open arms</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>arm</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="attention"> <hw highlight="yes">at*ten*tion</hw> <sound><wav>attent01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtɛnʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>at*ten*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act or power of carefully thinking about, listening to, or watching someone or something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>We focused our <it>attention</it> on this particular poem.</vi> <vi>My <it>attention</it> wasn't really on the game.</vi> <vi>The game was boring and my <it>attention</it> began to wander. [=I was losing interest in the game and started thinking about other things]</vi> <vi>You need to <phrase>pay more attention</phrase> in school.</vi> <vi>Please give me your <phrase>undivided/full/complete attention</phrase>. [=please listen carefully and concentrate on what I am saying and doing]</vi> <vi>The movie <phrase>keeps/holds your attention</phrase> [=<it>interest</it>] right to the very end.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Her job requires careful <it>attention to</it> detail.</vi> <vi>You need to <phrase>pay more attention to</phrase> the teacher.</vi> <vi><phrase>Don't pay any attention to</phrase> what the other kids say. [=ignore what the other kids say]</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>turn/give our attention to</phrase> the next project.</vi> <vi><phrase>Pay (close/careful) attention to</phrase> what he says.</vi></un> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Lately she's been focusing her <it>attentions</it> on making sales.</vi> <snote>This sense is sometimes used as an interjection. <vi><it>Attention</it>, please! [=please give me your attention]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:notice, interest, or awareness <vi>She likes all the <it>attention</it> she is getting from the media/press.</vi> <vi>The actor avoids drawing <it>attention</it> to himself.</vi> <vi>The book has received/attracted national <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The trial is getting a lot of public <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The children were competing for the teacher's <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>A cat on a leash is sure to attract <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>Your hard work and dedication have not <phrase>escaped my attention</phrase>. [=I have noticed your hard work and dedication]</vi> <vi>The book's title <phrase>grabbed/caught my attention</phrase>. [=the title caused me to look at the book]</vi> <vi>He was trying to <phrase>divert/distract attention</phrase> away from his friend's mistake. [=he was trying to keep people from noticing or thinking about his friend's mistake]</vi> <vi>We tried to <phrase>attract/get your attention</phrase> [=we tried to get you to see us], but you didn't hear us calling you.</vi> <vi>Thank you for <phrase>bringing the matter to my attention</phrase>. [=making me aware of the matter]</vi> <vi>It has been <phrase>brought to my attention</phrase> [=I've been made aware] that the meeting has been canceled.</vi> <vi>I would like to <phrase>call/bring your attention to</phrase> a problem we are having.</vi> <vi>It <phrase>came to my attention</phrase> [=I noticed] that several items were missing from my office.</vi> <vi>It has <phrase>come to my attention</phrase> [=I have been made aware] that some people were offended by my comments.</vi> <vi>He loves being the <phrase>center of attention</phrase>. [=he loves being noticed and watched by many people]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:special care or treatment <vi>Be sure the dog gets plenty of <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The house is in good shape, but the porch needs some <it>attention</it>.</vi> <vi>The victim needed immediate medical <it>attention</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>attentions</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:acts of kindness, care, or courtesy :acts that show affection or admiration for someone <vi>She found his <it>attentions</it> flattering.</vi> <vi>She has been receiving unwanted <it>attentions</it> from a coworker.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way a soldier stands with the body stiff and straight, the feet together, and both arms at the sides <un>often used as a command <vi><it>Attention</it>!</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at attention</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>to attention</va></svr> <dt>:standing silently with the body stiff and straight, the feet together, and both arms at the sides <vi>(<it>US</it>) The troops <phrase>stood at attention</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) The troops stood <phrase>to attention</phrase>.</vi> <dx>compare <tag>at ease</tag> at <dxt>ease</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a position that shows careful listening or attention <vi>The dog sat <it>at attention</it>, listening for something in the distance.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="back[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">back</hw> <sound><wav>back0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>backs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the rear part of the body :the part of the body that is opposite to the stomach and chest and that goes from the neck to the top of the legs <vi>She was carrying her little daughter on her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He injured his <it>back</it>. = He suffered a <it>back</it> injury.</vi> <vi>She has a pain in the small of her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>an aching <it>back</it></vi> <vi>I slapped/patted him on his/the <it>back</it> to congratulate him.</vi> <vi>He broke his <it>back</it> [=<it>spine</it>] in a fall.</vi> <vi>She stabbed/shot him in the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He was handcuffed with his hands behind his <it>back</it>.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an animal that is like a person's back <vi>a bird with a spotted <it>back</it></vi> <vi>riding on the <it>back</it> of a horse/donkey/camel</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>horseback</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something that is opposite the front or face :the rear side or surface of something <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>back</it> of the head</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of a mirror/spoon</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of the hand/leg/foot</vi> <vi>The book has fallen down the <it>back</it> of the couch.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something (such as a piece of paper) that is not usually used or seen first <un>usually singular <vi>She wrote something on the <it>back</it> of an envelope.</vi> <vi>He signed his name on the <it>back</it> of the check.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a place, position, or area that is at or near the rear of something <un>usually singular <vi>He put the letter in the <it>back</it> of the drawer.</vi> <vi>The kitchen is at/in the <it>back</it> of the house and the living room is at/in the front.</vi> <vi>Since our plane was leaving soon we were moved to the front of the line while others remained at the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>Please move to the <it>back</it> of the elevator to make room for others.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of a chair or seat that supports a person's back <vi>a comfortable chair with a padded <it>back</it></vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the section of a book, magazine, etc., that includes the last pages <un>usually singular <vi>There is an index in the <it>back</it> of the book.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a book's cover that can be seen when the book is on a shelf <vi>The title of the book is shown on its <it>back</it>. [=<it>spine</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a player in some games (such as soccer and American football) who is positioned behind the front line of players <vi>a defensive <it>back</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fullback</dxt> <dxt>halfback</dxt> <dxt>quarterback</dxt> <dxt>running back</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a pat on the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a stab in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at/in the back of your mind</dre> <def><dt>:in the part of your mind where thoughts and memories are kept <un>used to describe ideas, memories, etc., that someone has but that are not usually thought about or not perfectly remembered <vi>The thought of retiring and moving out into the country has been <it>in the back of her mind</it> for many years, and now she's finally doing it.</vi> <vi>Somewhere <it>in the back of my mind</it> I knew I'd met him before.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back is to/against the wall</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your back is to/against the wall</it> or <it>you have your back to/against the wall</it> you are in a bad position in which you are forced to do something in order to avoid failure. <vi><it>With our backs to the wall</it> we made a last desperate effort to finish the project on time.</vi> <vi>We knew that with so little time and money left to finish the project <it>we had our backs to the wall</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to back</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with backs opposite or against each other <vi>The soldiers stood <it>back to back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:happening one after the other <vi>She won the annual competition two times <it>back to back</it>. [=<it>in a row</it>]</vi> <vi>He's had two victories <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <vi>I've scheduled two appointments <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back-to-back</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to front</dre> <def><sl>of a piece of clothing</sl> <dt>:with the back where the front should be <vi>He accidentally put the sweater on <it>back to front</it>. [=<it>front to back, backwards</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>behind someone's back</dre> <def><dt>:without someone's knowledge :in secret <vi>You shouldn't gossip about people <it>behind their back(s)</it>.</vi> <vi>If you have something to say, why not say it to my face instead of whispering it <it>behind my back</it>?!</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went behind his back</phrase> and spoke directly to his supervisor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break the back of</dre> <def><dt>:to get control of (something you are trying to stop or defeat) :to greatly weaken or subdue (something) <vi>He says the government's new policies will <it>break the back of</it> inflation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your back up</dre> <def><dt>:to become angry or annoyed and want to fight or argue <vi>He <it>gets his back up</it> and becomes defensive whenever someone questions his work.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>put someone's back up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>watch someone's back <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in back</dre> <def><dt>:in an area at the back of something <vi>There was only room for one passenger in front. The rest of us sat <it>in back</it>. [=<it>in the back</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in back of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:directly behind (something or someone) <vi>There's a small yard <it>in back of</it> the house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the back of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:because of (something) <vi>Profits have increased <it>on the back of</it> [=<it>on the strength of</it>] improved international sales.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>disapproving</ssl> <dt>:by using the efforts of (other people) <vi>The company has achieved record profits <it>on the back of</it> cheap labor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/off your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who is always or frequently criticizing you or telling you what to do is <it>on your back</it> and won't <phrase>get off your back</phrase>. <vi>He says his wife is always <it>on his back</it> about doing chores around the house.</vi> <vi><it>Get off my back</it>! I'm working as hard as I can!</vi> <vi>My boss is always criticizing me. I wish I knew some way to <it>get him off my back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>(flat) on your back</it> you are lying with your back against the ground, on a bed, etc. <vi>The accident left him (lying) <it>flat on his back</it> (in bed) for two weeks.</vi> This phrase is sometimes used figuratively. <vi>The stock market has been <it>flat on its back</it> [=has been doing very poorly] in recent weeks.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out back</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>out the back</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>round the back</va></vr> <def><dt>:in the area behind something (such as a building) <vi>In my youth we didn't have a toilet in the house but there was one <it>out back</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put someone's back up</dre> <def><dt>:to offend or annoy someone :to make someone angry or ready to argue <vi>I don't want to question his decision because that will just <it>put his back up</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>get your back up <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your back into</dre> <def><dt>:to work very hard at (something) :to put a lot of effort into (something) <vi>If you want to get that floor clean you'll have to <it>put your back into</it> it.</vi> <vi>You'll really have to <it>put your back into</it> this project if you want it to succeed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>scratch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the back of</dre> <def><dt><snote>In British English, to be <phrase>glad/happy (etc.) to see the back of</phrase> someone is to be glad to see someone finally going away. <vi>He's done nothing but make trouble and I'll be <it>glad to see the back of</it> him! [=I'll be glad when he has gone]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stab (someone) in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the shirt off your back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shirt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn your back</dre> <def><dt>:to turn so that you are facing away from someone <vi>He <it>turned his back</it> and walked away from me.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>turned his back on</it> me and walked away.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His former supporters have <it>turned their backs on</it> him. [=have abandoned him]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch someone's back</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>have someone's back</va></vr> <def><dt>:to protect someone who is doing something that is dangerous or risky <vi>The police officer's partner always <it>watches his back</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't worry, <phrase>I've got your back</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If people tell you to <it>watch your back</it>, they are telling you to be careful. <vi>I hear the boss is in a bad mood this morning, so you'd better <it>watch your back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>back*less</ure> <sound><wav>back0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>backless</it> evening gown</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bat[1]"> <art><artref id="bat.eps"/><capt/><dim>80,116</dim></art> <hw hindex="1">bat</hw> <sound><wav>bat00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a long rounded stick that is used to hit the ball in baseball <vi>a baseball <it>bat</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a long flattened stick that is used to hit the ball in cricket</dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>paddle <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <vi>a table tennis <it>bat</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at bat</dre> <def><sl>baseball</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the player or team that is batting <vi>He got a home run on his first time <it>at bat</it>.</vi> <vi>It's the bottom of the first inning and the home team is <it>at bat</it>. [=is batting]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of batting <vi>She has two hits in three <it>at bats</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to bat</dre> <def><sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:to be the player or team that is batting <vi>The visiting team <it>goes to bat</it> first. [=the visiting team bats first]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to bat for</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to try to help, support, or defend (someone or something) in an active way <vi>Many of his friends <it>went to bat for him</it> while he was under investigation for fraud.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the bat</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:without any delay :<sx>immediately</sx> <un>usually used with <it>right</it> <vi>I could tell it was fake <phrase>right off the bat</phrase>. [=<it>right away</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off your own bat</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:through your own efforts <vi>He didn't need my help—he made good <it>off his own bat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bat</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bay[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bay</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɪ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>at bay</dre> <def><dt>:in the position of being unable to move closer while attacking or trying to approach someone <un>used with <it>keep</it> or <it>hold</it> <vi>The soldiers <it>kept the attackers at bay</it>. [=they did not allow the attackers to come closer]</vi> <vi>Armed with a gun, he <it>held the police at bay</it> [=he did not allow the police to arrest him] for 10 hours.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Although the doctors had been able to <it>keep her illness at bay</it> [=to prevent her illness from becoming worse] for a few months, the disease soon began to spread again.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bay</dxt> <dxt>bay</dxt> <dxt>bay</dxt> <dxt>bay</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="beck[1]"> <hw hindex="1">beck</hw> <sound><wav>beck0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>at someone's beck and call</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>at the beck and call of someone</va></vr> <def><dt>:always ready to do whatever someone asks <vi>He expects his employees to be <it>at his beck and call</it> day and night.</vi> <vi>She is <it>at the beck and call of</it> the committee.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>beck</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="beck[2]"> <hw hindex="2">beck</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>becks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>brook</sx></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>beck</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
