<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attack[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">at*tack</hw> <sound><wav>attack01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtæk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>at*tacks</if></in> <in><if>at*tacked</if></in> <in><if>at*tack*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to act violently against (someone or something) :to try to hurt, injure, or destroy (something or someone) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>attacked</it> the guard with a knife.</vi> <vi>Troops <it>attacked</it> the fortress at dawn.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) attacked</it> <vi>He <it>was attacked</it> by a dog.</vi> <vi>He <it>was attacked</it> from behind by two men.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Suddenly, the dog <it>attacked</it>.</vi> <vi>The troops <it>attacked</it> at dawn.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to criticize (someone or something) in a very harsh and severe way <vi>The study has been <it>attacked</it> as unscientific. [=people have criticized the study by saying that it is unscientific]</vi> <vi>People are <it>attacking</it> the mayor for breaking campaign promises.</vi> <vi>The professor has been widely <it>attacked</it> for her position on the issue.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to begin to work on or deal with (something, such as a problem) in a determined and eager way <vi>We eagerly <it>attacked</it> the problem. [=we eagerly tried to solve the problem]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin to eat (food) eagerly <vi>Did you see the way the kids <it>attacked</it> that pizza?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to harm, injure, or destroy (something) <vi>The virus <it>attacks</it> the body's immune system.</vi> <vi>A number of trees have been <it>attacked</it> by the disease.</vi> <vi>Insects have <it>attacked</it> the crops.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to try to score points or goals by moving forward in a very forceful way <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The team <it>attacked</it> from the outset, so it was no surprise that they won.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The offense <it>attacked</it> the weak defensive line.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>at*tack*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>at*tack*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>She was able to identify her <it>attacker</it>, and he was later brought to trial.</vi> <vi>The defense trapped the <it>attacker</it> and got the ball back.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="attack[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">attack</hw> <altpr>əˈtæk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>attacks</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a violent, harmful, or destructive act against someone or something <vi>dog/shark <it>attacks</it> = <it>attacks</it> by dogs/sharks</vi> <vi>One of the patients was the victim of a knife <it>attack</it>. [=an attack made using a knife]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>There have been a number of <it>attacks on</it> women on the campus.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:harmful or destructive action against something by a disease, insect, chemical, etc. <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The immune system is the body's defense against <it>attack</it> by germs.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The spray protects plants from <it>attacks</it> by many common pests.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an attempt by a military force to defeat an enemy :a military offensive <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>an air/ground <it>attack</it> = an <it>attack</it> made from the air/ground</vi> <vi>The surprise <it>attack</it> came at dawn.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There is a threat of nuclear <it>attack</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:strong or severe criticism <vi>There have been many <it>attacks</it> against the professor for her position on the issue.</vi> <vi>a verbal <it>attack</it></vi> <vi>The newspaper editorial is an <it>attack</it> on policy-makers.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sudden short period of suffering from an illness or of being affected by a strong emotion <vi>an asthma <it>attack</it></vi> <vi>a panic/anxiety <it>attack</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>an <it>attack of</it> the flu</vi> <vi>an <it>attack of</it> food poisoning</vi> <vi>an <it>attack of</it> nerves/melancholy</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>an <it>attack of</it> the giggles</vi> <vi>He had an unexpected <it>attack of</it> goodness and helped us out.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>heart attack</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an attempt to destroy or end something <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>City leaders have called for an <it>attack on</it> poverty.</vi> <vi>Local schools are mounting an <it>attack on</it> racism.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a method of dealing with something (such as a problem) <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Each problem calls for a different <it>attack</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The current approach isn't working. I think we need a new <phrase>plan of attack</phrase>. [=a new idea of how to do what we are trying to do]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an attempt by a player or group of players to score points, goals, or runs <un>usually singular <vi>They had a sustained <it>attack</it> but could not score.</vi> <vi>The players carried the <it>attack</it> deep into the opponent's side of the field.</vi> <vi>They won the game in the last two innings with an 8-hit <it>attack</it>. [=they won the game by getting eight hits in the last two innings]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the players on a team who try to score :<sx>offense</sx> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>The team's <it>attack</it> has been weakened by injury.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He will play <phrase>in attack</phrase>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>on offense</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>on the attack</dre> <def><dt>:making an attack <vi>The soldiers were <it>on the attack</it>. [=were attacking the enemy]</vi> <vi>The team was <it>on the attack</it> [=was aggressively trying to score] for most of the first half.</vi> <vi>The team <phrase>went on the attack</phrase> [=began to attack] and quickly scored a goal.</vi> <vi>The candidate <it>went on the attack</it> and accused his opponent of lying.</vi> <vi>Opponents of the project <it>went on the attack</it> and defeated the land sale.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>under attack</dre> <def><dt>:being affected or hurt by an attack :being attacked <vi>The troops were <it>under attack</it> [=were being attacked by the enemy] throughout the day.</vi> <vi>The troops suddenly <phrase>came under attack</phrase>. [=began to be attacked]</vi> <vi>The new policy has <it>come under attack</it> [=has been strongly criticized] by environmentalists.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="attack[3]"> <hw hindex="3">attack</hw> <altpr>əˈtæk</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:designed for or used in a military attack <vi>an <it>attack</it> helicopter/submarine</vi> <vi>The bombers were in <it>attack</it> formation.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="attack dog"> <hw>attack dog</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ dogs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a dog that has been trained to attack people</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a person who is known for making very harsh and personal criticisms of other people <vi>The charges against the candidate were made by one of the governor's <it>attack dogs</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="heart attack"> <hw>heart attack</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tacks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a sudden painful and dangerous condition in which your heart stops beating properly <vi>Her chest pains turned out to be caused by a minor <it>heart attack</it>.</vi> <vi>He died of a massive <it>heart attack</it>.</vi> <vi>He fell off the swing and <phrase>nearly gave me a heart attack</phrase>. [=scared me very badly]</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
