<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="attempt[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">at*tempt</hw> <sound><wav>attemp01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈtɛmpt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>at*tempts</if></in> <in><if>at*tempt*ed</if></in> <in><if>at*tempt*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to try to do (something) :to try to accomplish or complete (something) <vi>They've <it>attempted</it> a climb up Mount Everest once before.</vi> <vi>She <it>attempted</it> suicide early in their marriage.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Do not <it>attempt to repair</it> the equipment without the proper tools.</vi> <vi>The book <it>attempts to prove</it> that they were not guilty.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>attempted</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>attempted</it> robbery/murder/suicide</vi></utxt></uro> <syns><sc>attempt</sc>, <sc>try</sc>, <sc>endeavor</sc>, and <sc>strive</sc> mean to make an effort to do or accomplish something. <sc>attempt</sc> is a basic word that sometimes stresses the beginning of this kind of effort. <vi>He will <it>attempt</it> to photograph the rare bird.</vi> <sc>try</sc> is very close to <sc>attempt</sc> but often stresses effort that is made to test or prove something. <vi>The team is <it>trying</it> to determine which fuel is less efficient overall.</vi> <sc>endeavor</sc> is a more formal word that usually suggests a serious and continuing effort. <vi>As a teacher, he <it>endeavors</it> to inspire a love of learning in his students.</vi> <sc>strive</sc> suggests effort made over a long period of time in order to accomplish something difficult. <vi>Despite setbacks, we must continue to <it>strive</it> for peace.</vi></syns></entry>

	<entry id="attempt[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">attempt</hw> <altpr>əˈtɛmpt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>attempts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an act of trying to do something <vi>In an <it>attempt</it> [=<it>effort</it>] to raise money, the school will begin charging admission to school concerts.</vi> <vi>She failed her driving test on the first <it>attempt</it> but she succeeded on her second <it>attempt</it>.</vi> <vi>We both <phrase>made an attempt</phrase> [=<it>tried</it>] to be friendly despite recent arguments.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made no attempt</phrase> to apologize. [=he did not try to apologize]</vi> <vi>It was a successful <it>attempt at</it> climbing Mount Everest. = It was a successful <phrase>attempt on</phrase> Mount Everest.</vi> <snote><it>Attempt</it> often suggests that the effort made was unsuccessful. <vi>a suicide <it>attempt</it></vi> <vi>an assassination <it>attempt</it></vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that results from trying to do something <vi>Her <it>attempt</it> at a home-cooked meal consisted of frozen fish sticks and a can of soup.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>an attempt on someone's life</dre> <def><dt>:an act of trying to kill someone :a usually unsuccessful effort to kill someone <vi>Police report that there has been <it>an attempt on the actor's life</it>.</vi> <vi>Someone <phrase>made an attempt on her life</phrase>. [=someone tried to kill her]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
