<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="authority"> <hw highlight="yes">au*thor*i*ty</hw> <sound><wav>author07.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈθorəti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>au*thor*i*ties</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the power to give orders or make decisions :the power or right to direct or control someone or something <vi>Only department managers have the <it>authority</it> [=<it>right, power</it>] to change the schedule.</vi> <vi>Does he have the <it>authority</it> to do this? = (<it>US</it>) Does he have <it>authority</it> to do this?</vi> <vi>This office has <it>authority</it> over personnel matters. [=this office has the power to make decisions about personnel matters]</vi> <vi>You don't have <it>authority</it> over me. [=you don't have the power to give me orders]</vi> <vi>The boss is not popular but his <it>authority</it> is unquestioned.</vi> <vi>“Who gave him the <it>authority</it> to do this?” “He didn't do it <phrase>on his own authority</phrase> [=he didn't do it on his own]; he was acting <phrase>under the authority of</phrase> the company president.” [=the company president gave him the power to do it]</vi> <vi>No one <phrase>in authority</phrase> objected to the plan. = No one <phrase>in a position of authority</phrase> objected to the plan. [=no one with official power to make important decisions objected to the plan]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>figure of authority</phrase> = an <phrase>authority figure</phrase> [=a person who has authority over other people]</vi> <synref>power</synref></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the confident quality of someone who knows a lot about something or who is respected or obeyed by other people <vi>She has an air of <it>authority</it>.</vi> <vi>She spoke <phrase>with authority</phrase> [=<it>authoritatively</it>] about the history of the building.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a quality that makes something seem true or real <vi>His sincerity added much more <it>authority</it> [=<it>credibility</it>] to the story.</vi> <vi>Her southern accent lent <it>authority</it> to her performance.</vi> <vi>His opinions lacked <it>authority</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>authorities</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:people who have power to make decisions and enforce rules and laws <vi>We reported the incident to hospital <it>authorities</it>.</vi> <vi>Local <it>authorities</it> are investigating the accident.</vi> <un>often used with <it>the</it> <vi>He complained to <it>the authorities</it> [=the police] about the disturbance.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who is an expert on a subject <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>He is an <it>authority on</it> local history. [=he knows a lot about local history]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a government organization that has control of a specified activity or area <vi>She is the director of the city's housing <it>authority</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>have it on good/excellent authority</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have it on good/excellent authority</it> that something is true, you have been told that it is true by someone you trust and believe. <vi>I <it>have it on good authority</it> that she is writing a novel.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="local authority"> <hw>local authority</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ties</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:an organization that is in charge of the public services for a community</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="moral[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">mor*al</hw> <sound><wav>moral001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmorəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:concerning or relating to what is right and wrong in human behavior <vi>The church takes a strong stand on a number of <it>moral</it> [=<it>ethical</it>] issues.</vi> <vi>The author avoids making <it>moral</it> judgments.</vi> <vi><it>moral</it> arguments</vi> <vi>Each story teaches an important <it>moral</it> lesson.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:based on what you think is right and good <vi>He felt that he had a <it>moral</it> obligation/responsibility/duty to help the poor.</vi> <vi>He's a man with strong <it>moral</it> convictions. [=a man who believes strongly that some things are right and others are wrong]</vi> <vi>We're confident she has the <it>moral</it> fiber/fortitude to make the right decision.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>more mor*al; most mor*al</sgram> <dt>:considered right and good by most people :agreeing with a standard of right behavior <vi><it>moral</it> conduct</vi> <vi>Their behavior was not <it>moral</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>moral</it> young man [=a young man who tries to behave in a moral way]</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>amoral</dxt> <dxt>immoral</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:able to choose between right and wrong behavior <vi>Animals are not <it>moral</it> creatures and are not responsible for their actions.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>moral authority</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person, group, or organization that has <it>moral authority</it> is trusted to do what is right. <vi>The scandal has undermined the government's <it>moral authority</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>moral support</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who gives you <it>moral support</it> helps you by supporting or encouraging you rather than by giving you money or practical help. <vi>She counted on her sisters for <it>moral support</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>moral victory</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you achieve a <it>moral victory</it> you do not win anything but you achieve something that is important and good. <vi>Although they lost, the minority claimed the vote as a <it>moral victory</it> since they had won the support of so many former opponents.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
