<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bacon"> <hw>ba*con</hw> <sound><wav>bacon001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪkən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:thin strips of salted and smoked meat from the sides and the back of a pig <vi>We ate <it>bacon</it> and eggs for breakfast.</vi> <vi>a slice of <it>bacon</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a rasher of <it>bacon</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>bacon</it> fat</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring home the bacon</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to earn the money that is needed to live <vi>He worked hard all week to <it>bring home the bacon</it> for his family.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's bacon</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="Canadian bacon"> <hw>Canadian bacon</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:bacon from the back part of a pig that has little fat and that is cut into round slices</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="home[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">home</hw> <altpr>ˈhoʊm</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to or at the place where you live <vi>She called <it>home</it> to say she would be late for dinner.</vi> <vi>He's sending money <it>home</it> from a job overseas.</vi> <vi>She is on her way <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>It's great to be back <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) They're never <it>home</it> when I try to see them.</vi> <vi>I can't wait to <phrase>come/go/get home</phrase>.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) Let's <phrase>stay home</phrase> tonight. [=let's not go out tonight]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>brings/takes home</phrase> about $750 a week. [=the amount of money he gets after paying taxes, health insurance, etc., is about $750 each week]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:into a finished or final position <vi>He used a hammer to drive the nail <it>home</it>.</vi> <vi>shove the bolt <it>home</it> [=all the way into its place]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to, toward, or into a goal <vi>He fired the puck <it>home</it>. [=he shot the hockey puck into the goal]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring home the bacon</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bacon</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bring (something) home</dre> <def><dt>:to make (something) very clear and obvious in usually a forceful or unpleasant way <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>The importance of regular exercise was <it>brought home to him</it> when his best friend developed heart problems.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to home</dre> <dx>see <dxt>close</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come home to</dre> <def><dt>:to become very clear and obvious to (someone) in usually a forceful or unpleasant way <vi>The truth about her marriage <it>came home to her</it> when he left her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come home to roost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>drive your point home</dre> <def><dt>:to say something in a very strong or forceful way :to make a point very forcefully <vi>He <it>drove his point home</it> during the debate.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit/strike home</dre> <def><dt>:to become very clear and obvious in usually a forceful or unpleasant way <vi>The truth about their marriage finally <it>hit home</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>home free</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>home and dry</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:sure of succeeding, winning, etc. :no longer in danger of failing <vi>If we can meet this next deadline, we'll be <it>home free</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>nothing to write home about</dre> <dx>see <dxt>write</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>ram home</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ram</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>till/until the cows come home</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cow</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="save[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">save</hw> <sound><wav>save0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈseɪv</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>saves</if></in> <in><if>saved</if></in> <in><if>sav*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (someone or something) safe :to stop (someone or something) from dying or being hurt, damaged, or lost <vi>He risked his life to <it>save</it> his friend (from drowning).</vi> <vi>The organization is dedicated to <it>saving</it> [=<it>protecting</it>] endangered animals.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>save</it> the rain forests (from destruction).</vi> <vi>He grabbed her arm to <it>save</it> her from falling. [=to stop/prevent her from falling so that she would not be hurt]</vi> <vi>The doctors managed to <it>save</it> the soldier's wounded leg. [=to keep the leg from having to be cut off]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from ending or failing :to make (something that is in danger of failing) successful <vi>He is trying to <it>save</it> his marriage by going to counseling for his drug addiction.</vi> <vi>The new CEO <it>saved</it> the company (from bankruptcy).</vi> <vi>She <it>saved</it> a tense situation by staying calm.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) from being lost or wasted <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>This new plan will help us <it>save</it> time. = The new plan will <it>save</it> us some time.</vi> <vi>Thinner computer monitors <it>save</it> space.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>on</it> <vi>A more efficient furnace will <it>save on</it> energy.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to keep money instead of spending it :to put money away especially in a bank so that you will have it in the future <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She would rather <it>save</it> than spend.</vi> <vi>He has been <it>saving</it> (up) for a new car.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Save</it> a little money for later.</vi> <vi>She <it>saves</it> part of her pay every week.</vi> <vi>I <it>saved</it> $20,000 for a down payment on the house.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to spend less money <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Buy now and <it>save</it>!</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><it>Save on</it> everything in the store!</vi> <vi>He <it>saved on</it> [=spent less money for] his car insurance by switching to a different insurance company.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>saved</it> $15 at the grocery store by using coupons.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're trying to <it>save</it> money <it>on</it> our electric bill.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) available for use in the future <vi>Be sure to <it>save</it> some cookies for your sister.</vi> <vi>You need to <it>save</it> (up) your energy for tomorrow.</vi> <vi>He <it>saves</it> his best jacket for special occasions. [=he only wears his best jacket on special occasions]</vi> <vi>The runners <it>saved</it> their energy for the last lap. = The runners <phrase>saved themselves</phrase> for the last lap.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) for someone to use or have <vi>She <it>saved</it> a seat for her friend.</vi> <vi>Please <it>save</it> the next dance for me. = Please <it>save</it> me the next dance. [=please don't plan to dance the next dance with anyone but me]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) unnecessary <vi>Check that you have everything before you leave. It will <it>save</it> your having to go back again.</vi> <vi>The shortcut <it>saves</it> an hour's driving.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to keep (someone) from doing something <vi>Thanks for sending out that package. It <it>saved</it> me a trip to the post office.</vi> <vi>I'll make the appointment for you to <phrase>save you the trouble/bother</phrase>. [=so that you don't have to do it yourself]</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>You should cut up the vegetables to <it>save</it> you <it>from</it> doing it later when the guests are here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to collect or keep (something) <vi>She <it>saved</it> all his letters.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to store (data) in a computer or on a storage device (such as a CD) so that it can be used later <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You should <it>save</it> your work on/to a disk.</vi> <vi><it>save</it> a file</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Don't forget to <it>save</it> before you close the file.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (an opponent's shot) from scoring a goal <vi>He <it>saved</it> the penalty kick/shot.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (a game) from being lost to an opponent <vi>The relief pitcher <it>saved</it> the game.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>in Christianity</ssl> <dt>:to protect or free (someone) from sin or evil <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He believes that Jesus Christ will <it>save</it> him.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Jesus <it>saves</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a penny saved (is a penny earned)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>penny</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>save face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's bacon/hide/neck/skin</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to save someone :to help someone get out of a dangerous or difficult situation <vi>You really <it>saved my bacon</it> by helping out yesterday.</vi> <vi>He doesn't care what happens to us. All he's worried about is <it>saving his own skin/neck</it>. [=saving himself]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's life</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>save a life</va></svr> <dt>:to stop (someone) from dying or being killed :to rescue (someone) who is in terrible danger <vi>She thanked the firefighters who <it>saved her life</it>. [=rescued her]</vi> <vi>a surgical procedure that has <it>saved the lives</it> of thousands of people</vi> <vi>The use of seat belts can <it>save lives</it>.</vi> <vi>If you donate blood, you might <it>save a life</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help (someone) in an important way <un>often used to thank someone who helped you <vi>Thanks for covering for me. You really <it>saved my life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save the day</dre> <def><dt>:to make a bad situation end successfully <vi>Just when things looked hopeless, my brother came along and <it>saved the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to save your life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>cannot do something to save your life</phrase>, you are completely unable to do it. <vi>She <it>can't sing to save her life</it>. [=she is a very bad singer]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
