<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bad[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bad</hw> <sound><wav>bad00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>worse</if> <sound><wav>worse001.wav</wav><wav>ill00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɚs</pr></in> <in><if>worst</if> <sound><wav>worst001.wav</wav><wav>ill00003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɚst</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:low or poor in quality <vi>a <it>bad</it> repair job</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> work</vi> <vi>The house is in <it>bad</it> condition/shape.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not correct or proper <vi><it>bad</it> manners</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> [=<it>incorrect, faulty</it>] grammar</vi> <vi>a letter written in <it>bad</it> French</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> spelling</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> check [=a check that cannot be cashed]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad language</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:not pleasant, pleasing, or enjoyable <vi>He had a <it>bad</it> day at the office.</vi> <vi>I was having a <it>bad</it> dream.</vi> <vi>She made a very <it>bad</it> impression on her future colleagues.</vi> <vi>The food tastes <it>bad</it>.</vi> <vi>The flower smells <it>bad</it>.</vi> <vi>He has <it>bad</it> breath. [=breath that smells bad]</vi> <vi>We've been having <it>bad</it> weather lately.</vi> <vi>The medicine left a <it>bad</it> taste in his mouth.</vi> <vi>It feels <it>bad</it> [=<it>uncomfortable, painful</it>] to stretch out my arm.</vi> <vi>I look <it>bad</it> in this hat. = This hat looks <it>bad</it> on me.</vi> <vi>That hat doesn't look <it>bad</it> on you. [=that hat looks good on you]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having, marked by, or relating to problems, troubles, etc. <vi>good and <it>bad</it> news</vi> <vi>They have remained together in good times and <it>bad</it> (times).</vi> <vi>It's a <it>bad</it> time for business right now.</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> omen</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> luck/fortune</vi> <vi>Things are looking pretty <it>bad</it> for us at this point.</vi> <vi>I have a <it>bad</it> feeling about this.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad blood</dxt> <dxt>bad news</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not adequate or suitable <vi>I couldn't take a picture because the lighting was <it>bad</it>.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>bad</it> day for a picnic.</vi> <vi>She made a <it>bad</it> marriage.</vi> <vi>Is this a <it>bad</it> moment/time to have a word with you?</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:not producing or likely to produce a good result <vi>a <it>bad</it> deal</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> risk</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> idea/plan</vi> <vi>The plan has its good points and its <it>bad</it> points.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>bad debt</phrase> [=a debt that will not be paid]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>bad loan</phrase> [=a loan that will not be repaid]</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:expressing criticism or disapproval <vi>The movie got <it>bad</it> reviews.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:not healthy :marked or affected by injury or disease <vi>His health is pretty <it>bad</it>. = He's in pretty <it>bad</it> health.</vi> <vi>The patient was pretty <it>bad</it> [=<it>ill, sick</it>] last week and even <it>worse</it> yesterday but is doing better now.</vi> <vi>He came home early because he was feeling pretty <it>bad</it>. [=he wasn't feeling well]</vi> <vi>My father has a <it>bad</it> back/leg. [=a back/leg that is always or often painful]</vi> <vi>She has <it>bad</it> eyesight/hearing.</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> teeth</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:causing harm or trouble <vi>a <it>bad</it> diet</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> influence</vi> <vi><phrase>bad cholesterol</phrase> [=a type of cholesterol that can cause serious health problems when there is too much of it in your blood]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Eating too much can be <it>bad for</it> you. = It can be <it>bad for</it> you to eat too much.</vi> <vi>Eating all that candy is <it>bad for</it> your teeth.</vi> <vi>Watching too much TV is <it>bad for</it> children.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not morally good or right :morally evil or wrong <vi>a <it>bad</it> person</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> conduct/behavior</vi> <vi>a man of <it>bad</it> character</vi> <vi><it>bad</it> intentions/deeds</vi> <vi>It's hard to tell the good guys from the <phrase>bad guys</phrase> in this movie.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad faith</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not behaving properly <vi>a <it>bad</it> dog</vi> <vi>I'm afraid your son has been a very <it>bad</it> [=<it>naughty</it>] boy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad boy</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:not skillful :not doing or able to do something well <vi>a <it>bad</it> musician</vi> <vi>a <it>bad</it> doctor</vi> <vi>She was pretty <it>bad</it> in that movie. [=she did not act well]</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>a doctor who's <it>bad at</it> treating nervous patients</vi> <vi>He's very/really <it>bad at</it> expressing his true feelings.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a tendency not to do something <un>+ <it>about</it> <vi>He's <it>bad about</it> getting to work on time. [=he often fails to get to work on time]</vi> <vi>I'm very <it>bad about</it> remembering people's birthdays. [=I often forget people's birthdays]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:not happy or pleased :feeling regret or guilt about something <vi>I <phrase>feel bad</phrase> about what happened. [=I regret what happened]</vi> <vi>She <it>felt bad</it> that she forgot to call. = She <it>felt bad</it> about forgetting to call.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not cheerful or calm <vi>She's in a <it>bad</it> mood. [=an angry mood]</vi> <vi>He has a <it>bad</it> temper. [=he's bad-tempered; he becomes angry easily]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:serious or severe <vi>She's in <it>bad</it> trouble.</vi> <vi>He has a <it>bad</it> cough/cold.</vi> <vi>That bruise looks <it>bad</it>: you'd better see a doctor about it.</vi> <vi>How <it>bad</it> is the pain?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:no longer good to eat or drink :not fresh <vi>the smell of <it>bad</it> fish</vi> <vi>Is the milk still good or has it <phrase>gone bad</phrase>? [=<it>spoiled</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sin><if>bad*der</if></sin> <sin><if>bad*dest</if></sin> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:very good <vi>He's the <it>baddest</it> guitar player you'll ever hear!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very tough or dangerous <vi>Don't mess around with him. He's a <it>bad</it> dude.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a bad job</dre> <dx>see <dxt>job</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a bad lot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bad apple</dre> <dx>see <dxt>apple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to a bad end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from bad to worse</dre> <def><dt>:from a bad state or condition to an even worse state or condition <vi>The company has been struggling for years, and things have recently gone <it>from bad to worse</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a bad way</dre> <def><dt>:in a bad condition <vi>Without enough funding, public services are <it>in a</it> pretty <it>bad way</it> right now.</vi> <vi>The patient was <it>in a bad way</it> last week but is doing better now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's bad books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>book</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not bad</dre> <def><dt>:fairly good or quite good <vi>All things considered, she's <it>not</it> a <it>bad</it> singer. [=she's a pretty good singer]</vi> <vi>“How are you?” “<it>Not</it> (too/so) <it>bad</it>, thanks. And you?”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too bad</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to show that you are sorry or feel bad about something <vi>It's <it>too bad</it> [=<it>unfortunate</it>] that John and Mary are getting divorced. = It's <it>too bad</it> about John and Mary getting divorced. [=I'm sorry to hear that John and Mary are getting divorced]</vi> <vi>“I won't be able to come to the party.” “(That's) <it>Too bad</it>. I was hoping you'd be there.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in an ironic way to show that you are not sorry or do not feel bad about something <vi>“But I need your help!” “(That's just) <it>Too bad</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with bad grace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bad*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>badness</it> of his behavior</vi> <vi>the <it>badness</it> [=<it>severity</it>] of his injuries</vi> <vi>There's more goodness than <it>badness</it> in him.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bad[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bad</hw> <altpr>ˈbæd</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>worse</if></in> <in><if>worst</if></in> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>badly</sx> <vi>She was struggling when she first started the job, but she's not doing so <it>bad</it> now. [=she's doing fairly well now]</vi> <vi>He hasn't succeeded because he doesn't want it <it>bad</it> enough.</vi> <vi>He cut himself real <it>bad</it>. [=very badly]</vi> <vi>I need a vacation and I need it <it>bad</it>. [=I need it very much]</vi> <vi>“Is he in love with her?” “Oh yeah, he's <phrase>got it bad</phrase>.” [=he's extremely in love with her]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bad off</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:having little money <vi>They're pretty <it>bad off</it> [=they don't have enough money] now that he's lost his job.</vi> <vi>We're not rich, but we're not too <it>bad off</it> (for money). [=we're not poor]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a bad or difficult situation or condition <vi>When I heard how <it>bad off</it> they were, I asked if I could do anything to help.</vi> <vi>This state isn't too <it>bad off</it> compared to other parts of the country.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bad[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bad</hw> <altpr>ˈbæd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:morally bad forces or influences :<sx>evil</sx> <vi>There's more good than <it>bad</it> in him.</vi> <vi>We need to teach our children the difference between good and <it>bad</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the bad</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the unpleasant things that happen to people <vi>You have to <phrase>take the good with the bad</phrase>. [=you have to accept the bad things that happen to you as well as the good things]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:things that are morally wrong <vi>teaching children the difference between the good and <it>the bad</it></vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:morally bad people <vi>He believes that the good go to heaven when they die and <it>the bad</it> go to hell.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="worse[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">worse</hw> <sound><wav>worse001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɚs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <cx><cl>comparative form of</cl> <ct>bad</ct></cx> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:lower in quality <vi>His schoolwork/grades got <it>worse</it> after his parents split up.</vi> <vi>Her second book was <it>worse</it> than her first one.</vi> <vi>Her first book was bad, but her second one is <phrase>even worse</phrase>.</vi> <vi>This one is <phrase>no worse</phrase> than that one.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:less pleasant, attractive, appealing, effective, useful, etc. <vi>Could the situation get any <it>worse</it>?</vi> <vi>You have even <it>worse</it> luck than I do.</vi> <vi>It turned out to be a <it>worse</it> idea than we originally thought.</vi> <vi>She ended up in <it>worse</it> shape than when she started.</vi> <vi>Things are bad for him now, but he was in a <it>worse</it> situation last week.</vi> <vi>Cheer up. <phrase>Things could be worse</phrase>, you know.</vi> <vi>I have <phrase>even/still worse</phrase> news for you.</vi> <vi>He broke the vase but <phrase>what is worse</phrase>, he lied to me about it.</vi> <vi>There's <phrase>nothing worse than</phrase> having wet socks.</vi> <vi>My car broke down, and <phrase>to make matters worse</phrase>, I can't afford to fix it. [=the situation is even worse because I can't afford to fix it]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:more serious or severe <vi>Her symptoms have gotten/grown <it>worse</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't scratch your rash or you'll make it <it>worse</it>.</vi> <vi>Lying will only get you into <it>worse</it> trouble.</vi> <vi>The rain got <it>worse</it> as the day went on.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:in poorer health than before <vi>We thought she had recovered, but then she got/grew/became <it>worse</it>.</vi> <vi>I feel <it>worse</it> today than I felt yesterday.</vi> <vi>The medicine seems to have made the patient <it>worse</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:less happy or pleased <vi>After we talked, I felt even <it>worse</it>.</vi> <vi>The more I dwelled on my mistakes, <phrase>the worse</phrase> I felt.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:less appropriate or acceptable <vi>There are <it>worse</it> ways to spend your money/time.</vi> <vi>You couldn't have picked a <it>worse</it> time to ask for a raise.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:less morally right or good <vi>It may be no <it>worse</it> to cheat than to steal.</vi> <vi>People have done <it>worse</it> things.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:less skillful <vi>He's a <it>worse</it> dancer than I am.</vi> <vi>I've gotten <it>worse</it> at golf.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>from bad to worse</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bad</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>worse for wear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>your bark is worse than your bite</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bark</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="worse[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">worse</hw> <altpr>ˈwɚs</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <cx><cl>comparative form of</cl> <ct>badly</ct></cx> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a worse way <vi>I did much <it>worse</it> on my second try.</vi> <vi>You drive <it>worse</it> than he does.</vi> <vi>That isn't an excellent score, but you could have done <it>worse</it>.</vi> <vi>She was hurt <it>worse</it> than I was.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that what is going to be described is worse than what was mentioned before <vi>I got into an accident and suffered a cut on my arm. <it>Worse</it>, my car was totaled.</vi> <vi>I was scared that they were going to laugh at me—<phrase>or worse</phrase>, beat me up.</vi> <vi>She found out that he was cheating on her. <phrase>Even worse</phrase>, her friends knew that he was and never told her.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>could do worse</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a particular choice, action, etc., is not a bad one <vi>You <it>could do worse</it> than to vote for her. [=voting for her would be a good idea]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="worst[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">worst</hw> <sound><wav>worst001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɚst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>bad</ct></cx> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:worse than all others <vi>This is the <it>worst</it> car I've ever bought.</vi> <vi>In my opinion, it's her <it>worst</it> book.</vi> <vi>It was the <it>worst</it> movie I've ever seen.</vi> <vi>His <it>worst</it> quality is his impatience.</vi> <vi>This has got to be the <it>worst</it> day of my life.</vi> <vi>The <it>worst</it> part of working there is the long commute.</vi> <vi>My <it>worst</it> fears came true.</vi> <vi>I am my own <it>worst</it> critic. [=I criticize my work more harshly than anyone else]</vi> <vi>He lives in the <it>worst</it> area of the city.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:least skillful, talented, or successful <vi>He is the <it>worst</it> singer I've ever heard.</vi> <vi>They're the <it>worst</it> team ever.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:least appropriate, useful, or helpful <vi>That is the <it>worst</it> advice I've ever heard.</vi> <vi>I'm having the <it>worst</it> luck today.</vi> <vi>Leaving now is the <it>worst</it> thing you could do.</vi> <vi>He is the <it>worst</it> person to ask for advice.</vi> <vi>You've picked the <it>worst</it> time to come over.</vi> <vi>She called at the <it>worst</it> possible moment.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in the worst way</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very much <vi>I want a new bike <it>in the worst way</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>worst of all</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to the least pleasant or appealing part of something that has many bad parts <vi>I forgot my backpack, was late for class, and <it>worst of all</it>, I studied the wrong material for the test.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your own worst enemy</dre> <dx>see <dxt>enemy</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="worst[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">worst</hw> <altpr>ˈwɚst</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>badly</ct></cx> <def><dt>:in the worst way :in a way that is worse than all others <vi>My sister was hurt <it>worst</it>.</vi> <vi>the areas <it>worst</it> hit by the drought</vi> <vi>She was voted the <it>worst</it>-dressed celebrity of 2005.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bad blood"> <hw>bad blood</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:feelings of dislike between two people or groups <vi>There's been a lot of <it>bad blood</it> between them since their quarrel.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bad boy"> <hw>bad boy</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ boys</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a man who says or does things that shock other people</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a young and successful man who does things in a way that is very different from the usual way <vi>He has become known as the <it>bad boy</it> of the American television industry.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bad faith"> <hw>bad faith</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:lack of honesty in dealing with other people <vi>She accused her landlord of <it>bad faith</it> [=<it>dishonesty</it>] because he had promised to paint the apartment but never did it.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>good faith</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>in bad faith</dre> <def><dt>:in a dishonest and improper way <vi>She signed the contract <it>in bad faith</it>. [=with no intention of doing what it said she would do]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
