<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="balance[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bal*ance</hw> <sound><wav>balanc01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæləns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bal*anc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the state of having your weight spread equally so that you do not fall <vi>He held on to the rail for <it>balance</it>. = He held on to the rail to <phrase>keep/maintain his balance</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She had trouble <it>keeping her balance</it> as the boat rocked back and forth.</vi> <vi>The skater suddenly <phrase>lost his balance</phrase> and fell.</vi> <vi>Another skater bumped into him and <phrase>knocked/threw him off balance</phrase>.</vi> <snote>In figurative use, to <phrase>knock/throw someone off balance</phrase> or <phrase>keep someone off balance</phrase> is to make someone feel unsure about how to behave or what to expect. <vi>He was surprised and <it>thrown off balance</it> by her strong personality.</vi> <vi>The sudden change in the schedule <it>knocked me off balance</it>.</vi> <vi>The author <it>keeps</it> her readers <it>off balance</it> by always changing the subject.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the ability to move or to remain in a position without losing control or falling <vi>Gymnasts need flexibility and <it>balance</it>.</vi> <vi>She has a good <phrase>sense of balance</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a state in which different things occur in equal or proper amounts or have an equal or proper amount of importance <vi>To provide <it>balance</it> in her news story, she interviewed members of both political parties.</vi> <vi>Temperature changes could upset the delicate <it>balance</it> of life in the forest.</vi> <vi>To lose weight you need the proper/right <it>balance</it> of diet and exercise.</vi> <vi>The food had a perfect <it>balance</it> of sweet and spicy flavors.</vi> <vi>He needs to achieve/create/strike a better <it>balance</it> between his work life and his family life. [=he needs to spend less time at work and more time with his family]</vi> <vi>He's trying to keep his work life and his family life <phrase>in balance</phrase>. = He's trying to keep his work life <phrase>in balance with</phrase> his family life. [=he's trying to give a proper of amount of time and attention to both his work life and his family life]</vi> <vi>It's important to keep your life <it>in balance</it>.</vi> <vi>His work life and his family life are <phrase>out of balance</phrase>. = His work life is <phrase>out of balance with</phrase> his family life.</vi> <vi>If these ingredients are <it>out of balance</it> [=not used in good or correct amounts], the dish will not taste good.</vi> <vi>The death of his wife threw/sent his life <it>out of balance</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the amount of money in a bank account <vi>He has a comfortable/healthy/hefty bank <it>balance</it>. [=he has plenty of money in the bank]</vi> <vi>You must maintain a minimum <it>balance</it> of $1,000 [=you must keep at least $1,000] in your bank account.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the amount of money that still needs to be paid <vi>What are the unpaid <it>balances</it> on your credit cards?</vi> <vi>The bill was $500 and we've received $400, so the <it>balance</it> (of the bill) is $100.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>the balance</bnote> <dt>:something that remains or is left over after other things have been done or used <vi>We planned to stay there for <it>the balance</it> [=<it>the rest</it>, <it>the remainder</it>] of the summer.</vi> <vi>Although the beginning is funny, <it>the balance</it> of the book is very serious.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a device that measures weight and shows how heavy things are :<sx>scale</sx> <dx>see also <dxt>checks and balances</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>in the balance</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something (such as your future) <phrase>hangs in the balance</phrase> or <phrase>is in the balance</phrase>, it is not certain but will soon be known or decided. <vi>Our future <it>hangs in the balance</it> as we await their decision. [=our future depends on their decision; their decision will control our future]</vi> <vi>With his job <it>in the balance</it>, he went to ask his boss for a raise.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on balance</dre> <def><dt>:with all things considered :in general <vi>The meeting went well <it>on balance</it>.</vi> <vi>Although our lives are difficult now, I believe that <it>on balance</it> we are becoming stronger people.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip the balance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tip</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="balance[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">balance</hw> <altpr>ˈbæləns</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>balances</if></in> <in><if>balanced</if></in> <in><if>balanc*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make (something, such as a plate or your body) steady by keeping weight equal on all sides <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>The waiters <it>balanced</it> the food <it>on</it> large trays.</vi> <vi>She learned to walk while <it>balancing</it> a book <it>on</it> her head.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>balance</it> a spoon <it>on</it> your nose?</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I find it difficult to <it>balance on</it> one foot.</vi> <vi>He had trouble <it>balancing on</it> his skis.</vi> <vi>He helped his daughter <it>balance on</it> her bicycle before she started peddling.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>balancing act</tag> at <dxt>act</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to adjust (an account or budget) so that the amount of money available is more than or equal to the amount of money that has been spent <vi>The legislature is still trying to <it>balance</it> the state's budget.</vi> <vi>a <it>balanced</it> budget</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to check and make adjustments to financial records so that they are accurate <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>balances</it> his checkbook every month.</vi> <vi>The company hasn't done a good job <it>balancing</it> the books. [=keeping a record of the money it spends and earns]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Something's wrong: the books don't <it>balance</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (different or opposite things) equal in strength or importance <vi>She's able to <it>balance</it> her career with her family life. = She <it>balances</it> work and family.</vi> <vi>The group is <it>balanced</it> between new and old members. [=the group had an equal number of new and old members]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>balance out <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (a different or opposite thing) less powerful, noticeable, etc. <vi>Serve black coffee to help <it>balance</it> the sweetness of the dessert.</vi> <vi>His quickness will <it>balance</it> [=compensate for, make up for] the other fighter's greater strength.</vi> <vi>The movie's serious subject matter is <it>balanced</it> [=<it>offset</it>] with humor.</vi> <vi>His sadness was <it>balanced</it> by memories of happier days.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>balance out <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to think about (different things) and decide which is better or more important <un>usually + <it>against</it> or <it>with</it> <vi>Their fears must be <it>balanced</it> [=<it>weighed</it>] <it>against</it> the need for change.</vi> <vi>A national government must <it>balance</it> [=<it>compare</it>] the needs of individuals <it>with/against</it> the needs of the entire country.</vi> <vi>They'll have to <it>balance</it> the risks <it>with</it> the rewards. [=they'll have to decide if the possible good results are worth the possible bad results]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>balance out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>balance out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>balance (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (a different or opposite thing) less powerful, noticeable, etc. <vi>Serve black coffee to help <it>balance out</it> the sweetness of the dessert.</vi> <vi>His quickness will <it>balance out</it> [=compensate for, make up for] the other fighter's greater strength.</vi> <vi>The discount <it>balances out</it> the shipping charge. = The discount and the shipping charge <it>balance</it> each other <it>out</it>. [=the shipping charge and the discount together equal zero]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>balance <dxn>4 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be or become equal or even <vi>The good times and the bad times <it>balanced out</it> [=<it>evened out</it>] in the end.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>balance <dxn>3 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="balance beam"> <hw>balance beam</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ beams</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a thick bar of wood raised above the floor that is used in gymnastics for displays of balance</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="balance of payments"> <hw>balance of payments</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:the difference between the amount of money that a country spends and the amount it earns</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="balance of power"> <hw>balance of power</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a state or situation in which two countries or groups (such as two political parties) have equal amounts of power <un>usually used with <it>the</it> <vi>Their party's loss of two members shifted/tipped <it>the balance of power</it> in the legislature.</vi></un> <snote>A group that <phrase>holds the balance of power</phrase> is able to control what happens by choosing to support either one of two larger groups that oppose each other.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="balance of trade"> <hw>balance of trade</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:the difference between the amount of money that a country spends on its imports and the amount that it earns from its exports <vi>Each nation tries to maintain a favorable <it>balance of trade</it> with other countries. [=they try to earn more from their exports than they spend on their imports]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="balance sheet"> <hw>balance sheet</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sheets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a statement that shows the financial condition of a company at a particular time by listing the amount of money and property that the company has and the amount of money it owes</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="balanced"> <hw>bal*anced</hw> <sound><wav>balanc02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbælənst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more bal*anced; most bal*anced</gram> <dt>:having good or equal amounts of all the necessary parts of something <vi>Most news articles gave a <it>balanced</it> [=<it>fair</it>, <it>unbiased</it>] account of the event.</vi> <vi>a <it>balanced</it> diet [=a diet having all the kinds of food needed to be healthy]</vi> <vi>Every morning she eats a <it>balanced</it> breakfast of toast, yogurt, and a glass of orange juice.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>unbalanced</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="swing[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">swing</hw> <sound><wav>swing001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈswɪŋ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>swings</if></in> <in><if>swung</if> <sound><wav>swing002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈswʌŋ</pr></in> <in><if>swing*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move backward and forward or from side to side while hanging from something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The sheets <it>swung</it> on the clothesline.</vi> <vi>The clock's pendulum stopped <it>swinging</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She sat on the edge of the table, <it>swinging</it> her legs.</vi> <vi>She <it>swung</it> the bag by the handle. [=she held the handle of the bag and made the bag swing]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb, adjective, or preposition</slb> <dt>:to move with a smooth, curving motion <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The monkeys were <it>swinging</it> from branch to branch high up in the trees.</vi> <vi>The door <it>swung</it> open/shut.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>swung</it> himself (up) into the truck.</vi> <vi>I <it>swung</it> my suitcase into the backseat of the car.</vi> <vi>She sat on the counter and <it>swung</it> her legs over to the other side.</vi> <vi>She <it>swung</it> the door open.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to move (your arm, a tool, etc.) with a quick, curving motion especially to try to hit something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Be careful how you <it>swing</it> that ax.</vi> <vi>She <it>swung</it> the bat but missed the ball.</vi> <vi>She <it>swung</it> her purse at me.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>swung</it> (at the ball) but missed.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>swung at me</phrase> [=tried to hit me with his fist] for no reason.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move back and forth on a special type of seat (called a swing) <vi>a playground where kids go to <it>swing</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to turn or move quickly in a particular direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>swings</it> to the left sharply after a few miles.</vi> <un>often + <it>around</it> <vi>He <it>swung around</it> to look at the clock.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>swung</it> the car into the driveway.</vi> <vi>He <it>swung</it> the flashlight toward the noise.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change suddenly from one state or condition to another <vi>Sales <it>swung</it> up sharply at the end of the year.</vi> <vi>The game suddenly <it>swung</it> in favor of the home team.</vi> <vi>His mood can <it>swing</it> wildly from cheerful to angry.</vi> <vi>They have to be ready to <phrase>swing into action</phrase> [=to start doing something quickly] at a moment's notice.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to change or influence (something) in an important way <vi>His strong performance in the second half <it>swung</it> the game in our favor.</vi> <vi>Her promise to lower taxes may have <it>swung</it> [=changed the outcome of] the presidential election.</vi> <vi>They may still <it>swing</it> their votes to the other candidate.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to do or manage (something) successfully <vi>Do you think you can <it>swing</it> the job?</vi> <vi>She isn't able to <it>swing</it> [=<it>afford</it>] a new car on her income.</vi> <vi>If he can <phrase>swing it</phrase>, he'll visit next month.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to be lively or exciting <vi>The bar really <it>swings</it> on weekends.</vi> <vi>The party was <it>swinging</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to die by hanging <vi>He <it>swung</it> for his crimes.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>swing both ways</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be bisexual</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>swing by</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>swing over</va></vr> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to make a brief visit <vi>I'll <it>swing by</it> [=<it>stop by</it>] after work to drop off the paperwork.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>swing the balance</dre> <def><dt>:to change a situation so that one person, group, etc., is more able or likely to succeed than another <vi>Both candidates are qualified, but her experience could <it>swing the balance</it> in her favor.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="tip[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">tip</hw> <sound><wav>tip00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtɪp</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>tips</if></in> <in><if>tipped</if></in> <in><if>tip*ping</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to turn or move something so that it is not straight or level :to cause something to lean or slant :<sx>tilt</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>tipped</it> her head to the left.</vi> <vi>He <it>tipped</it> his glass and spilled some water.</vi> <vi>He <it>tipped</it> his chair back and fell over.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The glass <it>tipped</it> slightly and some of the water spilled out.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something) to move or fall from a place, container, etc. <vi>She <it>tipped</it> [=<it>poured</it>] the batter into a large bowl.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>tip over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>tip over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>tip (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>tip over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to fall over or to cause (something) to fall over <vi>The glass nearly <it>tipped over</it>.</vi> <vi>He accidentally <it>tipped</it> the lamp <it>over</it> and broke it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip the scales</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>tip the balance</va></svr> <dt>:to change a situation so that one person, group, etc., is more able or likely to succeed :to give an advantage to someone or something <vi>Both candidates are qualified, but her experience <it>tips the scales</it> in her favor.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>tip the scales at</bnote> <dt>:to have (a specified weight) <vi>He <it>tips the scales at</it> 285 pounds. [=he weighs 285 pounds]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>tip (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>tip up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to move or cause (something) to move so that one end is lifted up <vi>She <it>tipped up</it> the lid of the box and looked inside.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip your cap/hat</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to touch your hat or cap or to lift it off your head as a way of greeting or saying goodbye to someone <vi>He <it>tipped his hat</it> to her as she walked past.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used informally to say that you admire or respect someone <vi>I really have to <it>tip my hat</it> to those people for all their hard work.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip your hand</dre> <def><dt>:to show what you are planning to do <vi>The company wants to avoid <it>tipping its hand</it> about its decision until next month.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>tip</dxt> <dxt>tip</dxt> <dxt>tip</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
