<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bang[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bang</hw> <sound><wav>bang0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæŋ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bangs</if></in> <in><if>banged</if></in> <in><if>bang*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause or allow (something, such as part of your body) to hit something in a way that makes a loud noise <vi>He accidentally <it>banged</it> his knee against the door.</vi> <vi>He <it>banged</it> [=<it>bumped, struck</it>] his head getting out of the car.</vi> <vi>She fell and <it>banged</it> her elbow.</vi> <vi>She <it>banged</it> her fist on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>banged</it> his empty glass on the counter.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hit (something or someone) in a way that makes a loud noise <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>His knee accidentally <it>banged</it> the door.</vi> <vi>The chair fell over and <it>banged</it> the wall.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>into</it> or <it>against</it> <vi>His knee accidentally <it>banged into</it> the door.</vi> <vi>I thought the door was open and <it>banged</it> [=<it>bumped</it>] right <it>into</it> it.</vi> <vi>The bird <it>banged into/against</it> the window.</vi> <vi>One of the other players <it>banged into</it> her, knocking her to the ground.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use your hand or a tool to beat or hit (something) in a way that makes a loud noise <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>banged</it> the drum.</vi> <vi>She <it>banged</it> the table with her fist.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>banged on</it> the drum.</vi> <vi>She <it>banged on</it> the table.</vi> <vi>Who is <it>banging</it> [=<it>pounding</it>] <it>on</it> the door?</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>bang the drum for</tag> at <dxt>drum</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a sudden loud noise <vi>I could hear the screen door <it>bang</it> [=<it>slam</it>] as he left.</vi> <vi>The window suddenly <it>banged</it> shut.</vi> <vi>The pipes <it>banged</it> as the heat came on.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal + offensive</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone)</dt></def> <dro><dre>bang away</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to work hard at something <vi>We have to keep <it>banging away</it> if we want to finish on time.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>The students are <it>banging away at</it> their homework.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bang heads together</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to use angry or forceful methods to control or punish people <vi>I am going to go in there and <it>bang</it> their <it>heads together</it> if they don't start behaving.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bang on about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bang on about (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk about (something) repeatedly or for a long time <vi>She's always <it>banging on about</it> [=<it>going on about</it>] the importance of a good diet.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bang out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bang out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bang (something) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) quickly <vi>He <it>banged out</it> the speech in just a few hours.</vi> <vi>The two sides are trying to <it>bang out</it> an agreement.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to play (a song, melody, etc.) loudly on a piano <vi>She carelessly <it>banged out</it> a few melodies on the piano.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bang up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bang up (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bang (something or someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to injure or damage (something or someone) <vi>She <it>banged up</it> [=<it>hurt</it>] her knee.</vi> <vi>He <it>banged up</it> the car.</vi> <vi>He was pretty badly <it>banged up</it> [=<it>injured</it>] in the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bang up (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bang (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:to put (someone) in prison <vi>He got <it>banged up</it> [=<it>locked up</it>] for robbery.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bang[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bang</hw> <altpr>ˈbæŋ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bangs</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sudden loud noise <vi>I heard a loud <it>bang</it>.</vi> <vi>The door slammed shut with a <it>bang</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as an interjection to imitate a loud noise (such as the sound of a gun being fired) <vi>“<it>Bang, bang</it>! You're dead.”</vi></un> <snote>In British English the informal phrase <phrase>bang goes</phrase> is used when you are saying that something you wanted or planned has become impossible. <vi>The airport closed and <it>bang went</it> our holiday plans! [=our holiday plans were ruined because the airport closed]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a hard hit or blow <vi>She got a nasty <it>bang</it> [=<it>bump</it>] on her head.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bang for the buck</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>bang for your buck</va></vr> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe how much value is received when money is spent <vi>This restaurant offers people the most <it>bang for the buck</it>. [=offers more than other restaurants for the same price]</vi> <vi>He claims that the new stadium offers taxpayers too little <it>bang for the buck</it>. [=that the new stadium is not worth the tax money that is being spent on it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get a bang out of</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to enjoy (something) very much <vi>You'll <it>get a bang out of</it> [=you'll like] this story.</vi> <vi>She <it>got a bang out of</it> [=<it>got a kick out of</it>] watching her grandson at the beach.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with a bang</dre> <def><dt>:in a sudden and exciting way <vi>The movie begins/starts <it>with a bang</it> and never slows down.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bang[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bang</hw> <altpr>ˈbæŋ</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:exactly or directly <vi>There it was—<it>bang</it> [=<it>right</it>] in front of us!</vi> <vi>The show began <it>bang</it> on time.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>bang to rights</tag> at <dxt>right</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bang on</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:exactly right <vi>His explanation was <it>bang on</it>. [=<it>spot-on</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bang-up"> <hw>bang–up</hw> <sound><wav>bangu01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæŋˌʌp</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very good or excellent <vi>We had a <it>bang-up</it> [=<it>fine, first-rate</it>] time at the party.</vi> <vi>She did <phrase>a bang-up job</phrase> on/with the presentation.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="big bang"> <hw>big bang</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the big bang</dre> <def><dt>:a huge explosion that might have happened when the universe began <vi>a few billion years after <it>the big bang</it></vi> <snote>The scientific theory that the universe began with a huge explosion is called <phrase>the big bang theory</phrase>.</snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="gang bang"> <hw>gang bang</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bangs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal + impolite</sl> <dt>:an occurrence in which several men have sex with the same woman one after another</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="buck[1]"> <hw hindex="1">buck</hw> <sound><wav>buck0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bucks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:<sx>dollar</sx> <vi>I owe you a <it>buck</it>.</vi> <vi>Those toys are five <it>bucks</it> apiece.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>money</sx> <vi>That car costs <phrase>big bucks</phrase>. [=a lot of money]</vi> <vi>I am just working hard, trying to <phrase>make a buck</phrase>. [=to make money]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>fast/quick buck</phrase> [=money earned or gotten quickly]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a male animal (such as a male deer) <dx>compare <dxt>doe</dxt></dx> <vi>He's an outdoorsman who enjoys <it>buck</it> hunting.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>man</sx> <vi>a veteran tennis star competing against an ambitious young <it>buck</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bang for the/your buck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look/feel like a million bucks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>million</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass the buck</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid a responsibility by giving it to someone else <vi>Stop trying to <it>pass the buck</it> and take responsibility for what you've done.</vi> <vi>The federal government <it>passed the buck</it> to the state governments.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the buck stops here</dre> <def><dt><snote>Expressions like <it>the buck stops here</it> are used to say that you accept a responsibility and will not try to give it to someone else. <vi>I'm willing to accept the blame for what happened. <phrase>The buck stops with me</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="drum[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">drum</hw> <sound><wav>drum0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdrʌm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>drums</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a musical instrument that is made with a thin layer of skin or plastic stretched over the end of a round frame and that is played by hitting the skin or plastic with sticks or with your hands <vi>a child beating on a <it>drum</it></vi> <vi>We heard the rhythmic beating of <it>drums</it>.</vi> <vi>She plays the <it>drums</it>.</vi> <vi>That was Miles Davis on trumpet and Max Roach <phrase>on drums</phrase>. [=playing the drums]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>kettledrum</dxt> <dxt>snare drum</dxt> <dxt>steel drum</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the sound that is made when something hits a surface over and over again <vi>He lay listening to the steady <it>drum</it> of the rain on the roof.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a large usually metal container for liquids <vi>oil <it>drums</it></vi> <vi>a 55-gallon <it>drum</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a machine or part of a machine that is shaped like a cylinder <vi>the <it>drum</it> of a clothes dryer</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beat/bang the drum for</dre> <def><dt>:to say or write things that strongly support (someone or something) <vi>They joined together to <it>beat the drum for</it> their candidate.</vi> <vi><it>banging the drum for</it> human rights</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="head[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">head</hw> <sound><wav>head0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>heads</if> <il>or in sense 7</il> <if>head</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body containing the brain, eyes, ears, nose, and mouth <vi>She patted the dog on the <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>He nodded his <it>head</it> in agreement.</vi> <vi>The ceiling's low—watch your <it>head</it>!</vi> <vi><it>head</it> injuries</vi> <vi>They were covered <phrase>from head to foot/toe</phrase> in mud. [=they were completely covered in mud]</vi> <vi>He has a <phrase>full head of hair</phrase>. [=he has a full amount of hair on his head]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>talking head</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person's mental ability :mind or intellect <vi>You shouldn't let your heart rule your <it>head</it>. [=you should be guided by reason and not by your emotions]</vi> <vi>She did some quick calculations <phrase>in her head</phrase>. [=without writing anything; mentally]</vi> <vi>I keep hearing that song <it>in my head</it>. = That song keeps running through my <it>head</it>. = I can't get that song <phrase>out of my head</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It never even <phrase>entered my head</phrase> to run for office. [=I never thought of running for office]</vi> <vi>The problem is <phrase>all in his head</phrase>. [=the problem is not real; he's just imagining it]</vi> <vi>Don't go <phrase>putting ideas in/into his head</phrase>. [=don't cause him to have ideas or suspicions that he would not have himself]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>put that idea out of your head</phrase>. [=you should stop thinking about that idea]</vi> <vi>She always says the first thing that <phrase>comes/pops into her head</phrase>. [=the first thing that she thinks of]</vi> <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <phrase>use our heads</phrase>. [=think carefully]</vi> <vi>That guy should <phrase>have his head examined</phrase>. = That guy is <phrase>not right in the head</phrase>. [=that guy is crazy]</vi> <vi>You need a <phrase>cool/calm head</phrase> [=an ability to remain calm] to deal with someone like him.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>clear head</phrase> [=an ability to think clearly]</vi> <snote>If you have <phrase>a good head on your shoulders</phrase>, you are intelligent and have good judgment. <vi>You don't have to worry about her—she's got <it>a good head on her shoulders</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>When you <phrase>get/take it into your head</phrase> to do something, you suddenly decide to do it in a way that seems foolish or surprising. <vi>He's <it>taken it into his head</it> to try skydiving.</vi> <vi>I somehow <it>got it into my head</it> to run for public office.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>get it into your head</phrase> that something is true, you begin to believe something even though there is no good reason for believing it. <vi>She's somehow <it>gotten it into her head</it> that I don't like her. [=she believes that I don't like her although I do like her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who has a specified mental or emotional quality <vi>A fight was avoided when <phrase>cooler heads prevailed</phrase>. [=when calmer or less angry people were able to convince others not to fight]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hothead</dxt> <dxt>sorehead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a distance equal to the length of a head <vi>The horse won the race by a <it>head</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a <it>head</it> taller than you.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the front side of a coin :the side of a coin that shows a picture of a person's head <vi>the <it>head</it> of a penny</vi> <un>usually used in the plural to refer to one of the two choices you can make when a coin is thrown in the air to decide something <vi>I call <it>heads</it>.</vi> <vi>Is it <it>heads</it> or tails? [=did the coin land with heads or tails facing up?]</vi> <vi>It landed <it>heads</it> up.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>tail <dxn>3</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>head</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:individual animals <vi>100 <it>head</it> of cattle</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an end of something that is like a head in shape or position <un>usually singular</un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She placed the pillows at the <it>head of</it> the bed.</vi> <vi>We arrived early so that we'd be at the <it>head</it> [=<it>front</it>] <it>of</it> the line.</vi> <vi>The chairman sat at the <it>head of</it> the table.</vi> <vi>the <it>head</it> [=<it>top</it>] <it>of</it> a nail/pin/screw</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an object that hits or touches something else <vi>a grinding <it>head</it></vi> <vi>the hammer's <it>head</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a spear</vi> <vi>the <it>head of</it> a golf club</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>arrowhead</dxt> <dxt>spearhead</dxt> <dxt>warhead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the position of being a leader <vi>She's <phrase>at the head of</phrase> her class. [=she is the best student in her class]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person who leads or directs a group or organization <vi>Have you met the new department <it>head</it>?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She is the <it>head of</it> our sales division.</vi> <vi><it>heads of</it> families/households</vi> <vi><phrase>heads of state</phrase> [=leaders of countries]</vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the restaurant's <it>head</it> cook</vi> <vi>the team's <it>head</it> coach</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>head teacher</sx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a tight mass of leaves or flowers on a plant <vi>The flower <it>heads</it> on the plant are very large.</vi> <vi>a <it>head</it> of cabbage/lettuce</vi> <vi>a <it>head of</it> garlic</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where a stream or river begins <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>head</it> of the Nile</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:pressure caused by the water or steam in a machine <snote>When an engine has a <phrase>full head of steam</phrase>, it has built up a full amount of power. This phrase is often used figuratively to describe something that is moving forward in a fast and powerful way. <vi>The project started slowly, but now we have a <it>full head of steam</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the bubbles that form on the top of some liquids (such as beer) <un>usually singular <vi>the foamy <it>head</it> on a beer</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the point at which a situation becomes very serious or when action is required <vi>Things <phrase>came to a head</phrase> when the workers threatened to go on strike.</vi> <vi>These new revelations <phrase>brought</phrase> the scandal <phrase>to a head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small, inflamed area on the skin with a spot in the middle <dx>see also <dxt>blackhead</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a big/swelled head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an overly high opinion of yourself <vi>All those compliments have given him a <it>big head</it>. [=have made him very conceited]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>a head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a price on someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>price</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bang heads together</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bite someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bite</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>butt heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>butt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>count heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get it through someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to learn and remember something <vi>She's finally <it>gotten it through their heads</it> that she doesn't eat meat.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get it through your head</dre> <def><dt>:to accept or understand (something) <vi>He can't seem to <it>get it through his head</it> that I'm not interested in working with him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get your head round</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to understand (something) <vi>She couldn't <it>get her head round</it> why he had to leave.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over someone's head</dre> <def><dt>:to discuss something with a person who is higher in rank than someone else <vi>He <it>went over his supervisor's head</it> to complain about the policy to the company's president. [=he complained about the policy to the company's president rather than his supervisor]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of an alcoholic drink</ssl> <dt>:to make you feel drunk <vi>I just had one glass of wine, but it <phrase>went straight to my head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make you believe that you are better than other people <vi>He has never let his fame <it>go to his head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a head for</dre> <def><dt>:to have an ability to understand or deal with (something) <vi>She's always <it>had a</it> (good) <it>head for</it> business.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) He <phrase>has a head for heights</phrase>. [=he is not afraid of heights; being up high does not bother him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/get your head (screwed) on right/straight</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to think or act in a smart and sensible way <vi>She's young, but it's clear that she <it>has her head screwed on right</it>.</vi> <vi>You think that's a good idea? You need to <it>get your head screwed on straight</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head and shoulders above</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone or something is much better than others <vi>They <phrase>are/stand head and shoulders above</phrase> the competition.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head in the sand</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>bury/have/hide (etc.) your head in the sand</phrase>, you ignore something unpleasant that you should be dealing with. <vi>He can't just <it>bury his head in the sand</it> every time there's a problem.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>head over heels</dre> <def><dt>:very deeply in love <vi>We were <it>head over heels</it> (in love).</vi> <vi>He <phrase>fell head over heels for</phrase> some girl he met at school.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>went head over heels for</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>heads roll</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that <phrase>heads will roll</phrase> or (less commonly) <phrase>heads are going to roll</phrase>, you mean that people will be severely punished or will lose their jobs because of something that has happened. <vi>When the boss finds out about the mistake, <it>heads will roll</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hit the nail on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold up your head</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold your head (up) high</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be proud :to not feel ashamed <vi>Even though they lost the game, they can still <it>hold up their heads</it> because they tried their best.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head</dre> <def><dt>:to remain calm <vi>She has shown that she can <it>keep her head</it> in a crisis.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head above water</dre> <def><dt>:to avoid financial failure while having money problems <vi>We have so much debt that we're barely able to <it>keep our heads above water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head down</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in a quiet way that does not attract attention <vi>a politician who is <it>keeping his head down</it> and trying to avoid controversy</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock heads</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock someone's head off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock some sense into someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sense</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock (something) on the head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your head</dre> <def><dt>:to become very upset or angry <vi>He <it>lost his head</it> and said some things he regrets.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not make head or/nor tail of</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>not make heads or/nor tails (out) of</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be unable to understand (something) <vi>I <it>couldn't make heads or tails of</it> her reaction.</vi> <vi>His handwriting was so bad that we <it>couldn't make heads or tails out of</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off the top of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>off your head</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:crazy or foolish <vi>He's not just eccentric—he's completely <it>off his head</it>!</vi> <vi>He's gone <it>off his head</it> over some girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your head</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with the upper and lower parts of your body reversed in position <vi>Can you <phrase>stand on your head</phrase>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in or into great disorder <vi>News of the discovery <phrase>turned</phrase> the scientific world <phrase>on its head</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that you will be blamed for something <vi>If we miss our deadline, it will be <it>on your head</it>. [=it will be your fault]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to act or think in a reasonable and controlled way because of drunkenness or strong emotion <vi>He was (drunk) <it>out of his head</it>. [=he was extremely drunk]</vi> <vi>Her parents were <it>out of their heads</it> with worry [=were extremely worried and upset] when she didn't come home on time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over your head</dre> <def><dt>:beyond your understanding or ability <vi>The technical details were <it>over my head</it>. [=too complicated for me to understand]</vi> <vi>That joke went right <it>over my head</it>. [=I did not get that joke]</vi> <vi>We realized after we started the business that we were (in) <it>over our heads</it>. [=we were trying to do something that was too difficult]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>per head</dre> <def><dt>:for each person <vi>The price is $20 <it>per head</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick/raise your head above the parapet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>parapet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your heads together</dre> <def><dt>:to think of a solution to a problem with another person <vi>I'm sure we can solve this problem if we just <it>put our heads together</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rear/raise its ugly head</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something bad <it>rears/raises its ugly head</it>, it suddenly becomes obvious or causes trouble. <vi>Inflation threatened to <it>rear its ugly head</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch your head</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be confused about something and unable to understand the reason for it <vi>His odd behavior left us all <it>scratching our heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) your head off</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to scream/shout/yell/laugh (etc.) very loudly or for a long time <vi>She was <it>screaming her head off</it>.</vi> <vi>You can <it>shout your head off</it> at him, but he still won't listen.</vi> <vi>If they saw me dressed like this, they'd <it>laugh their heads off</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>shake your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two heads are better than one</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that it is easier for two people who help each other to solve a problem than it is for one person to solve a problem alone</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn heads</dre> <def><dt>:to attract attention or notice <vi>The car's sleek design is bound to <it>turn heads</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="right[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">right</hw> <altpr>ˈraɪt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>rights</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:behavior that is morally good or correct <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He's old enough to know the difference between <it>right</it> and wrong. = He's old enough to know <phrase>right from wrong</phrase>.</vi> <vi>You <phrase>did right</phrase> [=you did the right thing] to tell the teacher.</vi> <vi>(<it>old-fashioned</it>) He always tried to <phrase>do right by</phrase> his employees. [=to treat his employees fairly]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We discussed the <phrase>rights and wrongs</phrase> of genetic cloning.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>wrong</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that a person is or should be morally or legally allowed to have, get, or do <vi>women fighting for equal <it>rights</it></vi> <vi>The government has denied the people their <it>rights</it>. [=has not allowed the people to do the things that they should be allowed to do]</vi> <vi>Knowing the truth is her <it>right</it>.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She has a <it>right to know</it> the truth.</vi> <vi>They demanded the <it>right to vote</it>.</vi> <vi>You have no <it>right to order</it> me around!</vi> <vi>What gives you the <it>right to read</it> my diary?</vi> <vi>He has every <it>right to be</it> angry.</vi> <vi>You are <phrase>within your rights</phrase> <it>to demand</it> a refund. [=you have the right to demand a refund]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The government must protect the <it>rights of</it> its citizens.</vi> <vi>the constitutional <it>right of</it> privacy</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bill of rights</dxt> <dxt>birthright</dxt> <dxt>bragging rights</dxt> <dxt>civil rights</dxt> <dxt>divine right</dxt> <dxt>human right</dxt> <dxt>women's rights</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>rights</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the legal authority to reproduce, publish, broadcast, or sell something <vi>broadcast <it>rights</it></vi> <vi>movie <it>rights</it></vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The poet's family owns the publishing <it>rights to</it> all his books.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>copyright</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a location closer to the right side of your body than to the left :the right side <vi>Swing the bat from <it>right</it> to left.</vi> <un>often used with <it>on</it> <vi>As you come down the street, my house will be <it>on</it> your/the <it>right</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used with <it>to</it> <vi>Move it <it>to</it> the <it>right</it>.</vi> <vi>The picture is <phrase>to the right of</phrase> the window.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a turn or movement toward the right <vi>Take a <it>right</it> at the next intersection. = (<it>US</it>) Make/hang a <it>right</it> at the next intersection.</vi> <vi>two <it>rights</it> and then a left</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a punch made with the right hand <vi>He hit him with a left to the stomach followed by a <it>right</it> to the jaw.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <bnote>the Right</bnote> <dt>:political groups who favor traditional attitudes and practices and conservative policies <vi>His nomination is opposed by <it>the</it> country's <it>Right</it>.</vi> <vi>The new law is disliked by <it>the Right</it>.</vi> <vi>Members of <it>the Right</it> have voiced their opinions on this matter.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the right</bnote> <dt>:the position of people who support the beliefs and policies of the political Right <vi>The party has shifted to <it>the right</it>. [=has become more conservative]</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>left</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <tag>the far right</tag> at <dxt>far</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>by right</dre> <def><dt>:according to what is legally or morally correct <vi>The money is mine <it>by right</it>. [=I have the right to have the money]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by rights</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>by all rights</va></vr> <def><dt>:according to what is proper and reasonable <vi><it>By rights</it>, you should have been the one to receive the promotion.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead to rights</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bang to rights</va></svr> <dt>:with proof that you are guilty <vi>The police had him <it>dead to rights</it>.</vi> <vi>She was caught <it>dead to rights</it> on a bribery charge.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:with no chance of winning or succeeding <vi>The other team had us <it>dead to rights</it> by the end of the first half.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in its own right</dre> <def><dt>:because of its own special qualities and not because of a connection with something else <vi>Though it's based on a best-selling novel, the movie is great <it>in its own right</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the right</dre> <def><dt>:in the position or situation of being right <vi>You are <it>in the right</it> to demand a refund/apology.</vi> <vi>The judge agreed that he was <it>in the right</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your own right</dre> <def><dt>:because of your own efforts, talent, etc., and not because of your connection with someone else <vi>Her husband is a well-known novelist, but she is a successful writer <it>in her own right</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>might makes right</dre> <dx>see <dxt>might</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>of right</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:according to what is legally or morally correct <vi>The estate belongs <it>of right</it> to him.</vi> <vi>(<it>law</it>) The federal court may intervene <phrase>as of right</phrase>. [=the federal court has a right to intervene]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/set (something) to rights</dre> <def><dt>:to put (something) back into the normal or proper condition <vi>He helped his mother <it>put</it> things <it>to rights</it> [=put things in order] after his father died.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two wrongs don't make a right</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wrong</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
