<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bar[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bar</hw> <sound><wav>bar00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bars</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a building or room where alcoholic drinks and sometimes food are served <vi>We went to a <it>bar</it> for a drink.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sports bar</dxt> <dxt>tiki bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a counter where alcoholic drinks are served <vi>We sat at the restaurant's <it>bar</it> while we were waiting for a table.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cash bar</dxt> <dxt>open bar</dxt> <dxt>wet bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a building or room where a particular food or drink is served <vi>a seafood <it>bar</it></vi> <vi>a juice/coffee <it>bar</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>salad bar</dxt> <dxt>snack bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a straight piece of metal, wood, etc., that is used as a tool, as part of a structure, or to keep people from entering or leaving through a door or window <vi>There were <it>bars</it> across all the windows.</vi> <vi>The door was secured with an iron <it>bar</it>.</vi> <vi>The pole-vaulter narrowly cleared the <it>bar</it>. [=the long bar that is set at a specific height and that a jumper tries to go over]</vi> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>bar</it> is used figuratively in phrases like <phrase>raise/lower the bar</phrase> and <phrase>set the bar higher/lower</phrase> to refer to changing the standard that is used to judge whether someone or something is good, successful, etc. <vi>The company's new software <it>raises the bar</it> for its competitors. [=the company's new software is very good and its competitors will have to produce better software to compete with it]</vi> <vi>Critics say that he has <it>lowered the bar</it> on what is considered acceptable behavior by politicians. [=he has caused people to accept worse behavior by politicians]</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>crossbar</dxt> <dxt>crowbar</dxt> <dxt>parallel bars</dxt> <dxt>uneven bars</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a solid piece of something that is shaped like a rectangle <vi>She bought a chocolate/candy <it>bar</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>bar</it> of soap</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a straight line, stripe, or section that is longer than it is wide <vi>The bird's tail has an alternating series of white and black <it>bars</it>. [=<it>bands</it>]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>menu bar</phrase> [=a narrow section that is across the screen in a computer program and that shows the names of available menus]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bar code</dxt> <dxt>bar graph</dxt> <dxt>task bar</dxt> <dxt>toolbar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:something that makes it difficult or impossible to do or achieve something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>His poor attitude was a <it>bar to</it> his success. [=his poor attitude prevented him from succeeding]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the bar</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the profession of a lawyer <vi>She is a member of <it>the bar</it>. [=she is a lawyer]</vi> <vi>the American <it>Bar</it> Association</vi> <vi>She has been <phrase>called to the bar</phrase>. [=she has become a lawyer]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the Bar</va></svr> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the profession of a barrister</dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the test that a person must pass in order to be a lawyer <vi>She passed <it>the bar</it> on her first try.</vi> <vi><it>the bar</it> exam/examination</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>music</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a line in written music that shows where a measure begins</dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the beats between two bars in a piece of music <vi>I'm not sure I know that song. Can you hum a few <it>bars</it>? [=<it>measures</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>behind bars</dre> <def><dt>:in jail <vi>He has been <it>behind bars</it> for 10 years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tend bar</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to work as a bartender :to prepare and serve drinks at a bar <vi>He <it>tends bar</it> at the restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bar[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bar</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bars</if></in> <in><if>barred</if></in> <in><if>bar*ring</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to put a bar or a set of bars in front of a door, window, etc., so that people cannot go in or out of it <vi>He <it>barred</it> the door as soon as he got in.</vi> <vi>All the windows and doors were <it>barred</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>barred</it> window</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to put something in a road, path, etc., so that people cannot get by <vi>A herd of goats was <it>barring</it> the road.</vi> <vi>obstacles <it>barring</it> our way</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to prevent or forbid (someone) <it>from</it> doing something <vi>Nothing <it>barred</it> them <it>from</it> meeting together.</vi> <vi>The judge will <it>bar</it> the jurors <it>from</it> talking to reporters.</vi> <vi>A federal court has <it>barred</it> the group <it>from</it> using the name.</vi> <vi>Reporters were <it>barred</it> [=<it>excluded</it>] <it>from</it> the meeting. [=reporters were not allowed to go to the meeting]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prevent or forbid (something) <vi>The decision <it>bars</it> the possibility of additional development in the area.</vi> <vi>forms of punishment <it>barred</it> by the Constitution</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>no holds barred</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bar[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bar</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑɚ</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used in the phrase <phrase>bar none</phrase> to emphasize that a statement is completely true <vi>She is the brightest student I've ever known, <it>bar none</it>. [=I have never known a student who is brighter than she is]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:except for :<sx>barring</sx> <vi>They have lost every match, <it>bar</it> one.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bar chart"> <hw>bar chart</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ charts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>bar graph</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bar code"> <art><artref id="bar_code2.tif"/><capt>bar code</capt><dim>93.6,29</dim></art> <hw>bar code</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ codes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a group of thick and thin lines that is placed on a product so that a computer can get the price of the product and other information about it</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bar graph"> <art><artref id="bar_graph.eps"/><capt/><dim>90,59</dim></art> <hw>bar graph</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ graphs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a graph or chart that uses narrow columns of different heights to show and compare different amounts <ca>called also <cat>bar chart</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bar mitzvah"> <hw>bar mitz*vah</hw> <sound><wav>barmi01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɑɚˈmɪtsvə</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -vahs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a ceremony and celebration for a Jewish boy on his 13th birthday when he takes on the religious duties and responsibilities of an adult</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a boy for whom a bar mitzvah is held <dx>compare <dxt>bat mitzvah</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cash bar"> <hw>cash bar</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place at a party where guests can buy drinks <vi>They had a <it>cash bar</it> at their wedding reception.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="coffee bar"> <hw>coffee bar</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place where coffee and usually other drinks and refreshments are sold</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="open bar"> <hw>open bar</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a counter at a party or other gathering where alcoholic drinks are served for free <vi>They had a buffet and an <it>open bar</it> at the reception.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
