<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="base[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">base</hw> <sound><wav>base0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bas*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the bottom or lowest part of something :the part on which something rests or is supported <un>usually singular <vi>The lamp has a heavy <it>base</it>.</vi> <vi>He planted flowers around the stone's <it>base</it>.</vi> <vi>Make sure the <it>base of</it> the stove rests evenly on the floor.</vi> <vi>The climbers established a camp at the <it>base</it> of the mountain. = The climbers established a <phrase>base camp</phrase>.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Although I disagreed with the book's theoretical <it>base</it> [=<it>basis, foundation</it>], I couldn't really find fault with its logic.</vi> <vi>The tour was informative, thanks to the guide's <phrase>broad base of knowledge</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something (such as a group of people or things) that provides support for a place, business, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>At one time paper mills were the industrial <it>base</it> for the region.</vi> <vi>The economic <it>base</it> of the village is tourism. [=tourism is the most important part of the village's economy]</vi> <vi>The company has a solid <phrase>customer base</phrase>. [=set of customers it can depend on]</vi> <vi>The sport's <phrase>fan base</phrase> [=group of fans] is growing.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>power base</dxt> <dxt>tax base</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a main ingredient to which other things are added to make something <un>usually singular <vi>The paint has a water <it>base</it>, not an oil <it>base</it>.</vi> <vi>She uses chicken broth as the <it>base</it> of the soup.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the main place in which a person works or lives or a business operates <vi>He uses his home as the <it>base</it> for his accounting business.</vi> <vi>The company's <it>base</it> is in London. = The company's <phrase>base of operations</phrase> is (in) London. [=the company's main offices are in London]</vi> <vi>The band recently returned to its <phrase>home base</phrase> of Chicago after three months on tour.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a place where a military force keeps supplies and where people in the military live and work <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>naval/military <it>bases</it></vi> <vi>the commander of the <it>base</it> = the <it>base</it> commander</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The troops were ordered back to <it>base</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>air base</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:any one of the four places a runner must touch in order to score <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He threw the ball to the wrong <it>base</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There's a runner <phrase>on base</phrase>. [=there's a runner on first, second, or third base]</vi> <vi>The batter <phrase>reached base</phrase> on an error by the shortstop.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>home plate</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>first base</dxt> <dxt>second base</dxt> <dxt>third base</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chemistry</ssl> <dt>:a chemical that reacts with an acid to form a salt <snote>A base has a pH higher than 7.</snote> <dx>compare <dxt>acid <dxn>1</dxn></dxt> <dxt>ph</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt>:a number on which a system for counting and calculating is established <un>usually singular <vi>Computers use a binary, or <it>base</it> 2, system, rather than the decimal, or <it>base</it> 10, system we usually use.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>cover all the bases</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>cover every base</va></vr> <def><dt>:to do or include everything that needs to be done or included <vi>The book is sometimes confusing because the writer tries too hard to <it>cover all the bases</it>.</vi> <vi>They reviewed the contract to make sure that it <it>covered all the bases</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>off base</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:not correct :wrong or mistaken <vi>Her study proves that the theory is <it>off base</it>.</vi> <vi>It turns out that the estimates were <phrase>way off base</phrase>. [=very wrong]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in an unprepared state <vi>He was caught <it>off base</it> [=<it>off guard</it>] by the accusations. [=he was not prepared for the accusations]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>touch all the bases</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>touch every base</va></vr> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:to cover all the bases</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to mention every subject or point that needs to be considered <vi>She made sure that she <it>touched all the bases</it> in her report.</vi> <vi>His opening remarks at the meeting <it>touched all the bases</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>touch base</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to meet and talk as a way of learning about recent news <vi>Let's get together for lunch next week to <it>touch base</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He attended the conference for a chance to <it>touch base with</it> other people in the computer industry.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="base[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">base</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɪs</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bases</if></in> <in><if>based</if></in> <in><if>bas*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to have a particular place as the main place where a person works or lives or where a business operates <vi>They are going to <it>base</it> their new company in Seattle.</vi> <vi>The company has <phrase>based itself</phrase> in London.</vi> <vi>Our tour group <it>based itself</it> in a hotel in the heart of the city.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) based</it> <vi>The company <it>is based</it> in London. [=the company's main offices are in London]</vi> <vi>The band <it>was based</it> in Chicago until recently.</vi> <vi>a London-<it>based</it> company</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>base on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>base (something) on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to form, make, or develop (something, such as an opinion, decision, or calculation) by using (something, such as information) as a basis, starting point, etc. <vi>You've <it>based</it> your opinion <it>on</it> faulty information. = Your opinion is <it>based on</it> faulty information. [=the information that you used to form your opinion is wrong]</vi> <vi>The interest rate is <it>based on</it> credit history. [=credit history is used to determine the interest rate]</vi> <vi>The story is <it>based on</it> real-life events. [=the story was developed from real-life events]</vi> <vi>The island's economy is <it>based on</it> tourism.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="base[3]"> <hw hindex="3">base</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɪs</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sin><if>bas*er</if></sin> <sin><if>basest</if></sin> <sgram>also more base; most base</sgram> <ssl>formal + literary</ssl> <dt>:not honest or good <vi><it>base</it> motives</vi> <vi>a <it>base</it> criminal</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <ssl>of a metal</ssl> <dt>:having low quality and value <vi>Iron is a <it>base</it> metal.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>base*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>He acted <it>basely</it>.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>base*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>baseness</it> of his actions</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bases"> <hw>bases</hw> <cx><cl>plural of</cl> <ct>base</ct> <cl>or of</cl> <ct>basis</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="base hit"> <hw>base hit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ hits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:a hit that allows a batter to reach a base safely :a single, double, triple, or home run <vi>The pitcher gave up three <it>base hits</it> [=<it>hits</it>] in two innings.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="base on balls"> <hw>base on balls</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bases on balls</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:a movement to first base that is awarded to a batter who does not swing at four pitches that are balls <ca>called also <cat>walk</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="base path"> <hw>base path</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ paths</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the area between two bases on a baseball field where a player must remain while running from one base to the other</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="base pay"> <hw>base pay</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ pays</if></in> <def><gram>count, noncount</gram> <dt>:the amount of money paid to someone for work at a job that does not include any additional payments for bonuses, overtime, etc.</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="base runner"> <hw>base runner</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ners</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>baseball</sl> <dt>:a player who is on base or is trying to reach a base</dt></def> <uro><ure>base*run*ning</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>He is good at <it>baserunning</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="air base"> <hw>air base</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place where military aircraft take off and land :a base of operations for military aircraft</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
