<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="basis"> <hw highlight="yes">ba*sis</hw> <sound><wav>basis001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪsəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ba*ses</if> <sound><wav>basis002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪˌsi:z</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:something (such as an idea or set of ideas) from which another thing develops or can develop <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>This principle forms the <it>basis</it> [=<it>base</it>, <it>foundation</it>] of the country's economic policies and will provide a firm <it>basis</it> for future development.</vi> <vi>The actor's letters form the <it>basis</it> of the biography. [=the biography is based on the actor's letters; the most important information in the biography comes from the actor's letters]</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>These stories have very little <it>basis</it> [=<it>foundation</it>] in fact/reality. [=these stories are not based on or supported by facts/reality]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a reason for doing something <vi>The judge ruled that there is no legal <it>basis</it> [=<it>ground</it>] for a new trial.</vi> <vi>The latest news at least provides some <it>basis</it> for hope. [=some reason to hope]</vi> <vi><phrase>On what basis</phrase> were the students chosen/selected? [=how were the students chosen/selected?; what was considered when the students were chosen/selected?]</vi> <vi>Students were chosen/selected <phrase>on the basis of</phrase> [=<it>according to</it>] their grades and test scores.</vi> <vi>Our decisions are made <it>on the basis of</it> the available information. [=we base our decisions on the available information]</vi> <vi>The company does not hire employees <it>on the basis of</it> their race, sex, age, or religion.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a fixed pattern or system for doing something <un>used with <it>on</it> <vi>He visits his grandmother <phrase>on a regular basis</phrase>. [=<it>regularly</it>]</vi> <vi>The company changes its Web site <phrase>on a daily/weekly basis</phrase>. [=every day/week]</vi> <vi>changes that occur <phrase>on an hourly basis</phrase></vi> <vi>They hired her <phrase>on a trial/temporary basis</phrase>.</vi> <vi>People are seated <phrase>on a first-come, first-served basis</phrase>. [=the people who arrive first are given seats first]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way people act with each other <vi>The two golfers still compete <phrase>on a friendly basis</phrase>. [=in a friendly way]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>on a first-name basis</tag> at <dxt>first name</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bases"> <hw>bases</hw> <cx><cl>plural of</cl> <ct>base</ct> <cl>or of</cl> <ct>basis</ct></cx></entry>

</entry_list>
