<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="BASIC"> <hw>BA*SIC</hw> <sound><wav>basic001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪsɪk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>computers</sl> <dt>:a simple language used for programming computers <vi>The program is written in <it>BASIC</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="basic[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ba*sic</hw> <sound><wav>basic001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪsɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more ba*sic; most ba*sic</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:forming or relating to the most important part of something <vi>In this class, you will learn the <it>basic</it> principles of chemistry.</vi> <vi>At its most <it>basic</it> level, the book is about a father's relationship with his children.</vi> <vi>The <it>basic</it> difference between the two companies is their size.</vi> <vi>The organization fights for <it>basic</it> human rights [=the rights that all people should have] throughout the world.</vi> <vi>These ingredients are a <it>basic</it> part of Thai cooking. = These ingredients are <phrase>basic to</phrase> Thai cooking.</vi> <vi>rights that are <it>basic to</it> all human beings</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:forming or relating to the first or easiest part of something <vi>We're learning <it>basic</it> [=<it>beginning</it>] English.</vi> <vi><it>basic</it> reading, writing, and mathematics</vi> <vi>She lacks even the most <it>basic</it> skills necessary for the job.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not including anything extra <vi>That's just the <it>basic</it> salary without overtime or tips.</vi> <vi>The motel is comfortable but pretty <it>basic</it>: you get the necessities all right, but no luxuries.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="basic[2]"> <hw hindex="2">basic</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɪsɪk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>basics</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>basics</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the simplest and most important parts of something (such as a subject of study) <vi>He's teaching me the <it>basics</it> of Japanese cooking.</vi> <vi>the <it>basics</it> of computers = computer <it>basics</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:<sx>basic training</sx> <vi>He starts <it>basic</it> in two months.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get/go back to (the) basics</dre> <def><dt>:to return to a simpler way of doing something or thinking about something <vi>The restaurant is <it>getting back to basics</it> in terms of food, using fresh ingredients to make simple, good food.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="basic training"> <hw>basic training</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the first few weeks of training for someone who has recently joined the military <vi>Our son is in <it>basic training</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
