<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="battle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bat*tle</hw> <sound><wav>battle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbætl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bat*tles</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a military fight between groups of soldiers, ships, airplanes, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>That two-day conflict has become one of the most famous <it>battles</it> in history.</vi> <vi>The <it>battle</it> continued late into the night.</vi> <vi>the <it>battle</it> of Gettysburg</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The men never spoke of the difficulties of <it>battle</it>. [=<it>war</it>]</vi> <vi>Hundreds of dead soldiers lay on the <phrase>field of battle</phrase>. [=the battlefield]</vi> <vi>the brave warriors who died/fell <phrase>in battle</phrase> [=while fighting in a war]</vi> <vi>Thousands of soldiers were willing to go <phrase>into battle</phrase> to fight the enemy.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a violent fight in which people use weapons <vi>A police officer was injured in a gun <it>battle</it> that took place last night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a fight between people or groups in which each side tries to win a contest (such as a game or an election) or to gain control of something (such as a company) <vi>The divorced couple is now in a fierce custody <it>battle</it> over their son. [=a legal fight about who their son will live with]</vi> <vi>The company was involved in a legal <it>battle</it> with/against one of its employees.</vi> <vi>He has been engaged in a <phrase>running battle</phrase> [=a fight or disagreement that continues for a long time] with the government over the amount of money he owes in taxes.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>They are engaged in a <it>battle for</it> the presidency. [=a fight to win an election and become the president]</vi> <vi>a <it>battle for</it> control of the land</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>a <it>battle to control</it> the land</vi></un> <snote>A <phrase>battle of wits</phrase> is a contest in which each side tries to win by being smarter or cleverer than the other side. <vi>In this movie, it's a <it>battle of wits</it> as the bank robbers try to outsmart the city's detectives.</vi></snote> <snote>A <phrase>battle of wills</phrase> is a contest in which each side tries to win by refusing to stop trying. <vi>The workers' strike became a difficult <it>battle of wills</it> between the company and the labor union.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a fight between two different or opposite forces <vi>the never-ending <it>battle</it> between/of good and evil</vi> <vi>The comedy is a classic treatment of the <phrase>battle of the sexes</phrase>. [=the struggle for power between women and men]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a long struggle to succeed or survive during a difficult situation <vi>Last year, he lost his 10-year <it>battle</it> with/against AIDS. [=he died of AIDS after being sick with the disease for 10 years]</vi> <vi>Starting her own business has proven to be an <phrase>uphill battle</phrase>. [=a very difficult struggle]</vi> <snote>If you are involved in a <phrase>losing battle</phrase> you are trying to do something with little or no chance of success. <vi>I tried to get him to change his mind, but it was a <it>losing battle</it>. [=he refused to change his mind]</vi> <vi>She tried to stay awake but it was a <it>losing battle</it>.</vi> <vi>a gardener <phrase>fighting a losing battle</phrase> against weeds</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>do battle</dre> <def><dt>:to fight or struggle <vi>political opponents who have been <it>doing battle</it> [=<it>battling</it>] for years</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>political opponents who have been <it>doing battle with</it> each other for years</vi> <vi>soldiers <it>doing battle with</it> the enemy</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>half the battle</dre> <def><dt>:an important and necessary part of doing or achieving something <vi>When you're opening a new restaurant, good advertising is <it>half the battle</it>.</vi> <un>often used with words like <it>only</it> and <it>just</it> to stress that something is not enough by itself to achieve a desired goal <vi>If you want a career in show business, having talent is <it>only half the battle</it>—you also need to be lucky.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the heat of (the) battle</dre> <def><dt>:while fighting in a battle <vi>The soldier became confused <it>in the heat of battle.</it></vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>He apologized to his wife for the angry things he had said to her <it>in the heat of battle</it>. [=while they were arguing]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>join battle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>join</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="battle[2]"> <hw hindex="2">battle</hw> <altpr>ˈbætl̟</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>battles</if></in> <in><if>bat*tled</if></in> <in><if>bat*tling</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fight with weapons <vi>The army <it>battled</it> for control of the bridge.</vi> <vi>The <it>battling</it> armies agreed to a truce.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to try or struggle very hard <it>to do</it> something <vi>The team <it>battled</it> [=<it>fought</it>] bravely <it>to win</it> their last game.</vi> <vi>They <it>battled</it> [=<it>struggled</it>] <it>to keep</it> their son out of jail.</vi> :to struggle or fight <it>for</it> something <vi>The two families have <it>battled for</it> control of the land for many years.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to fight or argue with someone <it>over</it> something <vi>The couple <it>battled</it> fiercely <it>over</it> how to spend their money.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to fight, compete, or argue with (someone or something) <vi>The two teams are set to <it>battle</it> each other for the championship.</vi> <vi>Members of both parties continue to <it>battle</it> the governor over her policies.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to stop or defeat (something) <vi>Hundreds of firefighters came to help <it>battle</it> the forest fire.</vi> <vi>People often need help <it>battling</it> their drug and alcohol problems.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>battling</it> cancer for 10 years.</vi> <vi><it>battling</it> the forces of evil</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>battle it out</dre> <def><dt>:to argue or fight <vi>People were <it>battling it out</it> [=<it>fighting it out</it>] over parking spaces.</vi> <vi>The two sides are now <it>battling it out</it> in the courtroom.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="battle-ax"> <hw>bat*tle–ax</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bat*tle–axe</va> <sound><wav>battle04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbætl̟ˌæks</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bat*tle–ax*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an ax with a large blade that was used as a weapon in the past</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal + disapproving</ssl> <dt>:an unpleasant older woman who speaks in an angry way and tries to control others</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="battle cruiser"> <hw>battle cruiser</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a ship that is used in fighting wars and that is lighter and faster than a battleship</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="battle cry"> <hw>battle cry</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cries</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a word, phrase, or sound that is shouted by soldiers in a battle :<sx>war cry</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a phrase or saying that is used to make people support an idea, a cause, etc. <vi>“Just Say No!” was the President's <it>battle cry</it> [=<it>rallying cry</it>] for stopping the use of illegal drugs.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="battle fatigue"> <hw>battle fatigue</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a mental illness that is caused by the experiences of fighting in a war and that causes extreme feelings of nervousness, depression, etc. <ca>called also <cat>combat fatigue</cat> <cat>shell shock</cat></ca> <dx>compare <dxt>post-traumatic stress disorder</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="battle line"> <hw>battle line</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ lines</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a line of soldiers who are fighting in a battle <un>usually used figuratively in phrases like <phrase>the battle lines have been drawn</phrase> to say that groups of people strongly disagree about an issue and are fighting or arguing with each other <vi>When (the) <it>battle lines were drawn</it> over the issue of new taxes, she was quick to side with the governor.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="pitched battle"> <hw>pitched battle</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ battles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a major battle that is fought by large groups of soldiers</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a long argument or fight between people who have become very angry or emotional <vi>She has been in a <it>pitched battle</it> with her ex-husband over custody of their children.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="do[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">do</hw> <sound><wav>do000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdu:</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>does</if> <sound><wav>do000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdʌz</pr></in> <in><if>did</if> <sound><wav>do000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɪd</pr></in> <in><if>done</if> <sound><wav>done0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdʌn</pr></in> <in><if>do*ing</if> <sound><wav>doing001.wav</wav><wav>do000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdu:wɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to perform (an action or activity) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We should <it>do</it> something special to celebrate your birthday.</vi> <vi>This crime was <it>done</it> deliberately.</vi> <vi>I have to <it>do</it> some chores this afternoon.</vi> <vi>Tell me what to <it>do</it> and I'll <it>do</it> it.</vi> <vi>I'm obliged to <it>do</it> my duty.</vi> <vi>He <it>does</it> his work without complaining.</vi> <vi>I <it>do</it> the ironing on Wednesdays and the cooking on Thursdays. [=I iron on Wednesdays and cook on Thursdays]</vi> <vi>I <it>did</it> a favor for him. = I <it>did</it> him a favor.</vi> <vi>“What do you <it>do</it> with this lever? = What does this lever <it>do</it>?” “It operates the pump.”</vi> <vi>He <it>did</it> a lot for us.</vi> <vi>What can I <it>do</it> to help you? = What can I <phrase>do for</phrase> you? [=how can/may I help you?]</vi> <vi>What have I <phrase>done to</phrase> you to make you so angry?</vi> <vi>Have you <phrase>done something to/with</phrase> this room? [=have you changed this room in some way?] It looks different.</vi> <vi>My knee is sore. I must have <phrase>done something to</phrase> it [=I must have hurt it] when I fell.</vi> <vi>Don't just stand there: <phrase>do something</phrase>! [=take some sort of action to stop what is happening]</vi> <vi>We need to <phrase>do something about</phrase> this problem. [=we need to take some action to correct this problem]</vi> <vi><phrase>All we can do</phrase> is hope for the best. [=there is no other action we can take except to hope for the best]</vi> <vi>I didn't <it>do</it> it! = I didn't <phrase>do anything</phrase>! [=I didn't do what you said I did]</vi> <vi>Are you <phrase>doing anything</phrase> right now? [=are you busy right now?]</vi> <vi>If you're <phrase>not doing anything</phrase> this evening [=if you're not busy this evening], why not come over for dinner?</vi> <vi>“What are you <it>doing</it> this weekend?” “I'm just relaxing at home.”</vi> <vi>What is the stock market <it>doing</it> now: rising or falling?</vi> <vi><phrase>What have I done with</phrase> my keys? [=where did I put my keys?]</vi> <vi>My hair is a mess. I <phrase>can't do anything with</phrase> it.</vi> <vi>There's <phrase>nothing to do</phrase> in this town on a Saturday night!</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Do</it> as I say, not as I <it>do</it>. [=do the things that I say you should do, not the things that I do myself]</vi> <vi>Shut up and <phrase>do as you're told</phrase>! [=do what I tell you to do]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used with <it>what</it> to ask or talk about a person's job <vi>“What does your husband <it>do</it>?” “He's a writer.”</vi> <vi>She's a lawyer. I'm not sure what her husband <it>does</it>.</vi> <vi>What does she <phrase>do for a living</phrase>? [=what is her job?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to finish working on (something) <vi>His mother won't let him watch television until he has <it>done</it> his homework.</vi> <vi>I've only <it>done</it> three of the walls so far—I'll paint the last one tomorrow.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>done <dxn>1</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the success or progress of someone or something <vi>“How is she <it>doing</it> in school?” “She <it>did</it> badly/poorly at first, but now she's <it>doing</it> much better.”</vi> <vi>She <it>does</it> well in math but badly in history.</vi> <vi>The company is <it>doing</it> well.</vi> <vi>How is the stock market <it>doing</it> these days?</vi> <vi>He started out poor, worked hard, <it>did</it> very well (for himself) in business [=was very successful in business], and died rich.</vi></un> <snote><phrase>How are you doing?</phrase> or (very informally) <phrase>How you doing?</phrase> is used as a greeting. <vi>“Hi, Dave. <it>How are you doing</it>?” “I'm fine, thanks. How are you?”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the effect that something has <vi>You've been working too hard. A few days off will <phrase>do you (some) good</phrase>. [=a few days off will be good for you]</vi> <vi>We didn't mean to <phrase>do him (any) harm</phrase>. [=to harm him]</vi> <vi>Criticism can <it>do</it> people a lot of harm/damage; praise can <it>do</it> people a lot of good.</vi> <vi>The new design <phrase>doesn't do much for</phrase> me. [=I don't like the new design very much]</vi> <vi>That hat <phrase>does nothing for you</phrase>. [=that hat does not look good on you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the amount of effort someone makes</un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>did</it> nothing to help us. [=she did not try to help us at all]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>did my best</phrase>. = I <phrase>did my utmost</phrase>. = I <phrase>did all that I could</phrase>. = I <phrase>did everything I could</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>did</it> as well as I could.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to create or produce (something) <vi>a writer who is <it>doing</it> a new biography on Abraham Lincoln</vi> <vi>a painter who has <it>done</it> some beautiful landscapes</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to perform in or be the producer or director of (a movie, play, etc.) <vi>an actress who has <it>done</it> several hit movies</vi> <vi>a director who is <it>doing</it> a play on Broadway</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to play (a role or character) <vi>an actor who <it>did</it> Hamlet on Broadway</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to pretend to be (someone, such as a famous person) :to copy the speech and appearance of (someone) <vi>a comedian who <it>does</it> a great George Bush [=a comedian who does a very good and entertaining imitation of George Bush]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave like (someone) <vi>I wish he'd <it>do</it> a Houdini and disappear. [=I wish he'd go away]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to wash or clean (something) <vi>It's your turn to <it>do</it> [=<it>wash</it>] the laundry.</vi> <vi>The woman we hired to clean our house doesn't <it>do</it> windows.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to decorate (a place) <vi>They <it>did</it> the bedroom in blue and the living room in green.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>do over <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to make (someone's face, hair, etc.) more attractive by putting on makeup, etc. <vi>She wanted to <it>do</it> her face before the party.</vi> <vi>She had her hair <it>done</it> [=<it>styled</it>] at the beauty parlor.</vi> <vi>She was <it>doing</it> her fingernails/nails.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to put on (makeup) <vi>It took her a few minutes to <it>do</it> her makeup.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cook or prepare (food) <vi>I like my steak <it>done</it> rare.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>do</it> the salad while you <it>do</it> the pasta.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>done <dxn>2</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make or sell (a product) <vi>This is the company's most popular computer, but they also <it>do</it> a less expensive model.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to participate in (an activity) with other people <vi>We should <phrase>do dinner</phrase> some time. [=we should have dinner together some time]</vi> <vi><it>do</it> a meeting [=have a meeting]</vi> <vi>We should <it>do</it> a movie [=go to a movie] this weekend.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>do lunch</tag> at <dxt>lunch</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go to (a place) when traveling <vi>a group of tourists who are <it>doing</it> [=<it>visiting</it>] 12 countries in 30 days</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move or travel (a distance) <vi>We <it>did</it> [=<it>traveled</it>] 500 miles yesterday.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move at (a speed) <vi>They were <it>doing</it> [=<it>going</it>, <it>driving</it>] 85 on the turnpike.</vi> <vi>That plane can <it>do</it> [=<it>go</it>] 1,400 mph!</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in a place for (a period of time) <vi>He <it>did</it> [=<it>spent</it>] two years in college before he dropped out.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to be in a prison for (a period of time) <vi>He <it>did</it> [=<it>served</it>] five years (in prison) for robbery.</vi> <vi>He has been <phrase>doing time</phrase> in a federal penitentiary.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>I've <phrase>done my time</phrase> at that terrible job, and now it's time to move on.</vi></un></dt> <sn>15 a</sn> <dt>:to be enough :to be adequate <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I don't need any more cake, thank you. One piece <phrase>will do</phrase>. [=one piece is enough]</vi> <vi>I'd prefer to use glue, but tape <phrase>will/would do</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) One piece of cake <it>will do</it> me. [=one piece of cake is enough for me]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote>Phrases like <phrase>that will do (it)</phrase> and <phrase>that should do (it)</phrase> are used in informal speech to tell someone that you do not want or need anything more. <vi>“Would you like anything else?” “No, <it>that'll do it</it>.” = “No, <it>that should do it</it>.”</vi> <it>That will do it</it> and <it>that should do it</it> are also used to say that you have finished doing something or are about to finish doing something. <vi>I just have one more letter to sign and <it>that should do it</it>. [=and then I'll be finished]</vi> <it>That will do</it> is also sometimes used to tell someone (such as a child) to stop doing or saying something that is bothering you or making you angry. <vi><it>That will do</it> [=<it>that's enough</it>], young man: one more word out of you and you're grounded!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><snote>The phrase <phrase>that does it</phrase> is used to say that you have finished doing something. <vi>I just need to sign one more letter…There, <it>that does it</it>.</vi> <it>That does it</it> is also used in angry speech to say that you will not accept or allow something anymore. <vi>“They say we'll have to wait another hour.” “<it>That does it</it>! We're leaving right now!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be proper <un>used in negative statements <vi>It <phrase>doesn't do</phrase> for a doctor to become too friendly with his patients. = It <phrase>won't/wouldn't do</phrase> for a doctor to become too friendly with his patients. [=a doctor should not become too friendly with his patients]</vi> <vi>Such behavior will never <it>do</it>! [=such behavior should not be allowed]</vi> <vi>We should leave soon. It won't <it>do</it> to be late.</vi> <vi>This is a formal occasion, so jeans simply won't <it>do</it>. [=jeans are not appropriate]</vi></un> <snote>In U.S. English, this sense of <it>do</it> has a somewhat formal or old-fashioned quality.</snote> <dx>compare <dxt>done <dxn>3</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use (illegal drugs) <vi>He says that he doesn't <it>do</it> drugs anymore.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>Is there anything <it>doing</it> tomorrow?</vi> <vi>There is nothing <it>doing</it> around here.</vi> <vi>Let's find out <phrase>what's doing</phrase> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote>People ask <phrase>what is something/someone doing…?</phrase> when they are surprised or upset about where someone or something is. <vi><it>What are all my clothes doing</it> (lying/scattered) on the floor? [=why are all my clothes on the floor?]</vi> <vi><it>What were you doing</it> (standing) outside in the rain? [=why were you outside in the rain?]</vi> People ask <phrase>what is someone doing with (something)?</phrase> when they are surprised or upset because someone has something. <vi><it>What are you doing with</it> my notebook? = <phrase>What do you think you're doing with</phrase> my notebook? [=why do you have my notebook?]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal + offensive</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with (someone)</dt></def> <dro><dre>be to do with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>have to do with <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do a number on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>number</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do away with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>do away with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to kill (someone) <vi>She's accused of hiring a hit man to <it>do away with</it> [=<it>murder, do in</it>] her husband.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>do away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause the end of (something) :to get rid of (something) <vi>The struggling company had to <it>do away with</it> a number of jobs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do battle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>battle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do by (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to deal with or treat (someone) well or badly <vi>She feels that they <it>did</it> poorly/badly <it>by</it> her. [=that they treated her poorly/badly]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>did pretty well by</phrase> me when I retired. [=they treated me pretty well when I retired]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>hard done by</tag> at <dxt>hard</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk about (someone) in an insulting or critical way <vi>She thinks that if she <it>does</it> everybody else <it>down</it>, people will think more highly of her.</vi> <vi>Stop <it>doing</it> yourself <it>down</it>: you've got a lot to offer!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cause the death or ruin of (someone) <vi>All that hard work nearly <it>did for</it> him. [=nearly killed him]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>done for</tag> at <dxt>done</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do the cleaning and cooking for (someone) <vi>Mrs. Jones <it>does for</it> the vicar now his wife's passed on.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do good</dre> <dx>see <dxt>good</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to kill (someone) <vi>They threatened to <it>do</it> him <it>in</it> if he didn't pay the money he owed them.</vi> <vi>He's been so depressed lately that his friends are afraid he might <phrase>do himself in</phrase>. [=he might kill himself]</vi> :to cause the death of (someone) <vi>He struggled with lung disease for many years, but it was a heart attack that finally <it>did</it> him <it>in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the failure of (someone) <vi>His inability to attract Southern voters is what finally <it>did</it> him <it>in</it> as a presidential candidate. [=he failed because he was unable to attract Southern voters]</vi> <vi>a businessman who was <it>done in</it> by greed</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) very tired <vi>Working in the garden all day really <it>did</it> me <it>in</it>. = After working in the garden all day, I was/felt <it>done in</it>. [=<it>exhausted</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>done in</tag> at <dxt>done</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to have sex <vi>They've kissed—but have they actually <it>done it</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do justice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>justice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do out of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do (someone) out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to unfairly prevent (someone) from getting or having (something) <vi>I've been <it>done out of</it> what was rightfully mine!</vi> <vi>They <it>did</it> [=<it>cheated</it>] him <it>out of</it> his inheritance.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>do (something) over</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to do (something) again <vi>I made a mistake when I measured the window and I had to <it>do</it> it <it>over</it> (again).</vi> <vi>If I had to <it>do</it> it (all) <it>over</it> again, I would have stayed in college.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>do (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to decorate or change a room, house, etc., so that it looks very different <vi>We're planning to <it>do over</it> the kitchen next year.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>do (someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to attack and beat (someone) <vi>He got <it>done over</it> by a gang of teenagers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do someone proud</dre> <dx>see <dxt>proud</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do the trick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>do up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>do up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do (something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to decorate (something) <vi>They <it>did up</it> the room in bright colors for the party. = The room was all <it>done up</it> in bright colors for the party.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to adjust (something, such as your hair) in a particular way <vi>She <it>did up</it> her hair in a ponytail.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to wrap (something) <vi>packages <it>done up</it> [=<it>wrapped up</it>] in paper and ribbon</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to repair (something) <vi><it>do up</it> [=<it>fix up</it>] old furniture</vi> <vi><it>do up</it> an old house</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>do (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to dress (someone) up :to put attractive clothes, makeup, etc., on (someone) <vi>She really <phrase>did herself up</phrase> for the party. = She was all <it>done up</it> for the party.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>do up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do up (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>of clothing</ssl> <dt>:to be fastened or to fasten (something) with buttons, a zipper, etc. <vi>a dress that <it>does up</it> at the back = a dress that is <it>done up</it> at the back</vi> <vi>She <it>did up</it> her dress.</vi> <vi>buttons that <it>do up</it> easily = buttons that you can <it>do up</it> easily [=buttons that can be easily buttoned]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do well</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>would do well</phrase> to do something, you should do it. <vi>You <it>would do well</it> to avoid him right now. [=you should avoid him right now]</vi> If you <phrase>did well</phrase> to do something, you were correct to do it. <vi>You <it>did well to avoid</it> him when he was in a bad mood.</vi> If you <phrase>did well to escape, survive</phrase>, etc., you were lucky to escape, survive, etc. <vi>When the tornado hit, they <it>did well to escape</it> uninjured.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be helped by having (something) <vi>I <phrase>could (really) do with</phrase> a cup of hot coffee right now! [=I could use a cup of coffee; I would like/appreciate a cup of coffee]</vi> <vi>I <it>could do with</it> a little less criticism right now, if you don't mind!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do without</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>do without</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>do without (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not have (something) :to live, work, etc., without having (something) <vi>If you can't afford a new car, you'll just have to <it>do without</it> (one).</vi> <vi>I don't know how we ever <it>did without</it> computers.</vi> <vi>I'd like to get a new car, but I can <it>do without</it> it for now.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>can/could do without</phrase> is often used to say that you do not like or approve of something. <vi>I enjoy traveling, but I <it>can do without</it> having to wait around in crowded airports. [=I don't like having to wait around]</vi> <vi>He was late again. That's the kind of selfish behavior I <it>could do without</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>do your bit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy does it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have to do with</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>be to do with</va></svr> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to relate to (something) :to be about (something) <vi>The problem <it>has to do with</it> fishing rights. = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) The problem <it>is to do with</it> fishing rights.</vi> <vi>“What does her husband do?” “I think <phrase>it has something to do with</phrase> computers.” = “I think <phrase>it's got something to do with</phrase> computers.” [=it involves computers in some way]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relate to or involve (someone) <vi>That's your problem: <phrase>it has nothing to do with</phrase> me! = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>It's nothing to do with</it> me! [=it doesn't involve me in any way; it's not my problem]</vi> <vi>You're wrong. <phrase>It's got everything to do with</phrase> you: you're legally responsible for what went wrong.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be involved in or in some way responsible for (something) <vi>He claims that he <phrase>had nothing to do with</phrase> the accident. = He claims that he <phrase>didn't have anything to do with</phrase> the accident. [=that he was not involved in the accident]</vi> <vi>He claims he wasn't involved, but I know he <phrase>had something to do with</phrase> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>If you do not want to <phrase>have anything to do with</phrase> someone or if you <phrase>want nothing to do with</phrase> someone, you do not want to be involved with that person in any way. <vi>She thinks he's a liar and she refuses to <it>have anything to do with</it> him. [=she refuses to talk to him, to see him, etc.]</vi> <vi>After the way he's treated me, I <it>want nothing (further) to do</it> with him. = I <it>don't want (to have) anything (further) to do</it> with him.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how do you do?</dre> <dx>see <dxt>how</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make do</dre> <dx>see <dxt>make</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>nothing doing</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nothing</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>do</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="half[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">half</hw> <altpr>ˈhæf, <it>Brit</it> ˈhɑ:f</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><dt>:a number or amount that is equal to one half of a total <vi>“Do you want the whole piece?” “<it>Half</it> would be enough, please.”</vi> <vi>Thirty students took the exam; <it>half</it> (that number) passed. [=15 students passed]</vi> <vi><it>Half</it> of 30 is/equals 15.</vi> <vi>I seem to spend <it>half</it> (of) the day on the phone.</vi> <vi>She gave <it>half</it> (of) her money to charity.</vi> <vi><it>Half</it> a million people live in this area.</vi> <vi>Do you want <it>half</it> (of) my sandwich?</vi> <vi><it>Half</it> the time the kids are outside playing. [=the kids are often outside playing]</vi> <vi>Getting to your destination is <it>half</it> the fun of a vacation. = Getting there is <it>half</it> the fun.</vi> <vi><it>Half</it> the problem is that we do not have enough employees to handle the increased workload.</vi> <vi>I waited for <phrase>half an hour</phrase>. [=30 minutes]</vi> <vi>Please wait (for) <phrase>half a minute/second</phrase> [=for a moment] while I try to connect you.</vi> <vi><phrase>half a dozen</phrase> [=six] eggs</vi> <vi>He's always chasing women <phrase>half his age</phrase>. [=women who are much younger than he is]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>half the battle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>battle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have half a mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
