<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="beat[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">beat</hw> <sound><wav>beat0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:t</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>beat</if></in> <in><if>beat*en</if> <sound><wav>beaten01.wav</wav><wav>beat0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:tn̩</pr> <il>or chiefly US</il> <if>beat</if></in> <in><if>beat*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to hit (something) repeatedly <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>beat</it> the door with his fists. = He <it>beat</it> his fists against/on the door.</vi> <vi>He <it>beat</it> the dusty rug with a stick. = He <it>beat</it> a stick against the dusty rug.</vi> <vi>He <it>beat</it> the dust out of the rug with a stick.</vi> <vi>She used a hammer to <it>beat</it> the metal into shape.</vi> <vi>She used a hammer to <it>beat</it> the nail into the wall.</vi> <vi>The dented metal was <it>beaten</it> flat.</vi> <vi>The waves were <it>beating</it> the shore.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>beat</it> at/against/on the door with his fists.</vi> <vi>The waves were <it>beating</it> on/against the shore.</vi> <vi>The rain <it>beat</it> on the roof.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone) repeatedly in order to cause pain or injury <vi>They <it>beat</it> him with clubs.</vi> <vi>He was <it>beaten</it> badly/savagely/brutally.</vi> <vi>a man accused of <it>beating</it> his wife</vi> <vi>They <it>beat</it> him to the ground. [=they hit him repeatedly and he fell to the ground]</vi> <vi>They threatened to <phrase>beat the (living) daylights out of</phrase> him. [=to beat him very badly]</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>beaten to death</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>beating</dxt> <dxt>beat up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>beat up on <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to hit (a drum) repeatedly in order to produce music or a signal <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The drummer kept <it>beating</it> his drum.</vi> <vi>the sound of a <it>beaten</it> drum</vi> <vi>They <it>beat</it> (out) a message on their drums.</vi> <vi>The drum kept <it>beating</it> (out) its rhythm.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The drummer kept <it>beating</it>.</vi> <vi>The drum kept <it>beating</it>.</vi> <vi>the sound of a <it>beating</it> drum</vi> <dx>see also <tag>beat the drum for</tag> at <dxt>drum</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>cooking</ssl> <dt>:to stir or mix (something) in a forceful way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She used a whisk to <it>beat</it> the eggs.</vi> <vi>The recipe says you should <it>beat</it> the eggs lightly/thoroughly/well.</vi> <vi>Slowly <it>beat</it> the sugar into the batter. = Slowly <it>beat</it> in the sugar. = Slowly <it>beat</it> the sugar in.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Separate out the egg whites and <it>beat</it> until stiff.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to move (wings) with an up and down motion <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The bird was <it>beating</it> [=<it>flapping</it>] its wings.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>the sound of <it>beating</it> wings</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of the heart</ssl> <dt>:to make the regular movements needed to pump blood <vi>My heart was <it>beating</it> wildly/frantically with excitement and my pulse was racing!</vi> <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) We get free doughnuts? <phrase>Be still, my beating heart</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to defeat (someone) in a game, contest, etc. <vi>He gets very angry when I <it>beat</it> him at chess.</vi> <vi>We <it>beat</it> them 14 to 3.</vi> <vi>Our team was badly <it>beaten</it> in the championship game.</vi> <vi>She was narrowly <it>beaten</it> in the previous election, but she won this time.</vi> <vi>We <it>beat</it> them soundly/convincingly/comfortably/easily/badly. = (<it>US</it>) We <phrase>beat the pants off</phrase> them.</vi> <vi>They tried to lure away our customers by offering deep discounts, but we <phrase>beat them at their own game</phrase>. [=we offered even deeper discounts than they did]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>if you can't beat them, join them</phrase> or <phrase>if you can't beat 'em, join 'em</phrase> when they decide to do what other people are doing and to stop opposing them.</snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to do better than (something) <vi>She managed to <it>beat</it> the old record by several seconds.</vi> <vi>We can still <it>beat</it> the deadline if we work quickly.</vi> <vi>His wonderful performance will be <phrase>hard/tough to beat</phrase>. = His wonderful performance will <phrase>take some beating</phrase>. [=it will be difficult for anyone to do better than his wonderful performance]</vi> <vi>Most new restaurants fail, but this one somehow managed to <phrase>beat the odds</phrase>. [=this one succeeded even though it did not have a good chance of succeeding]</vi> <snote>People say <phrase>can you beat that?</phrase> when they are surprised or angry about something. <vi><it>Can you beat that</it>?! A person like him being elected mayor! [=it is surprising or ridiculous to think that a person like him has been elected mayor]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be better than (something) <vi>For sheer luxury <phrase>you can't beat</phrase> a nice hot bath. = For sheer luxury, <phrase>nothing beats</phrase> a nice hot bath. = For sheer luxury, a nice hot bath <phrase>beats anything</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to control or overcome (something) <vi>By working together we can <it>beat</it> crime!</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) His favorite way of <phrase>beating the heat</phrase> [=remaining cool in hot weather] is to have a couple of cold beers.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to be too difficult for (someone) <vi>This problem has <it>beaten</it> everyone. [=no one has been able to solve this problem]</vi> <snote>The informal expression <phrase>(it) beats me</phrase> means “I don't know.” <vi>“How did she manage to fix the problem so quickly?” “<it>Beats me</it>.”</vi> <vi>I don't believe anything he tells me. <it>It beats me</it> how people can continue to trust him.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to come, arrive, or act before (someone or something) <vi>I <it>beat</it> him narrowly to the finish line. [=I reached the finish line slightly before he did]</vi> <vi>I bet I can <it>beat</it> you to the front door!</vi> <vi>I wondered which of us would finish our work first, but she <phrase>beat me to it</phrase> by two days. [=she finished two days before I did]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to avoid having problems with (something) by acting earlier <vi>We left early so that we could <phrase>beat the traffic</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We got to the store when it opened and managed to <phrase>beat the rush</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beat a dead horse</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat a path</dre> <def><dt>:to make (a path) by walking over the ground many times <vi>They <it>beat a path</it> through the woods to the stream.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>If you work hard and well, success will <phrase>beat a path to your door</phrase>. [=you will be very successful]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat a retreat</dre> <def><dt>:to leave quickly <vi>A group of teenagers was causing trouble, but they <phrase>beat a hasty retreat</phrase> when the cops arrived.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat around/about the bush</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bush</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>beat back (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat (someone) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to go back or to retreat by fighting <vi>Our troops were <it>beaten back</it> by enemy forces.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of the sun</ssl> <dt>:to shine down with great heat and strength <vi>The blazing sun was <it>beating down</it> on us mercilessly/relentlessly.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat down (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to hit (something, such as a door) so that it falls down <vi>The police had to <it>beat down</it> the door to get into the house.</vi> <vi>The storm <it>beat down</it> the crops.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Years of failure had <it>beaten</it> him <it>down</it>. [=had caused him to lose hope or spirit]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to lower a price <vi>I <it>beat</it> her <it>down</it> from £30 to £15.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat (a price) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat down (a price)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause someone to lower (a price) <vi>I <it>beat</it> her asking price <it>down</it> from £30 to £15.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to go away quickly <vi>The teenagers <it>beat it</it> when the cops arrived.</vi> <un>often used as a command <vi>Stop bothering me. <it>Beat it</it>! [=<it>get lost</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat off (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat (someone or something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone or something) to go away by fighting <vi>She managed to <it>beat off</it> her attacker.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The company has managed to <it>beat off</it> [=<it>fight off</it>] its competitors and maintain control of the market.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal + impolite</ssl> <ssl>of a man</ssl> <dt>:<sx>masturbate</sx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to put out (a fire) by beating <vi>The fire was raging but we managed to <it>beat</it> it <it>out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to turn (a ground ball) into a base hit by running fast to first base <vi>He <it>beat out</it> a bunt.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>beat out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to defeat or overcome (a person, team, etc.) <vi>They were <it>beaten out</it> [=<it>beaten</it>] in the semifinals.</vi> <vi>She thought she would get the job, but someone else <it>beat</it> her <it>out</it>. [=someone else got the job]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat someone to the punch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>punch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat the clock</dre> <dx>see <dxt>clock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat the rap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>beat up (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>beat (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to hurt or injure (someone) by hitting <vi>A gang of bullies threatened to <it>beat</it> him <it>up</it>.</vi> <vi>He was <it>beaten up</it> badly by the bullies.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a politician who is getting <it>beat/beaten up</it> by liberal/conservative critics</vi> <vi>He's been <phrase>beating himself up</phrase> [=he has been harshly blaming or criticizing himself] because of the failure of his marriage.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>beat-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat up on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>beat up on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to hit (someone) repeatedly in order to cause pain or injury :to beat (someone) <vi>A gang of bullies was <it>beating up on</it> him.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>a politician who is getting <it>beat up on</it> by his critics</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to beat the band</dre> <dx>see <dxt>band</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>beat*able</ure> <sound><wav>beat0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:təbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an easily <it>beatable</it> opponent [=an opponent that can be easily defeated]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="beat[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">beat</hw> <altpr>ˈbi:t</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>beats</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of beating <vi>a single <it>beat</it> on a drum</vi> <vi>a <it>beat</it> of the bird's wings</vi> <vi>a single <it>beat</it> of his heart [=a single heartbeat]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>heart skipped a beat</tag> at <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a sound produced by beating <vi>We could hear the steady <it>beat</it> of the waves against the shore.</vi> <vi>They danced to the <it>beat</it> of the drums.</vi> <vi>listening to the <it>beat</it> of his heart</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a loud or strong sound that occurs regularly in music or poetry <vi>music that has four <it>beats</it> to a bar</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>downbeat</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the regular pattern of sounds in music or poetry :<sx>rhythm</sx> <vi>She likes music with a Latin <it>beat</it>.</vi> <vi>a pounding <it>beat</it></vi> <vi>The music had a steady <it>beat</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place or area that someone (such as a policeman) regularly goes to, walks through, or covers as part of a job <un>usually singular <vi>The policeman was patrolling/pounding his/the <it>beat</it>. = The policeman was on his/the <it>beat</it>.</vi> <vi>a reporter's <it>beat</it></vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>miss a beat</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:to have difficulty in continuing :to stop or hesitate briefly <vi>He answered their questions <phrase>without missing a beat</phrase>. [=he answered all their questions very easily and without hesitating]</vi> <vi>He answered all their questions and <phrase>never missed a beat</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>didn't miss a beat</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="beat[3]"> <hw hindex="3">beat</hw> <altpr>ˈbi:t</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>not used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very tired :<sx>exhausted</sx> <vi>Let me sit down. I'm absolutely <it>beat</it>!</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beat-up"> <hw>beat–up</hw> <sound><wav>beatu01w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:tˌʌp</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more beat–up; most beat–up</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:old and badly worn or damaged <vi>a <it>beat-up</it> old car</vi> <dx>see also <tag>beat up</tag> at <dxt>beat</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="band[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">band</hw> <sound><wav>band0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbænd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bands</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a usually small group of musicians who play popular music together <vi>The <it>band's</it> drummer is also the lead singer.</vi> <vi>a rock-and-roll <it>band</it></vi> <vi>a jazz <it>band</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>orchestra</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>big band</dxt> <dxt>brass band</dxt> <dxt>garage band</dxt> <dxt>marching band</dxt> <dxt>one-man band</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a group of people or animals <vi>A <it>band</it> of scientists questioned the theory.</vi> <vi>She photographed a <it>band</it> of gorillas.</vi> <vi>a <it>band</it> of hunters from the tribe</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a flat, straight piece of material (such as plastic or metal) that forms a circle around something <vi>A <it>band</it> of plastic holds the lid on the container.</vi> <vi>They placed a metal <it>band</it> with an identification number on the bird's leg.</vi> <vi>She lost her <phrase>wedding band</phrase>. [=<it>wedding ring</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>armband</dxt> <dxt>rubber band</dxt> <dxt>sweatband</dxt> <dxt>waistband</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a strip of something that is different from what is around it :a thick line <vi>The bird has black <it>bands</it> above its eyes.</vi> <vi>The dress has an embroidered <it>band</it> at the hem.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>There is a <it>band of</it> white near the hem of the dress.</vi> <vi>A <it>band of</it> thunderstorms crossed the area late last night.</vi> <vi>They left a narrow <it>band of</it> grass growing near the street.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a range of frequencies over which radio signals are broadcast <vi>The radio station broadcasts on the AM <it>band</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a range or group between a lower and an upper limit :<sx>bracket</sx> <vi>People in younger age <it>bands</it> may be in higher or lower tax <it>bands</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>to beat the band</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a very forceful or obvious way <vi>He was snoring <it>to beat the band</it>. [=he was snoring very loudly]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brain[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">brain</hw> <sound><wav>brain001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbreɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>brains</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the organ of the body in the head that controls functions, movements, sensations, and thoughts <vi>Scientists are learning more about how the human <it>brain</it> works.</vi> <vi>The left and right sides of the <it>brain</it> have different functions.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>brain</it> injury/tumor</vi> <vi><it>brain</it> damage/surgery</vi> <vi><it>brain</it> cells/tissue</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the ability to think and reason :<sx>intelligence</sx> <vi>Don't be such an idiot—use your <it>brain</it>. [=<it>head</it>]</vi> <vi>She has a good <it>brain</it>. [=she is smart]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry—I don't know where my <it>brain</it> is today. [=I'm not thinking clearly today]</vi> <vi>If he had <phrase>half a brain</phrase> [=if he was at all smart], he would have left a long time ago.</vi> <un>often plural <vi>If he had any <it>brains</it>, he would have left a long time ago.</vi> <vi>She has both <it>brains</it> and beauty.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a very intelligent person <vi>The other children always teased him about being such a <it>brain</it>.</vi> <vi>She is one of the best <it>brains</it> [=<it>intellects, minds</it>] in the field.</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>the brains of/behind</phrase> something, you are the person who thinks of plans or makes important decisions for a group. <vi>She's <it>the brains of</it> this organization.</vi> <vi>He was <it>the brains behind</it> the scheme.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>beat/bash someone's brains out</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>beat/bash someone's brains in</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to hit someone on the head in a way that causes serious injury or death :to beat someone very badly <vi>They threatened to <it>beat my brains in</it> if I ever came here again.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blow someone's brains out</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to kill someone with a shot to the head :to shoot someone fatally in the head <vi>When he refused to hand over the money, the robbers threatened to <it>blow his brains out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cudgel your brain/brains</dre> <def><sl>informal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to think very hard :to rack your brain <vi>I <it>cudgeled my brains</it> for a solution to the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the brain</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:always in your thoughts <vi>I've had pizza <it>on the brain</it> all day. [=I've been thinking about pizza all day]</vi> <vi>He's got sex <it>on the brain</it>. [=he's always thinking about sex]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pick someone's brain/brains</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to talk to someone in order to get helpful information or advice <vi>Do you have a moment? I need to <it>pick your brain</it> about a little situation that has come up.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rack your brain/brains</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rack</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bush"> <hw highlight="yes">bush</hw> <sound><wav>bush0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊʃ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bush*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a plant that has stems of wood and is smaller than a tree <vi>a rose/mulberry <it>bush</it></vi> <vi>The <it>bushes</it> [=<it>shrubs</it>] in my yard need to be trimmed.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thick growth of hair or fur <vi>a <it>bush</it> of hair</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the bush</bnote> <dt>:a large area (such as in Australia or Africa) that has not been cleared and that is not used for farming <vi>She recently spent several weeks in <it>the bush</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bird</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>beat around the bush</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>beat about the bush</va></vr> <def><dt>:to avoid saying something by talking about other things <vi>Stop <it>beating around the bush</it> and tell me why you're here.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clock[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clock</hw> <sound><wav>clock001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɑ:k</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clocks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a device that shows what time it is and that is usually placed in a room or attached to a wall <vi>She looked/glanced at the <it>clock</it> on the wall. It was now 2:30.</vi> <vi>the hands/face of the <it>clock</it></vi> <vi>a digital <it>clock</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>clock</it> tower [=a tower with a clock on at least one of its sides]</vi> <vi>a <it>clock</it> face</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>watch</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>alarm clock</dxt> <dxt>atomic clock</dxt> <dxt>biological clock</dxt> <dxt>body clock</dxt> <dxt>cuckoo clock</dxt> <dxt>grandfather clock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <dt>:a clock that is used in sports and that shows how much time remains for a particular part of a game <vi>They were winning by 2 points with 10 seconds (left) on <it>the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>They stopped <it>the</it> (game) <it>clock</it> with eight seconds remaining.</vi> <snote>In U.S. English, to <phrase>eat up the clock</phrase> or <phrase>run out the clock</phrase> or <phrase>kill the clock</phrase> is to keep control of the ball or puck near the end of a game so that your opponent will not have a chance to score. <vi>We kept moving the ball to try to <it>eat up the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>If we can <it>run out the clock</it>, we can keep our lead and win.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>shot clock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <dt>:<sx>time clock</sx> <vi>I punched <it>the clock</it> at 8:45 and started working right away.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a device that shows how far a vehicle has traveled :<sx>odometer</sx> <vi>a car with 100,000 miles <phrase>on the clock</phrase></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>against the clock</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in order to do or finish something before a particular time <vi>On our last project, we were working/racing <it>against the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>It was a race <it>against the clock</it> to finish the job on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>If a race is <it>against the clock</it>, the time of each racer is measured and the racer with the fastest time wins. <vi>One by one the skiers sped downhill, racing <it>against the clock</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>around the clock</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>round the clock</va></vr> <def><dt>:throughout the entire day and night :every hour of the day <vi>Our stores are now open <it>around the clock</it>. [=our stores are open 24 hours a day]</vi> <vi>Reporters worked <it>around the clock</it> to cover the story.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat the clock</dre> <def><dt>:to do or finish something quickly before a particular time <vi>In a desperate attempt to <it>beat the clock</it>, I raced to mail my tax return before midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/turn back the clock</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>put/turn the clock back</va></vr> <def><dt>:to return to a condition that existed in the past <vi>This new decision has effectively <it>turned back the clock</it> on 20 years of progress.</vi> <vi>I wish that we could <it>turn back the clock</it> and start all over again.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="dead[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dead</hw> <sound><wav>dead0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɛd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer alive or living :no longer having life <vi>Her husband is <it>dead</it>. He died last year.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>dead</it> for over 10 years now. [=she died more than 10 years ago]</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> insect/bird/dog</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> trees/leaves/skin</vi> <vi>the <it>dead</it> [=<it>lifeless</it>] bodies of the soldiers</vi> <vi>He was found <it>dead</it> in his apartment yesterday.</vi> <vi>He lay <it>dead</it> on the floor.</vi> <vi>The lost mountain climbers were believed/presumed <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>She shot him <it>dead</it>. [=she killed him by shooting him]</vi> <vi>When we found her, she was <phrase>more dead than alive</phrase>. [=almost dead; very close to death]</vi> <vi>The poster said that the robbers were wanted <phrase>dead or alive</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>as good as dead</phrase>. [=he was almost dead]</vi> <vi>She taught her dog to <phrase>play dead</phrase>. [=to lie on its back and pretend to be dead]</vi> <usageref>deceased</usageref> <snote>To <phrase>leave (someone or something) for dead</phrase> is to leave a person or animal that you know will probably die instead of trying to help. <vi>They hit the dog with their car and <it>left it for dead</it> on the side of the road.</vi> <vi>He had been badly beaten and <it>left for dead</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sin><if>dead*er</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:not able to feel or move <vi>My hand was <it>dead</it> [=<it>numb</it>] after holding the bag for so long.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very tired <vi>Our legs were completely <it>dead</it> after hiking all day.</vi> <vi>I arrived home from work <phrase>half dead</phrase>. [=<it>exhausted</it>]</vi> <vi>By the end of the day the workers were <phrase>dead on their feet</phrase>. [=very tired but still standing, working, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:feeling no emotions <vi>After the war, I was emotionally <it>dead</it>. [=I was no longer able to feel happiness, sadness, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:certain to be punished or hurt <vi>I'm <it>dead</it> if I come in late for work again.</vi> <vi>If I ever get my hands on you, you're <it>dead</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of a machine or device</ssl> <dt>:no longer working especially because of not having electricity <vi>The car's battery is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> electrical outlets</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> telephone line</vi> <vi>The phones <phrase>went dead</phrase> during the storm.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:no longer active or operating <vi>a <it>dead</it> [=<it>extinct</it>] volcano</vi> <vi><it>dead</it> companies</vi> <vi>That plan is <it>dead</it> for now. We've started developing a new one.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> deal</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:naturally not living <vi>rocks and other <it>dead</it> [=<it>inanimate</it>] matter</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sin><if>deader</if></sin> <sin><if>dest</if></sin> <sgram>or more dead; most dead</sgram> <dt>:lacking in activity or excitement <vi>The store's been <it>dead</it> [=<it>quiet</it>] all day.</vi> <vi>This party's completely <it>dead</it>. [=it is not lively]</vi> <vi>The audience was kind of <it>dead</it> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a time when nothing is being said or done <vi>We played cards to fill in the <it>dead</it> time between the two performances.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:no longer performed or enjoyed <vi>He says that disco is <it>dead</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>dead</it> art form</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>of a language</ssl> <dt>:no longer spoken <vi>Latin is a <it>dead</it> language.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe a situation in which play stops during a game <vi>In American football, the ball is <it>dead</it> [=<it>out of play</it>] after an incomplete forward pass.</vi> <vi>The ball is <it>dead</it> if it goes beyond the white line.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <dt>:complete, total, or absolute <vi>There was <it>dead</it> silence in the room.</vi> <vi>She spoke with <it>dead</it> certainty.</vi> <vi>I chased them at a <it>dead</it> run for three miles.</vi> <vi>The camera is a <phrase>dead giveaway</phrase> [=clearly shows] that you're a tourist.</vi> <vi>She fell to the floor in a <phrase>dead faint</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The evening wasn't all I had hoped for, but is wasn't a <phrase>dead loss</phrase>. [=it wasn't completely bad]</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>a dead ringer for</phrase> [=he looks exactly like] his father.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit, informal</it>) They're <phrase>a dead cert</phrase> [=<it>a sure thing, a sure bet</it>] to win. [=they are certain to win]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:sudden and complete <vi>The bus came to a <it>dead</it> [=<it>abrupt</it>] stop.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:perfect or exact <vi>Her arrow hit the <it>dead</it> [=<it>very</it>] center of the target.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) dead as a doornail</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) dead as a dodo</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to stress that someone or something is dead <vi>The old captain was <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The negotiations are <it>as dead as a doornail</it>.</vi> <vi>The deal is <it>dead as a doornail</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat a dead horse</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>flog a dead horse</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch/see (someone) dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you say that people <phrase>wouldn't/won't catch/see you dead</phrase> or that you <phrase>wouldn't/won't be caught/seen dead</phrase> doing something, you refuse to let others see you doing it because it would cause you to be embarrassed. <vi>I <it>wouldn't be caught/seen dead</it> wearing that hideous outfit.</vi> <vi>She <it>won't be caught dead</it> going to the movies with her obnoxious brother.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead and buried</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>dead and gone</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:no longer living :<sx>dead</sx> <vi>He's been <it>dead and buried</it> for 50 years.</vi> <vi>relatives long <it>dead and gone</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:no longer used or accepted <vi>Those old family traditions are <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>That idea is <it>dead and buried</it>.</vi> <vi>The days of our childhood are <it>dead and gone</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead from the neck up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very stupid or foolish <vi>Most of his friends are <it>dead from the neck up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead in the water</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not making any progress :not having any chance of success <vi>The peace talks were <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi> <vi>His election campaign is <it>dead in the water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead men tell no tales</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tale</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead on arrival</dre> <def><dt>:having died before getting to a hospital, emergency room, etc. <vi>The victim was <it>dead on arrival</it> at the hospital.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Some are saying that any new tax proposal would be <it>dead on arrival</it>. [=would have no chances of being approved]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>dead to rights</dre> <dx>see <dxt>right</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead to the world</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:sleeping very deeply <vi>You can't wake him up. He's <it>dead to the world</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop dead</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall to the ground and die very suddenly <vi>She <it>dropped dead</it> while playing basketball.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used as a rude way to tell someone to leave you alone <vi>“He asked you for help after being such a jerk? You should have told him to <it>drop dead</it>!”</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>drop-dead</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>knock dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>over my dead body</dre> <dx>see <dxt>body</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>dead*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="drum[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">drum</hw> <sound><wav>drum0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdrʌm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>drums</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a musical instrument that is made with a thin layer of skin or plastic stretched over the end of a round frame and that is played by hitting the skin or plastic with sticks or with your hands <vi>a child beating on a <it>drum</it></vi> <vi>We heard the rhythmic beating of <it>drums</it>.</vi> <vi>She plays the <it>drums</it>.</vi> <vi>That was Miles Davis on trumpet and Max Roach <phrase>on drums</phrase>. [=playing the drums]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>kettledrum</dxt> <dxt>snare drum</dxt> <dxt>steel drum</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the sound that is made when something hits a surface over and over again <vi>He lay listening to the steady <it>drum</it> of the rain on the roof.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a large usually metal container for liquids <vi>oil <it>drums</it></vi> <vi>a 55-gallon <it>drum</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a machine or part of a machine that is shaped like a cylinder <vi>the <it>drum</it> of a clothes dryer</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beat/bang the drum for</dre> <def><dt>:to say or write things that strongly support (someone or something) <vi>They joined together to <it>beat the drum for</it> their candidate.</vi> <vi><it>banging the drum for</it> human rights</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
