<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="beauty"> <hw highlight="yes">beau*ty</hw> <sound><wav>beauty01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbju:ti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>beau*ties</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the quality of being physically attractive <vi>Her <it>beauty</it> is beyond compare. [=she is very beautiful; no one is as beautiful as she is]</vi> <un>sometimes used before another noun <vi><it>beauty</it> products [=soaps, makeup, and other things that help make people more physically attractive]</vi> <vi>a <it>beauty</it> treatment</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the qualities in a person or a thing that give pleasure to the senses or the mind <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>the <it>beauty</it> [=<it>loveliness</it>] of the stars</vi> <vi>We explored the natural <it>beauty</it> of the island.</vi> <vi>I'm learning to appreciate the <it>beauty</it> of poetry.</vi> <vi>We have different ideas/notions/conceptions of <it>beauty</it>. [=different opinions about what makes things beautiful]</vi> <vi>“A thing of <it>beauty</it> is a joy for ever…” <aq>John Keats, <it>Endymion</it> (1818)</aq></vi> <wsgram>plural</wsgram> <vi>We explored the natural <it>beauties</it> of the island.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a beautiful woman <vi>She was one of the great <it>beauties</it> of her time.</vi> <vi>She was no <it>beauty</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a very good thing :a very good example of something <vi>That was a <it>beauty</it> of a fight. [=that was an excellent fight]</vi> <vi>Dad and I went fishing and we caught a couple of <it>beauties</it>.</vi> <un>often used in an ironic way to describe a bad thing or person <vi>That mistake was a <it>beauty</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a good or appealing part of something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The <it>beauty</it> of the game is that everyone can play.</vi> <vi>No one knows when it's going to happen, and that's the <it>beauty</it> of it!</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>One of the <it>beauties</it> of the system is that it allows you to adjust the schedule easily.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beauty contest"> <hw>beauty contest</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tests</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a contest in which people judge a group of women or girls and decide which one is the most beautiful <ca>called also <cat>beauty pageant</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beauty mark"> <hw>beauty mark</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ marks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>beauty spot <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beauty part"> <hw>beauty part</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the beauty part</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the best or most appealing part of something <vi>There's plenty of food, and <it>the beauty part</it> is that it's all free!</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="beauty queen"> <hw>beauty queen</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ queens</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a woman or girl who is a winner of a beauty contest <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She's fairly good-looking, but she's no <it>beauty queen</it>. [=she's not beautiful]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beauty salon"> <hw>beauty salon</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -lons</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a shop where women get beauty treatments (such as haircuts) to make them more attractive <ca>called also <cat>beauty parlor</cat> <cat>beauty shop</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beauty spot"> <hw>beauty spot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ spots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small dark mark (such as a mole) on a woman's face <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>beauty mark</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a beautiful place <vi>a famous <it>beauty spot</it> by a mountain lake</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
