<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="beautiful"> <hw highlight="yes">beau*ti*ful</hw> <sound><wav>beauti02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbju:tɪfəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more beau*ti*ful; most beau*ti*ful</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:having beauty: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:very attractive in a physical way <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> young woman/child</vi> <vi>You have the most <it>beautiful</it> smile/eyes.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:giving pleasure to the mind or the senses <vi>The film tells a <it>beautiful</it> story about two young lovers.</vi> <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> song</vi> <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> dress/color/garden/house</vi> <vi>Our hotel room had a <it>beautiful</it> view of the ocean.</vi> <vi>The sunsets here are absolutely <it>beautiful</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:very good or pleasing :not having any bad qualities <vi>We've been having such <it>beautiful</it> [=<it>excellent</it>, <it>fine</it>] weather lately.</vi> <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> sunny day</vi> <vi>What a <it>beautiful</it> day for a picnic!</vi> <vi>They did a <it>beautiful</it> job [=an excellent job] fixing up the house.</vi> <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> friendship/relationship</vi> <vi>This is a <it>beautiful</it> example of early American poetry.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>beau*ti*ful*ly</ure> <sound><wav>beauti03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbju:tɪfli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>You sang <it>beautifully</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>beautifully</it> written poem</vi></utxt></uro> <syns><sc>beautiful</sc>, <sc>pretty</sc>, <sc>lovely</sc>, and <sc>handsome</sc> describe people and things that are pleasing to look at, hear, etc. <sc>beautiful</sc> applies to things that give the greatest pleasure and cause people to feel strong emotions. <vi><it>beautiful</it> sunsets</vi> <vi>a <it>beautiful</it> poem</vi> When used of a person, it usually describes a woman, girl, or small child. <vi>She's the most <it>beautiful</it> woman I've ever met.</vi> <vi>Their son was a <it>beautiful</it> baby.</vi> <sc>pretty</sc> often applies to small things that are attractive in a delicate way. <vi>a <it>pretty</it> little dress with pink ribbons</vi> <vi>He paints <it>pretty</it> pictures and sells them on the street.</vi> When used of a person, it almost always describes a woman or girl. <vi>their <it>pretty</it> daughter</vi> <vi>She looked very <it>pretty</it> in her new dress.</vi> <sc>lovely</sc> applies to things that make people feel strong emotions by being very graceful or delicate. <vi>a <it>lovely</it> melody</vi> When used to describe a person's appearance, it almost always refers to a woman or girl. <vi>They have two <it>lovely</it> daughters.</vi> It can also describe a person's character, and in this use it refers to both women and men. <vi>My uncle is a <it>lovely</it> man. [=a very good man]</vi> <sc>handsome</sc> applies to things that are attractive because they have a balanced design or shape. <vi>a <it>handsome</it> house surrounded by gardens</vi> <vi>She wore a <it>handsome</it> gray suit to the office.</vi> When used to describe a person, it usually refers to a man or boy. <vi>their <it>handsome</it> son</vi> <vi>a very <it>handsome</it> actor</vi> <vi>He has a strong, <it>handsome</it> face.</vi> A woman who is described as <it>handsome</it> is attractive but usually not in a very delicate or feminine way.</syns></entry>

</entry_list>
