<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="because"> <hw highlight="yes">be*cause</hw> <sound><wav>becaus02.wav</wav><wav>becaus01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈkɑ:z, bɪˈkʌz</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><dt>:for the reason that <vi>I ran <it>because</it> I was afraid.</vi> <vi>We were late <it>because</it> our car wouldn't start. = <it>Because</it> our car wouldn't start, we were late.</vi> <vi>“Why did you do it?” “<it>Because</it> she told me to.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>because of</dre> <def><dt>:for the reason of <vi>The picnic has been canceled <it>because of</it> [=<it>due to, on account of</it>] bad weather.</vi> <vi><it>Because of</it> this [=for this reason], only very rich people can afford to live on the island.</vi> <vi><it>Because of</it> you, we missed the bus. [=you caused us to miss the bus]</vi> <vi>The accident happened <it>because of</it> [=<it>through</it>] carelessness.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just because</dre> <def><dt>:for the simple or single reason that <vi>Don't get nervous <it>just because</it> the teacher might ask you a question.</vi> <vi>We can't assume it will rain today <it>just because</it> it rained yesterday.</vi> <vi><it>Just because</it> your friends do it, that doesn't mean that you should do it, too.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="just[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">just</hw> <altpr>ˈʤʌst</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to an exact degree or in an exact manner <vi>You look <it>just</it> [=<it>exactly</it>] like your father.</vi> <vi>The store has <it>just</it> the tool you need.</vi> <vi>That's <it>just</it> what I expected.</vi> <vi>You have to accept me <it>just</it> as I am.</vi> <vi>This shirt fits <it>just</it> right.</vi> <vi>She called him a liar and told him he was <it>just</it> like all the other men she'd met.</vi> <vi>It's <it>just</it> like you to be jealous every time I speak to another woman. [=you're always jealous when I speak to another woman]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>just my luck</tag> at <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:very recently <vi>The bell <it>just</it> rang.</vi> <vi>He was <it>just</it> here a minute ago.</vi> <vi>She had <it>just</it> returned when he entered.</vi> <vi>She has <it>just</it> acted in her first play. = (<it>chiefly US</it>) She <it>just</it> acted in her first play.</vi> <vi>I've <it>just</it> been trying to call you! = (<it>chiefly US</it>) I was <it>just</it> trying to call you!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:at this or that exact moment or time <vi>I was <it>just</it> going to telephone you!</vi> <vi>She's <it>just</it> finishing a letter, and she'll be with you shortly.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to say that two or more events are happening at the same time or with very little time between them <vi>He confessed <it>just</it> before he died.</vi> <vi>The phone rang <it>just</it> as/when we were leaving.</vi> <vi>I came <phrase>just as soon</phrase> as I heard the news.</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize that a moment or time is not far from the present moment <vi>She'll be back in <it>just</it> a minute. [=she'll be back very soon]</vi> <vi>I saw her here <it>just</it> yesterday.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:by a small amount <vi>I had <it>just</it> [=<it>barely</it>] enough time to eat breakfast before leaving.</vi> <vi>I arrived <it>just</it> in time to see him win.</vi> <vi>We could (only) <it>just</it> see the ship coming over the horizon.</vi> <vi>The horse's time for the race was <it>just</it> short of the record. = The horse <it>just</it> missed breaking the record.</vi> <vi>It should take us <it>just</it> [=<it>slightly</it>] under/over an hour to get there.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:by a small distance <vi>She lives <it>just</it> west of here.</vi> <vi>The bathroom is <it>just</it> down the hall.</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> [=<it>directly</it>] across from the bank is a hotel.</vi> <vi>The restaurant is <it>just</it> around the corner.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>just around the corner</tag> at <dxt>corner</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:nothing more than :<sx>only</sx> <vi>This is <it>just</it> [=<it>simply</it>] a note to say I love you.</vi> <vi>He is <it>just</it> an assistant to the manager.</vi> <vi>She was <it>just</it> a baby when her father went off to war.</vi> <vi>Is it <it>just</it> a coincidence that I see him everywhere I go?</vi> <vi>He has <it>just</it> two months left before his retirement.</vi> <vi>“Will you have another drink?” “Well, perhaps <it>just</it> (the) one.”</vi> <vi>I don't know him well: I've met him <it>just</it> (the) once. [=I've met him only one time]</vi> <vi>“Who is she?” “Oh, <it>just</it> somebody who works in the same office as me.”</vi> <vi>I love <it>just</it> you and nobody else but you.</vi> <vi>She'll be away from her desk for <it>just</it> a few minutes. = She'll <it>just</it> be away from her desk for a few minutes.</vi> <vi>They took a nice field and turned it into <phrase>just another</phrase> shopping mall.</vi> <vi>He's <it>just another</it> guy trying to get rich without working too hard.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to stress the simple truth of a description or statement <vi>We'd like to buy a new car. We <it>just</it> [=<it>simply</it>] don't have enough money.</vi> <vi>Sometimes a person <it>just</it> wants to be left alone.</vi> <vi>She <it>just</it> wanted to say goodbye.</vi> <vi>You'll <it>just</it> have to be patient.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry if I seem grouchy. I'm <it>just</it> tired.</vi> <vi>The wedding was <it>just</it> wonderful.</vi> <vi>I feel <it>just</it> great!</vi> <vi>The kids want to camp in the backyard, <phrase>just for fun</phrase>. [=simply to have fun]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used in polite requests <vi>Could I <it>just</it> borrow that pen for a minute? Thanks!</vi> <vi>Would you <it>just</it> step this way, please, ladies and gentlemen.</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis when you give an order or make a suggestion <vi>Why don't we <it>just</it> forget the whole thing.</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> hold on a minute! Did you say you'd solved the problem?!</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> [=<it>simply</it>] tell him you don't feel like going out.</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> (you) wait until your father sees this mess, young lady!</vi> <vi>Don't argue with me: <it>just</it> do it!</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> imagine how silly she'll feel when she realizes that she was wrong.</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> look at the size of that thing!</vi> <vi><it>Just</it> think how happy we could be.</vi></un></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><un>used to describe what someone does instead of doing what is necessary or expected <vi>Don't <it>just</it> stand there: do something!</vi> <vi>She <it>just</it> stood there watching as he walked away.</vi> <vi>I can't <it>just</it> pretend nothing happened.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used with words like <it>might</it> and <it>may</it> to refer to something that is possible <vi>I know you don't expect him to succeed, but he might <it>just</it> surprise you. [=he might succeed]</vi> <vi>It's a crazy idea, but it <it>just</it> might work!</vi> <vi>You know, you <it>just</it> might be right about that.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>indeed</sx> <vi>Isn't the city hot, <it>just</it>!</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>just about</dre> <def><dt>:almost or nearly <vi>It was <it>just about</it> time to leave.</vi> <vi>The work is <it>just about</it> done.</vi> <vi>That is <it>just about</it> the biggest horse I have ever seen. [=that is a very big horse]</vi> <vi>That is <it>just about</it> the stupidest thing she has ever done.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just a minute/second/moment</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to ask someone to wait or stop briefly <vi><it>Just a second</it> and I will get that book for you.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to demand that someone stop or listen <vi><it>Just a minute</it>, young lady! You can't park there!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just anyone</dre> <def><dt>:any person at all <vi>I don't lend money to <it>just anyone</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just as</dre> <def><dt>:to an equal degree as <vi>Our house is <it>just as</it> nice as theirs.</vi> <vi>This one is <it>just as</it> good as that one.</vi> <vi>She performs <it>just as</it> well as he does.</vi> :in the same way as <vi><it>Just as</it> we hope to be forgiven, so we should forgive others.</vi> <vi><it>Just as</it> I thought/suspected, the door is locked. [=I thought that the door would be locked, and it is]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just as soon</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you would <it>just as soon</it> do something, you would prefer to do it. <vi>We asked him to come with us, but he said he'd <it>just as soon</it> stay home.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just as well</dre> <def><dt><snote>If it is <it>just as well</it> that something happens, then it is a good thing, even if it was not expected or intended. <vi>It's <it>just as well</it> she didn't get that job, since she will now be closer to home.</vi> <vi>I really didn't want to stay home this weekend, but it's <it>just as well</it>. I have a lot to do.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just because</dre> <dx>see <dxt>because</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>just like that</dre> <def><dt>:very suddenly <vi>The girl vanished <it>just like that</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Just like that</it> it started raining.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just now</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>just this minute/second</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a moment ago <vi>I saw him <it>just now</it>.</vi> <vi>I was <it>just this minute</it> thinking about calling you.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:at this moment <vi>They are <it>just now</it> heading out the door.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just on</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>exactly</sx> <vi>It was <it>just on</it> midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just so</dre> <def><dt>:in a particular way <vi>They feel they have to dress <it>just so</it> to be popular.</vi> :arranged in a very neat and tidy way <vi>Everything in her house has to be <it>just so</it> or she gets upset. [=everything has to be exactly as she likes it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just the same</dre> <dx>see <dxt>same</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>just the thing</dre> <def><dt>:the best or perfect thing <vi>I have <it>just the thing</it> for your hair.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just yet</dre> <def><dt>:right now <un>used in negative constructions to say that something is not done yet or true yet but will be soon <vi>I don't have the table finished <it>just yet</it>.</vi> <vi>“Are you ready to leave?” “Not <it>just yet</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not just</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that one thing is true and that another thing is also true <vi>She's <it>not just</it> my friend, she's my lawyer.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
