<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="behavior"> <hw highlight="yes">be*hav*ior</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>be*hav*iour</va> <sound><wav>behavi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈheɪvjɚ</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>be*hav*iors</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the way a person or animal acts or behaves <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I'm surprised by her bad <it>behavior</it> toward her friends.</vi> <vi>Students will be rewarded for good <it>behavior</it>.</vi> <vi>scientists studying the <it>behavior</it> of elephants</vi> <vi>normal adolescent <it>behavior</it></vi> <vi>criminal <it>behavior</it></vi> <vi>an interesting <phrase>pattern of behavior</phrase> = an interesting <phrase>behavior pattern</phrase></vi> <vi>The children were all <phrase>on their best behavior</phrase> [=were all behaving very well and politely] at the museum.</vi> <vi>Inmates may be released from prison early <phrase>for good behavior</phrase>. [=because they have followed prison rules and have not caused problems]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>An acceptable social <it>behavior</it> in one country may be unacceptable in another country.</vi> <vi>Doctors are trying to educate people about <it>behaviors</it> that can put them at increased risk for skin cancer.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way something (such as a machine or substance) moves, functions, or reacts <vi>The experiment tested the <it>behavior</it> of various metals under heat and pressure.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>be*hav*ior*al</ure> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>be*hav*iour*al</va> <sound><wav>behavi02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈheɪvjərəl</pr></vr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>behavioral</it> problems</vi> <vi><it>behavioral</it> patterns</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="best[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">best</hw> <sound><wav>best0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>good</ct> <cl>or of</cl> <ct>well</ct></cx> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:better than all others in quality or value <vi>You should wear your <it>best</it> clothes tonight.</vi> <vi>He took us to the (very) <it>best</it> restaurants in the city.</vi> <vi>We ate the <it>best</it> food and drank the <it>best</it> wines.</vi> <vi>You're our <it>best</it> customers.</vi> <vi>His modesty and sense of humor are his <it>best</it> qualities.</vi> <vi>Is that your <it>best</it> offer?</vi> <vi>I've had the <it>best</it> time with you! [=I've had a very enjoyable time with you]</vi> <vi>The <it>best</it> [=most valuable] things in life are free.</vi> <vi>Which of these do you think tastes <it>best</it>?</vi> <vi>Mary sends you her very <it>best</it> wishes/regards.</vi> <vi>He's my <phrase>best friend</phrase>. [=my closest/dearest friend] = He and I are <phrase>best friends</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:most skillful, talented, or successful <vi>She's the <it>best</it> student in her class.</vi> <vi>He won the award for <it>best</it> actor in a drama.</vi> <vi>the team's <it>best</it> player</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:most appropriate, useful, or helpful <vi>She truly believes that this is the <it>best</it> way to solve the problem.</vi> <vi>She's the team's <it>best</it> hope/chance for a medal.</vi> <vi>She thought waiting was <it>best</it>. = She thought that the <it>best</it> thing to do was to wait. = She thought that it was <it>best</it> to wait.</vi> <vi>It's <it>best</it> to leave early if you want to be sure of arriving on time.</vi> <vi>We want to do what's <it>best</it> for you.</vi> <vi>He's the <it>best</it> man for the job.</vi> <vi>You should do whatever you think is the <it>best</it> thing to do. = You should do whatever you <phrase>think best</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We're making the <phrase>best possible</phrase> use of these materials.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>best of all</dre> <def><dt><snote>The phrase <it>best of all</it> is often used to refer to the most important or appealing part of something that has many good parts. <vi>The machine is easy to use, easy to clean, and <it>best of all</it>, it's absolutely free when you order these books.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>next best</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person or thing that is <it>next best</it> is not as good as the best person or thing but is better than all others. <vi>The shortstop is the best player on the team, and the catcher is the <it>next best</it> player.</vi> <vi>We can't see each other often, but calling each other on the telephone is <phrase>the next best thing</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your best behavior</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>on your best behavior</it> you are behaving very politely and well. <vi>Remember to be <it>on your best behavior</it> with your grandmother.</vi> <vi>The children promised to be <it>on their best behavior</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
