<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="behind[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">be*hind</hw> <sound><wav>behind01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈhaɪnd</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in or toward the back <vi>look <it>behind</it></vi> <vi>The older students entered the room first with the younger students following <it>behind</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in the place that someone is going away from <vi>She <phrase>stayed behind</phrase> after the other guests left.</vi> <vi>They <phrase>left behind</phrase> everything they owned when they fled the country.</vi> <vi>We had to <it>leave</it> our family, friends, and neighbors <it>behind</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She has <it>left</it> her fears and doubts <it>behind</it>. [=she is no longer fearful and doubtful]</vi> <vi>She wanted to <phrase>leave the past behind</phrase>. [=forget about the past]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:later in time <vi>“If Winter comes, can Spring be far <it>behind</it>?” <aq>P. B. Shelley, “Ode to the West Wind” (1820)</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a losing position in a race or competition <vi>“How far <it>behind</it> was she?” “At least 50 yards (<it>behind</it>).”</vi> <vi>We were ahead in the first half, but now we're <it>behind</it>.</vi> <vi>We were <it>behind</it> by five runs. = We were five runs <it>behind</it>.</vi> <vi>a politician who is <it>behind</it> in the polls</vi> <vi>She was losing the race but she <phrase>came from behind</phrase> and is now in front.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that is not happening or proceeding as quickly as it should <vi>We're running about five minutes <it>behind</it> [=<it>late</it>] with tonight's schedule.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe someone who is not doing something (such as paying a debt) as quickly as required or expected <vi>He got a bit <it>behind</it> [=<it>late</it>] in/with his payments.</vi> <vi>He is <it>behind</it> in (paying) his rent.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="behind[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">behind</hw> <altpr>bɪˈhaɪnd</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or to a place at the back of or to the rear of (someone or something) <vi>Look <it>behind</it> you.</vi> <vi>He was standing in front of me and she was standing <it>behind</it> [=<it>in back of</it>] me.</vi> <vi>The older students entered the room first with the younger students following <it>behind</it> them.</vi> <vi>The house is <it>behind</it> some trees. [=there are some trees in front of the house]</vi> <vi>The cat hid <it>behind</it> the couch.</vi> <vi>The sun went/hid/was <it>behind</it> a cloud.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>behind the eight ball</tag> at <dxt>eight ball</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:losing to (someone or something) in a race or competition <vi>“How far <it>behind</it> the other runners was she?” “At least 50 yards (<it>behind</it> them).”</vi> <vi>They were ahead of us by 5 points earlier in the game, but now they're <it>behind</it> us by 7.</vi> <vi>The polls show that he is <it>behind</it> the other candidates.</vi> <vi>The company is now <it>behind</it> the competition.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in a less advanced position than (someone or something) <vi>He was a year <it>behind</it> me in school. [=he finished school a year after I did]</vi> :not happening or proceeding as quickly as (someone or something) <vi>He was <it>behind</it> the other students in his studies.</vi> <vi>This year's sales have lagged considerably/significantly <it>behind</it> last year's sales. [=sales have not been as good this year as they were last year]</vi> <vi>We're running about five minutes <phrase>behind schedule</phrase>. [=<it>late</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:in the past for (someone or something) <vi>Those problems are <it>behind</it> us now.</vi> <vi>Her best work is <it>behind</it> her. [=her best work was in the past]</vi> <vi>He has many years of experience <it>behind</it> him. [=he has many years of experience in his past]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:out of the mind or thoughts of (someone) <vi>Let's put our troubles <it>behind</it> us. [=let's stop thinking/worrying about our troubles]</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:providing the reason or explanation for (something) <vi>We need to learn more about the conditions <it>behind</it> the strike. [=the conditions that led to the strike]</vi> <vi>What was really <it>behind</it> his murder? [=what was the real reason for his murder?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:responsible for (something) <vi>We'll get to the bottom of this conspiracy and find out who's <it>behind</it> it!</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:in support of (someone or something) <vi>Despite the controversy, most of his supporters remain solidly <it>behind</it> him.</vi> <vi>We're <it>behind</it> you all the way!</vi> <vi>I encourage everyone to <phrase>get behind</phrase> these proposals. [=to support these proposals]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:with the support of (something) <vi>They won the game 1–0 <it>behind</it> brilliant pitching. [=brilliant pitching made it possible for them to win the game 1–0]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>behind bars</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bar</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>behind the times</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="behind[3]"> <hw hindex="3">behind</hw> <altpr>bɪˈhaɪnd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>behinds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the part of the body above the legs that is used for sitting :<sx>buttocks</sx> <vi>kicked him in the <it>behind</it></vi> <vi>Get your <it>behind</it> over here right now! [=come here right now]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="behind-the-scenes"> <hw>behind–the–scenes</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:working or happening privately without being known or seen by the public <vi>There has been a lot of <it>behind-the-scenes</it> lobbying for more money.</vi> <vi>She exerted a lot of <it>behind-the-scenes</it> influence when the project was being planned.</vi> <vi>an effective <it>behind-the-scenes</it> operator</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:revealing or reporting on things that usually happen privately without being known or seen by the public <vi>The documentary provides a <it>behind-the-scenes</it> glimpse of Congress in action.</vi> <vi>a <it>behind-the-scenes</it> account</vi> <dx>see also <tag>behind the scenes</tag> at <dxt>scene</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="back[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">back</hw> <sound><wav>back0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>backs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the rear part of the body :the part of the body that is opposite to the stomach and chest and that goes from the neck to the top of the legs <vi>She was carrying her little daughter on her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He injured his <it>back</it>. = He suffered a <it>back</it> injury.</vi> <vi>She has a pain in the small of her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>an aching <it>back</it></vi> <vi>I slapped/patted him on his/the <it>back</it> to congratulate him.</vi> <vi>He broke his <it>back</it> [=<it>spine</it>] in a fall.</vi> <vi>She stabbed/shot him in the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He was handcuffed with his hands behind his <it>back</it>.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of an animal that is like a person's back <vi>a bird with a spotted <it>back</it></vi> <vi>riding on the <it>back</it> of a horse/donkey/camel</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>horseback</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something that is opposite the front or face :the rear side or surface of something <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>back</it> of the head</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of a mirror/spoon</vi> <vi>the <it>back</it> of the hand/leg/foot</vi> <vi>The book has fallen down the <it>back</it> of the couch.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the side or surface of something (such as a piece of paper) that is not usually used or seen first <un>usually singular <vi>She wrote something on the <it>back</it> of an envelope.</vi> <vi>He signed his name on the <it>back</it> of the check.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a place, position, or area that is at or near the rear of something <un>usually singular <vi>He put the letter in the <it>back</it> of the drawer.</vi> <vi>The kitchen is at/in the <it>back</it> of the house and the living room is at/in the front.</vi> <vi>Since our plane was leaving soon we were moved to the front of the line while others remained at the <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>Please move to the <it>back</it> of the elevator to make room for others.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of a chair or seat that supports a person's back <vi>a comfortable chair with a padded <it>back</it></vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the section of a book, magazine, etc., that includes the last pages <un>usually singular <vi>There is an index in the <it>back</it> of the book.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a book's cover that can be seen when the book is on a shelf <vi>The title of the book is shown on its <it>back</it>. [=<it>spine</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a player in some games (such as soccer and American football) who is positioned behind the front line of players <vi>a defensive <it>back</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fullback</dxt> <dxt>halfback</dxt> <dxt>quarterback</dxt> <dxt>running back</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a pat on the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a stab in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at/in the back of your mind</dre> <def><dt>:in the part of your mind where thoughts and memories are kept <un>used to describe ideas, memories, etc., that someone has but that are not usually thought about or not perfectly remembered <vi>The thought of retiring and moving out into the country has been <it>in the back of her mind</it> for many years, and now she's finally doing it.</vi> <vi>Somewhere <it>in the back of my mind</it> I knew I'd met him before.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back is to/against the wall</dre> <def><dt><snote>When <it>your back is to/against the wall</it> or <it>you have your back to/against the wall</it> you are in a bad position in which you are forced to do something in order to avoid failure. <vi><it>With our backs to the wall</it> we made a last desperate effort to finish the project on time.</vi> <vi>We knew that with so little time and money left to finish the project <it>we had our backs to the wall</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to back</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:with backs opposite or against each other <vi>The soldiers stood <it>back to back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:happening one after the other <vi>She won the annual competition two times <it>back to back</it>. [=<it>in a row</it>]</vi> <vi>He's had two victories <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <vi>I've scheduled two appointments <it>back to back</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back-to-back</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>back to front</dre> <def><sl>of a piece of clothing</sl> <dt>:with the back where the front should be <vi>He accidentally put the sweater on <it>back to front</it>. [=<it>front to back, backwards</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>behind someone's back</dre> <def><dt>:without someone's knowledge :in secret <vi>You shouldn't gossip about people <it>behind their back(s)</it>.</vi> <vi>If you have something to say, why not say it to my face instead of whispering it <it>behind my back</it>?!</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went behind his back</phrase> and spoke directly to his supervisor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break the back of</dre> <def><dt>:to get control of (something you are trying to stop or defeat) :to greatly weaken or subdue (something) <vi>He says the government's new policies will <it>break the back of</it> inflation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your back up</dre> <def><dt>:to become angry or annoyed and want to fight or argue <vi>He <it>gets his back up</it> and becomes defensive whenever someone questions his work.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>put someone's back up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>watch someone's back <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in back</dre> <def><dt>:in an area at the back of something <vi>There was only room for one passenger in front. The rest of us sat <it>in back</it>. [=<it>in the back</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in back of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:directly behind (something or someone) <vi>There's a small yard <it>in back of</it> the house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the back of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:because of (something) <vi>Profits have increased <it>on the back of</it> [=<it>on the strength of</it>] improved international sales.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>disapproving</ssl> <dt>:by using the efforts of (other people) <vi>The company has achieved record profits <it>on the back of</it> cheap labor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/off your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who is always or frequently criticizing you or telling you what to do is <it>on your back</it> and won't <phrase>get off your back</phrase>. <vi>He says his wife is always <it>on his back</it> about doing chores around the house.</vi> <vi><it>Get off my back</it>! I'm working as hard as I can!</vi> <vi>My boss is always criticizing me. I wish I knew some way to <it>get him off my back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>(flat) on your back</it> you are lying with your back against the ground, on a bed, etc. <vi>The accident left him (lying) <it>flat on his back</it> (in bed) for two weeks.</vi> This phrase is sometimes used figuratively. <vi>The stock market has been <it>flat on its back</it> [=has been doing very poorly] in recent weeks.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out back</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>out the back</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>round the back</va></vr> <def><dt>:in the area behind something (such as a building) <vi>In my youth we didn't have a toilet in the house but there was one <it>out back</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put someone's back up</dre> <def><dt>:to offend or annoy someone :to make someone angry or ready to argue <vi>I don't want to question his decision because that will just <it>put his back up</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>get your back up <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put your back into</dre> <def><dt>:to work very hard at (something) :to put a lot of effort into (something) <vi>If you want to get that floor clean you'll have to <it>put your back into</it> it.</vi> <vi>You'll really have to <it>put your back into</it> this project if you want it to succeed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>scratch someone's back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>scratch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the back of</dre> <def><dt><snote>In British English, to be <phrase>glad/happy (etc.) to see the back of</phrase> someone is to be glad to see someone finally going away. <vi>He's done nothing but make trouble and I'll be <it>glad to see the back of</it> him! [=I'll be glad when he has gone]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stab (someone) in the back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the shirt off your back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shirt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn your back</dre> <def><dt>:to turn so that you are facing away from someone <vi>He <it>turned his back</it> and walked away from me.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He <it>turned his back on</it> me and walked away.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His former supporters have <it>turned their backs on</it> him. [=have abandoned him]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch someone's back</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>have someone's back</va></vr> <def><dt>:to protect someone who is doing something that is dangerous or risky <vi>The police officer's partner always <it>watches his back</it>.</vi> <vi>Don't worry, <phrase>I've got your back</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>watch your back</dre> <def><dt><snote>If people tell you to <it>watch your back</it>, they are telling you to be careful. <vi>I hear the boss is in a bad mood this morning, so you'd better <it>watch your back</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>back*less</ure> <sound><wav>back0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>backless</it> evening gown</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bar[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bar</hw> <sound><wav>bar00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bars</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a building or room where alcoholic drinks and sometimes food are served <vi>We went to a <it>bar</it> for a drink.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sports bar</dxt> <dxt>tiki bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a counter where alcoholic drinks are served <vi>We sat at the restaurant's <it>bar</it> while we were waiting for a table.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cash bar</dxt> <dxt>open bar</dxt> <dxt>wet bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a building or room where a particular food or drink is served <vi>a seafood <it>bar</it></vi> <vi>a juice/coffee <it>bar</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>salad bar</dxt> <dxt>snack bar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a straight piece of metal, wood, etc., that is used as a tool, as part of a structure, or to keep people from entering or leaving through a door or window <vi>There were <it>bars</it> across all the windows.</vi> <vi>The door was secured with an iron <it>bar</it>.</vi> <vi>The pole-vaulter narrowly cleared the <it>bar</it>. [=the long bar that is set at a specific height and that a jumper tries to go over]</vi> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>bar</it> is used figuratively in phrases like <phrase>raise/lower the bar</phrase> and <phrase>set the bar higher/lower</phrase> to refer to changing the standard that is used to judge whether someone or something is good, successful, etc. <vi>The company's new software <it>raises the bar</it> for its competitors. [=the company's new software is very good and its competitors will have to produce better software to compete with it]</vi> <vi>Critics say that he has <it>lowered the bar</it> on what is considered acceptable behavior by politicians. [=he has caused people to accept worse behavior by politicians]</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>crossbar</dxt> <dxt>crowbar</dxt> <dxt>parallel bars</dxt> <dxt>uneven bars</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a solid piece of something that is shaped like a rectangle <vi>She bought a chocolate/candy <it>bar</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>bar</it> of soap</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a straight line, stripe, or section that is longer than it is wide <vi>The bird's tail has an alternating series of white and black <it>bars</it>. [=<it>bands</it>]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>menu bar</phrase> [=a narrow section that is across the screen in a computer program and that shows the names of available menus]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bar code</dxt> <dxt>bar graph</dxt> <dxt>task bar</dxt> <dxt>toolbar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:something that makes it difficult or impossible to do or achieve something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>His poor attitude was a <it>bar to</it> his success. [=his poor attitude prevented him from succeeding]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the bar</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the profession of a lawyer <vi>She is a member of <it>the bar</it>. [=she is a lawyer]</vi> <vi>the American <it>Bar</it> Association</vi> <vi>She has been <phrase>called to the bar</phrase>. [=she has become a lawyer]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the Bar</va></svr> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the profession of a barrister</dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the test that a person must pass in order to be a lawyer <vi>She passed <it>the bar</it> on her first try.</vi> <vi><it>the bar</it> exam/examination</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>music</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a line in written music that shows where a measure begins</dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the beats between two bars in a piece of music <vi>I'm not sure I know that song. Can you hum a few <it>bars</it>? [=<it>measures</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>behind bars</dre> <def><dt>:in jail <vi>He has been <it>behind bars</it> for 10 years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tend bar</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to work as a bartender :to prepare and serve drinks at a bar <vi>He <it>tends bar</it> at the restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="closed"> <hw>closed</hw> <sound><wav>closed01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:covering an opening <vi>All the windows in the house are <it>closed</it>. [=<it>shut</it>]</vi> :having an opening that is covered <vi>Keep your eyes <it>closed</it>.</vi> <vi>He looked at me through half-<it>closed</it> eyes.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> container</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> umbrella</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not operating or open to the public <vi>The store is <it>closed</it> for lunch between 1 and 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The beach is <it>closed</it> this time of night.</vi> <vi>These restrooms are <it>closed</it> for cleaning.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> road/bridge</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:having ended :not being worked on anymore <vi>The case is <it>closed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:no longer able to be discussed <vi>The question is <it>closed</it>.</vi> <vi>The chairman declared the discussion <it>closed</it> and allowed no further speeches.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:including only people from a particular group <vi>There was a <it>closed</it> circle of advisers protecting the President.</vi> <vi>clubs with <it>closed</it> memberships</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:happening in private :not allowing the public to participate or know what is being said or done <vi>The meeting was <it>closed</it> to the public.</vi> <vi>The Prime Minister said that today's <it>closed</it> meeting with the President was particularly constructive.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> session of Congress</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:not willing to listen to or accept different ideas or opinions <vi><it>closed</it> societies</vi> <vi>I had a <phrase>closed mind</phrase> at first, but now I understand the need for change.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>behind closed doors</dre> <def><dt>:in a private room or place :in private <vi>All of their meetings are held <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi> <vi>They seemed like the perfect couple, but you never know what goes on <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi> <vi>The decisions are made <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes closed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="curve[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">curve</hw> <sound><wav>curve001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɚv</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>curves</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a smooth, rounded line, shape, path, etc. <vi>The dog's tail has a slight <it>curve</it>.</vi> <vi>There is a sharp/gentle <it>curve</it> coming up in the road.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a curved line on a graph that shows how something changes or is affected by one or more conditions <vi>the price <it>curve</it> in relation to inflation</vi> <vi>the population growth <it>curve</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>learning curve</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a curving line or shape of the human body and especially of a woman's body <un>usually plural <vi>The dress follows the <it>curves</it> of the body.</vi> <vi>voluptuous <it>curves</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:<sx>curveball</sx> <vi>The pitcher threw him a <it>curve</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Life has <phrase>thrown him some curves</phrase> [=<it>thrown him some curveballs</it>] over the years but he's never given up. [=he has had some difficult and unexpected problems in his life]</vi> <vi>The reporter <it>threw the actress a curve</it> [=surprised her with a difficult and unexpected question] when he asked about her past drug use.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>ahead of the curve</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>approving</sl> <dt>:faster about doing something than other people, companies, etc. <vi>The company has been <it>ahead of the curve</it> in adopting new technologies. [=has adopted new technologies faster than other companies]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>behind the curve</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:slower about doing something than other people, companies, etc. <vi>We are <it>behind the curve</it> when it comes to advances in medicine. [=we have not been keeping up with the latest advances as well as others]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="door"> <art><artref id="door_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,195.8</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes">door</hw> <sound><wav>door0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdoɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>doors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a movable piece of wood, glass, or metal that swings or slides open and shut so that people can enter or leave a room, building, vehicle, etc. <vi>open/shut/slam/lock/bolt the <it>door</it></vi> <vi>I heard a knock on/at the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>the bedroom/bathroom/cellar <it>door</it></vi> <vi>The car has four <it>doors</it>. = It's a four-<it>door</it> car.</vi> <vi>Leave the package at the front/back/side <it>door</it>. [=the door at the front/back/side of the house, building, etc.]</vi> <vi>Can you <phrase>answer the door</phrase>? [=open the door to see who is knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Is somebody <phrase>at the door</phrase>? [=knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Let me open the <it>door</it> for you. = (<it>US</it>) Let me <phrase>get the door</phrase> for you.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Can you <it>get the door</it>? [=can you open or close the door for me?] My hands are full.</vi> <vi>an <phrase>exterior/outside door</phrase> [=a door that can be used to enter or leave a building]</vi> <vi>an <phrase>interior door</phrase> [=a door inside a building; a door that connects rooms]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>garage door</phrase> [=a large door that covers the opening through which a car enters and leaves a garage]</vi> <vi>turn/pull the <phrase>door handle</phrase></vi> <vi>a large brass <phrase>door knocker</phrase> [=<it>knocker</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back door</dxt> <dxt>dutch door</dxt> <dxt>french door</dxt> <dxt>revolving door</dxt> <dxt>storm door</dxt> <dxt>trapdoor</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a part of an object (such as piece of furniture or an appliance) that swings or slides open and shut <vi>the cupboard/closet/refrigerator/oven <it>door</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the opening for a door :the entrance to a room or building :<sx>doorway</sx> <vi>Please don't block the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>I peeked through the open <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He stood at/before the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He greeted his guests as they <phrase>came in/through the door</phrase>. = He greeted his guests <phrase>at the door</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>walked out the door</phrase> [=<it>left</it>] without saying goodbye.</vi> <vi>standing (just/right) <phrase>inside/outside the door</phrase> [=inside/outside the room, building, etc., near the door]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a house, building, apartment, office, etc. <un>used with an adverb to indicate where something is in relation to something else <vi>She lives in a house two <phrase>doors down/up</phrase> from me. [=there is one house between our houses]</vi> <vi>The library is a <phrase>few doors down</phrase> from the bank. [=there are several buildings between the library and the bank]</vi> <vi>We grew up <phrase>two doors apart</phrase>. [=with one house/apartment between our houses/apartments]</vi></un> <snote>If you do something <phrase>(from) door to door</phrase>, you do it at each of the houses, apartments, or buildings in an area. <vi>Girl Scouts are selling cookies <it>door to door</it>. = Girl Scouts are <phrase>going door to door</phrase> selling cookies.</vi> <vi>She <it>went (from) door to door</it> looking for her cat.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>door-to-door</dxt> <dxt>next door</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used especially with <it>open</it> or <it>unlock</it> to describe an opportunity or possibility <vi>The grant will <it>open</it> new <it>doors</it> for our town. [=will give our town new opportunities]</vi> <vi>The discovery may <it>unlock</it> the <it>door</it> to a cure for the disease.</vi> <vi>The <it>door</it> is <it>open</it> (to you) if you want a better job.</vi> <vi>A good education can <it>open/unlock</it> the <it>door</it> of success. [=can make success possible]</vi> <vi>The patent on the product has expired, which <phrase>leaves the door open for</phrase> [=makes it possible for] other companies to make it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>out of doors</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>at death's door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>behind closed doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>closed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close the door on</dre> <def><dt>:to no longer think about, consider, or accept (something) <vi>I'd like to <it>close the door on</it> that chapter in my life.</vi> <vi>The former senator says she hasn't <it>closed the door on</it> politics.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>close the door on</it> your options.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>closed its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to close permanently :to stop operating <vi>The museum may be forced to <it>close its doors</it>.</vi> <vi>The store <it>closed its doors</it> (for the last time) last fall.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>darken someone's door/doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>darken</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your foot in the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep the wolf from the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wolf</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay the blame for (something) at someone's door</dre> <def><dt>:to blame someone for (something) <vi>They <it>laid the blame for</it> the book's failure <it>at my door</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open doors for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>opened its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi> <vi>local churches that <it>open their doors</it> to the homeless in the winter months [=that let homeless people stay there]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to open for business :to begin operating <vi>The new store will be <it>opening its doors</it> next month.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show (someone) the door</dre> <def><dt>:to tell or force (someone) to leave <vi>We don't tolerate bad behavior. If you cause trouble, we'll <it>show you the door</it>.</vi> <vi>If the coach doesn't win this year, they'll <it>show him the door</it>. [=they'll fire him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show/see (someone) to the door</dre> <def><dt>:to go to the door with (someone who is leaving) <vi>My secretary will <it>show you to the door</it>. [=<it>show you out</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>doorless</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>doorless</it> cubicle</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="ear[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ear</hw> <sound><wav>ear00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ears</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you hear with <vi>He was whispering something in her <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>a dog with floppy <it>ears</it></vi> <vi><phrase>pierced ears</phrase> [=ears with earlobes that have been pierced for wearing earrings]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something heard <vi>He has a good <it>ear</it> for music/languages.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something sounds to you <vi>It sounds a little old-fashioned to my <it>ear</it>. [=it sounds old-fashioned to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:attention that is shown or given by listening to what someone says <vi>Thanks for your <it>ear</it>. [=thanks for listening]</vi> <vi>When I told my story, my brother <phrase>listened with only half an ear</phrase>. [=did not listen closely]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>lend an ear</phrase> or, in literary language, to <phrase>lend someone your ears</phrase> is to listen to what someone has to say. <vi>She's always willing to <it>lend a</it> sympathetic <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>“Friends, Romans, countrymen, <it>lend me your ears</it>.” <aq>Shakespeare, <it>Julius Caesar</it> (1599)</aq></vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>all ears</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone is listening very closely <vi>As I told the story, my daughter was <it>all ears</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a word in someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bend someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>box someone's ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>box</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>ears are burning</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <phrase>your ears are burning</phrase> or you <phrase>feel your ears burning</phrase>, you have the feeling that other people are talking about you. <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) “We were talking about you last night.” “That explains why I <it>felt my ears burning</it>.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ears pop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fall on deaf ears</dre> <def><dt>:to fail to be heard :to be ignored <vi>Her pleas for mercy <it>fell on deaf ears</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>grin/smile from ear to ear</dre> <def><dt>:to smile widely :to have a big smile on your face <vi>He was <it>grinning from ear to ear</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's ear</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have someone's ear</it> you can talk and give advice to that person because you are trusted. <vi>an adviser who <it>has the President's ear</it></vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in one ear and out the other</dre> <def><dt>:through someone's mind without being remembered or noticed <vi>Everything you say to him goes <it>in one ear and out the other</it>. [=he doesn't listen to or remember what you say]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out on your ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:forced out :thrown out <vi>If you're late to work again, you'll be <it>out on your ear</it>! [=you'll be fired]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play by ear</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><snote>To play a song or a piece of music <it>by ear</it> is to play it after hearing it without looking at written music. <vi>He could play any tune <it>by ear</it> after hearing it only once.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>play it by ear</phrase> is to do something without special preparation. <vi>I don't know how they'll react to our proposal, so we'll just have to <it>play it by ear</it> [=<it>improvise</it>, (<it>informal</it>) <it>wing it</it>] and hope for the best.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set (something) on its ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to cause something to be in a state of great excitement or shock <vi>She <it>set</it> the racing world <it>on its ear</it> [=she surprised and shocked the racing world] by winning several major races.</vi> <vi>His early recordings <it>set</it> the jazz world <it>on its ear</it>. [=his recordings caused a sensation in the jazz world]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>talk someone's ear off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>talk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a deaf ear</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to listen to what someone says <vi>The company president <it>turned a deaf ear</it> to my proposals.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your ears</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in something <vi>They are <it>up to their ears</it> in debt. [=they are deeply in debt]</vi> <vi>We're <it>up to our ears</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wet behind the ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wet</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>ear</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>eared</ure> <sound><wav>eared001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a long-<it>eared</it> dog</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>ear*less</ure> <sound><wav>earle01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
