<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="belief"> <hw highlight="yes">be*lief</hw> <sound><wav>belief01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bəˈli:f</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>be*liefs</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a feeling of being sure that someone or something exists or that something is true <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>a heartfelt/deep/deep-seated/firm/strong/passionate <it>belief</it></vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>He says that he is given strength by his <it>belief in</it> God.</vi> <vi>He has a strong <it>belief in</it> his ability to win. [=he is certain that he can win]</vi> <vi>His family has an unshakable <it>belief in</it> his innocence.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>that</it> <vi>It's my <it>belief that</it> the current policy is certain to fail. [=I believe that the current policy is certain to fail]</vi> <vi>She bought the rug <phrase>in the belief that</phrase> [=because she believed that] it was a real antique, not a fake.</vi> <vi>Many people arrived early <phrase>in the mistaken/erroneous belief that</phrase> [=because they mistakenly believed that] free tickets would be available.</vi> <vi>There is a <phrase>growing belief that</phrase> [=an increasing number of people believe that] these policies will not succeed.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There is <it>growing belief that</it> these policies will not succeed.</vi> <vi><phrase>Contrary to popular belief</phrase>, the economy has actually improved in recent months. [=the economy has improved although many/most people do not think that it has]</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>disbelief</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a feeling that something is good, right, or valuable <un>+ <it>in</it> <vi>a <it>belief in</it> democracy</vi> <vi>a judge who had a firm/strong <it>belief in</it> judicial restraint</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a feeling of trust in the worth or ability of someone <un>+ <it>in</it> <vi>He has a strong <it>belief in</it> himself. [=he strongly believes that he will succeed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that a person accepts as true or right :a strongly held opinion about something <vi>He gets angry if anyone challenges his religious/political <it>beliefs</it>.</vi> <vi>We challenged his <it>beliefs</it> about religion.</vi> <vi>erroneous/mistaken/false <it>beliefs</it></vi> <vi>a system of <it>beliefs</it> = a <it>belief</it> system</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>unbelief</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the state of being accepted as true :the state of being believed <vi>a story that is <phrase>worthy of belief</phrase> [=a story that deserves to be believed, a believable story]</vi> <vi>a story that <phrase>defies belief</phrase> = (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) a story that <phrase>beggars belief</phrase> [=an unbelievable story]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beyond belief</dre> <def><dt>:not capable of being believed <vi>events that are <it>beyond belief</it> [=events that are unbelievable]</vi> <vi>She is beautiful <it>beyond belief</it>. [=she is unbelievably/extremely beautiful]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your belief</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you say something is <it>to the best of your belief</it>, you mean that it agrees with what you know and believe to be true. <vi><it>To the best of my belief</it> [=(more commonly) <it>to the best of my knowledge, as far as I know</it>], everyone arrived on time. [=I think that everyone arrived on time, but it is possible that someone arrived late and I don't know about it]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sn>1</sn> <bnote>the best</bnote> <dt>:the best person or thing <vi>Out of all of my workers, he's <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Our company is <it>the best</it> in the business.</vi> <vi>Thanks, Dad. You're <it>the best</it>!</vi> <vi>I have one more gift for you, and I saved <it>the best</it> for last.</vi> :the best group of people or things <vi>Our store sells nothing but <it>the best</it>. = We sell only <it>the best</it>. [=the best products]</vi> <vi>She's one of <it>the best</it> in the world. = She's among <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Bad things happen to <it>the best</it> of us.</vi> <vi>They want <it>the best</it> for their children.</vi> <vi>Even in <it>the best</it> of times, we had trouble paying our bills.</vi> <vi>In <it>the best</it> of all possible worlds, no one would be without food and clean water.</vi> <vi>He can compete <phrase>with the best of them</phrase>. [=he can compete as well as anyone]</vi> <vi>We were <phrase>the best of friends</phrase>. [=we were very good friends]</vi> <vi>I have a wonderful family and a great job, so I feel that I have <phrase>the best of both worlds</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Problems can occur even in/under <phrase>the best of circumstances</phrase>. [=even if the situation is as good as possible]</vi> <vi>All of the students are good, but these three are <phrase>the best of the bunch</phrase>. [=the best ones in the group]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sunday best</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:someone's or something's most effective, capable, or successful condition <un>used in phrases like <phrase>at your best</phrase> and <phrase>at its best</phrase> <vi>He's <it>at his best</it> in front of a live audience.</vi> <vi>She's <it>at her best</it> in the morning.</vi> <vi>This is democracy <it>at its best</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the highest level that you can do or achieve <vi>Was that your <it>best</it>? = Was that the <it>best</it> you could do?</vi> <vi>No one expects you to do the job perfectly. Just <phrase>do your best</phrase>. = Just <phrase>do the best you can</phrase>. [=do as well as you can]</vi> <vi>He <it>did his best</it> to help them.</vi> <vi>Her time in the race was a <phrase>personal best</phrase>. [=it was the fastest time she had ever achieved]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) for the best</dre> <def><dt>:having or producing a better result <un>used to say that something will have a good result even though it was not the intended result <vi>I won't be able to go, but maybe it'<it>s all for the best</it>. I have a lot of work to do anyway.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(all) the best</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you wish someone <it>(all) the best</it>, you hope that person will be happy and successful. <vi>We wish you <it>all the best</it> in your new job.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at best</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to a result, condition, etc., that is the best one possible even though it is not very good <vi>The company won't make a profit this year. <it>At best</it>, they'll break even.</vi> <vi>The work won't be finished for another three months <it>at best</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>best of luck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>best (out) of three (five, seven, etc.)</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that the winner of a series of games will be the one who has won the most times after three (five, seven, etc.) games have been played</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring out the best in</dre> <def><dt><snote>If someone or something <it>brings out the best in you</it>, that person or thing helps you to use or show your best qualities. <vi>She seems to <it>bring out the best in him</it>.</vi> <vi>Performing in front of an audience <it>brings out the best in me</it>. [=I perform better when I am in front of an audience]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feel your best</dre> <def><dt>:to feel very healthy <vi>Exercise helps you look and <it>feel your best</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm not <it>feeling my best</it> this morning. [=I'm not feeling very well this morning]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <def><dt><snote>If an emotion or feeling <it>gets the best of you</it>, it causes you to do something that you should not do or that you are trying not to do. <vi>I did get a little carried away. I guess the excitement <it>got the best of me</it>. [=<it>got the better of me</it>]</vi> <vi>Their emotions have <it>gotten the best of them</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know best</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>know what's best</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look your best</dre> <def><dt>:to look very good :to look as attractive and pleasant as possible <vi>Try to <it>look your best</it> when interviewing for a job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make the best of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (something) in an effective way <vi>We may not get another chance, so we need to <it>make the best of</it> this opportunity.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to deal with (a bad situation) as well as possible <vi>Life is not very good right now—but let's try to <phrase>make the best of it</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We're trying to <phrase>make the best (out) of a bad situation</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) We're trying to <phrase>make the best of a bad job</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the best is yet to come/be</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that good things have happened but that even better things will happen in the future <vi>Life is good now, but <it>the best is yet to come</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of my knowledge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knowledge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your ability</dre> <def><dt>:as well as you are able to <vi>Every game, we go out and play <it>to the best of our ability</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your belief</dre> <dx>see <dxt>belief</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="make-believe[1]"> <hw hindex="1">make–be*lieve</hw> <sound><wav>makebe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪkbəˌli:v</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:things that are imagined or pretended to be true or real <vi>He has been living in <phrase>a world of make-believe</phrase>. [=he has been believing things that are not true; he has been living in a fantasy world]</vi> <snote>When children <phrase>play make-believe</phrase>, they think of an imaginary world and pretend to live in it as people, animals, fairies, etc.</snote> <dx>see also <tag>make believe</tag> at <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
