<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="believe"> <hw highlight="yes">be*lieve</hw> <sound><wav>believ04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bəˈli:v</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <lb>not used in progressive tenses</lb> <in><if>be*lieves</if></in> <in><if>be*lieved</if></in> <in><if>be*liev*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to accept or regard (something) as true <vi>The scientists <it>believed</it> the reports.</vi> <vi>Many people seem to <it>believe</it> that theory, but I find it hard/difficult to <it>believe</it>.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't <it>believe</it> everything you read.</vi> <vi>I knew that he was a liar and so I didn't <it>believe</it> a word he said. [=I didn't believe anything he said]</vi> <vi>I did not want to <it>believe</it> (that) it could happen.</vi> <vi>He says he'll help us, but I don't <it>believe</it> what he says.</vi> <vi>They were tricked into <it>believing</it> that he was a doctor.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disbelieve</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to accept the truth of what is said by (someone) <vi>He says he'll help us, but I don't <it>believe</it> him.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disbelieve</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (a specified opinion) :<sx>think</sx> <vi>I'm beginning to <it>believe</it> (that) this war will never end.</vi> <vi>I used to <it>believe</it> (that) I was the only one who felt that way but now I know (that) there are others like me.</vi> <vi>He clearly/firmly/honestly <it>believes</it> (that) it is possible. = He clearly/firmly/honestly <it>believes</it> it (to be) possible.</vi> <vi>He had reason to <it>believe</it> that they would accept his offer. = He had reason for <it>believing</it> that they would accept his offer.</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>widely believed</phrase> to be guilty. [=many people believed that she was guilty]</vi> <vi>We were <phrase>led to believe</phrase> it was true. [=we heard, saw, or read something that made us think it was true]</vi> <vi>“Has he accepted the job?” “<phrase>I believe so</phrase>.” = “<phrase>So I believe</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>“Has he accepted the job?” “<phrase>I believe not</phrase>.” = “<phrase>I don't believe so</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to regard the existence of God as a fact :to have religious beliefs <vi>She went to church because her family expected it, but she didn't really <it>believe</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have trust in the ability, worth, etc., of someone or something <vi>The team hasn't won a championship in many years, but their fans still <it>believe</it>. [=their fans still believe in them; their fans still believe that they will win]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used for emphasis in phrases that express certainty, surprise, annoyance, etc. <vi>“Do you think they can win?” “<phrase>You/You'd better believe it</phrase>!” [=yes, I definitely think so]</vi> <vi><phrase>Believe me</phrase>, he can really play the game. = <phrase>Believe you me</phrase>, he can really play the game.</vi> <vi><phrase>I can't believe</phrase> how ugly that dress is. [=what an ugly dress]</vi> <vi>You broke the window? <phrase>I can't believe</phrase> you guys! [=I'm annoyed and shocked by what you did] How could you do such a thing?</vi> <vi><phrase>I can't believe</phrase> [=I am amazed/surprised] that that terrible restaurant is still in business.</vi> <vi>That terrible restaurant is still in business, <phrase>if you can believe it/that</phrase>.</vi> <vi><phrase>Can/Would you believe it</phrase>?! That terrible restaurant is still in business.</vi> <vi><phrase>You won't believe</phrase> what I just heard! [=you will be very surprised by what I just heard]</vi> <vi><phrase>You wouldn't believe</phrase> how long it took us to get here. [=it took us a surprisingly long/short time to get here]</vi> <vi><phrase>I don't believe it</phrase>! I swept the floor 10 minutes ago, and it's already dirty again!</vi> <vi><phrase>I could not believe</phrase> my good fortune/luck.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>hard to believe</phrase> that he's gone.</vi> <vi>His latest movie, <phrase>believe it or not</phrase>, is a romantic comedy about a group of lawyers. [=it is surprising but true that his latest movie is a romantic comedy about a group of lawyers]</vi> <vi>“I hear that their marriage is in trouble.” “<phrase>Don't you believe it</phrase>! [=that is completely untrue] They're the happiest couple I know!”</vi> <vi>“He says he's going to become a doctor.” “<phrase>If you believe that, you'll believe anything</phrase>!” [=it would be very foolish to believe that he is going to become a doctor]</vi> <vi>“He says he's going to become a doctor.” “<phrase>I'll believe that when I see it</phrase>!”</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>believe in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>believe in (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have faith or confidence in the existence of (something) <vi>Do you <it>believe in</it> ghosts?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have trust in the goodness or value of (something) <vi>She <it>believes in</it> (the value of) regular exercise.</vi> <vi>They <it>believed in</it> liberty for all.</vi> <vi>I <it>believe in</it> working hard to achieve success.</vi> <vi>She doesn't <it>believe in</it> using pesticides. [=she doesn't believe that it's right to use pesticides; she believes that pesticides do more harm than good]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>believe in (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have trust in the goodness or ability of (someone) <vi>Despite his problems, his parents still <it>believe in</it> him.</vi> <vi>She <it>believes in</it> herself and in her abilities.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your eyes/ears</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>can't believe your eyes/ears</it> or <it>can hardly/scarcely believe your eyes/ears</it>, you are very surprised at or upset by what you are seeing or hearing. <vi>I <it>could hardly believe my eyes</it> when I saw what he was wearing.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make believe</dre> <def><dt>:to act as though something that is not true or real is true or real :<sx>pretend</sx> <vi>When we were children we used to <it>make believe</it> (that) we were soldiers fighting in a war.</vi> <vi>He isn't really angry, he's just <it>making believe</it> (that he is).</vi> <vi>They want to <it>make believe</it> that everything is all right.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>make-believe</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>seeing is believing</dre> <def><dt><snote>The expression <it>seeing is believing</it> means that when you actually see something, you have to believe that it exists or is true. <vi>I didn't think it could happen, but <it>seeing is believing</it>. [=I saw it happen, so now I believe it's possible]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>be*liev*able</ure> <sound><wav>believ01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bəˈli:vəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more be*liev*able; most be*liev*able</gram> <utxt><vi>The novel's ending is not very <it>believable</it>.</vi> <vi>His excuse was barely/scarcely <it>believable</it>.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>be*liev*ably</ure> <sound><wav>believ03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bəˈli:vəbli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>The characters are all <it>believably</it> portrayed.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>be*liev*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>be*liev*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>believer</it> in religion</vi> <vi>devout <it>believers</it></vi> <vi>She's a firm/great/strong <it>believer</it> in adult education. [=she firmly/strongly believes in the value of adult education; she thinks adult education is very useful and important]</vi> <vi>I was doubtful that he could run his own company, but he's <phrase>made a believer out of me</phrase>. = He's <phrase>made me a believer</phrase>. [=he's convinced me that he can run his own company]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="make-believe[1]"> <hw hindex="1">make–be*lieve</hw> <sound><wav>makebe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪkbəˌli:v</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:things that are imagined or pretended to be true or real <vi>He has been living in <phrase>a world of make-believe</phrase>. [=he has been believing things that are not true; he has been living in a fantasy world]</vi> <snote>When children <phrase>play make-believe</phrase>, they think of an imaginary world and pretend to live in it as people, animals, fairies, etc.</snote> <dx>see also <tag>make believe</tag> at <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="make-believe[2]"> <hw hindex="2">make–believe</hw> <altpr>ˈmeɪkbəˌli:v</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:not real <vi>The commercial showed a <it>make-believe</it> scientist in a white lab coat talking about the benefits of the product.</vi> <vi>He has been living in a <it>make-believe</it> world.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ear[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ear</hw> <sound><wav>ear00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ears</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you hear with <vi>He was whispering something in her <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>a dog with floppy <it>ears</it></vi> <vi><phrase>pierced ears</phrase> [=ears with earlobes that have been pierced for wearing earrings]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something heard <vi>He has a good <it>ear</it> for music/languages.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something sounds to you <vi>It sounds a little old-fashioned to my <it>ear</it>. [=it sounds old-fashioned to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:attention that is shown or given by listening to what someone says <vi>Thanks for your <it>ear</it>. [=thanks for listening]</vi> <vi>When I told my story, my brother <phrase>listened with only half an ear</phrase>. [=did not listen closely]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>lend an ear</phrase> or, in literary language, to <phrase>lend someone your ears</phrase> is to listen to what someone has to say. <vi>She's always willing to <it>lend a</it> sympathetic <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>“Friends, Romans, countrymen, <it>lend me your ears</it>.” <aq>Shakespeare, <it>Julius Caesar</it> (1599)</aq></vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>all ears</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone is listening very closely <vi>As I told the story, my daughter was <it>all ears</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a word in someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bend someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>box someone's ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>box</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>ears are burning</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <phrase>your ears are burning</phrase> or you <phrase>feel your ears burning</phrase>, you have the feeling that other people are talking about you. <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) “We were talking about you last night.” “That explains why I <it>felt my ears burning</it>.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ears pop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fall on deaf ears</dre> <def><dt>:to fail to be heard :to be ignored <vi>Her pleas for mercy <it>fell on deaf ears</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>grin/smile from ear to ear</dre> <def><dt>:to smile widely :to have a big smile on your face <vi>He was <it>grinning from ear to ear</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's ear</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have someone's ear</it> you can talk and give advice to that person because you are trusted. <vi>an adviser who <it>has the President's ear</it></vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in one ear and out the other</dre> <def><dt>:through someone's mind without being remembered or noticed <vi>Everything you say to him goes <it>in one ear and out the other</it>. [=he doesn't listen to or remember what you say]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out on your ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:forced out :thrown out <vi>If you're late to work again, you'll be <it>out on your ear</it>! [=you'll be fired]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play by ear</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><snote>To play a song or a piece of music <it>by ear</it> is to play it after hearing it without looking at written music. <vi>He could play any tune <it>by ear</it> after hearing it only once.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>play it by ear</phrase> is to do something without special preparation. <vi>I don't know how they'll react to our proposal, so we'll just have to <it>play it by ear</it> [=<it>improvise</it>, (<it>informal</it>) <it>wing it</it>] and hope for the best.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set (something) on its ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to cause something to be in a state of great excitement or shock <vi>She <it>set</it> the racing world <it>on its ear</it> [=she surprised and shocked the racing world] by winning several major races.</vi> <vi>His early recordings <it>set</it> the jazz world <it>on its ear</it>. [=his recordings caused a sensation in the jazz world]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>talk someone's ear off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>talk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a deaf ear</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to listen to what someone says <vi>The company president <it>turned a deaf ear</it> to my proposals.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your ears</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in something <vi>They are <it>up to their ears</it> in debt. [=they are deeply in debt]</vi> <vi>We're <it>up to our ears</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wet behind the ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wet</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>ear</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>eared</ure> <sound><wav>eared001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a long-<it>eared</it> dog</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>ear*less</ure> <sound><wav>earle01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="eye[1]"> <art><artref id="eye.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,72.5</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">eye</hw> <sound><wav>eye00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈaɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>eyes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you see with <vi>Her <it>eyes</it> slowly became accustomed to the dark.</vi> <vi>He wears a patch over one <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>I have something in my <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has (a pair of) bright blue <it>eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>bright/sad/sleepy <it>eyes</it></vi> <vi>She has good/strong/bad/weak <it>eyes</it>. [=<it>eyesight</it>]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes lit up</phrase> [=she looked excited and happy] when he showed her the ring.</vi> <vi>His <phrase>eyes were popping out of his head</phrase> with astonishment [=he looked very astonished] when he saw how big it was!</vi> <vi>He punched him <phrase>right between the eyes</phrase>. [=punched him hard in the face]</vi> <vi>She looked me (right) <phrase>in the eye</phrase> [=she looked directly at me] and told me I was fired.</vi> <vi>The garden is <phrase>a feast for the eyes</phrase>. [=the garden is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The display was very pleasing <phrase>to the eye</phrase>. [=pleasing to look at]</vi> <vi>I measured the distance <phrase>by eye</phrase>. = I measured the distance <phrase>with my eye</phrase>. [=by looking at it to get a rough idea of its size]</vi> <vi>Their daughter came home from school <phrase>with tears in her eyes</phrase>. [=she was crying]</vi> <vi>Seeing her again <phrase>brought tears to my eyes</phrase>. = Seeing her again <phrase>brought a tear to my eye</phrase>. [=made me shed tears]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>had/kept half an eye on</phrase> [=he occasionally looked at] the TV while he read the paper.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something seen <vi>Only a trained <it>eye</it> can tell the difference between the original painting and a good copy.</vi> <vi>For decorating, they rely on her discerning/discriminating/expert <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has an artist's <it>eye</it> for color.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>have an eye for</phrase> something or <phrase>a good/keen/sharp eye for</phrase> something, you have a special ability to recognize a particular thing or quality. <vi>He <it>has a keen eye for</it> detail.</vi> <vi>He <it>has a good eye</it> for quality.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something looks to you <vi>It looks a little awkward to my <it>eye</it>. [=it looks awkward to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a way of looking at or judging something <vi>He reviewed the proposal with a jaundiced/critical <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>The biographer <phrase>cast a cold/critical/skeptical eye</phrase> on the artist's life.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe where someone is looking <vi>Her <it>eye</it> was attracted to the bright colors in the painting.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>dropped her eyes</phrase> [=she looked down] when he looked at her. = Her <phrase>eyes fell</phrase> when he looked at her.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>averted his eyes</phrase> [=he looked away] when she approached him.</vi> <vi>I saw something moving <phrase>out of the corner of my eye</phrase>. [=to the side of where I was looking]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes fell on</phrase> [=she noticed] a piece of evidence no one had noticed before.</vi> <vi><phrase>All eyes were on her</phrase> [=everyone was looking at her] as she entered the room.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>fixed her eyes on</phrase> me [=she kept looking or staring at me] for a long time before answering.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of looking at or thinking about something <vi>We need to look at this problem with a fresh <it>eye</it>. [=to look at the problem in a new way]</vi> <vi><phrase>Beauty is in the eye of the beholder</phrase>. [=different people have different ideas about what is beautiful]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He was guilty in the <it>eyes</it> of the police. [=the police considered him guilty]</vi> <vi>He was handsome in her <it>eyes</it>. [=she thought he was handsome]</vi> <vi>In the <it>eyes</it> [=<it>opinion</it>] of many, he is the best person for the job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hole through the top of a needle <vi>the <it>eye</it> of a needle</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a loop that a hook fits into to fasten or attach something</dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area on a potato from which a new plant can grow :a bud on a potato</dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the center of a storm (such as a hurricane) where there is little wind or rain and sometimes there is clear sky <vi>The <it>eye</it> of the storm should reach the coast by morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all eyes</dre> <def><dt>:watching something or someone closely :very attentive <vi>She was <it>all eyes</it> as I opened the box.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an eye for an eye</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that a person who has committed a crime should be given punishment that is the same as or as serious as the crime <vi>The ancient code of law called for punishment in the form of <it>an eye for an eye</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as far as the eye could see</dre> <def><dt>:as far as could be seen <vi>The crowd stretched away <it>as far as the eye could see</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a sight for sore eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a twinkle in your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twinkle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bawl your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bawl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>before your eyes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>in front of your eyes</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If something happens (<it>right</it>) <it>before your eyes</it> or <it>in front of your (very) eyes</it>, it happens in a very open and visible way so that you can see it very clearly. <vi>Technology is changing <it>right before our eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>We were watching a disaster take place <it>in front of our very eyes</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast/run your eye over</dre> <def><dt>:to read it or look at (something) quickly. <vi>Please <it>run your eye over</it> this and let me know what you think.</vi> <vi>She <it>cast her eye over</it> the apartment, appalled by the mess.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close/shut your eyes to</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to notice or accept the truth or existence of (something) :to ignore (something) <vi>Our legislators have <it>closed their eyes to</it> the poverty that surrounds them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cry your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy on the eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people are surprised that you have seen or noticed something that is behind you, they may say that you have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>. <vi>How did you know we were here? You must have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feast your eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>feast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for your eyes only</dre> <def><dt>:intended to be seen only by you <vi>This memo is <it>for your eyes only</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Several men were <it>giving her the eye</it> across the bar.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep an/your eye out for</dre> <def><dt>:to be looking for (someone or something) :to hope to see or find (someone or something) <vi>I'm <it>keeping my eye out for</it> a good cheap used car.</vi> <vi>He'll be here soon, so <it>keep your eye out for</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:to have (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>She <it>has an eye to</it> attending graduate school. [=she hopes to attend graduate school]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(have) stars in your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>star</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have your eye on</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to watch (someone or something) closely <vi>I'll <it>have my eye on</it> the kids while they're swimming.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be thinking about buying (something) <vi>I <it>have my eye on</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>She's <it>had her eye on</it> that house for a long time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a pig's eye</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt><un>used to express strong disagreement <vi>You want me to apologize to him? <it>In a pig's eye</it>! [=<it>Never!</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the blink of an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blink</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the public eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a position that receives a lot of public notice and attention <vi>The job requires someone who is comfortable being <it>in the public eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a very short time :very quickly <vi>He was back <it>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your mind's eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you see something <it>in your mind's eye</it>, you imagine or remember how it looks. <vi>I can still see the old playground <it>in my mind's eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep an/your eye on</dre> <def><dt>:to watch or take care of (someone or something) <vi>Will you <it>keep an eye on</it> my suitcase (for me) while I get something to eat?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eye on the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes glued to</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to watch (something) very closely for a long time <vi>They <it>kept their eyes glued to</it> the television, waiting for more news about the accident.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes open</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>keep your eyes peeled</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>keep your eyes skinned</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look or watch closely in order to see or find (something) <vi>We <it>kept our eyes peeled</it> for a sign that would tell us where to turn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/set eyes on</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>clap eyes on</va></vr> <def><dt>:to see or look at (someone or something) <vi>I hope never to <it>lay eyes on</it> him again!</vi> <vi>We liked the house from the moment we <it>set eyes on</it> it. [=the moment when we first saw it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Some guy was <it>making eyes at</it> her from across the room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than meets the eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>more than meets the eye</it> or there is <phrase>more to something than meets the eye</phrase>, there is more to it than there appears to be at first. <vi>There is <it>more to this proposal than meets the eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>my eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise or mild disagreement <vi>A diamond, <it>my eye</it>! That's glass!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not bat an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>only have eyes for</dre> <def><dt>:to only be attracted to (a particular person) :to only feel love for (someone) <vi>He <it>only has eyes for</it> you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open someone's eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to notice or be aware of something important <vi>The experience really <it>opened his eyes</it> and changed the way he felt about his life.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>It's time they <it>opened their eyes to</it> the truth.</vi> <vi>His film helped <it>open people's eyes to</it> the problem.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to notice or be aware of something important <vi>You need to <it>open your eyes</it> and face the truth.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We have to <it>open our eyes to</it> these problems and stop ignoring them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull the wool over someone's eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wool</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roving eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roving</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>run your eye down</dre> <def><dt>:to quickly read or look at (something, such as a list) <vi>She <it>ran her eye down</it> the list looking for her name.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see eye to eye</dre> <def><dt>:to have the same opinion :<sx>agree</sx> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>They don't <it>see eye to eye</it> (with each other) on this issue.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your eyes off</dre> <def><dt>:to stop looking at (someone or something) <vi>I <it>took my eyes off</it> the road for one second.</vi> <vi>She was so beautiful, he <phrase>couldn't take his eyes off</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the apple of someone's eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>apple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>under the eye of</dre> <def><dt>:while being watched by (someone) <vi>Students work <phrase>under the watchful/vigilant eye of</phrase> their teacher.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in or affected by something <vi>We're <it>up to our eyes</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi> <vi>They're <it>up to their eyes</it> in debt.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:with (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>They hired him <it>with an eye toward</it> increased sales.</vi> <vi>They bought the house <it>with an eye toward</it> its restoration.</vi> <vi>He took the job <phrase>with an eye to the future</phrase>. [=he took the job because he felt it would help him in the future]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your/both eyes open</dre> <def><dt>:fully aware of what could happen <vi>I went into the job <it>with my eyes (wide) open</it>.</vi> <vi>If you do this, you need to do it <it>with both eyes open</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes shut/closed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:with little or no effort :very easily <vi>She could run that company <it>with her eyes shut</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</it>, you have taken more food than you can possibly eat. <vi>I can't finish my meal—I guess <it>my eyes were bigger than my stomach</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>black eye</dxt> <dxt>evil eye</dxt> <dxt>private eye</dxt> <dxt>rib eye</dxt> <dxt>seeing eye</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="make[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">make</hw> <sound><wav>make0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>makes</if></in> <in><if>made</if> <sound><wav>made0001.wav</wav><wav>make0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪd</pr></in> <in><if>mak*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to build, create, or produce (something) by work or effort <vi><it>make</it> a box/chair/suit</vi> <vi><it>make</it> someone a dress = <it>make</it> a dress for someone</vi> <vi>He works in a factory that <it>makes</it> jet engines.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> the curtains herself.</vi> <vi>He collected wood to <it>make</it> a fire.</vi> <vi>She used cheese and a mixture of other ingredients to <it>make</it> a delicious sauce.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>with</it> to describe the things that are used to produce something <vi>She <it>made</it> the sauce <it>with</it> cheese and other ingredients.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>of</it> to describe the material that forms something <vi>The box is <it>made of</it> wood. [=it is a wood/wooden box; the material used to produce the box was wood]</vi> <vi>The topping is <it>made</it> entirely <it>of</it> cheese. [=the topping consists entirely of cheese]</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>from</it> to describe the source of a product <vi>Cheese is <it>made from</it> milk.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) to create a product <un>+ <it>into</it> <vi>She <it>made</it> the material <it>into</it> a dress.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a mixture of ingredients <it>into</it> a delicious sauce.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to exist, happen, or appear <vi>Someone was <it>making</it> a disturbance.</vi> <vi>The car's engine has been <it>making</it> a strange noise lately.</vi> <vi>The rock <it>made</it> a dent in the car's fender.</vi> <vi>I'm not trying to <it>make</it> trouble.</vi> <vi>The typist <it>made</it> a mistake.</vi> <vi>I called the doctor's office to <it>make</it> an appointment.</vi> <vi>They moved over and <it>made</it> room for her.</vi> <vi>I want to <it>make</it> a good home for my children.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to create or write (something) in an official or legal way <vi>The government should <it>make</it> laws to protect poor people.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>make</it> the rules; I just follow them.</vi> <vi>You should <it>make</it> a will.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce, direct, or act in (something, such as a movie) <vi>a director who has <it>made</it> some classic films</vi> <vi>That actor has <it>made</it> many films.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to be changed in a specified way <vi>They adapted a Russian play and <it>made</it> the setting Dublin rather than Moscow.</vi> <vi>We originally planned on a one-week vacation, but we decided to <it>make</it> it two weeks instead.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>made</it> him a cynic. = The experience <it>made</it> a cynic (out) of him. = The experience <it>made</it> [=<it>changed, turned</it>] him into a cynic.</vi> <vi>I'd like a hamburger. No, wait—<it>make</it> that a cheeseburger.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to have a specified quality, feeling, etc. <vi>A good teacher <it>makes</it> learning enjoyable.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> what she wanted clear to us. = She <it>made</it> (it) clear to us what she wanted. [=she said or showed clearly what she wanted]</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> it understood/known that he expected us to help.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>made</it> him cynical.</vi> <vi>Working in the garden <it>makes</it> me very tired.</vi> <vi>It <it>makes</it> me sad to think that the summer is ending.</vi> <vi>The photograph <it>makes</it> me seem/look fat.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>make yourself useful</phrase> means to do something useful. <vi>Why don't you <it>make yourself useful</it> by washing the dishes?</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>make yourself heard/understood (etc.)</phrase> means to do what is necessary to be sure that people hear you, understand you, etc. <vi>The music was so loud that she could hardly <it>make herself heard</it>.</vi> <vi>She doesn't speak French well, but she can <it>make herself understood</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to be or become something <vi>A good teacher <it>makes</it> learning a pleasure. = A good teacher <it>makes</it> it a pleasure to learn.</vi> <vi>Yes, you can leave work early today, but don't <it>make</it> it a habit.</vi> <vi>The bright paint really <it>makes</it> the room come alive!</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to do something <vi>He yelled at her and <it>made</it> her cry.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>make</it> you understand that I love you?!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to force (someone) to do something <vi>We have to find a way to <it>make</it> them work faster.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> me wait for an hour.</vi> <vi>If he doesn't want to do it, we can't <it>make</it> him (do it).</vi> <vi>They used threats to <it>make</it> her do it. = She was <it>made</it> to do it by the use of threats.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give a particular job, title, status, etc., to (someone) <vi>They <it>made</it> him (the) Emperor.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> her a member of their club. = She was <it>made</it> a member of their club.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to perform (a particular action) <vi>He <it>made</it> a bow. [=he bowed]</vi> <vi>We <it>made</it> [=<it>took</it>] a detour to avoid traffic.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> [=<it>got</it>] an early start. [=they started early]</vi> <vi>I have to <it>make</it> a (telephone) call to my boss. [=I have to call/telephone my boss]</vi> <vi>May I <it>make</it> a suggestion? [=may I suggest something?]</vi> <vi>“<it>Make</it> love, not war!” shouted the demonstrators.</vi> <vi>I'm not used to <it>making</it> [=<it>giving</it>] speeches.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> a bet [=they bet] that she would win.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> any sudden movements.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> a contribution. [=they contributed]</vi> <vi>We should <it>make</it> a distinction between them.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a promise to him. = She <it>made</it> him a promise.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> note of her address.</vi> <vi>Time is running out. You'll have to <it>make</it> a decision soon.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to form (a plan) in your mind <vi>Have you <it>made</it> any plans for your vacation?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrange the blankets and sheets on (a bed) so that the mattress is covered <vi>She always <it>makes</it> the bed after she gets up in the morning.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to prepare (food or drink) <vi>Let me <it>make</it> dinner for you. = Let me <it>make</it> you dinner.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>make</it> you a drink?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>make</it> the pasta if you <it>make</it> the salad.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a cake for her daughter's birthday.</vi></dt> <sn>14 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to indicate a total <vi>That <it>makes</it> the third time you've said the same thing!</vi> <vi>I've lost again! That <it>makes</it> $3 I owe you.</vi> <vi>“I'm hungry.” “<phrase>That makes two of us</phrase>.” [=I'm hungry too]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be equal to (an amount) <vi>Three plus two <it>make/makes</it> [=<it>equals, totals</it>] five.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to calculate (an amount, total, etc.) <vi>“What do you <it>make</it> the time?” [=what do you think the time is?] “(I <it>make</it> it) About half past three.”</vi> <vi>I <it>make</it> the distance back to camp about four miles. = I <it>make</it> it about four miles back to camp.</vi></dt> <sn>15 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be used to produce (something) <vi>Rags <it>make</it> the best paper.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to be suited for use as (something) <vi>This new building would <it>make</it> [=<it>be</it>] a fine school.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to be or become (something) <vi>She and her boyfriend <it>make</it> [=<it>are</it>] a lovely couple.</vi> <vi>She will <it>make</it> a fine judge one day.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> [=<it>was</it>] a loving wife to him. = She <it>made</it> him a loving wife.</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The ship <it>made</it> port today.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to earn or gain (money, a profit, etc.) <vi>He <it>makes</it> $50,000 a year.</vi> <vi>She <it>makes</it> a good salary.</vi> <vi>Their products are so inexpensive I don't know how they <it>make</it> a profit.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> $100 on the deal. = The deal <it>made</it> $100 for her. = The deal <it>made</it> her $100.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>makes a/his living</phrase> by doing small jobs.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made a/his fortune in</phrase> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted as a member of (a group, team, etc.) <vi>She's finally <it>made</it> the team.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to appear on or in (a newspaper, a headline, etc.) <vi>The story of his accident <it>made</it> the front page of the paper.</vi> <vi>The story <it>made</it> headlines all across the country.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to be promoted to (a level or rank) <vi>My uncle is in the army. He <it>made</it> major last year.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to succeed in doing (something that you attempt) <vi>I missed the first foul shot but <it>made</it> the second one.</vi> <vi>He has to <it>make</it> this putt to win the tournament.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (a particular score) <vi>She <it>made</it> a 6 on the second hole.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> a birdie/bogey.</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be too late for (something) <vi>They (just/barely) <it>made</it> the deadline.</vi> <vi>We got to the station just in time to <it>make</it> the train.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reach or go to (a place) <vi>We <it>made</it> [=<it>reached</it>] Atlanta in just under two hours.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to succeed in reaching or going to (something) <vi>The team <it>made</it> [=qualified for] the play-offs last year.</vi> <vi>I don't know if I'll be able to <it>make</it> that meeting.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to act in a way that causes someone to be your friend, enemy, etc. <vi>She <it>makes</it> friends easily.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> a few enemies when he worked here.</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause the success of (someone or something) <vi>This film could <phrase>make or break</phrase> her career. [=the success or failure of her career could depend on the success or failure of this film]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>make-or-break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to be enjoyable, attractive, etc. <vi>The bright paint really <it>makes</it> the room!</vi> <vi>Meeting the star of the show really <phrase>made our day</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned + literary</ssl> <dt>:to seem to begin an action <vi>She <it>made</it> to go. = She <it>made</it> as if to go. [=she moved in a way that suggested she was going]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>make a face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make away with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>make away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to steal and take away (something) <vi>Someone had <it>made away with</it> [=<it>made off with</it>] all the money.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make believe</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make do</dre> <def><dt>:to proceed or do what you can with the things that you have even though you do not have what you want <vi>They didn't have much money but they somehow managed to <it>make do</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>If we can't get what we want, we'll just have to <it>make do with</it> what we've got.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>without</it> <vi>If we don't have carrots for the soup, we'll just have to <it>make do without</it> them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>make for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go toward (a place) quickly <vi>Everyone <it>made for</it> [=<it>headed for</it>] the exit as soon as the show was over.</vi> <vi>After he left the office he <it>made</it> straight <it>for</it> home.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen or to be more likely <vi>Courtesy <it>makes for</it> safer driving.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make friends</dre> <dx>see <dxt>friend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make it</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to reach a particular place, goal, etc. <vi>The ship <it>made it</it> to port.</vi> <vi>You'll never <it>make it</it> that far.</vi> <vi>The climbers finally <it>made it</it> to the top of the mountain.</vi> <vi>Welcome to the party. I'm glad you could <it>make it</it>! = Welcome! I'm glad you could <it>make it</it> to the party!</vi> <vi>The story <it>made it</it> to the front page. [=the story appeared on the front page]</vi> <vi>She's finally <it>made it</it> onto the team. [=she finally was accepted on the team]</vi> <vi>If we hurry, we can still <it>make it</it> home before dark.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to not fail, die, etc. :<sx>survive</sx> <vi>Many new businesses don't <it>make it</it> through their first year.</vi> <vi>He's very sick. The doctor doesn't think he's going to <it>make it</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become successful <vi>It's tough to succeed in this business, but if you work hard I know you'll <it>make it</it> eventually.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made it big</phrase> [=became very successful] in real estate.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex <vi>His girlfriend caught him <it>making it</it> with another girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make like</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to pretend to be (someone or something) <vi>He <it>made like</it> a rooster and strutted across the stage.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to act in a way that does not show your true feelings <vi>He <it>made like</it> [=<it>acted like</it>] he didn't care.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make love</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make merry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>merry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make much of</dre> <def><dt>:to treat (something) as very important <vi>In talking about his past, the book <it>makes much of</it> the influence of his brother. [=the book says that his brother's influence was very important]</vi> <vi>She tends to <it>make</it> far too <it>much of</it> her problems.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't <it>make</it> too <it>much of</it> what he said—he was only joking.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make nice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have or form an opinion about (something or someone) <vi>What do you <it>make of</it> this? [=what is your opinion about this?]</vi> <vi>I can't <it>make</it> anything <it>of</it> it at all.</vi> <vi>I don't know what to <it>make of</it> her behavior. [=I don't understand her behavior]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I don't know quite what to <it>make of</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (a day, night, etc.) of it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue with an enjoyable activity during all of (a day, night, etc.) <vi>Since we're going out to dinner anyway, let's <it>make an evening of it</it> and go to a movie afterward.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make something of (yourself or your life)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become successful <vi>She has worked very hard to <it>make something of herself</it>.</vi> <vi>He wants to <it>make something of his life</it>. [=to have a successful and productive life]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make something of it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to treat something as a reason for arguing or being angry <un>used in speech as an angry way of telling someone that you are prepared to fight or argue about something <vi>Yes, I got home late last night. Do you want to <it>make something of it</it>? [=do you want to argue/fight about it?]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>make much of <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to leave quickly especially in order to escape <vi>After taking the money, the thieves <it>made off</it> toward the main highway.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take or steal (something) and go away <vi>Someone broke into the office and <it>made off with</it> some valuable equipment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to write down the required information on (something, such as a check) <vi>He <it>made out</it> a check for $100 to cover the cost of the repairs.</vi> <vi><it>make out</it> [=<it>fill out</it>] a form</vi> <vi>The doctor will <it>make out</it> a prescription for you. = The doctor will <it>make</it> you <it>out</it> a prescription.</vi> <vi>She <it>made out</it> a shopping list before going to the grocery store.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to see and identify (something) <vi>We could just <it>make out</it> a ship approaching through the fog.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I couldn't quite <it>make out</it> what she said.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to learn or understand (something) by studying, searching, etc. <vi>I can't quite <it>make out</it> [=<it>tell</it>] whether he's drunk or sober.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>make out</it> [=<it>find out, figure out</it>] what really happened.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to understand the behavior of (someone) <un>used in negative statements <vi>I just <it>can't make</it> him <it>out</it> [=figure him out]—he's so contradictory.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to describe (someone or something) in a specified and usually false way <vi>The book <it>makes</it> them <it>out</it> to be criminals.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> them <it>out</it> as worse than they are.</vi> <vi>He's not as bad as he's <it>made out</it> (to be). = He's not as bad as people <it>make</it> him <it>out</it> (to be).</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to ask about or describe the success or progress of someone or something <vi>“How are you <it>making out</it> [=<it>doing, getting along</it>] in your new job?” “Just fine, thank you!”</vi> <vi>“How did the team <it>make out</it> yesterday?” “They won.”</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>made out like a bandit</phrase> [=he made a lot of money] when he sold the company.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to kiss and touch for a long time in a sexual way <vi>She was <it>making out</it> [=(<it>old-fashioned</it>) <it>necking</it>] with her boyfriend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something or someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make over (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to change the appearance of (something or someone) <vi>We <it>made</it> the whole house <it>over</it> so it looked more modern.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>makeover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (property) to another person in an official or legal way <vi>He <it>made</it> the ranch/shares <it>over</it> to his eldest son.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to create or invent (a story, a lie, etc.) <vi>He entertained the children by <it>making up</it> a funny story about a cat that lived on a sailboat.</vi> <vi>He <it>made up</it> some excuse about having problems with his car, but no one believed him.</vi> <vi>It never happened: you <it>made</it> it all <it>up</it>!</vi> <vi>He didn't have a prepared speech. He just <it>made</it> it <it>up</it> as he went along.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>made-up</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to combine to produce (something) <vi>Ten chapters <it>make up</it> this volume. = This volume is <it>made up</it> [=<it>composed</it>] of 10 chapters.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce or create (something) by putting together different parts <vi>They're going to <it>make up</it> a list of requirements for us. = They're going to <it>make</it> us <it>up</it> a list of requirements.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to prepare (something) so that it is ready to be used <vi>I'll <it>make up</it> a bed for you. = I'll <it>make</it> you <it>up</it> a bed. [=I'll prepare a bed for you to sleep in]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to supply (something) according to directions <vi><it>make up</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>fill</it>] a prescription</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to provide an amount of time, money, etc., that is needed <vi>The total cost of the repairs is $200. If you can pay half of that, I'll <it>make up</it> the rest.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>make up</it> the difference.</vi> <vi>I have to leave work early today, but I'll <phrase>make up the time</phrase> by working late tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make (someone or something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to put makeup on (someone or someone's face) <vi>She <it>made</it> herself <it>up</it> for the party.</vi> <vi>Her face was heavily <it>made up</it>. [=there was a lot of makeup on her face]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>made-up</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change the appearance of (someone or something) by using costumes, decorations, etc. <vi>The actor was <it>made up</it> to look like George Washington.</vi> <vi>The room was <it>made up</it> to look like a disco.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become friendly again after being angry <vi>They quarreled but later <it>made up</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>He <it>made up</it> with his girlfriend.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) She's trying to <phrase>make it up</phrase> with him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or have something as a way of correcting or improving (something else) <vi>He wanted to <it>make up for</it> [=<it>atone for</it>] neglecting his children by spending more time with them.</vi> <vi>She tried to <it>make up for</it> lost time by working extra hard.</vi> <vi>What the movie lacks in plot it <it>makes up for</it> in special effects.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to treat (someone) in a very friendly or helpful way in order to get something for yourself <vi>an employee who's always <it>making up to</it> [=(<it>US, informal</it>) <it>sucking up to</it>] the boss</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>make it up to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do something helpful or good for (someone you have hurt or treated wrongly) <vi>He'd neglected his children and wanted to <it>make it up to</it> them by spending more time with them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make up your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make your way, make way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>made</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
