<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="below[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">be*low</hw> <sound><wav>below001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈloʊ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or to a lower place <vi>The pencil rolled off the desk and fell to the floor <it>below</it>.</vi> <vi>The pilot looked down at the sea far <it>below</it>.</vi> <vi>We heard the elevator stop at the floor <it>below</it>.</vi> <snote>The opposite of every sense of <it>below</it> is <it>above</it>.</snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:on or to a lower deck on a ship or boat <vi>They secured the goods on deck and went <it>below</it>.</vi> <vi>The captain ordered the men <it>below</it>. [=ordered them to go below the main deck]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in or to a lower rank or number <vi>All personnel, captain and <it>below</it>, were ordered to report for duty.</vi> <vi>The game is suitable for children at age 10 and <it>below</it>. [=<it>younger, under</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:lower than zero <vi>The temperature ranged from 5 <it>below</it> to 10 above. [=from −5 degrees to 10 degrees Fahrenheit]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:lower, further down, or later on the same page or on a following page :at a later point in the same document <vi>The results of the test are discussed/explained/listed/shown <it>below</it>.</vi> <vi>See the graph <it>below</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>from below</dre> <def><dt>:from a lower place <vi>We heard voices calling <it>from below</it>.</vi> <vi>I felt a draft <it>from below</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="below[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">below</hw> <altpr>bɪˈloʊ</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in or to a lower place than (something) :<sx>beneath</sx> <vi>Our apartment is <it>below</it> theirs.</vi> <vi>She wore a skirt that reached <it>below</it> her knees. = The bottom of her skirt was <it>below</it> her knees.</vi> <vi>We could see only clouds <it>below</it> us.</vi> <vi>The diver descended <it>below</it> 25 meters.</vi> <vi>The sun disappeared <it>below</it> the horizon.</vi> <vi>a spot directly <it>below</it> us</vi> <vi>the valley far <it>below</it> us</vi> <vi>just/slightly <it>below</it> the horizon</vi> <snote>The opposite of every sense of <it>below</it> is <it>above</it>.</snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:lower in number, amount, or size than (something) :less than (something) <vi>Temperatures were <it>below</it> average/normal all week.</vi> <vi>The game is suitable for children <it>below</it> [=<it>younger than, under</it>] the age of 10.</vi> <vi>She worked for wage rates <it>below</it> those of other workers.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:less important or powerful than (someone) :having a lower rank than (someone) <vi>A lieutenant is <it>below</it> a captain. [=a captain outranks a lieutenant]</vi> <vi>He ranks far <it>below</it> his superior.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:in a lower or less important position than (something) <vi>He puts his own needs <it>below</it> his child's needs.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="belt[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">belt</hw> <sound><wav>belt0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛlt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>belts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a band of material (such as leather) that is worn around a person's waist <vi>I fastened/unfastened the buckle on my <it>belt</it>. = I buckled/unbuckled my <it>belt</it>.</vi> <vi>I tied the <it>belt</it> of my robe.</vi> <dx>see color picture on page C14</dx> <dx>see also <dxt>black belt</dxt> <dxt>garter belt</dxt> <dxt>safety belt</dxt> <dxt>seat belt</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a band that runs around wheels or other parts in a machine and that is used for moving or carrying something <dx>see also <dxt>fan belt</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a region that has a lot of a particular thing <vi>a <it>belt</it> of hilly land [=an area with many hills]</vi> <vi>a storm <it>belt</it></vi> <vi>the farm/farming <it>belt</it></vi> <vi>the corn/cotton <it>belt</it> [=a region with many farms growing corn/cotton]</vi> <vi>an asteroid <it>belt</it></vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly US</it>) cities in the <phrase>Rust Belt</phrase> [=an area formerly known for industry and manufacturing]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bible belt</dxt> <dxt>sunbelt</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>below the belt</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:too harsh and unfair <vi>That remark was <it>below the belt</it>. = That remark really <phrase>hit</phrase> (him) <phrase>below the belt</phrase>.</vi> <snote>The phrase <it>below the belt</it> comes from the sport of boxing, where it is against the rules to hit your opponent anywhere below the belt.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tighten your belt</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to spend less money :to make changes in order to save money <vi>Many companies are <it>tightening their belts</it> during the recession.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>belt-tightening</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>under your belt</dre> <def><dt>:as an achievement or as part of your experience <vi>She has a best-selling book <it>under her belt</it>. [=she has written a best-selling book]</vi> <vi>an actor who has several films <it>under his belt</it> [=who has appeared in several films]</vi> <vi>He finally has a full year of experience <it>under his belt</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>belt</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>belt*ed</ure> <sound><wav>belt0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛltəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>belted</it> coat/jacket/robe</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="ground[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ground</hw> <sound><wav>ground01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>grounds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the ground</bnote> <dt>:the surface of the earth <vi>An apple fell to <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>Mechanical problems kept the plane on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They were lying/sitting on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>close to <it>the ground</it> = low to <it>the ground</it></vi> <vi>The flight was watched by many observers on <it>the ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They sent in <phrase>ground forces/troops</phrase>. [=soldiers who fight on the ground instead of in the air or at sea]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>ground war</phrase> [=a war fought by soldiers on the ground]</vi> <vi><phrase>ground transportation</phrase> [=transportation that is over the ground instead of on water or in the air]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the soil that is on or under the surface of the earth <vi>planting seeds in the <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>She drove a spike into the <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>damp/frozen <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>solid/firm/dry <it>ground</it></vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of land <vi>They built their house on bare/level/flat <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>We realized that we were on hallowed/sacred <it>ground</it>.</vi> <vi>They built their house on high <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area of land or sea that is used for a particular purpose <vi>a camping <it>ground</it></vi> <vi>fishing/hunting <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>Each fall the birds return to their wintering <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a football <it>ground</it> [=(<it>US</it>) a soccer field]</vi> <vi>an ancient <phrase>burial ground</phrase> [=a place where people were buried in ancient times]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>spawning ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the land around a building <vi>the capitol <it>grounds</it></vi> <vi>He was trespassing on school <it>grounds</it>.</vi> <vi>We toured the <it>grounds</it> of the estate.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the bottom of the ocean, a lake, etc. <vi>The boat struck <it>ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of knowledge or interest <vi>We have a lot of <it>ground</it> to go over before the test.</vi> <vi>We covered much more <it>ground</it> [=we went over more information] than we expected to at the meeting.</vi> <vi>The book covers <phrase>familiar ground</phrase>. [=subjects that have often been discussed before]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a place or situation in which someone or something is developed or tested <vi>The laboratory has become a <phrase>testing ground</phrase> for ideas about the origins of the universe.</vi> <vi>The tournament has come to be regarded as a <phrase>proving ground</phrase> for young players.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a set of beliefs, opinions, or attitudes <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The two sides are trying to find some <phrase>common ground</phrase> [=an area in which they can agree with each other] on these issues.</vi> <vi>When a politician talks about raising taxes, he's <phrase>on dangerous ground</phrase>. [=he is doing or saying something that may cause anger or criticism]</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>The two sides continue to look for a <phrase>middle ground</phrase> [=a middle position] between two extremes.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>high ground</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a reason for doing or thinking something <un>usually plural <vi>The company has been accused of discriminating on the <it>grounds</it> of race.</vi> <vi>We have no <it>grounds</it> for believing that the crisis will end soon.</vi> <vi>Her husband's infidelity was <it>grounds</it> for divorce.</vi> <vi>Many critics have objected to the proposal <phrase>on the grounds that</phrase> [=because] it would be too costly.</vi> <vi>The law was rejected <it>on the grounds that</it> it was not constitutional. = The law was rejected on constitutional <it>grounds</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <bnote>grounds</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:very small pieces of crushed coffee beans <vi>coffee <it>grounds</it></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a wire or metal object that makes an electrical connection with the earth <un>usually singular <vi>This metal bracket provides the <it>ground</it>.</vi></un> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>earth</cat></ca></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the area behind or around a design <vi>The wallpaper has red tulips on a white <it>ground</it>. [=<it>background</it>]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>above ground</dre> <def><dt>:on top of the earth's surface <vi>The bird's nest is located high <it>above ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>below ground</dre> <def><dt>:under the earth's surface <vi>The seeds should be planted a few inches <it>below ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>break ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to dig into the ground at the start of building something <vi>Workers <it>broke ground</it> on the new stadium last week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>break new ground</va></svr> <dt>:to make new discoveries <vi>Critics say that the study does not <it>break</it> (any) <it>new ground</it> in the search for a cure for cancer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>burn to the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>down to the ground</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:completely or perfectly <vi>The job <phrase>suits her down to the ground</phrase>. [=suits her perfectly]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from the ground up</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:completely or thoroughly <vi>The car has been redesigned <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:from a point at which nothing has been done :from the very beginning <vi>They built the resort <it>from the ground up</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>gain ground</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make up ground</va></vr> <def><dt>:to move faster so that you come closer to someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was trailing in the race, but she was beginning to <it>gain ground</it> (on the leaders).</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Alternative forms of energy are quickly <it>gaining ground</it>. [=becoming more popular or successful]</vi> <vi>The company has been <it>gaining ground on</it> [=<it>catching up with</it>] its competitors.</vi> <vi>The campaign is trying to <it>make up ground</it> by advertising heavily in key states.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get off the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin to operate or proceed in a successful way <vi><it>The project</it> never really <it>got off the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>get (something) off the ground</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to begin to operate or proceed in successful way <vi>We're still trying to <it>get</it> this project <it>off the ground</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move backward when you are being attacked :<sx>retreat</sx> <vi>The troops were forced to <it>give ground</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The controversy has continued, and both sides are still refusing to <it>give ground</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep your feet on the ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the ground running</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold/stand your ground</dre> <def><dt>:to not change your position when you are being attacked :to not retreat <vi>The troops managed to <it>hold their ground</it> despite a fierce enemy attack.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The company has managed to <it>hold its ground</it> in the marketplace.</vi> <vi>The president has continued to <it>stand his ground</it> despite criticism.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into the ground</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to the point of being very tired or exhausted <vi>She's been working/running/driving herself <it>into the ground</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to the point of complete failure or ruin <vi>He ran that company <it>into the ground</it>. [=he destroyed that company]</vi> <vi>She drove that old car <it>into the ground</it>. [=she drove it until it would not run anymore]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose ground</dre> <def><dt>:to move slower so that you are farther away from someone or something that is in front of you <vi>She was beginning to <it>lose ground</it> (to the leaders) in the race.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The political party <it>lost ground</it> [=became less popular or successful; did not do well] in the election.</vi> <vi>The company is <it>losing ground to</it> [=falling behind; not doing as well as] its competitors.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="par"> <hw>par</hw> <sound><wav>par00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpɑɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>pars</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the number of strokes a good golfer is expected to take to finish a golf hole or course <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He made/scored <it>par</it> on the ninth hole.</vi> <vi>She finished the 18th hole three strokes under/over <it>par</it>.</vi> <vi>The 18th hole is a <it>par</it> 5. [=par for the 18th hole is five strokes]</vi> <vi>a <it>par</it>-5 hole</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He made/scored a <it>par</it> on the ninth hole.</vi> <vi>She made/scored nine <it>pars</it> in a row.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>business</ssl> <dt>:the value of a stock or bond that is printed on the paper of the stock or bond itself or that is decided upon when the stock or bond is issued <vi>That stock is trading (at) 16 percent above/below <it>par</it>.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>par value</cat></ca></dt></def> <dro><dre>above par</dre> <def><dt>:better than normal or expected :very good <vi>The performance was <it>above par</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>below par</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>under par</va></vr> <def><dt>:worse than expected :not very good :<sx>bad</sx> <vi>Our meal was <it>below par</it>. [=<it>subpar</it>]</vi> <vi>I'm feeling a little <it>below par</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on (a) par with</dre> <def><dt>:at the same level or standard as (someone or something else) <vi>The new version of the software is <it>on a par with</it> the old one. [=is as good as the old one]</vi> <vi>His new book is <it>on par with</it> his best sellers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>par for the course</dre> <def><sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:normal or typical :not unusual or unexpected <vi>His son's bad behavior is just <it>par for the course</it>. [=his son often/always behaves badly]</vi> <vi>It's <it>par for the course</it> that she's late to the meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to par</dre> <def><dt>:good enough :as good as expected or wanted <vi>She was checking to see if his work was <it>up to par</it>.</vi> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>His course work is <it>not up to par</it>. [=not as good as it should be]</vi> <vi>She's not feeling <it>up to par</it>. [=she is not feeling well; her health is not good]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
