<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bend[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bend</hw> <sound><wav>bend0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛnd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bends</if></in> <in><if>bent</if> <sound><wav>bend0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>bend*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use force to cause (something, such as a wire or pipe) to become curved <vi><it>bend</it> a wire into a circle</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> the cable around a wheel</vi> <vi>He <it>bent</it> the bow and shot an arrow from it.</vi> <vi>His glasses got <it>bent</it> when he dropped them.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to curve out of a straight line or position <vi>The road <it>bends</it> [=<it>curves, turns</it>] to the left.</vi> <vi>The trees were <it>bending</it> in the wind.</vi> <vi>The branch will <it>bend</it> before it breaks.</vi> <vi>The branches of the fruit tree were <phrase>bending under their own weight</phrase>. [=were bending because they were so heavy]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She refused to <it>bend</it> under pressure to change her decision.</vi> <vi>a politician accused of <phrase>bending to the will</phrase> of wealthy supporters [=being influenced by wealthy supporters; doing the things that are wanted by wealthy supporters]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move your body so that it is not straight <vi>She <it>bent</it> down/over/forward to pick up a piece of paper and then she straightened up again.</vi> <vi>He <it>bent</it> back to look up at the ceiling.</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> to the left and then <it>bend</it> to the right</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> at the waist</vi> <vi>He <phrase>bent double</phrase> with pain. [=he bent forward from the waist because he was in extreme pain]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (part of your body, such as an arm or leg) so that it is not straight <vi><it>bend</it> a knee</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> a leg</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> an arm</vi> <vi><it>bend</it> [=<it>tilt</it>] your head</vi> <snote>In formal language, if you <phrase>bend yourself to</phrase> or <phrase>bend your strength/energy/efforts (etc.) to/toward</phrase> something (such as a job or task), you work hard in order to do it. <vi>He has <it>bent himself</it> [=<it>applied himself</it>] <it>to</it> the task of making the company more efficient and profitable.</vi> <vi>They are <it>bending their efforts toward</it> completing the job on time.</vi> <vi>They <it>bent their minds</it> to [=gave a lot of thought to; thought hard about] the problem.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>bend a rule</dre> <def><dt>:to not be strict or exact about following a rule <vi>She's not really quite old enough to be admitted as a member, but she's very close, so I think we can <it>bend the rule(s)</it> a little in her case and let her in now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bend over backward</dre> <dx>see <dxt>backward</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bend someone's ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to talk to someone for a long time <vi>He didn't really care about me, he just wanted to <it>bend my ear</it> about his own problems.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bend (the) facts</dre> <def><dt>:to change facts in a dishonest way in order to deceive people <vi>a journalist who has been accused of <it>bending the facts</it> in order to gain support for his political agenda</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bend the truth</dre> <def><dt>:to say something that is not true or that misleads people but that is usually not regarded as a serious or harmful lie <vi>When he tells people he's from Manhattan he's <it>bending the truth</it> a little since he really grew up in Brooklyn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on bended knee</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>on bended knees</va></vr> <def><dt>:in a kneeling position :in the position of someone who is kneeling on one knee <vi>He proposed to her <it>on bended knee</it>. = He got down <it>on bended knee</it> and proposed to her.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was forced to ask for their help <it>on bended knee</it>. [=he was forced to beg for their help; he was forced to ask for their help in a very humble way]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bend[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bend</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛnd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bends</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a curved part of something <vi>a <it>bend</it> in a road/stream</vi> <vi>They live just around/past the next <it>bend</it> (in the road).</vi> <vi>the graceful <it>bends</it> [=curves] of the stairway</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act or process of bending something <vi>a quick <it>bend</it> of the body</vi> <vi>knee <it>bends</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the bends</bnote> <ssl>medical</ssl> <dt>:a painful and dangerous condition caused by rising to the surface too quickly after being deep underwater <ca>called also <cat>decompression sickness</cat></ca></dt></def> <dro><dre>around the bend</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>round the bend</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>crazy</sx> <vi>The pressure of his job nearly drove him <it>around the bend</it>.</vi> <vi>He almost went <it>around the bend</it>.</vi> <vi>If you ask me, she's completely <it>round the bend</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:occurring soon <vi>The end of summer is just/right <it>around the bend</it>. [=<it>around the corner</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bendy</ure> <sound><wav>bendy001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛndi</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bend*i*er</if></in> <in><if>bend*i*est</if></in> <gram>also more bendy; most bendy</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <utxt><vi>a <it>bendy</it> [=<it>flexible</it>] toy</vi> <vi>a <it>bendy</it> road [=a road with many curves]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="S-bend"> <hw>S–bend</hw> <sound><wav>sbend01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛsˌbɛnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>S–bends</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a bend in a road or pipe in the shape of the letter S</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="U-bend"> <hw>U–bend</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>U–bends</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>technical</sl> <dt>:<sx>trap <sxn>5</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="South Bend"> <hw>South Bend</hw> <sound><wav>ggsout03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛnd</pr> <fl>geographical name</fl> <def><dt>:U.S. city, Indiana</dt></def> </entry>

	<entry id="backward[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">back*ward</hw> <sound><wav>backwa01.wav</wav></sound> <hsl>chiefly US</hsl> <pr>ˈbækwɚd</pr> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>back*wards</va> <sound><wav>backwa02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbækwɚdz</pr></vr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:toward the back :to or toward what is behind <vi>a sudden movement <it>backward</it>, not forward</vi> <vi>I heard a noise behind me and glanced <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>He pushed the throttle <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>She took a small step <it>backward</it>.</vi> <vi>Can you skate <it>backward</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:opposite to the usual way :in reverse <vi>Count <it>backward</it> from 10.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:toward the past <vi>a journey <it>backward</it> in time</vi> <vi>The narrative moves <it>backward</it> and forward in time.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to or toward a less advanced state or condition :toward a worse state <vi>His new job, which paid less and had fewer responsibilities, felt like a step <it>backward</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bend over backward</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>lean over backward</va> <vl>also</vl> <va>fall over backward</va></vr> <def><dt>:to make a great effort to help someone or to reach agreement with someone <vi>The salesman said he would <it>bend over backward</it> to make the deal.</vi> <vi>I've <it>leaned over backward</it> to please you—and you haven't even said thank you!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know something backward and forward</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="double[4]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="4">double</hw> <altpr>ˈdʌbəl</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:two times as many or as much <vi>The last question on the exam counts <it>double</it>. [=is worth twice as many points]</vi> <vi>I was charged/billed <it>double</it>. [=twice the usual amount]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:two times <un>usually used in combination <vi>I was <phrase>double-charged/billed</phrase>. [=I was charged/billed twice for the same product or service]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bend double</dre> <def><dt>:to fold in the middle. <vi>I held on tight as my fishing rod <it>bent double</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>bent double</it> [=<it>doubled over</it>] in pain.</vi> <snote><it>Bend double</it> is used more frequently in British English than in U.S. English.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see double</dre> <def><dt>:to see two things when only one thing is present <vi>As her eyesight got worse, she began <it>seeing double</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>that goes double for</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something you have just said about one person or thing relates even more strongly to another <vi>You're in trouble, Steven. And <it>that goes double for</it> you, John. [=you, John, are in even more trouble than Steven]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="ear[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ear</hw> <sound><wav>ear00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ears</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you hear with <vi>He was whispering something in her <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>a dog with floppy <it>ears</it></vi> <vi><phrase>pierced ears</phrase> [=ears with earlobes that have been pierced for wearing earrings]</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something heard <vi>He has a good <it>ear</it> for music/languages.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something sounds to you <vi>It sounds a little old-fashioned to my <it>ear</it>. [=it sounds old-fashioned to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:attention that is shown or given by listening to what someone says <vi>Thanks for your <it>ear</it>. [=thanks for listening]</vi> <vi>When I told my story, my brother <phrase>listened with only half an ear</phrase>. [=did not listen closely]</vi> <snote>To <phrase>lend an ear</phrase> or, in literary language, to <phrase>lend someone your ears</phrase> is to listen to what someone has to say. <vi>She's always willing to <it>lend a</it> sympathetic <it>ear</it>.</vi> <vi>“Friends, Romans, countrymen, <it>lend me your ears</it>.” <aq>Shakespeare, <it>Julius Caesar</it> (1599)</aq></vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>all ears</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone is listening very closely <vi>As I told the story, my daughter was <it>all ears</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a word in someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bend someone's ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>box someone's ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>box</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your ear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>ears are burning</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <phrase>your ears are burning</phrase> or you <phrase>feel your ears burning</phrase>, you have the feeling that other people are talking about you. <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) “We were talking about you last night.” “That explains why I <it>felt my ears burning</it>.”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ears pop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fall on deaf ears</dre> <def><dt>:to fail to be heard :to be ignored <vi>Her pleas for mercy <it>fell on deaf ears</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>grin/smile from ear to ear</dre> <def><dt>:to smile widely :to have a big smile on your face <vi>He was <it>grinning from ear to ear</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have someone's ear</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have someone's ear</it> you can talk and give advice to that person because you are trusted. <vi>an adviser who <it>has the President's ear</it></vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in one ear and out the other</dre> <def><dt>:through someone's mind without being remembered or noticed <vi>Everything you say to him goes <it>in one ear and out the other</it>. [=he doesn't listen to or remember what you say]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out on your ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:forced out :thrown out <vi>If you're late to work again, you'll be <it>out on your ear</it>! [=you'll be fired]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play by ear</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><snote>To play a song or a piece of music <it>by ear</it> is to play it after hearing it without looking at written music. <vi>He could play any tune <it>by ear</it> after hearing it only once.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>play it by ear</phrase> is to do something without special preparation. <vi>I don't know how they'll react to our proposal, so we'll just have to <it>play it by ear</it> [=<it>improvise</it>, (<it>informal</it>) <it>wing it</it>] and hope for the best.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>set (something) on its ear</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to cause something to be in a state of great excitement or shock <vi>She <it>set</it> the racing world <it>on its ear</it> [=she surprised and shocked the racing world] by winning several major races.</vi> <vi>His early recordings <it>set</it> the jazz world <it>on its ear</it>. [=his recordings caused a sensation in the jazz world]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>talk someone's ear off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>talk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a deaf ear</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to listen to what someone says <vi>The company president <it>turned a deaf ear</it> to my proposals.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your ears</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in something <vi>They are <it>up to their ears</it> in debt. [=they are deeply in debt]</vi> <vi>We're <it>up to our ears</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wet behind the ears</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wet</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>ear</dxt></dxnl> <uro><ure>eared</ure> <sound><wav>eared001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a long-<it>eared</it> dog</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>ear*less</ure> <sound><wav>earle01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈiɚləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="fact"> <hw highlight="yes">fact</hw> <sound><wav>fact0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfækt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>facts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that truly exists or happens :something that has actual existence <vi>Rapid electronic communication is now a <it>fact</it>.</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>the fact that</phrase> <vi>It's hard to accept <it>the fact that</it> she's gone. [=it's hard to accept that she's gone]</vi> <vi>What they're proposing is impractical, apart from <it>the fact that</it> it's also illegal.</vi> <vi>In spite of <it>the fact that</it> he was sick [=although he was sick], I went to visit him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a true piece of information <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The book is filled with interesting <it>facts</it> and figures.</vi> <vi>Those are the (cold) hard <it>facts</it> of the case.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>know for a fact</phrase> that he did it. [=I am sure that he did it]</vi> <vi>He did it, and <phrase>that's a fact</phrase>.</vi> <vi>There's no doubt that he did it. <phrase>The facts speak for themselves</phrase>. [=the facts make it clear that he did it]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>It can sometimes be hard to separate <phrase>fact from fiction</phrase>. [=to know what is true and what is false]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>after the fact</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:after a crime has been committed <vi>She was charged with being an <phrase>accessory after the fact</phrase>. [=she was charged with helping someone who had committed a crime after the crime was committed]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:after something has happened :<sx>afterward</sx> <vi>They informed me of their decision only <it>after the fact</it>. [=after they had already made their decision]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as a matter of fact</dre> <def><dt><un>used to stress the truth of a statement <vi>“Do you know her personally?” “<it>As a matter of fact</it>, I do.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bend (the) facts</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in fact</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in truth <un>used to stress that a statement is true although it may be surprising or unlikely <vi>painters who are <it>in fact</it> anything but unsophisticated</vi> <vi>He looks younger, but he is <it>in</it> (actual) <it>fact</it> almost 60 years old.</vi> <vi>They know each other; <it>in fact</it>, they're close friends. = They know each other; they're close friends, <it>in fact</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>also</vl> <va>in point of fact</va></svr> <dt><un>used to introduce a true statement which shows that another statement is not true or accurate <vi>He claims that he supported the bill, but <it>in fact</it> he voted against it. [=the truth is that he voted against it]</vi> <vi>She says that she doesn't know him, but <it>in point of fact</it> they have been seen together many times.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>is that a fact?</dre> <def><dt><un>used to respond to a statement that is thought to be surprising or unlikely <vi>“He looks much younger, but he's actually almost 60 years old.” “<it>Is that a fact</it>?” [=I am surprised he is 60 years old]</vi> <vi>“A lot of people agree with me.” “<it>Is that a fact</it>?” [=I doubt that a lot of people agree with you]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the fact is/remains</dre> <def><dt><un>used to stress that a statement is true and that its truth is not affected or changed by a previous statement <vi>He may not have meant it, but <it>the fact remains</it> that he committed a crime.</vi> <vi>The company has struggled recently, but <it>the fact is</it> that they are still making a profit.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the fact of the matter</dre> <dx>see <dxt>matter</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="truth"> <hw highlight="yes">truth</hw> <sound><wav>truth001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtru:θ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>truths</if> <sound><wav>truth002.wav</wav><wav>truth003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtru:ðz, ˈtru:θs</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the truth</bnote> <dt>:the real facts about something :the things that are true <vi>Are you telling (me) <it>the truth</it>?</vi> <vi>At some point you have to face <it>the</it> simple/hard/honest/plain/naked <it>truth</it> that we failed.</vi> <vi>Their explanation was simpler but came closer to <it>the truth</it>.</vi> <vi>The article explains <it>the truth</it> about global warming.</vi> <vi>A reporter soon discovered/revealed/uncovered <it>the truth</it>.</vi> <vi>Do you swear to tell <phrase>the whole truth</phrase> and nothing but <it>the truth</it>?</vi> <vi>I know you think I don't care, but <phrase>nothing could be further from the truth</phrase>. [=that is absolutely not true]</vi> <vi><phrase>The truth of the matter is (that)</phrase> you failed the exam and it's going to be reflected in your final grade.</vi> <vi><phrase>To tell (you) the truth</phrase>, I liked her first book better than this one. [=I am being honest when I say that I liked her first book better]</vi> <vi>“When was the last time you went to New York?” “<it>To tell you the truth</it>, I don't remember.” [=I have to admit that I don't remember]</vi> <vi>I told her I liked the restaurant but <it>the truth</it> is that the food was pretty bad. = I told her I liked the restaurant but, <phrase>truth be told/known</phrase>, the food was pretty bad.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the quality or state of being true <vi>There's no <it>truth</it> in anything he says. [=nothing he says is true]</vi> <vi>I doubt the <it>truth</it> of their accusations. [=I doubt that their accusations are true]</vi> <vi>Her story contains <phrase>a grain/kernel of truth</phrase> but also lots of exaggeration.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a statement or idea that is true or accepted as true <un>usually plural <vi>Her experience taught her some basic/fundamental/eternal/universal <it>truths</it> about human nature.</vi> <vi>mathematical <it>truths</it></vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>half-truth</dxt> <dxt>home truth</dxt> <dxt>untruth</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>bend the truth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in truth</dre> <def><dt>:in fact :actually or really <vi>She said she was feeling fine, but <it>in truth</it> she was very ill.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>moment of truth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moment</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
