<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="beneath[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">be*neath</hw> <sound><wav>beneat01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈni:θ</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><dt>:in or to a lower position :<sx>below</sx> <vi>the mountains and the towns <it>beneath</it></vi> <vi>the sky above and the earth <it>beneath</it></vi> <vi>an awning with chairs and tables <it>beneath</it></vi> <vi>The ground <it>beneath</it> is covered with flowers.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="beneath[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">beneath</hw> <altpr>bɪˈni:θ</altpr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in or to a lower position than (something or someone) :<sx>below</sx> <vi>the sky above us and the earth <it>beneath</it> us</vi> <vi>just <it>beneath</it> the surface of the water</vi> <vi>The painting is hanging on the wall with a plaque <it>beneath</it> it.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:directly under (something or someone) <vi>the ground <it>beneath</it> [=<it>underneath</it>] her feet</vi> <vi>We had a picnic <it>beneath</it> a large tree.</vi> <vi>The paper was hidden <it>beneath</it> a pile of books.</vi> <vi>She wore a sweater <it>beneath</it> her coat.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not worthy of (someone) :not good enough for (someone) <vi>He won't do any work that he considers <it>beneath</it> him. [=work that he thinks is not good enough for a person of his social class]</vi> <vi>She refused to marry <it>beneath</it> her. [=to marry someone with a lower social standing than hers]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>above</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:under the pressure or influence of (something) <vi>The chair sagged <it>beneath</it> [=<it>under, underneath</it>] his weight. [=his weight caused the chair to sag]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:hidden under (something) <vi>He has a warm heart <it>beneath</it> [=<it>under, underneath</it>] his gruff manner.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>from beneath</dre> <def><dt>:from a place below or under (something) <vi>She gazed at us <it>from beneath</it> the brim of her hat.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="contempt"> <hw>con*tempt</hw> <sound><wav>contem13.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈtɛmpt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a feeling that someone or something is not worthy of any respect or approval <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He feels that wealthy people view/regard him with <it>contempt</it> because he is poor.</vi> <vi>He spoke with <it>contempt</it> in his voice.</vi> <vi>She has <it>contempt</it> for them. = She <phrase>holds them in contempt</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>She has displayed a profound <it>contempt</it> for her opponents.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a lack of respect for or fear of something that is usually respected or feared <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They have acted with <it>contempt</it> for public safety. [=they have completely ignored public safety]</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>He has <it>contempt</it> for danger. [=he ignores danger; he is not afraid of doing things that other people are afraid to do]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:speech or behavior that does not show proper respect to a court or judge <vi>She was arrested for <phrase>contempt of court</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>held in contempt</phrase> [=considered by the court to have broken the law by disobeying or disrespecting the judge] for his outbursts during the trial.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beneath contempt</dre> <def><dt>:completely bad or worthless <un>used to describe someone or something that is too bad to deserve any respect <vi>She's a liar who is <it>beneath contempt</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>familiarity breeds contempt</dre> <dx>see <dxt>familiarity</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="dignity"> <hw>dig*ni*ty</hw> <sound><wav>dignit02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɪgnəti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a way of appearing or behaving that suggests seriousness and self-control <vi>She showed <it>dignity</it> in defeat.</vi> <vi>The ceremony was conducted with great <it>dignity</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the quality of being worthy of honor or respect <vi>Theirs is a country that cherishes freedom and human <it>dignity</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beneath your dignity</dre> <def><dt>:suitable for someone who is less important than you <vi>He thought washing dishes was <it>beneath his dignity</it>. [=he thought that he was too good or important to wash dishes]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
