<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="beside"> <hw highlight="yes">be*side</hw> <sound><wav>beside01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>bɪˈsaɪd</pr> <fl>preposition</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:by the side of (someone or something) :next to (someone or something) <vi>She sat <it>beside</it> him during dinner.</vi> <vi>The man <it>beside</it> her was wearing a brown suit and hat.</vi> <vi>They were walking <it>beside</it> me.</vi> <vi>Stand <it>beside</it> the statue and I'll take your picture.</vi> <vi>Their house is <it>beside</it> a small lake.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in comparison with (something) <vi>These problems seem unimportant <it>beside</it> the potential benefits of the new system.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beside the point</dre> <def><dt>:not related to the main idea that is being discussed :not important <vi>No one knows what we did, but that's <it>beside the point</it>. What we did was wrong.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beside yourself</dre> <def><dt>:not thinking clearly because you are feeling very strong emotions :in a state of extreme excitement <vi>We were <it>beside ourselves</it> with anger/worry/embarrassment/joy.</vi> <vi>He was <it>beside himself</it> [=very upset] after hearing the bad news.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="point[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">point</hw> <sound><wav>point001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpoɪnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>points</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an idea that you try to make other people accept or understand <vi>She showed us several graphs to illustrate the <it>point</it> she was making.</vi> <vi>I see your <it>point</it>, but I don't think everyone will agree.</vi> <vi>There's no use in arguing the <it>point</it>.</vi> <vi>He made a very good <it>point</it> about the need for change.</vi> <vi>Let me make one final <it>point</it>.</vi> <vi>That's the <it>point</it> I've been trying to make.</vi> <vi>“What's your <it>point</it>?” “Actually, I have two <it>points</it>.”</vi> <vi>My <it>point</it> is simply that we must do something to help the homeless.</vi> <vi>That's my <it>point</it> exactly.</vi> <vi>Maybe there's a better way to <phrase>get your point across</phrase>. [=to make people understand what you are saying]</vi> <vi>He's willing to do almost anything to <phrase>prove a point</phrase>. [=to show that he is right about something]</vi> <vi>If you want to <phrase>stretch a point</phrase> [=exaggerate slightly], you could say that he is handsome.</vi> <vi>“If we leave now, we won't make it back in time.” “That's a <phrase>good point</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>“You have to help them.” “<phrase>Point taken</phrase>. [=I understand what you are saying] I'll do what I can.”</vi> <vi>I don't want to <phrase>labor/belabor the point</phrase> [=repeat myself too many times], but I think I should mention again that we are running out of time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular detail of an idea or argument <vi>There are two critical/crucial/key <it>points</it> that I would like to discuss.</vi> <vi>There are several weak <it>points</it> in their theory.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>the point</bnote> <dt>:the main or most important idea of something that is said or written <vi>It took several paragraphs for her to <phrase>come/get to the point</phrase> of her argument.</vi> <vi>If you drive while drunk, you could lose your license, but even <phrase>more to the point</phrase> [=more importantly], you could kill someone.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>to the point <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a reason for doing something :<sx>purpose</sx> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>Is there a <it>point</it> to/for all of this paperwork?</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>What's the <it>point of</it> having [=why have] a swimming pool if you never use it?</vi></un> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>I saw no <it>point in</it> continuing the discussion.</vi> <vi>There's no <it>point in</it> getting upset. [=there is no reason to get upset]</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>There's not much <it>point in</it> making rules if no one's going to follow them.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an individual detail or part of something <vi>The only <it>point</it> at issue is when the meeting should be held.</vi> <vi>Carefully consider each <it>point</it> in the witness's testimony.</vi> <vi>We debated the <phrase>fine/finer points</phrase> of the law.</vi> <vi>The main <phrase>point of contention</phrase> [=the main thing that people are arguing over] is who owns the rights to the land.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rallying point</dxt> <dxt>selling point</dxt> <dxt>sticking point</dxt> <dxt>talking point</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular position, location, or place <vi>We met at a <it>point</it> halfway between the two cities.</vi> <vi>The sun reaches its highest <it>point</it> in the sky at noon.</vi> <vi>the country's northernmost <it>point</it></vi> <vi>distant <it>points</it> in the solar system</vi> <vi>Change trains here for all <it>points</it> south.</vi> <vi>The break occurred at a weak <it>point</it> in the bone.</vi> <vi>She showed us the old capital building and other <phrase>points of interest</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Ellis Island in Manhattan was the <phrase>point of entry</phrase> of many American immigrants. [=the place where many immigrants entered the U.S.]</vi> <vi>The package's <phrase>point of origin</phrase> [=the place from where the package was sent] was somewhere in the U.S.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular time or a particular stage in the development of something <un>usually singular <vi>At no <it>point</it> (in time) did the defendant ask for a lawyer.</vi> <vi>By this <it>point</it> in the conversation, I was beginning to lose my patience.</vi> <vi>I imagine the change will take place at some <it>point</it> in the next year or so.</vi> <vi>We are approaching the cutoff <it>point</it> of the negotiations.</vi> <vi>At that time, she enjoyed more success than at any other <it>point</it> in her career.</vi> <vi>That was the high/low <it>point</it> of her career.</vi> <vi>At this <it>point</it> in my life, I can't afford to take any risks. = I'm at a <it>point</it> in my life where I can't afford to take any risks.</vi> <vi>It got to the <it>point</it> where we could no longer ignore his behavior.</vi> <vi>The game had gone past the <it>point</it> of being fun. [=the game had stopped being fun]</vi> <vi>We walked all day and were beyond the <it>point</it> of exhaustion.</vi> <vi>The temperature will rise to 33 degrees Fahrenheit, <phrase>at which point</phrase> the ice will begin to melt.</vi> <vi>It's the natural <phrase>starting point</phrase> for a discussion on how to help the homeless.</vi> <vi><phrase>There comes a point</phrase> in a man's life when he has to think seriously about his future.</vi> <vi><phrase>From that point on</phrase> [=beginning at that time], I took my studies more seriously.</vi> <vi><phrase>From this point on</phrase>, any further changes must be approved by your supervisor.</vi> <vi><phrase>Up to that point</phrase> it had been a successful meeting.</vi> <vi>The animals were hunted <phrase>to the point of</phrase> extinction. [=the animals were hunted until they were extinct]</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>at the point of</phrase> leaving [=she was just about to leave] when he asked her to dance.</vi> <vi>The police are <phrase>on the point of</phrase> solving the case. [=the police have almost solved the case]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>breaking point</dxt> <dxt>point of no return</dxt> <dxt>turning point</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a unit of measurement <vi>Her blood pressure had risen 16 <it>points</it> since her last checkup.</vi> <vi>Support for the President dropped three <it>points</it> [=<it>percent</it>] after the incident.</vi> <vi>She is currently 10 <it>points</it> behind the leading candidate in the polls.</vi> <vi>Interest rates have risen about two <phrase>percentage points</phrase>. [=interest rates rose about two percent]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>boiling point</dxt> <dxt>dew point</dxt> <dxt>flash point</dxt> <dxt>freezing point</dxt> <dxt>melting point</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a unit that is used to score a game or contest <vi>We won (the game) by three <it>points</it>.</vi> <vi>They scored 13 <it>points</it> in the first quarter.</vi> <vi>She has to win this <it>point</it> in order to win the match.</vi> <vi>She lost a <it>point</it> for falling off the balance beam.</vi> <vi>A touchdown is worth six <it>points</it>.</vi> <vi>He beat his opponent <phrase>on points</phrase>. [=by winning more points than his opponent]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>extra point</dxt> <dxt>game point</dxt> <dxt>match point</dxt> <dxt>set point</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>points</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:praise, credit, or approval for doing something good or helpful <vi>She washed the car in order to score <it>points</it> [=<it>brownie points</it>] with her father.</vi> <vi>He's not too smart, but he gets <it>points</it> for effort. [=he should be given credit for the effort he makes]</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the usually sharp end of something (such as a sword, needle, or pencil) <vi>the sharp <it>point</it> [=<it>tip</it>] of the needle</vi> <vi>She sharpened the pencil down <phrase>to a point</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The alligator's tail tapers <it>to a point</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small dot <vi>We see the stars and planets as tiny <it>points</it> of light.</vi> <vi>a line drawn between two <it>points</it></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>decimal point</sx> <un>used especially in speech to say a number that includes a decimal point <vi>The number 9.5 is read aloud as “nine <it>point</it> five.”</vi> <vi>He had a temperature of one hundred and four <it>point</it> two. [=104.2]</vi> <vi>You're listening to ninety-three <it>point</it> nine [=93.9] FM.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:any one of the 32 marks on a compass that are used for showing directions <vi>The <it>point</it> SSW is between the <it>points</it> S and SW.</vi> <vi>The <phrase>cardinal points</phrase> [=the four main directions] are North, South, East, and West.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of land that sticks out into a lake, ocean, etc. <vi>The light was coming from the lighthouse on the <it>point</it>.</vi> <un>sometimes used in names <vi>Montauk <it>Point</it> is at the eastern tip of Long Island.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>outlet <sxn>4</sxn></sx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a unit that measures the size of letters typed on a computer or printed in a published work <vi>Your essays should be double-spaced and written in 12-<it>point</it> type.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>beside the point</dre> <dx>see <dxt>beside</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from point A to point B</dre> <dx>see <dxt>a</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in point of</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:when considering (a particular quality) :with regard to (something) <vi>The two painters differ greatly <it>in point of</it> skill. [=the level of their skill is very different]</vi> <vi>Some people think that all fat is unhealthy to eat when, <phrase>in point of fact</phrase> [=in truth, in actuality], some types of fat are good for you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a point</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>make a point of</phrase> doing something or <phrase>make it a point</phrase> to do something, you give your attention to it so that you are sure that it happens. <vi>She <it>makes a point of</it> treating her employees fairly. = She <it>makes it a point to</it> treat her employees fairly.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not to put too fine a point on it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fine</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on point</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:relating very well to the subject that is being discussed :accurate and appropriate <vi>His criticisms about the war were very much <it>on point</it>.</vi> <vi>Her message is (right) <it>on point</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the point</dre> <def><dt>:relating to the thing that is being thought about or discussed <vi>Please keep your questions brief and <it>to the point</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>point <dxn>1c (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to a point</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that a statement is partly but not completely true <vi>I understand his feelings <it>up to a point</it>. [=<it>to some extent</it>]</vi> <vi>Competition is good but only <it>up to a</it> certain <it>point</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>case in point</dxt> <dxt>exclamation point</dxt> <dxt>price point</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
