<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="best[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">best</hw> <sound><wav>best0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛst</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>good</ct> <cl>or of</cl> <ct>well</ct></cx> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:better than all others in quality or value <vi>You should wear your <it>best</it> clothes tonight.</vi> <vi>He took us to the (very) <it>best</it> restaurants in the city.</vi> <vi>We ate the <it>best</it> food and drank the <it>best</it> wines.</vi> <vi>You're our <it>best</it> customers.</vi> <vi>His modesty and sense of humor are his <it>best</it> qualities.</vi> <vi>Is that your <it>best</it> offer?</vi> <vi>I've had the <it>best</it> time with you! [=I've had a very enjoyable time with you]</vi> <vi>The <it>best</it> [=most valuable] things in life are free.</vi> <vi>Which of these do you think tastes <it>best</it>?</vi> <vi>Mary sends you her very <it>best</it> wishes/regards.</vi> <vi>He's my <phrase>best friend</phrase>. [=my closest/dearest friend] = He and I are <phrase>best friends</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:most skillful, talented, or successful <vi>She's the <it>best</it> student in her class.</vi> <vi>He won the award for <it>best</it> actor in a drama.</vi> <vi>the team's <it>best</it> player</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:most appropriate, useful, or helpful <vi>She truly believes that this is the <it>best</it> way to solve the problem.</vi> <vi>She's the team's <it>best</it> hope/chance for a medal.</vi> <vi>She thought waiting was <it>best</it>. = She thought that the <it>best</it> thing to do was to wait. = She thought that it was <it>best</it> to wait.</vi> <vi>It's <it>best</it> to leave early if you want to be sure of arriving on time.</vi> <vi>We want to do what's <it>best</it> for you.</vi> <vi>He's the <it>best</it> man for the job.</vi> <vi>You should do whatever you think is the <it>best</it> thing to do. = You should do whatever you <phrase>think best</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We're making the <phrase>best possible</phrase> use of these materials.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>best of all</dre> <def><dt><snote>The phrase <it>best of all</it> is often used to refer to the most important or appealing part of something that has many good parts. <vi>The machine is easy to use, easy to clean, and <it>best of all</it>, it's absolutely free when you order these books.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>next best</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person or thing that is <it>next best</it> is not as good as the best person or thing but is better than all others. <vi>The shortstop is the best player on the team, and the catcher is the <it>next best</it> player.</vi> <vi>We can't see each other often, but calling each other on the telephone is <phrase>the next best thing</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your best behavior</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>on your best behavior</it> you are behaving very politely and well. <vi>Remember to be <it>on your best behavior</it> with your grandmother.</vi> <vi>The children promised to be <it>on their best behavior</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <cx><cl>superlative form of</cl> <ct>well</ct></cx> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the best way :in a way that is better than all others <vi>The sauce is <it>best</it> served/eaten/enjoyed cold.</vi> <vi>His cooking is <it>best</it> described as spicy. = It can <it>best</it> be described as spicy.</vi> :with the most success or benefit <vi>They work <it>best</it> under pressure.</vi> <vi>That's what we do <it>best</it>!</vi> <vi>We need to think about how <it>best</it> to fix this problem.</vi> <vi>This is a job <it>best</it> left to the professionals. [=it's better/best to allow professional workers to do this job]</vi> <vi>Some things are <it>best</it> left unsaid. [=it's better/best not to talk about some things]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to the greatest degree or extent :<sx>most</sx> <vi>That's the one we liked (the) <it>best</it>.</vi> <vi>The work should be done by the people who are <it>best</it> able to do it.</vi> <vi>She's <it>best</it> suited to life in the city.</vi> <vi>He is <it>best</it> known for his invention of the lightbulb.</vi> <vi>The museum features some of the <it>best</it>-known examples of this style of painting.</vi> <vi>the industry's <it>best</it>-kept secret</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as best you can</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the best (that) you can</va></vr> <def><dt>:as well, skillfully, or accurately as you can <vi>She answered their questions <it>as best she could</it>. [=as well as she could]</vi> <vi>You don't have to do it perfectly. Just do it <it>the best you can</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>had best</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>had best</it> do something, you should do it. <vi><it>You'd best</it> get ready for school. [=you'd better get ready for school; you should get ready for school]</vi> <vi><it>Had</it>n't you <it>best</it> get ready for school?</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sn>1</sn> <bnote>the best</bnote> <dt>:the best person or thing <vi>Out of all of my workers, he's <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Our company is <it>the best</it> in the business.</vi> <vi>Thanks, Dad. You're <it>the best</it>!</vi> <vi>I have one more gift for you, and I saved <it>the best</it> for last.</vi> :the best group of people or things <vi>Our store sells nothing but <it>the best</it>. = We sell only <it>the best</it>. [=the best products]</vi> <vi>She's one of <it>the best</it> in the world. = She's among <it>the best</it>.</vi> <vi>Bad things happen to <it>the best</it> of us.</vi> <vi>They want <it>the best</it> for their children.</vi> <vi>Even in <it>the best</it> of times, we had trouble paying our bills.</vi> <vi>In <it>the best</it> of all possible worlds, no one would be without food and clean water.</vi> <vi>He can compete <phrase>with the best of them</phrase>. [=he can compete as well as anyone]</vi> <vi>We were <phrase>the best of friends</phrase>. [=we were very good friends]</vi> <vi>I have a wonderful family and a great job, so I feel that I have <phrase>the best of both worlds</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Problems can occur even in/under <phrase>the best of circumstances</phrase>. [=even if the situation is as good as possible]</vi> <vi>All of the students are good, but these three are <phrase>the best of the bunch</phrase>. [=the best ones in the group]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>sunday best</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:someone's or something's most effective, capable, or successful condition <un>used in phrases like <phrase>at your best</phrase> and <phrase>at its best</phrase> <vi>He's <it>at his best</it> in front of a live audience.</vi> <vi>She's <it>at her best</it> in the morning.</vi> <vi>This is democracy <it>at its best</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the highest level that you can do or achieve <vi>Was that your <it>best</it>? = Was that the <it>best</it> you could do?</vi> <vi>No one expects you to do the job perfectly. Just <phrase>do your best</phrase>. = Just <phrase>do the best you can</phrase>. [=do as well as you can]</vi> <vi>He <it>did his best</it> to help them.</vi> <vi>Her time in the race was a <phrase>personal best</phrase>. [=it was the fastest time she had ever achieved]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) for the best</dre> <def><dt>:having or producing a better result <un>used to say that something will have a good result even though it was not the intended result <vi>I won't be able to go, but maybe it'<it>s all for the best</it>. I have a lot of work to do anyway.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(all) the best</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you wish someone <it>(all) the best</it>, you hope that person will be happy and successful. <vi>We wish you <it>all the best</it> in your new job.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at best</dre> <def><dt><un>used to refer to a result, condition, etc., that is the best one possible even though it is not very good <vi>The company won't make a profit this year. <it>At best</it>, they'll break even.</vi> <vi>The work won't be finished for another three months <it>at best</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>best of luck</dre> <dx>see <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>best (out) of three (five, seven, etc.)</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that the winner of a series of games will be the one who has won the most times after three (five, seven, etc.) games have been played</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring out the best in</dre> <def><dt><snote>If someone or something <it>brings out the best in you</it>, that person or thing helps you to use or show your best qualities. <vi>She seems to <it>bring out the best in him</it>.</vi> <vi>Performing in front of an audience <it>brings out the best in me</it>. [=I perform better when I am in front of an audience]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feel your best</dre> <def><dt>:to feel very healthy <vi>Exercise helps you look and <it>feel your best</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm not <it>feeling my best</it> this morning. [=I'm not feeling very well this morning]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get the best of</dre> <def><dt><snote>If an emotion or feeling <it>gets the best of you</it>, it causes you to do something that you should not do or that you are trying not to do. <vi>I did get a little carried away. I guess the excitement <it>got the best of me</it>. [=<it>got the better of me</it>]</vi> <vi>Their emotions have <it>gotten the best of them</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know best</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>know what's best</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>look your best</dre> <def><dt>:to look very good :to look as attractive and pleasant as possible <vi>Try to <it>look your best</it> when interviewing for a job.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make the best of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (something) in an effective way <vi>We may not get another chance, so we need to <it>make the best of</it> this opportunity.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to deal with (a bad situation) as well as possible <vi>Life is not very good right now—but let's try to <phrase>make the best of it</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We're trying to <phrase>make the best (out) of a bad situation</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) We're trying to <phrase>make the best of a bad job</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the best is yet to come/be</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that good things have happened but that even better things will happen in the future <vi>Life is good now, but <it>the best is yet to come</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of my knowledge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knowledge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your ability</dre> <def><dt>:as well as you are able to <vi>Every game, we go out and play <it>to the best of our ability</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the best of your belief</dre> <dx>see <dxt>belief</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best[4]"> <hw hindex="4">best</hw> <altpr>ˈbɛst</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bests</if></in> <in><if>best*ed</if></in> <in><if>best*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to do better than (someone or something) :to defeat or outdo (someone or something) <vi>They were <it>bested</it> [=<it>beaten</it>] by their opponents in the opening game.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="good[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">good</hw> <sound><wav>good0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgʊd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bet*ter</if> <sound><wav>bettor01.wav</wav><wav>good0002.wav</wav><wav>better01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛtɚ</pr></in> <in><if>best</if> <sound><wav>good0003.wav</wav><wav>best0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛst</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:of high quality <vi>The food was <it>good</it>. = It was <it>good</it> food.</vi> <vi>You'll need <it>better</it> tools for this job.</vi> <vi>The car is in <it>good</it> condition/shape.</vi> <vi>There are some <it>good</it> restaurants in this neighborhood.</vi> <vi>That was a <it>good</it> game. [=the game was exciting, people played well, etc.]</vi> <vi>I'm afraid your work is just not <it>good</it> enough.</vi> <vi>Keep up the <it>good</it> work.</vi> <vi>“Would you hire her again?” “Yes, I would. She <phrase>does good work</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>His most recent movie is <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=it is boring, poorly made, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of somewhat high but not excellent quality <vi>The food was <it>good</it> but not great.</vi> <vi>He has done <it>good</it> but not outstanding work.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:correct or proper <vi><it>good</it> manners</vi> <vi><it>good</it> grammar</vi> <vi>She speaks very <it>good</it> English. [=she uses correct pronunciation, grammar, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:pleasant, pleasing, or enjoyable <vi>Did you have a <it>good</it> time at the party?</vi> <vi>We're expecting <it>good</it> weather for the weekend.</vi> <vi>The soup tastes/smells <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>food that is <it>good</it> to eat</vi> <vi>It feels <it>good</it> to sit down after so much walking.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> feeling to know that we were able to help.</vi> <vi><it>good</it> [=<it>happy</it>] memories</vi> <vi>I want to make a <it>good</it> [=<it>favorable</it>] impression on my future in-laws.</vi> <vi>his rugged <it>good</it> looks [=attractive appearance]</vi> <vi>You look <it>good</it> in that dress. = That dress looks <it>good</it> on you.</vi> <vi>You don't look so <it>good</it>. [=you look like you feel sick] Do you feel okay?</vi> <vi><phrase>Have a good day</phrase>! = (<it>US, informal</it>) <phrase>Have a good one</phrase>! [=I hope you have an enjoyable day]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good life</dxt> <dxt>good-looking</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not having, marked by, or relating to problems, troubles, etc. <vi><it>good</it> and bad news</vi> <vi>They've been together in <it>good</it> times and bad.</vi> <vi>I had a <it>good</it> feeling about the meeting.</vi> <vi>Things are looking pretty <it>good</it> for the company right now.</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> omen</vi> <vi>I had the <it>good</it> luck/fortune to meet her when I was in New York.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>good luck</tag> at <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:adequate or suitable <vi>It's a <it>good</it> day for a sail.</vi> <vi>We need to have a meeting. Is tomorrow <it>good</it> [=<it>convenient</it>] for you?</vi> <vi>He's a <it>good</it> person to contact if you're ever in trouble.</vi> <vi>I need tires that are <it>good</it> (for driving) in snow.</vi> <vi>These tires aren't <phrase>any good</phrase>. = These tires are <phrase>no good</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:sensible or reasonable <vi>She has a very <it>good</it> reason for being angry.</vi> <vi>He showed <it>good</it> judgment in buying a small car.</vi> <vi>She gave us some <it>good</it> advice.</vi> <vi>That's a very <it>good</it> question/point.</vi> <vi>She had the <it>good</it> sense to ask for help. [=she showed that she is able to think in a reasonable way by asking for help]</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> idea to arrive early.</vi> <vi>“We'd better arrive early.” “<it>Good</it> idea/thinking.”</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:producing or likely to produce a pleasant or favorable result <vi>a <it>good</it> deal/plan</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> risk/investment</vi> <vi>a lot of <it>good</it> marketing ideas</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> time to be investing in the stock market.</vi> <vi>Please accept our <it>best</it> wishes for your success.</vi> <vi>“The plane arrived on time.” “That's <it>good</it>.”</vi> <vi>Nothing <it>good</it> came of our efforts.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> thing (that) you answered so quickly. = It was <it>good</it> that you answered so quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:having a desired quality <vi>We paid a <it>good</it> price [=a low price] for the tickets.</vi> <vi>The painting should fetch/bring a <it>good</it> price [=a high price] when it's sold.</vi> <vi>Did you get <it>good</it> [=<it>high</it>] grades in school?</vi> <vi>We found a <it>good</it> parking space near the restaurant.</vi> <vi>She has <it>good</it> taste in clothes. [=she likes clothes that are fashionable, of high quality, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:expressing approval or praise <vi>a movie that has been getting <it>good</it> reviews</vi> <vi>I've heard a lot of <it>good</it> things about you.</vi></dt> <sn>h</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a response <vi>“I'm ready to go when you are.” “<it>Good</it>. Let's get going.”</vi> <vi>“I passed the exam!” “(Very) <it>Good</it>!”</vi> <vi>“I passed the exam!” “<phrase>Good for you</phrase>!” = (<it>chiefly Australia</it>) “<phrase>Good on you</phrase>!” [=well done]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not marked or affected by injury or disease :<sx>healthy</sx> <vi>I went home early because I wasn't feeling too/very <it>good</it>. [=I wasn't feeling well; I was feeling sick]</vi> <vi>Her health is pretty <it>good</it>. = She's in pretty <it>good</it> health.</vi> <vi>The patient was reported to be in <it>good</it> condition following surgery.</vi> <vi>His hearing is still <it>good</it> but his eyesight is pretty poor/bad.</vi> <vi>my <it>good</it> arm/leg [=the arm/leg that is not injured or weak]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not causing harm or trouble :causing something desired <vi>a <it>good</it> [=<it>healthy, healthful</it>] diet</vi> <vi><it>good</it> nutrition</vi> <vi>You've been a <it>good</it> influence on the kids.</vi> <vi><it>good</it> habits</vi> <vi><phrase>good cholesterol</phrase> [=a type of cholesterol that helps prevent a disease that stops your blood from flowing easily]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Regular exercise is <it>good for</it> you. [=regular exercise makes you healthier]</vi> <vi>Hot soup is <it>good for</it> a cold. [=hot soup makes you feel better when you have a cold]</vi> <vi>Being with friends is especially <it>good for</it> him right now.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:not morally bad or wrong :morally proper or correct <vi>a <it>good</it> person</vi> <vi><it>good</it> conduct/behavior</vi> <vi>a woman/man of <it>good</it> character</vi> <vi>Like most people, she has a <it>good</it> side and a bad side.</vi> <vi>My intentions were <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>You did a <it>good</it> thing/deed when you helped that stranger.</vi> <vi>He lived a <it>good</it> life.</vi> <vi>It's hard to tell the <phrase>good guys</phrase> [=morally correct people/characters] from the bad guys in this movie.</vi> <vi>She is admired for her many <phrase>good works</phrase>. [=for the many things she does to help poor people, sick people, etc.]</vi> <vi>You should stay away from that guy. He's <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=he's a bad person]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good life</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:kind or helpful <vi>You've always been so <it>good</it> to me.</vi> <vi>It was <it>good</it> of you to answer my request so quickly.</vi> <un>sometimes used to formally make a request <vi><phrase>Would you be good enough</phrase> to show me the way? = <phrase>Would you be so good</phrase> as to show me the way? [=would you please show me the way?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:behaving properly :not causing trouble <vi>a <it>good</it> dog</vi> <vi>The children were very <it>good</it> today.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:having or showing talent or skill :doing or able to do something well <vi>She's a very <it>good</it> golfer.</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> musician/doctor/cook</vi> <vi>He was really <it>good</it> in his last movie. [=he acted very well]</vi> <vi>I don't know if I'm <it>good</it> enough to make the team.</vi> <vi>I have a <it>good</it> memory. [=I am good at remembering things]</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> sense of direction [=an ability to find your way easily in a new place]</vi> <vi>an agent with a <phrase>good eye</phrase> for new talent [=an agent who is good at finding talented people who are not yet known or famous]</vi> <vi>It's a great school where you know your kids are <phrase>in good hands</phrase>. [=with people who are able to teach and take care of them well]</vi> <vi>I'm confident the café will be <it>in good hands</it> with you in charge.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>She's very <it>good at</it> (playing) golf.</vi> <vi>He's not very/any <it>good at</it> expressing his feelings. = He's <phrase>no good at</phrase> expressing his feelings.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in a joking way <vi>I'm very/really <it>good at</it> saying the wrong thing. [=I often say things that make people uncomfortable, unhappy, etc.]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>no good</tag>, <tag>not any good</tag> at <dxt>good</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:able to use something or to deal with something or someone well <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>He's very <it>good with</it> his hands. [=he can easily make/do things with his hands]</vi> <vi>She's <it>good with</it> children. [=she manages and interacts with children well; children like her and behave well when they are with her]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a tendency to do something <un>+ <it>about</it> <vi>He's <it>good about</it> writing everything down. [=he usually writes everything down]</vi> <vi>I'm trying to be <it>better about</it> exercising. [=I'm trying to exercise more often]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:happy or pleased <vi>I <phrase>feel good</phrase> about what happened. [=I'm pleased by what happened]</vi> <vi>She <it>felt good</it> that she had remembered his birthday. = She <it>felt good</it> about remembering his birthday.</vi> <vi>Helping other people makes me <it>feel good</it>.</vi> <vi>She didn't <it>feel good</it> about having to fire her secretary.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:cheerful or calm <vi>She's in a <it>good</it> mood. [=a happy mood]</vi> <vi>He has a <it>good</it> temper. [=he is good-tempered; he doesn't become angry easily]</vi> <vi>Everyone was in <it>good</it> spirits.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how long something will continue or be valid <vi>This offer is <it>good</it> only until the end of the month.</vi> <vi>This offer is <phrase>good for</phrase> the remainder of the month.</vi> <vi>Our old car should be <it>good for</it> a few more years. [=it should last a few more years; it should continue to operate for a few more years]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:still suitable to eat or drink :not spoiled <vi>Is the milk still <it>good</it> or has it gone bad?</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>good heavens</phrase> and <phrase>good God</phrase> to express surprise or anger or to make a statement or question more forceful <vi><it>Good heavens</it>! You startled me!</vi> <vi>“Do you agree with him?” “<it>Good God</it>, no!”</vi> <vi>(<it>somewhat old-fashioned</it>) <it>Good gracious</it>, I completely forgot!</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>good grief</tag> at <dxt>grief</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:causing laughter :<sx>funny</sx> <vi>I heard a <it>good</it> joke the other day.</vi> <vi>“He says he's never met her.” “That's a <it>good</it> one. [=that's amusing because it isn't true] I saw them together last week.”</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>good for a laugh</phrase>. [=she is always funny]</vi></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt>:large in size, amount, or quantity <vi>The store has a <it>good</it> selection of products.</vi> <vi>She won the election by a <it>good</it> [=<it>considerable</it>] margin.</vi> <vi>He makes <it>good</it> money as a lawyer. = He makes a <it>good</it> living as a lawyer. [=he earns a lot of money]</vi> <vi>They couldn't have succeeded without <phrase>a good deal of</phrase> luck. [=a lot of luck]</vi> <vi>Things could be <phrase>a good deal</phrase> worse. [=things could be much worse]</vi> <vi>Tourists have been coming to the area <phrase>in good numbers</phrase>. [=many tourists have been coming to the area]</vi> <vi>an actress who has appeared in <phrase>a good number of</phrase> films [=in many films]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not less or fewer than a particular amount :at least <un>used in the phrase <phrase>a good</phrase> <vi>He weighs <it>a good</it> 200 pounds.</vi> <vi>We waited <it>a good</it> hour. [=we waited at least an hour]</vi> <vi>There are <it>a good</it> 80 people here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:forceful or thorough <vi>If you give the machine a <it>good</it> kick, it might start working again.</vi> <vi>Give the bottle a <it>good</it> shake before you open it.</vi> <vi>Take a <it>good</it> look at this.</vi> <vi>You just need (to get) a <it>good</it> night's sleep.</vi> <vi>We were scared when it happened, but we had a <it>good</it> laugh about it later.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:having a high social position or status <vi>He comes from a <it>good</it> family.</vi> <vi>She thinks her son is too <it>good</it> for me.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> neighborhood.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe people who know each other well and care about each other very much <vi>She's a <it>good</it> [=<it>close</it>] friend of mine. = She and I are <it>good</it> friends.</vi> <vi>my <it>good</it> friend/pal/buddy Joe</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:showing true and constant support for someone <vi>He's been a <it>good</it> friend to me.</vi> <vi>I'm trying to be a <it>better</it> sister.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:belonging to and having loyalty to a group or organization <vi>a <it>good</it> party member</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> Catholic</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a serve or shot</ssl> <dt>:landing in the proper area of the court in tennis and similar games <vi>I thought the ball/serve was <it>good</it> but my opponent said it was out.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a shot or kick</ssl> <dt>:successfully done <vi>(<it>basketball</it>) The first foul shot was <it>good</it>, but he missed the second one.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The field goal was <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The field goal was <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=the field goal was missed]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:not wanting or needing anything more <vi>“Would you like more coffee?” “No, thanks. I'm <it>good</it>.”</vi> <vi>“Here's the money I owed you. So we're <it>good</it> now, right?” “Yeah, we're <it>good</it>.” [=we have settled our business; there is no longer any problem between us]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all in good time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all well and good</dre> <dx>see <dxt>well</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as good as</dre> <def><dt>:almost or nearly <vi>The plan is <it>as good as</it> dead.</vi> <vi>Those people <it>as good as</it> ruined the school with their foolish ideas!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(as) good as gold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as good as it gets</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that nothing better is possible or available <vi>It's not a great restaurant, but in this part of the city, it's <it>as good as it gets</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is very good and cannot be improved <vi>There's nothing I enjoy more than spending time at home with my family. That's <it>as good as it gets</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as good as new</dre> <dx>see <dxt>new</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fight the good fight</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for good measure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>measure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give as good as you get</dre> <dx>see <dxt>give</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good and</dre> <sound><wav>good0005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌgʊdn̩</pr> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <vi>I hit him <it>good and</it> hard.</vi> <vi>He was <it>good and</it> angry.</vi> <vi>I like my coffee <it>good and</it> hot.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:completely or entirely <vi>We'll leave when I'm <it>good and</it> ready.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good egg</dre> <dx>see <dxt>egg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good for</dre> <def><sl>somewhat informal</sl> <dt>:able to provide or produce (something) <vi>I'm <it>good for</it> a hundred dollars if you need a loan.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good <dxn>4b, 8a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good for it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:able to pay back a loan <vi>Why won't you lend me the money? You know I'm <it>good for it</it>. [=you can trust me to pay it back]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good graces</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good old</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used before a noun to describe a familiar person or thing with affection or approval <vi><it>Good old</it> John: you can always count on him to help.</vi> <vi>I don't need fancy shoes. I prefer <it>good old</it> sneakers.</vi> <vi>They were talking about <phrase>the good old days</phrase>. [=happy times in the past]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>good old boy</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good riddance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>riddance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good to go</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:ready to leave or to start doing something <vi>We have all the tools and supplies we need, so we're <it>good to go</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good word</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have it good</dre> <def><dt>:to be in a favorable position or situation <vi>There's no reason for her to be so unhappy. She really <it>has it</it> (pretty) <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>never had it so good</phrase>. [=he has never been in such a favorable situation]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have the good grace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold good</dre> <def><dt>:to be true <vi>The advice she gave us 10 years ago still <it>holds good</it> [=(more commonly) <it>holds true</it>] today.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you know what's good for you</dre> <def><dt>:if you want to avoid trouble, problems, etc. <vi>You'll take my advice <it>if you know what's good for you</it>.</vi> <vi>She'll forget about the whole thing <it>if she knows what's good for her</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in good company</dre> <dx>see <dxt>company</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in good part</dre> <dx>see <dxt>part</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make good</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become successful <vi>It's a story about a kid from a small town trying to <it>make good</it> in the big city.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>make good your escape</phrase>, you escape successfully. <vi>The prisoners dug a tunnel under the fence and <it>made good their escape</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do something that you have promised or threatened to do <vi>He <it>made good</it> his promise.</vi> <un>usually + <it>on</it> in U.S. English <vi>He <it>made good on</it> his promise.</vi> <vi>They <it>made good on</it> their threat and forced the company to go out of business.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to pay for (something) <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>The insurance company was required to <it>make good on</it> the loss.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to repair (something) <vi>The contract obliges you to <it>make good</it> any damaged windows.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>so far, so good</dre> <dx>see <dxt>far</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>too good to be true</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something cannot be as good as it seems to be <vi>The price of the car is <it>too good to be true</it>. There must be something wrong with it.</vi> <vi>If it looks/seems <it>too good to be true</it>, it probably is. [=there is probably some cost or bad part you do not know about]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>very good</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt><un>used as a response to say you will do something that you have been told or asked to do <vi>“Show the ambassador in.” “<it>Very good</it>, sir.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what's good for the goose is good for the gander</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with (a) good grace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="good[3]"> <hw hindex="3">good</hw> <altpr>ˈgʊd</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:<sx>well <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <vi>Things have been going <it>good</it> lately.</vi> <vi>The team is doing <it>good</it> this year.</vi> <vi>“How did you hit the ball today?” “<it>Good</it>.”</vi> <snote>The use of <it>good</it> to mean “well” is considered wrong by many people. It occurs mainly in very informal speech.</snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:completely and thoroughly <vi>The other team whipped us <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>That was a funny joke you played on him. You really <phrase>got him good</phrase>. [=he was completely fooled by the joke]</vi> <vi>“They sure soaked you with that bucket of water.” “Yeah, they really <it>got me good</it>.” [=I got completely soaked with water]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Clean it up <phrase>good and proper</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis before words like <it>long</it> and <it>many</it> <vi>I haven't seen her for <phrase>a good long</phrase> time. [=a very long time]</vi> <vi>There were <phrase>a good many</phrase> people [=a lot of people] at the meeting.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) Not all our students go on to university, but <phrase>a good few</phrase> [=<it>quite a few</it>] of them do.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="well[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">well</hw> <sound><wav>well0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɛl</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>bet*ter</if> <sound><wav>bettor01.wav</wav><wav>good0002.wav</wav><wav>better01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛtɚ</pr></in> <in><if>best</if> <sound><wav>good0003.wav</wav><wav>best0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛst</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in a successful way <vi>“How did everything go?” “It went <it>well</it>, thank you.”</vi> <vi>The plan worked <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>She works <it>well</it> under pressure.</vi> <vi>I did surprisingly <it>well</it> on my history test.</vi> <vi>The company is doing <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>He has his own business and is <phrase>doing well for</phrase> himself.</vi> <vi>You got a perfect score! <phrase>Well done</phrase>!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>do well</tag> at <dxt>do</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in a skillful way <vi>She sings and plays the guitar quite <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>The essay is <it>well</it> written.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:in a good, proper, or positive way <vi>He doesn't smoke or drink, and he eats <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>She doesn't treat her boyfriend very <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>Did he take the news <it>well</it>? [=did he respond to the news in a positive way?]</vi> <vi>The decision did not <phrase>sit well with</phrase> him. [=he was not happy about the decision]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:in a kind, friendly, or generous way <vi>The novel was <it>well</it> received by the critics.</vi> <vi>They always speak <it>well</it> of you.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>wish her well</phrase>. [=I hope she does well; I hope that she succeeds]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>means well</phrase> [=he has good intentions], but he's not really helping anyone.</vi> <vi>The company <phrase>did well by</phrase> me when I retired. [=the company treated me well when I retired]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:completely or fully <vi>We are <it>well</it> aware of the problem.</vi> <vi>The food at the restaurant is <it>well</it> worth the trip.</vi> <vi>Their kitchen is <it>well</it> equipped.</vi> <vi>Your promotion is <it>well</it> deserved.</vi> <vi>The plane was <it>well</it> out of sight.</vi> <vi>I can understand your dilemma very <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>She knows the area quite <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>I knew him <it>well</it> when we were in high school together.</vi> <vi>I remember her <phrase>well enough</phrase>. = I remember her <phrase>fairly well</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to a great degree or extent <vi>The group has sold <it>well</it> over a million albums.</vi> <vi>The temperature will be <it>well</it> [=<it>far</it>] above average today. It will be <it>well</it> into the nineties.</vi> <vi>He is <it>well</it> on his way to becoming a superstar.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>well</it> into the book and should finish it soon.</vi> <vi>She walked <it>well</it> ahead of the group.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis to say that something is or is not proper, appropriate, etc. <vi>She's angry, and <it>well</it> she should be. [=she has a good reason to be angry]</vi></un> <un>usually used with <it>can, could, may</it>, or <it>might</it> <vi>I <it>cannot</it> very <it>well</it> refuse the invitation. [=it would be improper for me to refuse the invitation]</vi> <vi>I <it>couldn't</it> very <it>well</it> just walk right in!</vi> <vi>And what, one <it>might/may well</it> ask, makes this computer system worth its high price?</vi> <vi>The decision <it>may well</it> be questioned.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very possibly <un>usually used with <it>could, may</it>, or <it>might</it> <vi>You <it>could</it> very <it>well</it> be right. [=it is very possible that you are right]</vi> <vi>The concert <it>may well</it> be sold-out. [=it is possible/likely that the concert is sold-out]</vi> <vi>It <it>may well</it> be true.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:without doubt or question <vi>They can <it>well</it> afford to be generous.</vi> <vi>As you <phrase>well know</phrase>, I don't approve of this. = As you know very <it>well</it>, I don't approve of this.</vi> <vi>You know <phrase>perfectly well</phrase> how to do it.</vi> <vi>Their relationship is <phrase>well and truly</phrase> over.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>live well</phrase> is to live in the comfortable and enjoyable way of people who have a lot of money, possessions, etc. <vi>He made a lot of money in real estate and was able to <it>live</it> very <it>well</it> after his retirement.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>marry well</phrase> is to marry someone who has high social status, wealth, etc. <vi>Their son/daughter married <it>well</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>as well</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>as well (as)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:in addition to someone or something else <vi>You bought a new car? I bought one <it>as well</it>. [=<it>also, too</it>]</vi> <vi>He is loyal, and brave <it>as well</it>. = He is brave <it>as well as</it> loyal. [=he is brave and also loyal]</vi> <vi>The coach, <it>as well as</it> the team, is ready.</vi> <vi>She is good at softball <it>as well as</it> basketball.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>might as well</phrase> and <phrase>may as well</phrase> to say that something should be done or accepted because it cannot be avoided or because there is no good reason not to do it <vi>You <it>might as well</it> tell them the truth.</vi> <vi>We <it>may as well</it> begin now.</vi> <vi>They're not going to change their decision, so you <it>might (just) as well</it> get used to it.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) “Should we start now?” “<it>Might as well</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something else could have been done with the same result <vi>The party was so dull that I <it>might (just) as well</it> have stayed home.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:in the same way <vi><phrase>You know as well as I do</phrase> [=you and I both know] that we can't afford that car.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="well[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">well</hw> <altpr>ˈwɛl</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>better</if></in> <in><if>best</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in good health :<sx>healthy</sx> <vi>The children are <it>well</it> again.</vi> <vi>He is not <it>well</it>. = He is not a <it>well</it> man.</vi> <vi>I don't feel very <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>You don't look so <it>well</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope you <phrase>get well soon</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:in a good or satisfactory state <vi>I hope all is <it>well</it> with you and your family.</vi> <vi>We almost didn't make it here, but <phrase>all's well that ends well</phrase>. [=we can forget about how unpleasant or difficult it was because everything ended in a good way]</vi> <vi>I should have <phrase>left/let well (enough) alone</phrase> [=I should not have tried to make the situation better], but instead I tried to help and only made things worse.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:wise, sensible, or reasonable <vi>It might be <it>well</it> [=it might be a good idea] for you to leave now.</vi> <vi>It would be <phrase>as well</phrase> for you to get some rest. [=you should get some rest]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>alive and well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alive</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all very well</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>all well and good</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that something may seem proper, good, or reasonable by itself but that there are other things that also have to be considered <vi><phrase>It's all very well</phrase> your telling me to take it easy, but I have a deadline to meet!</vi> <vi>They say we have to improve our schools. <phrase>That's all very well</phrase>, but the question is, how can we find the money to do it?</vi> <vi>It is <it>all well and good</it> that you have been enjoying yourself, but you have to start saving your money.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>just as well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>just</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>very well</dre> <dx>see <dxt>very</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="best man"> <hw>best man</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:the most important male friend or relative who helps a groom at his wedding <vi>The groom asked his brother to be his <it>best man</it> and the bride asked her sister to be her maid of honor.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="best seller"> <hw>best seller</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a popular product (such as a book) that many people have bought <vi>She has written several <it>best sellers</it>.</vi> <vi>Her book is on the <it>best-seller</it> list.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>best–sell*ing</ure> <sound><wav>bests03w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛstˈsɛlɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>his <it>best-selling</it> novel</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
