<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bid[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bid</hw> <sound><wav>bid00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bids</if></in> <in><if>bade</if> <sound><wav>bid00003.wav</wav><wav>bid00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæd, ˈbeɪd</pr> <il>or</il> <if>bid</if></in> <in><if>bid*den</if> <sound><wav>bid00004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪdn̩</pr> <il>or</il> <if>bid</if></in> <in><if>bid*ding</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sin><il>past tense and past participle</il> <if>bid</if></sin> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to offer to pay (a particular amount of money) for something that is being sold :to make a bid at an auction <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll <it>bid</it> $100 for/on the lamp but no higher.</vi> <vi>The auctioneer said, “What am I <it>bid</it> [=<it>offered</it>] <it>for</it> this lamp?”</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He plans to stop <it>bidding</it> if the bids go over $500.</vi> <vi>She <it>bid</it> for/on a desk and a chair.</vi> <vi>The two brothers <it>bid against</it> each other for the same chair. [=they each tried to buy the chair by repeatedly making higher bids than the other one had made]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to offer to do work for a particular price <vi>Several local companies are <it>bidding</it> for the same job.</vi> <vi>His company <it>bid</it> on the snow removal contract.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sin><il>past tense and past participle</il> <if>bid</if></sin> <dt>:to say how many points you are trying to win in a card game <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bid</it> two.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bid</it> and I passed.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to order or command (someone) to do something <vi>We did as we were <it>bid/bidden</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>bid/bade</it> them enter. [=told them to come in]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>unbidden</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to express (greetings or good wishes) to (someone) :to say (something, such as “good morning,” “good evening, etc.”) to (someone) <vi>They <it>bade</it> me farewell. = They <it>bade</it> farewell to me. [=they said goodbye to me]</vi> <vi>She <it>bid</it> him good day.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bid fair</dre> <def><dt>:to seem likely <vi>a movie that <it>bids fair</it> to become a big hit [=a movie that will probably be very successful]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bid up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bid up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bid (something) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to raise the price of (something that is being sold) by repeatedly offering more money than other people <vi>Several antique dealers <it>bid up</it> the best lots to shut out less experienced bidders.</vi> <vi>Investors quickly <it>bid</it> stock prices <it>up</it> to record levels.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bid*der</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bid*ders</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>Items will be sold to the highest <it>bidder</it>. [=to the person who offers to pay the most]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bid[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bid</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bids</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:an offer to pay a particular amount of money for something <vi><it>Bids</it> for the painter's work have been quite high at recent auctions.</vi> <vi>She had the highest <it>bid</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made a bid</phrase> of $100 for the painting.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> the opening <it>bid</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an offer to do a job for a particular price <vi>The company is accepting <it>bids</it> for the renovation project.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an attempt to win, get, or do something <vi>The company is facing a <phrase>takeover bid</phrase>. [=someone is trying to gain control of the company by buying most of its stock]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Two convicts made a dramatic <it>bid for</it> freedom but were soon recaptured.</vi> <vi>They made a strong <it>bid for</it> the championship.</vi> <vi>a <it>bid for</it> power/reelection</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>They failed in their <it>bid to close</it> the school.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a statement of how many points a player is trying to win in a card game</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bade"> <hw>bade</hw> <cx><cl>past tense of</cl> <ct>bid</ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="fair[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fair</hw> <sound><wav>fair0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfeɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>fair*er</if></in> <in><if>fair*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:agreeing with what is thought to be right or acceptable <vi>We received <it>fair</it> treatment.</vi> <vi><it>fair</it> elections</vi> <vi>a <it>fair</it> fight</vi> <vi>a <it>fair</it> bargain/deal/trade</vi> <vi>I'm just trying to get a <it>fair</it> price for the house. [=I'm not trying to get more money for the house than most people think is right]</vi> <vi>That's a <it>fair</it> question, and it deserves an honest reply.</vi> <vi>The workers claim that they are not being paid <phrase>fair wages</phrase>. [=they are being paid less than they should be paid]</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>only fair</phrase> [=it is the right thing] to tell him the truth.</vi> <vi>I washed the dishes yesterday, so it's <it>only fair</it> (that) you to do them today.</vi> <vi>He gets his <phrase>fair share</phrase> of attention too. [=he gets a reasonable amount of attention]</vi> <vi>She's had more than her <it>fair share</it> of trouble. [=she has had a lot of trouble]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:treating people in a way that does not favor some over others <vi>He is known as a very <it>fair</it> man.</vi> <vi>I try to be <it>fair</it> to/with my children.</vi> <vi>He claims that the competition wasn't <it>fair</it>.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>fair</it> that she gets to leave early and I don't.</vi> <vi>Sometimes life isn't <it>fair</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>fair</it> and impartial jury</vi> <vi>a bargain/deal/trade that is <it>fair</it> to/for everyone</vi> <vi>All she wants is a <phrase>fair chance</phrase>. [=the same chance everyone else gets]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not too harsh or critical <vi>“What a bad movie!” “<phrase>Be fair</phrase>! Parts of it are actually pretty funny.”</vi> <vi>I can't say I liked the movie, but, <phrase>to be fair</phrase>, parts of it are pretty funny.</vi> <vi>She did poorly on the test, but, <it>to be fair</it>, so did a lot of other people.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not very good or very bad :of average or acceptable quality <vi>Her work has been <it>fair</it> to good.</vi> <vi>The quality of her work has been only <it>fair</it>.</vi> <vi>I think our waiter did a <it>fair</it> job.</vi> <vi>The patient has been upgraded from serious to <it>fair</it> condition.</vi> <vi>The food was <phrase>fair to middling</phrase>. [=just average; not especially good]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>approving</ssl> <dt>:reasonably good :good although usually not excellent <vi>The team has a <it>fair</it> [=<it>pretty good</it>] chance of winning the championship this year.</vi> <vi>He does a pretty <it>fair</it> [=<it>good</it>] imitation of the President.</vi> <vi>He was able to give us a <it>fair</it> idea of the problems involved.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>fair</it> bet that the weather will improve soon.</vi> <vi>“I'm guessing that he's about 50 years old.” “That's a <it>fair</it> guess, but he's actually almost 60.”</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:reasonably large <un>used to describe an amount or size that is not small although it is also not extremely large <vi>There were a <it>fair</it> number of new participants at the convention.</vi> <vi>Researchers now know a <it>fair</it> amount about the earliest humans.</vi> <vi>He lives a <it>fair</it> distance from here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:not stormy or cloudy <vi><it>fair</it> skies</vi> <vi><it>fair</it> weather</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>of a person's hair, skin, etc.</ssl> <dt>:having a light color <vi><it>fair</it> hair/skin</vi> <vi>a person of <it>fair</it> complexion</vi> <vi>a <it>fair</it>-skinned person</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>dark</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>literary + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:attractive or pleasing to look at <vi>We're happy to welcome you to our <it>fair</it> [=<it>lovely</it>] city.</vi> <vi>a <it>fair</it> maid/maiden</vi> <vi>Who's the <it>fairest</it> of them all?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:in the area between the foul lines <vi>The ball was caught in <it>fair</it> territory.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>fair ball</phrase> is a batted ball that lands in the area between the foul lines.</snote> <dx>compare <dxt>foul</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a fair bit</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a fair shake</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all's fair in love and war</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe a situation in which people do not follow the usual rules of behavior and do things that are normally considered unfair <vi>Sure, it was underhanded to steal his customers, but <it>all's fair in love and war</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bid fair</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fair and square</dre> <def><dt>:in an honest and fair manner <vi>He won the election <it>fair and square</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fair crack of the whip</dre> <dx>see <dxt>crack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fair enough</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is reasonable or fair <vi>“I'll wash the dishes today, and you can wash them tomorrow.” “<it>Fair enough</it>.”</vi> <vi>“He needs more time.” “<it>Fair enough</it>, but we can't wait too much longer.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fair's fair</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something was done or should be done because it is fair <vi><it>Fair's fair</it>: I washed the dishes yesterday, so it's your turn to do them today.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fair to say</dre> <def><dt><snote>A comment that is <it>fair to say</it> is reasonable and is not expected to cause argument. <vi>The key concept in this book, I think it is <it>fair to say</it>, is freedom.</vi> <vi>She's not entirely to blame, but it's (only) <it>fair to say</it> that she handled the situation badly.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fair warning</dre> <def><dt>:enough warning to be able to avoid something bad <vi>I'm giving you <it>fair warning</it> that you had better not discuss politics at dinner tonight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>it's a fair cop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cop</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>fair</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>He claims that his opponent wasn't <phrase>playing fair</phrase>. [=wasn't playing according to the rules]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>fair*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>She questioned the <it>fairness</it> of the decision.</vi> <vi>In the interest of <it>fairness</it>, let's not mention any names.</vi> <vi>She did poorly, but <phrase>in all fairness</phrase> [=to be fair to her], she was tired.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
