<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bill[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bill</hw> <sound><wav>bill0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a document that says how much money you owe for something you have bought or used <vi>He paid the telephone <it>bill</it>.</vi> <vi>Did our water <it>bill</it> arrive yet?</vi> <vi>I've been having a hard time paying the <it>bills</it> since I lost my job. [=paying what I owe for housing, heat, electricity, etc.]</vi> <vi>The waiter gave us our <it>bill</it>.</vi> <vi>I can't pay for it now: just put it on my <it>bill</it>. [=add the amount I now owe to what I already owe and I will pay the total amount later]</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>bill of sale</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a written description of a new law that is being suggested and that the lawmakers of a country, state, etc., must vote to accept before it becomes law <vi>They will introduce an antismoking <it>bill</it> in Congress.</vi> <vi>The Senate passed/rejected the <it>bill</it>.</vi> <vi>How does a <it>bill</it> become a law?</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:such a bill after it has become a law <vi>the GI <it>bill</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bill of rights</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a piece of paper money <vi>He handed me a 5-dollar <it>bill</it>.</vi> <vi><it>bills</it> and coins</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>note</cat></ca></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a written or printed advertisement that is used to announce a play, movie, or concert to the public and to list the names of the performers <vi>Who is on the <it>bill</it>? [=who is performing?]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>double bill</phrase> [=a concert that has two parts] featuring two of the world's best jazz trumpeters</vi> <vi>The notice on the wall said “<phrase>Post No Bills</phrase>.” [=do not put any advertisements on the wall]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>fill the bill</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>fit the bill</va></vr> <def><dt>:to be exactly what is needed :to be suitable <vi>If you want to stay near the beach, this hotel will <it>fit the bill</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>foot the bill</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone or something) a clean bill of health</dre> <def><dt>:to officially say that someone is healthy or that something is working correctly <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him <it>a clean bill of health</it>.</vi> <vi>The governor <it>gives</it> the program <it>a clean bill of health</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bill</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bill[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bill</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪl</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bills</if></in> <in><if>billed</if></in> <in><if>bill*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to send a bill to (someone or something) :to provide (a person, business, organization, etc.) with a statement that says how much money is owed for something that has been bought or used <vi>They <it>billed</it> me for the repairs they made to the roof.</vi> <vi>The company was <it>billed</it> for the deliveries.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to describe (someone or something) <it>as</it> a particular thing so that people will like or want that person or thing <un>usually used as <it>(be) billed</it> <vi>The city is <it>being billed</it> [=<it>advertised</it>] <it>as</it> one of the best places to live in the state.</vi> <vi>She <it>was billed as</it> the next big movie star.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>billing</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to officially say that someone is going <it>to do</it> something <un>usually used as <it>(be) billed</it> <vi>Both writers <it>are billed to appear</it> at the conference.</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bill</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bill[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bill</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪl</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a bird's beak <vi>a duck's <it>bill</it></vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>bird</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the part of a cap that sticks out in front :the visor of a hat</dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bill</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bill[4]"> <hw hindex="4">bill</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪl</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bills</if></in> <in><if>billed</if></in> <in><if>billing</if></in> <dro><dre>bill and coo</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to kiss and talk quietly <vi>A young couple sat together in the corner, <it>billing and cooing</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bill</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bill of exchange"> <hw>bill of exchange</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bills of exchange</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>business</sl> <dt>:a document that tells a person or business to pay a particular amount of money to another person or business</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bill of fare"> <hw>bill of fare</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bills of fare</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>somewhat formal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:a list of the things that are served at a restaurant :<sx>menu</sx> <vi>The <it>bill of fare</it> includes several soups.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bill of rights"> <hw>bill of rights</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>Bill of Rights</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a written statement that lists the basic rights of the citizens of a country <vi>Certain freedoms are guaranteed to all Americans by <phrase>the Bill of Rights</phrase>. [=the first 10 amendments to the U.S. Constitution]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bill of sale"> <hw>bill of sale</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bills of sale</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a document saying that something has been sold to a new owner <vi>Do you have the <it>bill of sale</it> for the car?</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="double bill"> <hw>double bill</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:two movies, plays, concerts, etc., that are seen one after the other <dx>compare <dxt>double feature</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="private member's bill"> <hw>private member's bill</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a bill prepared or introduced in the British House of Commons by a private member</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
