<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bitter[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bit*ter</hw> <sound><wav>bitter01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪtɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more bit*ter; most bit*ter</gram> <dt><snote>The form <it>bitterer</it> is almost never used to mean “more bitter,” but the form <it>bitterest</it> is commonly used to mean “most bitter.”</snote></dt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a strong and often unpleasant flavor that is the opposite of sweet <vi>Cocoa beans have a <it>bitter</it> flavor.</vi> <vi>The medicine had a <it>bitter</it> aftertaste.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:causing painful emotions <vi><it>bitter</it> disappointments</vi> <vi>a <it>bitter</it> defeat</vi> :felt or experienced in a strong and unpleasant way <vi>We were struck by the <it>bitter</it> irony of the situation.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>bitter pill</phrase> or <phrase>a bitter pill to swallow</phrase> is something that is difficult or painful to accept. <vi>The defeat was a <it>bitter pill</it> for the team <it>to swallow</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:angry and unhappy because of unfair treatment <vi>His betrayal had made her <it>bitter</it>.</vi> <vi>She was still <it>bitter</it> toward her ex-husband.</vi> <vi>He's the <it>bitterest</it> man I know.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:feeling or showing a lot of hatred or anger <vi><it>bitter</it> enemies</vi> <vi>a <it>bitter</it> argument</vi> <vi>a <it>bitter</it> reply</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:very cold <vi>a <it>bitter</it> wind</vi> <vi><it>bitter</it> cold</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>to/until the bitter end</dre> <def><dt>:until the end of something that may be very bad, unpleasant, etc. <vi>I knew she would stand by me <it>to the bitter end</it>.</vi> <vi>He vowed that he would keep fighting <it>until the bitter end</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bit*ter*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>We were <it>bitterly</it> disappointed.</vi> <vi>He complained <it>bitterly</it> about the crowds.</vi> <vi><it>bitterly</it> cold</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>bit*ter*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bitter[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bitter</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪtɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bitters</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>bit*ters</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:a bitter alcoholic liquid that is used especially in mixed drinks <vi>The cocktail recipe called for a dash of <it>bitters</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a type of beer that has a slightly bitter flavor <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a pint of <it>bitter</it></vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a good selection of <it>bitters</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="end[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">end</hw> <sound><wav>end00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɛnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ends</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a point that marks the limit of something :the point at which something no longer continues to happen or exist <vi>The report is due at/by the <it>end</it> of the month.</vi> <vi>She interviewed several players at the <it>end</it> of the game.</vi> <vi>There is no <it>end</it> [=<it>limit</it>] to their generosity. [=they are extremely generous]</vi> <vi>I'm <phrase>at the end of</phrase> my patience. = I've <phrase>reached the end of</phrase> my patience. [=I can no longer be patient; I have run out of patience]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the last part of a story, movie, song, etc. <vi>I liked most of the book, but I didn't like the <it>end</it>. [=<it>ending</it>]</vi> <vi>He read the book from beginning to <it>end</it> [=he read the entire book] in one day.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the part at the edge or limit of an area <vi>The restaurant is in the north <it>end</it> of the city.</vi> <vi>We biked from one <it>end</it> of the island to the other.</vi> <vi>The house is at the <it>end</it> of the road.</vi> <vi>They live at opposite <it>ends</it> of town.</vi> <vi>He left the car at the far <it>end</it> [=most distant part] of the parking lot.</vi> <vi>the deep/shallow <it>end</it> of a swimming pool</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dead end</dxt> <dxt>rear end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the first or last part or section of something that is long <vi>She drove the <it>end</it> of the stake into the ground.</vi> <vi>The car's front/rear/back <it>end</it> was damaged.</vi> <vi>One <it>end</it> of the rope was tangled.</vi> <vi>Smoke curled off the <it>end</it> of the cigarette.</vi> <vi>The hose is leaking at both <it>ends</it>.</vi> <vi>the pointed <it>end</it> of the knife</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:either limit of a scale or range <vi>The car was in the high/low <it>end</it> of the price range.</vi> <vi>The candidates represent opposite <it>ends</it> of the political spectrum.</vi> <vi>The resort attracts tourists from the upper <it>end</it> of the social scale.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the stopping of a condition, activity, or course of action <vi>The agency's goal is the <it>end</it> of world hunger.</vi> <vi>The treaty marked the <it>end</it> of the war.</vi> <vi>His death marks the <it>end</it> of an era.</vi> <snote>When something is <phrase>at an end</phrase> it is finished or completed. <vi>The battle was <it>at an end</it>. [=<it>over</it>]</vi> <vi>We would like to see this matter <it>at an end</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>bring something to an end</phrase> or <phrase>bring an end to something</phrase>, you stop, finish, or complete it. <vi>She <it>brought</it> the concert <it>to an end</it> with a piano solo.</vi> <vi>Negotiations <it>brought an end to</it> the conflict.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>put an end to something</phrase>, you cause it to stop or prevent it from continuing. <vi>They promise to <it>put an end to</it> unfair policies.</vi> <vi>The new mayor vowed to <it>put an end to</it> the violence.</vi></snote> <snote>Something <phrase>comes to an end</phrase> when it stops or finishes. <vi>After three weeks the strike finally <it>came to an end</it>.</vi> <vi>Summer always seems to <it>come to an end</it> much too quickly.</vi> <vi>The curtain fell as the play <it>came to an end</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If there is <phrase>no end in sight</phrase>, the point at which something will be finished is not known. <vi>There is <it>no end in sight</it> to this heat wave.</vi> <vi>Prices continue to go up with <it>no end in sight</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the point at which someone is no longer living :<sx>death</sx> <vi>He came to a tragic <it>end</it> [=he died] in a freak accident.</vi> <vi>The doctors told her that the <it>end</it> was near. [=that she would die soon]</vi> <un>sometimes used with <it>meet</it> <vi>He <it>met</it> his <it>end</it> [=he died] in the icy water.</vi> <vi>She <it>met</it> an untimely <it>end</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a goal or purpose <vi>Our ultimate <it>end</it> [=<it>aim</it>] in sponsoring the event is to raise money for charity.</vi> <vi>corrupt leaders who use their power for their own <it>ends</it></vi> <vi>There are several ways to achieve/accomplish the same <it>end</it>.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>an end in itself</phrase>, it is something that you do because you want to and not because it will help you achieve or accomplish something else. <vi>She started exercising for her health, but she enjoyed it so much that exercising became <it>an end in itself</it>.</vi> <vi>For him, taking classes was <it>an end in itself</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If <phrase>the end justifies the means</phrase>, a desired result is so good or important that any method, even a morally bad one, may be used to achieve it. <vi>They believe that <it>the end justifies the means</it> and will do anything to get their candidate elected.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:a player whose position is at the end of the line of scrimmage <dx>see also <dxt>end run</dxt> <dxt>split ends</dxt> <dxt>tight end</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a specific part of a project, activity, etc. <vi>She is in the creative <it>end</it> of the business.</vi> <vi>It's important to know what's going on in all <it>ends</it> of a business.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:the part of a project, activity, etc., that you are responsible for <vi>Let me know if you have any problems at your <it>end</it>.</vi> <un>usually used with <it>keep up</it> or <it>hold up</it> <vi>He promised to <it>keep up</it> his <it>end</it> of the agreement. [=he promised to do what he had agreed to do]</vi> <vi>You can count on her to <it>hold up</it> her <it>end</it>. [=to do what she is supposed to do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:any one of the places connected by a telephone call <vi>She picked up the phone and heard an unfamiliar voice at the other <it>end</it>.</vi> <vi>I can't hear you very well—there is a lot of noise at this <it>end</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <bnote>ends</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:parts of something that are left after the main part has been used <vi>a quilt made from bits and <it>ends</it> of fabric</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>loose end</dxt> <dxt>odds and ends</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a light at the end of the tunnel</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at the end of the day</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:when all things are considered :in the end <vi>It was a difficult decision, but <it>at the end of the day</it>, we knew we made the right choice.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at (your) wits'/wit's end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>burn the candle at both ends</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come to a bad end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to end up in a bad situation because of your actions <vi>If he keeps living this way he's sure to <it>come to a bad end</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to die in an unpleasant way <vi>According to legend, more than one person <it>came to a bad end</it> because of her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>end to end</dre> <def><dt>:with ends touching each other <vi>Put the two small tables <it>end to end</it>.</vi> <vi>railroad cars lined up <it>end to end</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go off the deep end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>deep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:finally or after a long time <vi>We worked hard, and <it>in the end</it> [=<it>ultimately</it>], we achieved our goal.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:when all things are considered <vi>He thought about moving to the city, but <it>in the end</it>, decided to stay where he was.</vi> <vi><it>In the end</it>, what really matters in a relationship is trust.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make ends meet</dre> <def><dt>:to pay for the things that you need to live when you have little money <vi>We had a hard time <it>making ends meet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make your hair stand on end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hair</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>never/not hear the end of it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not the end of the world</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If something is <it>not the end of the world</it>, it is not as terrible or unpleasant as it seems to be. <vi>It <it>won't be the end of the world</it> if it rains on the day of the wedding.</vi> <vi>Losing your job does <it>not</it> have <it>to be the end of the world</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on end</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:without interruption <vi>For days <it>on end</it> [=for many days] she didn't answer the phone.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in an upright position :not lying flat <vi>We set the bricks <it>on end</it> around the garden.</vi> <vi>His skis stood <it>on end</it> in the corner.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/at the receiving end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>receive</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the end of the line</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the end of the road</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the point or time when someone or something stops or cannot continue :the end <vi>A loss in the primary elections will mean <it>the end of the road</it> for his campaign.</vi> <vi>It will be <it>the end of the line</it> for me unless there are some changes around here.</vi> <vi>They reached <it>the end of the road</it> as a couple [=their relationship was over] a long time ago.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the end of time</dre> <def><dt>:<sx>forever</sx> <sx>always</sx> <un>used figuratively after <it>to, till</it>, or <it>until</it> <vi>He promised to love her <it>to the end of time</it>.</vi> <vi>Their heroism will be remembered <it>until the end of time</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the end of your rope</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>the end of your tether</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a state in which you are not able to deal with a problem, difficult situation, etc., any longer <vi>It was clear from her outburst that she was at <it>the end of her rope</it>.</vi> <vi>I've been dealing with their lies for too long. I'm at the <it>end of my rope</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the ends of the earth</dre> <def><dt>:places in the world that are very far away from cities, large groups of people, etc. :the most remote places in the world <un>used figuratively <vi>He would go to <it>the ends of the earth</it> [=he would do anything] to please her.</vi> <vi>We will search <it>the ends of the earth</it> [=<it>everywhere; for a long time</it>] if we have to.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the short end of the stick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the wrong end of the stick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(to) no end</dre> <def><dt>:a lot :a great deal <vi>It pleases me <it>to no end</it> [=<it>very much</it>] to see you so happy.</vi> <vi>We've had <it>no end</it> of trouble finding somewhere to live.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to that/this end</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:as a way of dealing with or doing something <vi>We want to save the building. <it>To this end</it>, we have hired someone to assess its current state.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to/till/until the bitter end</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bitter</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="pill[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">pill</hw> <sound><wav>pill0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpɪl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>pills</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a small, rounded object that you swallow and that contains medicine, vitamins, etc. <vi>She took a <it>pill</it> for her headache.</vi> <vi>The drug is available as a <it>pill</it> or a liquid.</vi> <vi>diet <it>pills</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pep pill</dxt> <dxt>poison pill</dxt> <dxt>sleeping pill</dxt> <dxt>sugar pill</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>the pill</bnote> <dt>:a pill that a woman takes so that she will not become pregnant :a contraceptive in pill form <vi>She is <phrase>on the pill</phrase>. [=she is taking birth control pills regularly]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>morning-after pill</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an annoying person <un>usually singular <vi>Don't be such a <it>pill</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>(a) bitter pill (to swallow)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bitter</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sugar/sweeten the pill</dre> <def><dt>:to make an unpleasant thing less difficult to accept or deal with <vi>Faster service may <it>sugar the pill</it> of higher fees.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="swallow[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">swal*low</hw> <pr>ˈswɑ:loʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>swal*lows</if></in> <in><if>swal*lowed</if></in> <in><if>swal*low*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to take (something) into your stomach through your mouth and throat <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>swallowed</it> the grape whole.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Chew your food well before you <it>swallow</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move the muscles in your throat as if you are swallowing something often because you are nervous <vi>I <it>swallowed</it> before answering.</vi> <vi>The boss said, “Come in.” I <phrase>swallowed hard</phrase> and walked in.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>If she insults you, just <it>swallow hard</it> [=make an effort to control yourself] and don't say anything.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to flow over and cover (something) completely <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>The wave <it>swallowed up</it> the small vessel.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>More small companies are being <it>swallowed</it> (<it>up</it>) [=<it>taken over, absorbed</it>] by giant conglomerates.</vi> <vi>We watched as he was <it>swallowed up</it> by the crowd. [=as he disappeared into the crowd]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use up (an amount of money) <un>usually + <it>up</it> <vi>The cost of childcare <it>swallows up</it> most of her income.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to accept or believe (something) <vi>Her story is pretty hard to <it>swallow</it>.</vi> <vi>I can usually take criticism, but this is more than I can <it>swallow</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to not allow yourself to show or be affected by (an emotion) <vi>We have to <it>swallow</it> our disappointment/anger about the election and keep trying to make things better.</vi> <vi>She had to <phrase>swallow her pride</phrase> and ask for help.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(a) bitter pill to swallow</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pill</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
