<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="blank[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">blank</hw> <sound><wav>blank001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblæŋk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>blank*er</if></in> <in><if>blank*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:without any writing, marks, or pictures <vi>a <it>blank</it> sheet of paper</vi> <vi>Leave that line <it>blank</it>. [=don't write on that line]</vi> <vi>a book with <it>blank</it> pages</vi> <vi>a <it>blank</it> wall</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blank slate</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having empty spaces to be filled in with information :not yet written in or filled out <vi>a <it>blank</it> passport application/form</vi> <vi>Sign your name on the <phrase>blank line</phrase>. [=a line that marks a place where you should write something]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blank check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:without any recorded sound or information <vi>a <it>blank</it> tape/disk/CD</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not showing any emotion <vi>She gave me a <it>blank</it> look [=did not show any emotion or response] when I asked her where she had been.</vi> <vi>a <it>blank</it> expression/stare</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:stated in a very direct and certain way <vi>I was surprised by her <it>blank</it> refusal to loan me the money.</vi> <vi>a <it>blank</it> [=(more commonly) <it>flat</it>] denial</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>point-blank</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>go blank</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to suddenly stop showing letters, images, etc. <vi>The screen on my computer <it>went blank</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>If your <phrase>mind goes blank</phrase>, you are unable to remember or think of something. <vi>My <it>mind went blank</it> when I heard the question.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>blank*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>She stared at him <it>blankly</it>. [=without any expression; her face showed no emotion]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>blank*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the wall's <it>blankness</it> = the <it>blankness</it> of the wall</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="blank[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">blank</hw> <altpr>ˈblæŋk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>blanks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an empty space on a document where you put information <vi>The form has a <it>blank</it> for your signature.</vi> <vi>Please <phrase>fill in the blanks</phrase>. [=put information in the blank spaces]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>At the end of the movie, the narrator goes back and <it>fills in</it> (all) <it>the blanks</it>. [=the narrator provides missing information about the movie's plot]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a period of time that you cannot remember anything about <vi>He says that the first hour after the accident is a complete <it>blank</it>. [=he cannot remember anything that happened for an hour after the accident]</vi> <snote>If your <phrase>mind is/draws a blank</phrase> or if you <phrase>draw a blank</phrase>, you are unable to remember or think of something. <vi>I should know the answer, but my <it>mind's a blank</it>.</vi> <vi>I <it>drew a blank</it> when I tried to remember his name.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a gun cartridge that is filled with powder but that does not contain a bullet <vi>The actors are shooting/firing <it>blanks</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blank[3]"> <hw hindex="3">blank</hw> <altpr>ˈblæŋk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>blanks</if></in> <in><if>blanked</if></in> <in><if>blank*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to keep (the opposing team) from scoring <vi>The goalie <it>blanked</it> the Falcons for two periods in the hockey game.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:to behave in an unfriendly way toward (someone you have been friendly with in the past) :to ignore or refuse to talk to (someone) <vi>His former friends <it>blanked</it> [=<it>cut, snubbed</it>] him in the street after the scandal.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blank out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>blank out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>blank (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to completely hide or cover (something) <vi>They <it>blanked out</it> [=<it>blacked out</it>] parts of the document before making it public.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to be forgotten <vi>The injury <it>blanked out</it> parts of his memory.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to completely forget (something) <vi>She has <it>blanked out</it> [=<it>blocked out</it>] what happened that night.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blank check"> <hw>blank check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>blank cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a signed check that does not have the amount of money written on it yet</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:complete control or freedom <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>give/hand (someone) a blank check</phrase> <vi>The director had a lot of creative freedom on this project; the film's backers essentially <it>handed him a blank check</it>. [=let him direct the film exactly the way he wanted to]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blank slate"> <hw>blank slate</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ slates</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:someone or something that is still in an original state and that has not yet been changed by people, experiences, etc. <vi>She viewed her students as <it>blank slates</it>, just waiting to be filled with knowledge.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that does not show or express anything <vi>Her expression was a <it>blank slate</it>. [=it did not show any emotion]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blank verse"> <hw>blank verse</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:poetry that is not rhymed but that has a regular rhythm <vi>the <it>blank verse</it> of Shakespeare and Milton</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>free verse</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="point-blank"> <hw>point–blank</hw> <sound><wav>pointb01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpoɪntˈblæŋk</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:from a very close distance <vi>The victim was shot <it>point-blank</it> in the head.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a direct and open way that does not hide anything <vi>He told me <it>point-blank</it> [=<it>bluntly, outright</it>] that he didn't believe me.</vi> <vi>I asked her <it>point-blank</it> what she wanted.</vi> <vi>She refused him <it>point-blank</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>point–blank</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>point–blank</it> question/refusal</vi> <vi>a <it>point-blank</it> shot to the goal</vi> <vi>The shots were taken at/from <it>point-blank</it> range.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="draw[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">draw</hw> <sound><wav>draw0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdrɑ:</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>draws</if></in> <in><if>drew</if> <sound><wav>draw0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdru:</pr></in> <in><if>drawn</if> <sound><wav>draw0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdrɑ:n</pr></in> <in><if>draw*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make (a picture, image, etc.) by making lines on a surface especially with a pencil, pen, marker, chalk, etc., but not usually with paint <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>drew</it> me a picture of the bike. = He <it>drew</it> a picture of the bike for me.</vi> <vi>The computer can <it>draw</it> the graph for you.</vi> <vi>Students <it>drew</it> maps of the states and labeled them.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>draw</it> very well.</vi> <vi>She sat down and began to <it>draw</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>paint</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (attention) to be given <it>to</it> someone or something <vi>The case has <it>drawn</it> attention <it>to</it> the fact that many athletes never graduate.</vi> <vi>I would like to <it>draw</it> your attention <it>to</it> the third line.</vi> <vi>He didn't want to <it>draw</it> attention <it>to</it> himself. [=he did not want to cause people to notice him]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to come :to attract (someone or something) <vi>The band always <it>draws</it> a large crowd.</vi> <vi>She felt <it>drawn</it> [=<it>attracted</it>] to the young man.</vi> <vi>The college <it>draws</it> students from around the world.</vi> <vi>The animals were <it>drawn</it> to the campsite by the smell of food.</vi> <vi>We hope the display in the window will <it>draw</it> customers in from the street.</vi> <vi>The lure of city life has <it>drawn</it> away many of the town's young people.</vi> <vi>My eye was <it>drawn</it> to the painting. [=some characteristic of the painting made me want to look at it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to become involved or interested in something or someone <un>+ <it>in, into</it>, or <it>to</it> <vi>What first <it>drew</it> you <it>to</it> teaching?</vi> <vi>A good writer knows how to <it>draw</it> readers <it>in</it>. [=how to make readers interested; how to make people want to read something]</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be/get) drawn</it> <vi>She <it>was drawn in</it> by his friendly manner. [=she wanted to know and talk to him because he was friendly]</vi> <vi>She <it>got drawn into</it> the conversation.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get or receive (something) <vi>a television show that has <it>drawn</it> consistently high ratings</vi> <vi>The player <it>drew</it> a foul.</vi> :to get (a particular response or reaction) <vi>His speech <it>drew</it> cheers from the crowd.</vi> <vi>The movie has <it>drawn</it> much criticism/praise from critics.</vi> <vi>He is a talented high school athlete who has <it>drawn</it> the interest of several major colleges.</vi> <vi>The principal's remarks have <phrase>drawn fire</phrase> [=attracted angry criticism] from both parents and teachers.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in a specified direction <vi>She <it>drew</it> away from the spider.</vi> <vi>He opened the door and <it>drew</it> back in horror/shock/fear.</vi> <vi>The car <it>drew</it> (up) alongside us.</vi> <vi>The train <it>drew</it> [=pulled] into the station.</vi> <vi>She <it>drew</it> her eyebrows together in a frown of concentration.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He <it>drew</it> away [=(more commonly) <it>withdrew</it>] from his family.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (something) by pulling <vi>a carriage <it>drawn</it> by horses = a horse-<it>drawn</it> carriage</vi> <vi><it>Draw</it> the curtains/blinds/shades. [=open or close the curtains/blinds/shades]</vi> <vi>a special fabric that <it>draws</it> moisture away from the skin</vi> <vi>She <it>drew</it> the blanket over her head.</vi> <vi><it>Draw</it> up a chair and join us. [=bring a chair to where we are and sit down with us]</vi> <vi>She sat down in the chair and <phrase>drew up her knees/legs</phrase>. [=she bent her legs and moved her knees toward her chest]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The tragedy <it>drew</it> us closer together. [=made us emotionally closer]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move gradually or steadily in time or space <vi>The lion <it>drew</it> closer to its prey.</vi> <vi>The sun is setting and the day is <phrase>drawing to a close</phrase>. [=<it>ending</it>]</vi> <vi>Spring is <phrase>drawing near/nigh</phrase>. [=<it>approaching</it>]</vi> <vi>The car <phrase>drew to a halt/stop</phrase>. [=the car slowed down and stopped]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to form (something, such as an idea or conclusion) after thinking carefully about information you have <vi>You can <it>draw</it> your own conclusions.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>a writer who <it>draws</it> ideas <it>from</it> newspaper stories</vi> <vi>We can <phrase>draw lessons from</phrase> past mistakes. [=we can learn from past mistakes]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to describe how two or more things are similar or different :to make (a comparison, distinction, etc.) <it>between</it> two or more things <vi>Many people have been <it>drawing</it> comparisons <it>between</it> the two movies. [=have been saying that the movies are similar]</vi> <vi>She <it>drew</it> important distinctions <it>between</it> the two methods. [=described important ways that the two methods are different]</vi></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (something) out of a container, pocket, etc. <vi>They were arguing, and then one of them <it>drew</it> [=<it>pulled</it>] a gun.</vi> <vi>One of the thieves <it>drew</it> a knife on her. [=one of the thieves took a knife out of a pocket, container, etc., and pointed it at her]</vi> <vi>She <it>drew</it> water from the well.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>at daggers drawn</tag> at <dxt>dagger</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to come out of a source <vi>He <it>drew</it> [=<it>ran</it>] water for a bath.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get (something) <it>from</it> a source <vi>The car also <it>draws</it> power <it>from</it> a battery.</vi> <vi>She <it>draws</it> strength/inspiration <it>from</it> her loving family.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to take (a card) from a group of cards <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Draw</it> four cards.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You haven't <it>drawn</it> yet.</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to choose (a thing) from a group without knowing which one you are choosing <vi>She <it>drew</it> the winning number/ticket.</vi> <vi>We <it>drew</it> names from a hat to decide who would go on the trip.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) The U.S. team have been <phrase>drawn against</phrase> [=chosen to play against] Greece in the first round.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>draw lots</tag> at <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to decide something by choosing something from a group <vi>We'll <it>draw</it> to see who will drive.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>draw straws <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as a legal document) in a proper or legal form <vi>We hired a lawyer to <it>draw</it> a will.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>They <it>drew up</it> a contract/proposal/plan/list.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (something, such as air or smoke) into your lungs by breathing <vi>She <it>drew</it> a deep breath before responding.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>He <it>drew</it> the fresh air <it>in</it>. = He <it>drew in</it> the fresh air.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to let air flow through <vi>Make sure the chimney is <it>drawing</it> properly.</vi> <vi>The pipe <it>draws</it> well.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take (money) from a bank account :<sx>withdraw</sx> <un>usually + <it>from</it> or <it>out</it> <vi>He <it>drew</it> $100 <it>from</it> the bank.</vi> <vi>She <it>drew out</it> the money.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to receive (money) regularly from an employer, government, bank, etc. <vi>He <it>draws</it> a salary of about $100,000.</vi> <vi>He <it>draws</it> unemployment benefits.</vi> <vi>She has started to <it>draw</it> her pension.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to write (a check) and have money taken from a bank account <vi>You are now authorized to <it>draw</it> checks from the corporate account.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to finish a game, contest, etc., without having a winner :<sx>tie</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We <it>drew</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>tied</it>] the game 3–3.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The teams <it>drew</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>tied</it>] 3–3. [=each team scored three points]</vi> <un>often + <it>against</it> <vi>The teams have <it>drawn against</it> each other.</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>archery</ssl> <dt>:to bend (a bow) by pulling back the string <vi>He <it>drew</it> his bow and aimed at the target.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to cause (someone) to say more about something especially by questioning <un>often used as <it>(be) drawn</it></un> <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>She refused to <it>be drawn on</it> whether the company is considering a merger.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>technical</ssl> <ssl>of a boat</ssl> <dt>:to need (a particular depth of water) in order to float <vi>The ship <it>draws</it> 45 feet of water.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>draw a bead on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw a blank</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw a/the line</dre> <dx>see <dxt>line</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw blood</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw in your horns</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>draw off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>draw (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take or remove (something) from a source or supply <vi>They illegally <it>drew off</it> thousands of dollars that had been donated to the charity.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw on</pva></phrasev> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to come closer in time <vi>It became colder as night <it>drew on</it>. [=<it>approached</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to use (something) as a source or supply <vi>The family is <it>drawing on/upon</it> the community for support.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (information, experience, knowledge, etc.) to make something <vi>Her new book <it>draws on</it> her personal experience as a firefighter.</vi> <vi>The report <it>draws upon</it> several recent studies.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to breathe in smoke from (a cigarette, cigar, pipe, etc.) <vi>He <it>drew on</it> his cigarette.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>draw out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause something to leave a source or supply <vi>Trees <it>draw</it> water <it>out</it> of the soil.</vi> <vi>Salt will <it>draw out</it> moisture from the vegetables.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>draw out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to last longer than the usual or expected amount of time <vi>Questions <it>drew</it> the meeting <it>out</it> for another hour.</vi> <vi>The movie's love scene was <it>drawn out</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>drawn-out</dxt> <dxt>long-drawn-out</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>draw out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to talk freely <vi>She tried to <it>draw</it> the frightened child <it>out</it> by asking him questions about his toys.</vi> <vi>The reporter had an ability to <it>draw out</it> people.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw straws</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>draw straws</it>, you choose a stick from a group of sticks that are different sizes but that are being held in such a way that they look like they are all the same size. Usually, whoever chooses the shortest stick or <phrase>gets/draws the short straw</phrase> will have to do a particular thing. <vi>Let's <it>draw straws</it> to see who will drive.</vi> <vi>He <it>drew the short straw</it> so he has to drive.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw the blinds/curtain/shades on</dre> <def><dt>:to end (something that has been continuing for a long time) <vi>Let's <it>draw the curtain on</it> this investigation.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>draw <dxn>5b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a vehicle</ssl> <dt>:to approach and stop at a place <vi>A car <it>drew up</it> [=<it>pulled up</it>] in front of the house.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>draw (yourself) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stand as straight and tall as you can <vi>He <it>drew himself up</it> to (his) full height.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>draw <dxn>10 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
