<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bless"> <hw>bless</hw> <sound><wav>bless001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblɛs</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bless*es</if></in> <in><if>blessed</if> <sound><wav>bless002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblɛst</pr></in> <in><if>bless*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make (something or someone) holy by saying a special prayer <vi>The priest <it>blessed</it> their marriage at the wedding.</vi> <vi>The water for the baptism has been <it>blessed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to ask God to care for and protect (someone or something) <vi>The priest <it>blessed</it> the baby I held in my arms.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used in the phrase <phrase>God bless</phrase> to express good wishes or appreciation for someone or something <vi>May <it>God bless</it> this country.</vi> <vi><it>God bless</it> modern medicine. [=thank God for modern medicine]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>god bless you <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>bless his/her heart</phrase> and <phrase>bless him/her</phrase> to express affection, appreciation, or understanding <vi>She tries so hard, <it>bless her heart</it>.</vi> <vi>My aunt Clare, <it>bless her</it>, watched the kids while we went out.</vi> <vi>Our cousin, <it>bless his heart</it>, is just so disorganized.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bless you <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to provide (a person, place, etc.) <it>with</it> something good or desirable <vi>Nature has <it>blessed</it> the area <it>with</it> good soil and a sunny climate.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) blessed</it> <vi>I have <it>been blessed with</it> good health and a wonderful wife and children.</vi> <vi>He <it>was blessed</it> [=<it>endowed</it>] <it>with</it> great speed as a runner.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to give approval to (something) <vi>The committee has not yet <it>blessed</it> the plan.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bless my soul</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used in speech to express surprise <vi>You decided to come see us after all. Well, <it>bless my soul</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bless you</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>God bless you</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to express thanks or good wishes <vi>“I'll be happy to help in any way I can.” “Oh, <it>bless you</it>! That's very kind of you.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>said to someone who has just sneezed</un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="god"> <hw highlight="yes">god</hw> <sound><wav>god00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:d</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>God</bnote> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the perfect and all-powerful spirit or being that is worshipped especially by Christians, Jews, and Muslims as the one who created and rules the universe <vi>Does she believe in <it>God</it>?</vi> <vi>(May) <it>God</it> bless us all.</vi> <vi>(May) <it>God</it> rest her soul. [=I pray that God will give her soul peace now that she has died]</vi> <vi>I pray to <it>God</it> that no one was seriously injured in the accident.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>man of god</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote><it>God</it> is used informally by itself and in phrases to make a statement or question more forceful or to express surprise, anger, etc. These uses are common but are considered offensive by some people. <vi><it>God</it>, it's hot out today.</vi> <vi><phrase>Good God</phrase>, that's a lot of food!</vi> <vi><phrase>God Almighty</phrase>, is it that late already?</vi> <vi><phrase>My God</phrase>, what were you thinking?!</vi> <vi><phrase>Oh my God</phrase>! I can't believe it!</vi> <vi><phrase>By God</phrase>, I refuse to give up!</vi> <vi><phrase>For God's sake</phrase>, what do you want from me?</vi> <vi>Who <phrase>in God's name</phrase> [=<it>on earth, in heaven's name</it>] could that be?</vi> <vi>Where <it>in God's name</it> have you been?</vi> <vi>I <phrase>swear to God</phrase>, if you're not ready in five minutes, I'm leaving without you.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>wish to God</phrase> you would stop complaining.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a spirit or being that has great power, strength, knowledge, etc., and that can affect nature and the lives of people :one of various spirits or beings worshipped in some religions <vi>the <it>gods</it> and goddesses of ancient Egypt</vi> <vi>a Hindu <it>god</it></vi> <vi>a myth about the <it>god</it> of war</vi> <vi>an offering for the <it>gods</it></vi> <un>often used informally to suggest that what happens to someone is controlled by gods or by luck <vi>The <it>gods</it> smiled/frowned on us. = The <it>gods</it> were/weren't on our side [=we had good/bad luck; things went well/badly for us]</vi> <vi>(<it>humorous</it>) The golf <it>gods</it> seem to like you today. [=you are playing golf very well today]</vi> <vi>Her sudden arrival was <phrase>a gift from the gods</phrase>. [=a very lucky and helpful thing]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person and especially a man who is greatly loved or admired <vi>a professor who was regarded as a kind of <it>god</it></vi> <vi>a guitar <it>god</it> like Jimi Hendrix</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person who is very important or powerful in a particular field <un>usually plural <vi>a talented writer who never found favor with the <it>gods</it> of the literary world</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is regarded as one of the most important things in someone's life <vi>He made a <it>god</it> of money. [=he worshipped money; he regarded money as more important than it really is]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>the gods</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:the highest and cheapest seats in a theater <vi>The people in <it>the gods</it> can be the hardest to please.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>act of God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>act</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for the love of God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God bless you</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bless</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God forbid</dre> <dx>see <dxt>forbid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God help someone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>help</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God knows</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God's gift</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gift</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>God willing</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say what you hope and expect to do or happen if no problems occur <vi>We'll be able to move into our new house next week, <it>God willing</it>.</vi> <vi><it>God willing</it>, I'll finish my degree this year.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the lap of the gods</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>play God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>play</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put the fear of God into</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fear</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>so help me God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>help</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>thank God</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(there) but for the grace of God (go I)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>god*like</ure> <sound><wav>godlik01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈga:dˌlaɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="soul"> <hw highlight="yes">soul</hw> <sound><wav>soul0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsoʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>souls</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the spiritual part of a person that is believed to give life to the body and in many religions is believed to live forever <vi>salvation of the human <it>soul</it> [=<it>spirit</it>]</vi> <vi>the <it>souls</it> of the dead</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person's deeply felt moral and emotional nature <vi>He could not escape the guilt that he felt in the inner recesses of his <it>soul</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability of a person to feel kindness and sympathy for others, to appreciate beauty and art, etc. <vi>She has no <it>soul</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a human being :<sx>person</sx> <vi>a brave/gentle/kind <it>soul</it></vi> <vi>Some poor <it>soul</it> was asking for handouts on the street.</vi> <vi>There wasn't a <it>soul</it> in sight. [=there wasn't anyone in sight]</vi> <vi>He didn't tell a <it>soul</it> [=<it>anyone</it>] that he was leaving.</vi> <vi>a village of barely a hundred <it>souls</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a quality that gives emotional force and effectiveness to a performance, a work of art, etc. <vi>He's a skillful performer, but his music lacks <it>soul</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:<sx>soul music</sx> <vi>My favorite types of music are jazz and <it>soul</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a person who has a lot of a particular quality <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi>He is the <it>soul of</it> integrity. [=he is a very honest person]</vi> <vi>I promise I'll be <phrase>the soul of discretion</phrase>. [=I'll be very discreet]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the central or most important part of something that makes it effective, valuable, etc. <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>Honesty is the very <it>soul of</it> any good relationship.</vi> <vi>Our employees are the <phrase>heart and soul of</phrase> our company.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>bless my soul</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bless</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>body and soul</dre> <dx>see <dxt>body</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep body and soul together</dre> <dx>see <dxt>body</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pour your soul out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pour</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>sell your soul (to the devil)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sell</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
