<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="blind[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">blind</hw> <sound><wav>blind001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblaɪnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>blind*er</if></in> <in><if>blind*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:unable to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> person</vi> <vi>He was born <it>blind</it>.</vi> <vi>She is <it>blind</it> in one eye. [=she can see with one of her eyes but not with the other]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>went blind</phrase> [=she became unable to see] at age 67.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>color-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:unable to notice or judge something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He is <it>blind to</it> his son's faults.</vi> <vi>Each party was <it>blind to</it> the other's concerns.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>usually disapproving</ssl> <dt>:accepting the actions or decisions of someone or something without any questions or criticism <vi><it>blind</it> loyalty/allegiance/obedience</vi> <vi>I'm not sure <it>blind</it> faith [=unquestioning belief] in our leaders is wise.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe strong emotions that make someone unable to think clearly or to act reasonably <vi>a <it>blind</it> fury/rage</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:done in a way that prevents participants, judges, etc., from seeing or knowing certain things that might influence them <vi>a <it>blind</it> taste test [=a test in which people taste something without knowing what it is, who made it, etc.]</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> clinical trial for the new medicine</vi> <vi><it>blind</it> auditions</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind date</dxt> <dxt>double-blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:difficult for a driver to see <vi>a <it>blind</it> driveway/drive</vi> <vi>a <it>blind</it> curve</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blind spot</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) blind as a bat</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:unable to see well at all :having very poor vision <vi>Without glasses I'm <it>blind as a bat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>love is blind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>not a blind bit</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:not even a very small amount :not the slightest bit <vi>I told them what I wanted, but they <it>didn't</it> take <it>a blind bit</it> of notice. [=they didn't notice at all; they did not listen to me]</vi> <vi>It does <it>not</it> make <it>a blind bit</it> of difference what you do. [=it does not matter at all what you do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the blind</dre> <def><dt>:blind people :people who are not able to see <vi>The agency provides assistance to <it>the blind</it>.</vi> <snote>The expression <phrase>the blind leading the blind</phrase> is used informally to describe a situation in which someone who is not sure about how to do something is helping another person who also is not sure about how to do it. <vi>I'll try to help, but it's <it>the blind leading the blind</it> because I've never done this before either.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <def><dt>:to ignore a problem instead of dealing with it <vi>Corruption in the police force is rampant, but authorities are <it>turning a blind eye</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Colleges can't afford to <it>turn a blind eye to</it> alcohol abuse.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>blind*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>a leading cause of <it>blindness</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="blind[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">blind</hw> <altpr>ˈblaɪnd</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>blinds</if></in> <in><if>blind*ed</if></in> <in><if>blind*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be unable to see :to make (someone) blind <vi>The accident <it>blinded</it> me in one eye. = The accident left me <it>blinded</it> in one eye.</vi> <vi>She was <it>blinded</it> as a child in a terrible fire.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be unable to see for a short time <vi>I was <it>blinded</it> by the sun as I came around the corner.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be unable to think clearly or to act reasonably <vi>He was <it>blinded</it> by love.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Greed <it>blinds</it> them <it>to</it> everything except money. [=greed causes them to think and care about only money]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blind[3]"> <hw hindex="3">blind</hw> <altpr>ˈblaɪnd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>blinds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is used to cover a window from the inside of a room</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a roll of cloth or plastic that is hung at the top of a window and pulled down over the window <un>usually plural <vi>Raise/lower/open/close the <it>blinds</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see picture at <dxt>window</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>venetian blind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a place where hunters hide from animals while they are hunting <vi>a duck <it>blind</it> [=a place to hide when hunting ducks]</vi> <ca>called also (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>hide</cat></ca></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that is used to trick people or to prevent people from noticing a particular thing <vi>Some say the investigation is a <it>blind</it> to keep the public's attention off the governor.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>draw the blinds on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>draw</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blind[4]"> <hw hindex="4">blind</hw> <altpr>ˈblaɪnd</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:without seeing outside of an airplane :using only a plane's instruments <vi>They had to <phrase>fly blind</phrase> through heavy smoke.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to the degree that you are unable to think clearly or to act reasonably <vi>He was <phrase>blind drunk</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>rob someone blind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rob</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blind alley"> <hw>blind alley</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -leys</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a narrow path between two buildings that can only be entered at one end <un>often used figuratively <vi>Police had been down several <it>blind alleys</it> [=they had tried several methods that did not produce useful results] in the murder investigation before they found the evidence they needed.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blind date"> <hw>blind date</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ dates</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an occasion for two people who do not know each other to meet and decide if they may want to have a romantic relationship <vi>She went out on a <it>blind date</it> with her friend's cousin.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blind side"> <hw>blind side</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sides</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the side that is not the side you are facing <vi>He was hit on his <it>blind side</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blind spot"> <hw>blind spot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ spots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an area around a car, truck, etc., that the driver cannot see <vi>When driving on the highway, you need to make sure no one is in your <it>blind spot</it> before changing lanes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a tendency to ignore something especially because it is difficult or unpleasant <vi>She has a <it>blind spot</it> concerning her son's behavior.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a small area at the back of the eye that is not sensitive to light</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="color-blind"> <hw>col*or–blind</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>col*our–blind</va> <sound><wav>color_02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌlɚˌblaɪnd</pr></vr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:unable to see the difference between certain colors <vi>Many <it>color-blind</it> people cannot distinguish between red and green.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:treating people of different skin colors equally :not affected by racial prejudice <vi>The company claims to be <it>color-blind</it>.</vi> <vi><it>color-blind</it> policies</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>color blindness</ure> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>colour blindness</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>He has a common form of <it>color blindness</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="double-blind"> <hw>dou*ble–blind</hw> <sound><wav>double07.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌdʌbəlˈblaɪnd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>technical</sl> <dt><un>used to describe an experiment that is done so that neither the people who are doing the experiment nor the people who are the subjects of the experiments know which of the groups being studied is the control group and which is the test group <vi>a <it>double-blind</it> drug trial</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
