<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="blood"> <hw highlight="yes">blood</hw> <sound><wav>blood001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblʌd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the red liquid that flows through the bodies of people and animals <vi>The accident victim has already lost a lot of <it>blood</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>blood</it> in your veins</vi> <vi>She <phrase>donates/gives blood</phrase> twice a year. [=twice a year she has blood taken out of her body so that it can be put into the body of a person who needs it]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bad blood</dxt> <dxt>cold-blooded</dxt> <dxt>full-blooded</dxt> <dxt>hot-blooded</dxt> <dxt>red-blooded</dxt> <dxt>warm-blooded</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that a person's ancestors were of a particular kind <vi>There's some Italian <it>blood</it> in her family. [=one or more of her family's ancestors was Italian]</vi> <vi>a man of royal <it>blood</it> [=a man with kings and queens in his family]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>blue blood</dxt> <dxt>blue-blooded</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:members of a team, company, or organization <un>usually used in the phrases <phrase>new blood</phrase> or <phrase>young blood</phrase> <vi>Our company could benefit from some <it>new blood</it>. [=new employees]</vi> <vi>We've just added some <it>young blood</it> to the team.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>blood and guts</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>blood is thicker than water</dre> <def><dt><snote>The saying <it>blood is thicker than water</it> means that a person's family is more important than a person's other relationships or needs.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blood is up</dre> <def><dt><snote>In British English, when you say that someone's <it>blood is up</it>, you mean that someone is angry and wants to fight or argue. <vi>It's best to avoid her when her <it>blood is up</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>blood on your hands</dre> <def><dt><snote>If someone's <it>blood is on your hands</it>, you are responsible for that person's death. <vi>Her <it>blood is on your hands</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by blood</dre> <def><dt>:by a relationship that connects two people through their natural parents, grandparents, etc. <vi>My aunt and I are <phrase>related by blood</phrase>. [=my aunt is the sister of one of my parents]</vi> <vi>My aunt and I are not <phrase>related by blood</phrase>. [=my aunt is/was married to the brother of one of my parents]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw blood</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to take blood from a person's body for medical reasons <vi>We need to <it>draw</it> some <it>blood</it> to test you for the virus.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause blood to flow from a person's body <vi>The punch to the nose <it>drew blood</it>. [=caused the nose to bleed]</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Some politicians view debates as chances to <it>draw blood</it> from their opponents.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>flesh and blood</dre> <dx>see <dxt>flesh</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in cold blood</dre> <def><dt>:in a deliberate way :following a plan <vi>They were killed <it>in cold blood</it> by terrorists.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your blood</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something (such as an ability or activity) is <it>in your blood</it>, it is part of your nature and is often shared by your family members. <vi>With two parents who are painters, art is <it>in her blood</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood boil</dre> <def><dt>:to make someone very angry <vi>His hate-filled speeches <it>make my blood boil</it>! [=<it>make me see red</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood curdle</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make someone's blood run cold</va></vr> <def><dt>:to cause someone to be very afraid or disgusted <vi>The horrible news <it>made our blood run cold</it>.</vi> <vi>a ghost story that will <it>make your blood curdle</it></vi> <vi>The mere sight of a cockroach <it>makes my blood curdle</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out for blood</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>out for blood</it> or <it>out for someone's blood</it>, you are very angry and you want to kill someone or to cause someone pain or discomfort. <vi>Those soldiers were <it>out for blood</it>.</vi> <vi>His ex-wife is <it>out for his blood</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>spill/shed blood</dre> <def><dt>:to kill people violently <vi>The <it>blood</it> of too many young people <it>has been spilled/shed</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>sweat blood</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to care a lot about something and work very hard for it <vi>basketball players who <it>sweat blood</it> for their teams</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>taste blood</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to experience pleasure as a result of defeating an opponent <vi>She has <it>tasted blood</it> now, and can't wait to meet her rival on the court again.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="blood bank"> <hw>blood bank</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ banks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place where blood is stored so that it later can be given to people who are ill</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood brother"> <hw>blood brother</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a man or boy who has promised to be loyal to another man or boy usually in a ceremony in which they mix their blood <vi>He would never betray me—he's my <it>blood brother</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood cell"> <hw>blood cell</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cells</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a cell that is normally present in blood <dx>see also <dxt>red blood cell</dxt> <dxt>white blood cell</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood clot"> <hw>blood clot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a thick and sticky clump of dried blood that stops blood from flowing through a blood vessel in a person or an animal <vi>She had a <it>blood clot</it> in her lungs.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>clot</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood count"> <hw>blood count</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the number of cells in someone's blood <un>usually singular <vi>The patient has a low <it>blood count</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood doping"> <hw>blood doping</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:an illegal method for temporarily improving an athlete's performance in a race or competition by increasing the number of red blood cells in the blood</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood feud"> <hw>blood feud</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ feuds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a very long fight between two families or groups in which each group kills members of the other group in order to punish the group for earlier murders</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood group"> <hw>blood group</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ groups</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>blood type</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blood heat"> <hw>blood heat</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:the normal temperature of the human body <snote>In U.S. English, this temperature (98.6 degrees Fahrenheit or 37 degrees Celsius) is referred to as a person's normal <phrase>body temperature</phrase>.</snote></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
