<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="body"> <hw highlight="yes">body</hw> <sound><wav>body0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:di</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bod*ies</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a person's or animal's whole physical self <vi>the human <it>body</it></vi> <vi>a part of the <it>body</it></vi> <vi>Her <it>body</it> is very muscular.</vi> <vi>A bird's <it>body</it> is covered in feathers.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>body</it> weight/fat</vi> <vi><it>body</it> parts</vi> <vi>A person's normal <phrase>body temperature</phrase> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>blood heat</it>] is 98.6 degrees Fahrenheit or 37 degrees Celsius.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a dead person or animal <vi>The <it>body</it> [=<it>corpse</it>] was shipped home for burial.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the main physical part of a person or animal <vi>This species has a black <it>body</it> and a white head.</vi> <vi>She held her arms tightly against her <it>body</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of a vehicle that does not include the engine, wheels, etc. <vi>There was extensive damage to the truck's <it>body</it>.</vi> <vi>The <it>body</it> of the bus is almost entirely rusted out.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the main or most important part of something written <vi>The (main) <it>body</it> of the text/letter is devoted to a description of the author's childhood home.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an object that is separate from other objects <vi>heavenly/celestial <it>bodies</it>, such as the moon, the planets, and the stars</vi> <snote>A <phrase>foreign body</phrase> is an object that is inside something (such as someone's body) where it should not be. <vi>The X-ray showed a <it>foreign body</it> in his stomach.</vi> <vi>Dust particles and other <it>foreign bodies</it> can irritate the eyes.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large area of water <un>used in the phrase <phrase>body of water</phrase> <vi>This lake is the largest <it>body of water</it> in the state.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who are involved together in the same job, activity, etc. <vi>a <it>body</it> of troops</vi> <vi>the student <it>body</it></vi> <vi>the state's legislative <it>body</it> [=the group of people who make the state's laws]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of things that are related or connected in some way <vi>They've accumulated quite a <it>body</it> of evidence.</vi> <vi>a writer with an impressive <it>body</it> of work</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>of wine</ssl> <dt>:a strong and appealing flavor <vi>a wine with full <it>body</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>of hair</ssl> <dt>:a thick and appealing quality <vi>hair that lacks <it>body</it></vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the section of a piece of clothing that covers the main part of a person's body <vi>the <it>body</it> of a wetsuit</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a human being :<sx>person</sx> <un>usually singular <vi>What's a <it>body</it> to do?</vi> <vi>It was just some poor <it>body</it> looking for work.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>body and soul</dre> <def><dt>:with all of your energy and enthusiasm <vi>He devoted himself <it>body and soul</it> to the cause.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep body and soul together</dre> <def><dt>:to have or get enough food and money to survive <vi>She <it>kept body and soul together</it> by working two jobs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>over my dead body</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you are very determined to not let something happen <vi>“We're getting married.” “<it>Over my dead body</it>!”</vi> <vi>I told her she could go with them <it>over my dead body</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="body bag"> <hw>body bag</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bags</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a large bag that a dead person's body is put in to be carried or moved to another place</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body blow"> <hw>body blow</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ blows</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a hard hit to a person's body <un>usually used figuratively to describe a sudden event or occurrence that causes severe trouble, damage, sorrow, etc. <vi>The economy has taken some serious <it>body blows</it> in the past few years.</vi> <vi>The latest attack has dealt a real <it>body blow</it> to the chances for peace.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body clock"> <hw>body clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a system in the body that controls when you need to sleep, eat, etc. <vi>It takes a while for my <it>body clock</it> to get adjusted when I fly from New York to London.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>biological clock</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body count"> <hw>body count</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the number of people killed in a war, disaster, etc. <vi>The rising <it>body count</it> fueled opposition to the war.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body double"> <hw>body double</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ doubles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person who takes an actor's place in a movie or television show for certain scenes (such as sex scenes)</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body language"> <hw>body language</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:movements or positions of the body that express a person's thoughts or feelings <vi>We could tell from his <it>body language</it> that he was nervous.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body mass index"> <hw>body mass index</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ indexes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a measurement that shows the amount of fat in your body and that is based on your weight and height <vi>A person with a <it>body mass index</it> of more than 30 is considered to be obese.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body odor"> <hw>body odor</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:an unpleasant smell from the body of a person who has been sweating or is not clean <un>abbr. <it>BO</it></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body politic"> <hw>body politic</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the body politic</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:all the people in a particular country considered as a single group <vi>The article examines the language politicians use to appeal to <it>the body politic</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
