<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="born"> <hw highlight="yes">born</hw> <sound><wav>born0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚn</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:brought into life by the process of birth <vi>She was <it>born</it> in a hospital.</vi> <vi>He was <it>born</it> on a farm.</vi> <vi>She was <it>born</it> in Nigeria in 1911.</vi> <vi>The baby was <it>born</it> on July 31st.</vi> <vi>Their second son was <it>born</it> prematurely.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>firstborn</dxt> <dxt>newborn</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having certain qualities or characteristics from the time of birth <vi><it>born</it> blind/deaf</vi> <vi>Both twins were <it>born</it> healthy.</vi> <vi>The author Mark Twain was <it>born</it> Samuel Clemens. [=was named Samuel Clemens at birth]</vi> <vi>She's a <it>born</it> teacher/leader. [=she was born with the qualities that make someone a teacher/leader]</vi> <snote>If you were <phrase>born to do</phrase> something or <phrase>born to be</phrase> something, you have natural qualities or talents that make you perfectly suited to do or be something. <vi>She was <it>born to teach</it>. = She was <it>born to be</it> a teacher.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt><un>used to describe the place where someone was born <vi>He's American <it>born</it>. [=he was born in America]</vi> <vi>He's Mexican <phrase>born and bred</phrase>. = He was <it>born and bred</it> in Mexico. [=his birth and childhood took place in Mexico]</vi></un> <un>often used in combination <vi>Maine-<it>born</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt><un>used to describe the social conditions or situations that exist when people are born <vi>Some are <it>born</it> in slavery, others <it>born</it> merely poor.</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>born to</phrase> riches/wealth. = She was <phrase>born into</phrase> a rich/wealthy family.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>highborn</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:brought into existence <vi>Her dream of owning farm was <it>born</it> when she visited the countryside as a child.</vi> <vi>The wine is <it>born</it> [=<it>created</it>] from the union of two very different grapes.</vi> <vi>a mentality <it>born</it> in the age of computers</vi> <vi>Their relationship was <phrase>born of necessity</phrase> [=established because it was necessary in some way], but it has developed into a true and lasting friendship.</vi> <vi>Church leaders assert that the recent unrest in the city is <phrase>born out of</phrase> [=has occurred because of] years of neglect of the city's poor neighborhoods.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>born too late</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who is said to be <it>born too late</it> seems to be better suited for life in an earlier time period. <vi>John prefers early jazz music over the modern stuff. I guess he was <it>born too late</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>born with a silver spoon in your mouth</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you were <it>born with a silver spoon in your mouth</it>, you were born into a very wealthy family.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in all your born days</dre> <def><sl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:in your entire life <un>used to express how unexpected or unusual something is <vi>I never saw anything like it <it>in all my born days</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>there's one born every minute</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>there's a sucker born every minute</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that there are many people in the world who are foolish and can be easily deceived</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the manner born</dre> <dx>see <dxt>manner</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the manor born</dre> <dx>see <dxt>manor</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>wasn't born yesterday</dre> <def><dt><snote>Someone who <it>wasn't born yesterday</it> is unlikely to believe something that is not true or to trust someone who is not trustworthy. <vi>He said he'd pay me back, but I'll believe it when I see it. I <it>wasn't born yesterday</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bear[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bear</hw> <altpr>ˈbeɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bears</if></in> <in><if>bore</if> <sound><wav>bear0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚ</pr></in> <in><if>borne</if> <sound><wav>borne001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈboɚn</pr></in> <in><if>bear*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to accept or endure (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>bore</it> [=<it>tolerated</it>] their insults patiently.</vi> <un>usually used in questions and negative statements with <it>can, can't, could</it>, and <it>couldn't</it> <vi>He <it>could</it> hardly <it>bear</it> [=<it>stand</it>] the pain.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> cold weather. [=I strongly dislike cold weather]</vi> <vi>I <it>couldn't bear</it> the suspense.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> it if/when people behave like that!</vi> <vi>I <it>can't bear</it> doing this. = I can't <it>bear</it> to do this.</vi> <vi>How <it>can</it> you <it>bear</it> to see him again after the way he's treated you?</vi> <vi>I couldn't <it>bear</it> you to get the wrong idea.</vi> <vi>I <it>couldn't bear</it> his behavior. = His behavior was <phrase>more than I could bear</phrase>.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>couldn't bear the thought/idea</phrase> of moving again.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> (<it>US</it>) <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>I couldn't <it>bear for</it> you to get the wrong idea.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be worthy of (something) :to deserve or allow (something) <vi>a joke too silly to <it>bear</it> repeating [=a joke that is too silly to be worth repeating]</vi> <vi>It's so horrible it doesn't <it>bear</it> thinking about! [=it's so horrible that I don't want to think about it]</vi> <vi>a symphony that can <it>bear</it> comparison with Beethoven's best</vi> <vi>a plan that will not <it>bear</it> [=<it>withstand</it>] close scrutiny/examination</vi> <vi>suspicious behavior that <phrase>bears watching</phrase> [=that should be watched]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to assume or accept (something, such as cost or responsibility) <vi>The company agreed to <it>bear</it> the costs/expenses.</vi> <vi>The criminals must <it>bear</it> full responsibility for the deaths of these innocent people.</vi> <vi>Who will <it>bear</it> the blame for this tragedy?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal + literary</ssl> <dt>:to move while holding up and supporting (something) :<sx>carry</sx> <vi>The demonstrators <it>bore</it> banners and sang songs.</vi> <vi>They arrived <it>bearing</it> gifts.</vi> <vi>The leaves were <it>borne</it> aloft/away by the wind.</vi> <vi>disease-<it>bearing</it> germs [=germs that carry and spread diseases]</vi> <vi>germ-<it>borne</it> diseases [=diseases that are carried and spread by germs]</vi> <vi>He believes that citizens should have the right to <phrase>bear arms</phrase>. [=to carry weapons]</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>borne in on/upon</phrase> you, it is made very clear to you. This is a formal phrase. <vi>It was <it>borne in on</it> us by the new evidence that prompt action was very important. [=the new evidence strongly indicated that prompt action was very important]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) as a feature or characteristic <vi>His leg was badly injured in the accident and it still <it>bears</it> [=<it>shows</it>] the scars/wounds/marks.</vi> <vi>His face <it>bears</it> marks/signs of suffering.</vi> <vi>Your conclusion <it>bears</it> [=<it>has</it>] no relation to the evidence.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>bore a resemblance</phrase> to her aunt. [=she looked like her aunt]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a surface on which something is written, drawn, etc. <vi>The cornerstone <it>bears</it> a Latin inscription.</vi> <vi>a letter <it>bearing</it> the date of 1900</vi> <vi>a shield <it>bearing</it> strange symbols</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to have (a name, price, etc.) <vi>He <it>bore</it> the name (of) John.</vi> <vi>The store sells imported goods <it>bearing</it> [=<it>having, with</it>] high prices.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to have or hold (a feeling) in the mind <vi>She still <it>bears</it> a grudge against him. = She still <it>bears</it> him a grudge.</vi> <vi>She says she <it>bears</it> him no resentment for the way he treated her.</vi> <vi>I can't deny the love I still <it>bear</it> [=<it>feel</it>] for her.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give birth to (a child) <vi>She has <it>borne</it> three children.</vi> <vi>She has <it>borne</it> her husband three children.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (something) <vi>a bank account that <it>bears</it> interest = an interest-<it>bearing</it> bank account</vi> <vi>a bush that <it>bears</it> red flowers</vi> <vi>trees that <it>bear</it> fruit</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bear fruit <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to support the weight of (something) <vi>How much weight is that wall able to <it>bear</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go, move, or turn in a specified direction <vi><it>Bear</it> south.</vi> <vi>The road <it>bears</it> (to the) right.</vi> <vi>When you get to the fork in the road, you should <it>bear</it> [=<it>turn</it>] left.</vi></dt> <snotebox>Do not confuse <it>bear</it> with <it>bare</it>.</snotebox></def> <dro><dre>bear down</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:to use all of your strength and effort to do something :to try very hard to do something <vi>The pitcher <it>bore down</it> and struck out the last batter.</vi> <vi>If we're going to finish on time, we really have to <it>bear down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear down on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to push or lean down on (something) <vi>The old man <it>bore down</it> heavily <it>on</it> his cane.</vi> <vi>She <it>bore down</it> hard <it>on</it> her pencil.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to place pressure on (someone) <vi>Don't let your problems <it>bear down</it> too hard <it>on</it> you. [=don't let your problems weigh you down]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>bear down on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to approach or move toward (something or someone) quickly and in a frightening or impressive way <vi>The enemy battleship <it>bore down on</it> us.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear fruit</dre> <def><dt>:to produce a desired result or reward <vi>All his plans have finally <it>borne fruit</it>. [=all his plans have finally been realized]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bear <dxn>6b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear in mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bear on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have an effect on (something) <vi>Personal feelings did not <it>bear on</it> our decision. [=did not affect or influence our decision]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to apply or relate to (something) <vi>What are the facts <it>bearing</it> directly <it>on</it> this matter?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear out (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bear (something or someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to show the correctness of (something or someone) <vi>The facts <it>bore out</it> [=<it>confirmed</it>] her story. [=the facts showed that her story was true]</vi> <vi>Research has fully <it>borne him out</it>. [=has shown that he was completely correct]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to not be overwhelmed during a time of trouble, pain, etc. <vi>She's been going through a tough time, but she's <it>bearing up</it> pretty well.</vi> <un>often + <it>under</it> <vi>She has found it hard to <it>bear up under</it> the strain.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bear with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be patient with (someone) <vi>I'll have that information for you soon. Just <it>bear with</it> me for another minute or two.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bear witness</dre> <dx>see <dxt>witness</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bear yourself</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to move, stand, or behave in a specified way <vi>The soldier <it>bore himself</it> [=<it>carried himself</it>] stiffly upright.</vi> <vi>The soldier never failed to <it>bear himself</it> [=<it>conduct himself, behave</it>] courageously on the battlefield.</vi> <vi>He always <it>bore himself</it> [=<it>behaved</it>] like a gentleman.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (something) to bear</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (something) to have an effect or influence <vi>The company's new president <it>brings</it> 30 years of experience <it>to bear</it>.</vi> <vi>If we hope to resolve these issues, more resources must be <it>brought to bear</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>on</it> <vi>They will <it>bring</it> their considerable skills/talent/experience/knowledge <it>to bear on</it> the problem.</vi> <vi>The demonstrators will continue to <phrase>bring pressure to bear on</phrase> the government.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross to bear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>grin and bear it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="born-again"> <hw>born–again</hw> <sound><wav>borna01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌboɚnəˈgɛn</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a new or stronger belief in the Christian religion <vi>The <it>born-again</it> actor often talks about his faith during interviews.</vi> <vi>She's <it>born-again</it> now.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>born-again Christian</phrase></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:newly interested in and enthusiastic about something and eager to make other people think the way you do <vi>a <it>born-again</it> fitness buff</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="natural-born"> <hw>natural–born</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:able to do something well immediately or from the very first time <vi>She's a <it>natural-born</it> artist/leader. [=she has natural abilities that make her a good artist/leader]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="day"> <hw highlight="yes">day</hw> <sound><wav>day00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdeɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>days</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a period of 24 hours beginning at midnight :one of the seven time periods that make up a week <vi>We're open seven <it>days</it> a week, 365 <it>days</it> a year.</vi> <vi>Payment is due on the first <it>day</it> of every month.</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> is (it) today?” “Tuesday.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> [=<it>date</it>] is Friday?” “It's the 28th.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> of the week is the 28th?” “It's a Friday.”</vi> <vi>He spent five <it>days</it> in the hospital.</vi> <vi>She left on Thursday and came back four <it>days</it> later.</vi> <vi>The baby is due (to be born) in three <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>That was the happiest <it>day</it> of my life.</vi> <vi>Parenthood gets better every <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>We'll be finished in a <it>day</it> or two. = We'll be finished in a couple of <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It rained for a <it>day</it> and a half. [=it rained for about 36 hours]</vi> <vi>The office is closed for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I call him every (single) <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow is another <it>day</it>. [=there will be more opportunities to do things tomorrow]</vi> <vi>a <it>day</it> of celebration/mourning [=a day for people to celebrate/mourn]</vi> <vi>Take one pill two times <phrase>a day</phrase>. [=each day]</vi> <vi>She works eight hours <it>a day</it>.</vi> <vi>It costs 10 dollars <it>a day</it> to park there.</vi> <vi>The party is <phrase>the day after tomorrow</phrase>. = The party is in two <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It happened <phrase>the day before yesterday</phrase>. = It happened two <it>days</it> ago.</vi> <vi>Sometimes they didn't speak to each other for <phrase>days on end</phrase>. [=several days]</vi> <vi><phrase>From that day forth/forward</phrase> [=(less formally) <it>from then on</it>], I was determined to do better.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>do not look a day over</phrase> a particular age, you appear to be that age. <vi>“Today's my 50th birthday.” “Really? I'm surprised. You <it>don't look a day over</it> 40.” [=you don't look any older than 40 years old]</vi></snote> <snote>If you say that someone is a particular age <phrase>if he/she is a day</phrase>, you mean that the person is that age or older. <vi>The man she's dating is 60 <it>if he's a day</it>. [=he is at least sixty years old]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the time of light between one night and the next :the part of the day when light from the sun can be seen <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What a beautiful summer <it>day</it>!</vi> <vi>a cold/wet/rainy <it>day</it></vi> <vi>The shortest <it>day</it> of the year is usually December 22, and June 22 is usually the longest.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He sleeps during the <it>day</it> [=<it>daytime</it>] and works at night.</vi> <vi>You can call me any time, <it>day</it> or night.</vi> <vi>These animals are mostly active during the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I work during the <it>day</it>. [=I work days]</vi> <vi>She's a student <phrase>by day</phrase> [=during the day] and a waitress by night.</vi> <vi>I woke at (the) <phrase>break of day</phrase>. [=(more commonly) <it>dawn, daybreak, sunrise</it>]</vi> <vi><phrase>day workers</phrase> [=people who work during the day]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>night</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of the day when people are usually most active and when most businesses are open <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>I like to start my <it>day</it> with a cup of coffee. [=I like to drink a cup of coffee as soon as I wake up]</vi> <vi>We decided to rent a car for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>How was your <it>day</it>?</vi> <vi>By the end of the <it>day</it>, we were all exhausted.</vi> <vi>Our neighbors play their loud music <phrase>at all hours of the day</phrase>. [=throughout the day]</vi> <vi>Let's go to bed. We have an <phrase>early day</phrase> [=we will get out of bed early] tomorrow.</vi> <vi>I needed to relax after a <phrase>long day</phrase> at work/school. [=after working/being at school for a long time]</vi> <vi>“Thank you, ma'am. <phrase>Have a nice day</phrase>!”</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I'll be gone <phrase>all day</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It rained <phrase>all day long</phrase>.</vi> <snote>People sometimes say that they <phrase>can't wait all day</phrase> or <phrase>don't have all day</phrase> when they are in a hurry and need someone to move or act more quickly. These phrases are usually used in a rude way. <vi>Hurry up! I <it>can't wait all day</it>! = I <it>don't have all day</it>. = I <it>haven't got all day</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hours during a day when a person works or goes to school or when a company does business <vi>I put in four twelve-hour <it>days</it> [=<it>workdays</it>] this week.</vi> <vi>She makes about 50 dollars a/per <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>He was late for his first <it>day</it> on the job.</vi> <vi>They collected a full <it>day</it>'s pay for half a <it>day</it>'s work.</vi> <vi>We had a busy couple of <it>days</it> at the store.</vi> <vi>We have a short <it>day</it> tomorrow. [=we have to work fewer hours tomorrow than usual]</vi> <vi>The school committee is pushing for a longer school <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow's our last <it>day</it> of school (for the school year).</vi> <vi>Please allow 14 <phrase>business days</phrase> [=days when most businesses are open; weekdays that are not holidays] for delivery.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>all in a day's work</phrase> for someone, it is part of a person's typical work. <vi>Solving violent crimes is <it>all in a day's work</it> for these police detectives.</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>take a/the day off</phrase> is to decide not to work on a particular day. <vi>He <it>took the day off</it> to go fishing.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the day on which something specified happens or is expected to happen <vi>It rained on their wedding <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>day</it> of his birth</vi> <vi>This Sunday is <phrase>family day</phrase> [=a day for families especially with young children] at the amusement park.</vi> <vi>If you've been waiting for the perfect skiing conditions, <phrase>today's the day</phrase>. [=the conditions are perfect today]</vi> <vi>So, when's <phrase>the big day</phrase>? When are you getting married?</vi> <vi>Did you ever think you'd <phrase>see the day</phrase> when he would apologize? [=did you believe he would ever apologize?]</vi> <vi>I never thought I would <phrase>live to see the day</phrase> when you would graduate from college. [=I did not think I would live long enough to see you graduate]</vi> <vi>Let her have her <phrase>day in court</phrase> [=let her defend herself in a court of law] before you pass judgment on her.</vi> <vi>This is <phrase>your lucky day</phrase>. [=a day when something good happens to you]</vi> <snote>If a day <phrase>is your day</phrase>, something good will happen to you on that day. <vi>You never know. Maybe today will <it>be my day</it>. [=maybe I will succeed, win, etc., today]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry you lost. I guess it just <it>wasn't your day</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>People sometimes use the phrase <phrase>that'll be the day</phrase> to say that they think something will not happen. <vi>“Do you think he'll ever admit he made a mistake?” “<it>That'll be the day</it>!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular period of time <vi>She was the most talented actress of her <it>day</it>. [=during the time when she lived and worked as an actress]</vi> <vi><phrase>In my day</phrase> [=when I was young], boys asked girls out on dates, not the other way around.</vi> <vi>Life was simpler <it>in my grandmother's day</it>, but it wasn't easier.</vi> <vi>We sell books dating from 1875 to <phrase>the present day</phrase>. [=<it>today</it>]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He often spoke about his <it>days</it> as a soldier.</vi> <vi>I was quite an athlete in my younger <it>days</it>. [=when I was young]</vi> <vi>The practice dates back to the <it>days</it> of ancient Rome.</vi> <vi>the olden <it>days</it></vi> <vi>my college <it>days</it> [=when I was in college]</vi> <vi>the <it>days</it> of stagecoaches [=when stagecoaches were used]</vi> <vi>In those <it>days</it> many factory workers were children.</vi></un> <snote>The saying <phrase>those were the days</phrase> is sometimes used to say that a period of time in the past was pleasant and often better than the present time. <vi>When I was a kid, we spent our summers at the beach. <it>Those were the days</it>!</vi> <vi>In the 1960s, everything seemed possible. Those were <phrase>the good old days</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) the livelong day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>livelong</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any day now</dre> <def><dt>:within the next few days :<sx>soon</sx> <vi>We're expecting a phone call from him <it>any day now</it>. [=in the near future]</vi> <vi><it>Any day now</it>, the decision could be made.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the end of the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call it a day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>call</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry/win the day</dre> <def><dt>:to win or be successful <vi>The “no” vote <it>carried the day</it>. [=<it>prevailed</it>]</vi> <vi>We believe that truth and justice will <it>carry/win the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day after day</dre> <def><dt>:for several days without stopping or changing <vi>She wore the same pants <it>day after day</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Day after day</it>, we hear the same complaints from our customers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day and night</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>night and day</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:all the time :without stopping <vi>We've been working on it <it>day and night</it>. = We've been working on it <it>night and day</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:complete or total <vi>The difference between them is <it>day and night</it>. = The difference between them is <it>night and day</it>. [=they are completely different]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day by day</dre> <def><dt>:in small amounts every day <vi><it>Day by day</it>, the situation is becoming more complex.</vi> <vi>She felt herself growing stronger <it>day by day</it>. [=every day]</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>take it/things day by day</phrase>, you make progress in a slow and careful way by dealing with each day as it comes. <vi>He hopes to make a full recovery after his surgery, but right now he's just <it>taking it day by day</it>. [=<it>taking it one day at a time</it>, <it>taking each day as it comes</it>]</vi> <vi>I don't know if our relationship is going to work out. I'm <it>taking things day by day</it> at this point.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day in, day out</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>day in and day out</va></vr> <def><dt>:every day for many days :for a long time without stopping or changing <vi>She does the same thing at her job <it>day in</it>, <it>day out</it>.</vi> <vi>It can be difficult to spend all of your time with one person <it>day in and day out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>days are numbered</dre> <dx>see <dxt>number</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>early days (yet)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>early</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every dog has its day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for a rainy day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rainy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from day to day</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>His opinions seem to change <it>from day to day</it>. [=<it>from one day to the next</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>day-to-day</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from one day to the next</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>She changes her mind <it>from one day to the next</it>. [=<it>from day to day</it>]</vi> :as one day becomes another day <vi>You never know <it>from one day to the next</it> what's going to happen to you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the time of day</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to pay attention to someone <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>No one would <it>give us the time of day</it>.</vi> <vi>I needed their help, but they wouldn't <it>give me the time of day</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>glory days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>glory</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have seen/known better days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in all your born days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the cold light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in this day and age</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time in history <vi>Computers are essential to getting work done <it>in this day and age</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>It's unbelievable that <it>in this day and age</it> people are still dying from hunger.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>it is not every day</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something happens very rarely <vi><it>It's not every day</it> that I get to meet the President.</vi> <vi>Go ahead and spend the extra money. <it>It's not every day</it> that you get married.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>late in the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>late</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's day</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's day to be pleasant or happy <vi>Thanks for the compliment. You've really <it>made my day</it>!</vi> <vi>It <it>made my day</it> to see his smiling face.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of the day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:served in a restaurant as a special item on a particular day <vi>What's the fish/vegetable <it>of the day</it>?</vi> <vi>Our soup <it>of the day</it> [=<it>du jour</it>] is vegetable beef.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:of a particular period of time <vi>What were some of the popular movies <it>of the day</it>? [=that were popular during that time]</vi> <vi>the important issues <it>of the day</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at some time in the future <vi><it>One day</it>, it'll happen. You'll see.</vi> <vi>People may <it>one day</it> [=<it>someday</it>] be able to take vacations to the moon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:on a day in the past <vi>I went to her house <it>one day</it> and had lunch with her.</vi> <vi><it>One day</it>, we had a terrible argument.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the day</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:on the day that an event happens <vi>I know we seem a bit disorganized now, but we'll be all right <it>on the day</it>.</vi> <vi>Whether we win or not depends on which players are healthy <it>on the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>some day</dre> <def><dt>:at some time in the future :<sx>someday</sx> <vi><it>Some day</it> I may be rich enough to own two houses.</vi> <vi>I'd like to return there <it>some day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take each day as it comes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take one day at a time</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>take it/things one day at a time</va></vr> <def><dt>:to deal with each day's problems as they come instead of worrying about the future <vi>There's no way to know what the future will bring, so just <it>take each day as it comes</it> and hope for the best.</vi> <vi><it>Take one day at a time</it> and don't expect things to change overnight.</vi> <vi>It's important to <it>take things one day at a time</it> so you don't feel too overwhelmed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the other day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>other</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>these days</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time <vi>It seems that everyone has a cell phone <it>these days</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>What kind of music are you listening to <it>these days</it>?</vi> <vi><it>These days</it>, she has a very busy social life.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>one of these days</phrase> means at some time in the future. <vi><it>One of these days</it>, [=<it>one day</it>] I'm going to buy myself a boat.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>those days</dre> <def><dt>:a period of time in the past <vi>Remember when we were kids and life was easy? Well, <it>those days</it> are gone.</vi> <vi><phrase>In those days</phrase>, women weren't allowed to own property.</vi> <vi>No one knew <it>in those days</it> what caused the disease.</vi> <snote>If it is (<phrase>just) one of those days</phrase>, it is a day in which many bad or unpleasant things happen. <vi>It's <it>just one of those days</it> when everything seems to go wrong.</vi> <vi>I missed the bus and sprained my ankle; it was <it>one of those days</it> when nothing was going right.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the day</dre> <def><dt>:to exactly a specified number of years <vi>It's been 100 years <it>to the day</it> since their great discovery.</vi> <vi>Soon after their wedding, almost a year <it>to the day</it>, they got divorced.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to this day</dre> <def><dt>:up to now :continuing until today <vi><it>To this day</it>, I still don't know what happened.</vi> <vi>The belief persists <it>to this day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="late[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">late</hw> <sound><wav>late0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈleɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>lat*er</if></in> <in><if>lat*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:existing or happening near the end of a period of time <vi>It happened in <it>late</it> spring.</vi> <vi>His health problems began when he was in his <it>late</it> thirties. [=when he was about 38 or 39 years old]</vi> <vi>The problems began in the <it>late</it> 1930s. [=in about 1938 or 1939]</vi> <vi>a word first recorded in the <it>late</it> 17th century</vi> <vi>It was <it>late</it> (in the evening) when we finally went to bed.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>early</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>later</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:coming or happening after the usual, expected, or desired time <vi>The train is (a half hour) <it>late</it>.</vi> <vi>We had a <it>late</it> spring this year.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I'm <it>late</it>.</vi> <vi>He made a <it>late</it> payment. = He was <it>late</it> with his payment. = He was <it>late</it> (in) paying.</vi> <vi>Hurry up or we'll be <it>late</it> for school.</vi> <vi>We arrived late because we <phrase>got/had/made a late start</phrase>. [=we started at a later time than we had meant to]</vi> <vi>Their warning was <phrase>too late</phrase> to help him.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>early</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:doing something after the usual time or before others usually do <vi>I've always been a <it>late</it> riser.</vi> <vi>a <it>late</it> walker [=a child who learned to walk at a later age than most other children]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>early</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:living until recently :not now living <vi>He made a donation to the school in memory of his <it>late</it> wife.</vi> <vi>the <it>late</it> John Smith</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>born too late</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>it's getting late</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that time is passing and especially that evening or late evening is coming <vi><it>It's getting late</it> so we should probably go home.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>late bloomer</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bloomer</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>late in the day</dre> <def><dt>:after the expected or proper time <vi>It's rather <it>late in the day</it> for an apology now, don't you think? [=it's late for an apology; you should have apologized sooner]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>late night</dre> <def><dt>:a night when you stay awake until a late hour <vi>We're tired today because we <phrase>had a late night</phrase> [=stayed up late] last night.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>late-night</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>late*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>lateness</it> of the hour</vi> <vi>the <it>lateness</it> of the payment</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="manner"> <hw highlight="yes">man*ner</hw> <sound><wav>manner01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmænɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>man*ners</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:the way that something is done or happens <vi>She has a very forceful <it>manner</it> of speaking.</vi> <vi>I objected to the <it>manner</it> in which the decision was made.</vi> <un>often used after <it>in</it> <vi>Continue stirring <it>in</it> this <it>manner</it> until the sauce thickens.</vi> <vi><it>In</it> this <it>manner</it>, we were able to save enough money for a new car.</vi> <vi><it>In</it> what <it>manner</it> was the data collected? [=how was the data collected?]</vi> <vi>We worked <it>in</it> a quick <it>manner</it>. [=we worked quickly]</vi> <vi>She taught her class <it>in</it> an informal <it>manner</it>.</vi> <vi>He always begins his stories <it>in</it> the same <it>manner</it>.</vi> <vi>We were allowed to spend the money <it>in</it> any <it>manner</it> we wanted.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the way that a person normally behaves especially while with other people <un>usually singular <vi>He had a gentle <it>manner</it> (about him).</vi> <vi>He listened patiently to his children, as was his <it>manner</it>.</vi> <vi>It was her energetic and friendly <it>manner</it> that got her the job.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bedside manner</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>manners</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:behavior while with other people <vi>His children have excellent <it>manners</it>. [=his children behave very well]</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>bad manners</phrase> [=it is impolite] to talk with your mouth full.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>manners</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:knowledge of how to behave politely while with other people <vi>Some people have no <it>manners</it>.</vi> <vi>Someone should teach you some <it>manners</it>!</vi> <vi>He <phrase>forgot his manners</phrase> and reached across the table for the salt.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>remember/mind your manners</phrase> is to behave in a polite and proper way. <vi>“<it>Mind your manners</it>,” Mom said sternly, “and thank your uncle for the nice gifts.”</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>table manners</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:an artistic style or method <vi>He painted this picture in his early <it>manner</it>.</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>in/after the manner of</phrase> <vi>She wrote <it>after the manner of</it> [=in the style of] her favorite poet.</vi> <vi>This church was built <it>in the manner of</it> the English Gothic style.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>all manner of</dre> <def><dt>:all kinds or sorts of (things or people) <vi>The store sells <it>all manner of</it> musical instruments.</vi> <vi><it>All manner of</it> people come to the city.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a manner of speaking</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a statement is true or accurate in a certain way even if it is not literally or completely true <vi>His retirement was, <it>in a manner of speaking</it>, the beginning of his real career.</vi> <vi>After the storm destroyed their house, they were, <it>in a manner of speaking</it> [=<it>so to speak, as it were</it>], lost at sea. [=they felt lost and confused after their house was destroyed]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not by any manner of means</dre> <dx>see <dxt>means</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the manner born</dre> <def><dt>:suited to a particular position, role, or status in a way that seems very natural <vi>He had never been on a boat before, but he walked along the deck as if <it>to the manner born</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what manner of</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned + literary</sl> <dt>:what kind or sort of <vi><it>What manner of</it> person could have committed such a crime?</vi> <vi><it>What manner of</it> woman is she to have done something like that?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="manor"> <hw>man*or</hw> <sound><wav>manor001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmænɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>man*ors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a large country house on a large piece of land</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the area or section of a city that a particular group of police officers are responsible for</dt></def> <dro><dre>to the manor born</dre> <def><dt>:born into a wealthy family that has a high social status</dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>ma*no*ri*al</ure> <sound><wav>manor002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>məˈnorijəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>manorial</it> landowners/estates</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="mouth[1]"> <art><artref id="mouth_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>100,76</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">mouth</hw> <sound><wav>mouth001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmaʊθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>mouths</if> <sound><wav>mouth002.wav</wav><wav>mouth003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmaʊðz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the opening through which food passes into the body :the part of the face that includes the lips and the opening behind them <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He kissed her on the <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>He threatened to punch me in the <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>She stood there with her <it>mouth</it> agape/open.</vi> <vi>I burned the roof of my <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>They told him to keep his <it>mouth</it> closed when chewing and not to talk with his <it>mouth</it> full.</vi> <vi>He wiped his <it>mouth</it> with a napkin after eating.</vi> <vi>She regretted saying it as soon as the words were out of her <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>The smell of the food made my <it>mouth</it> water.</vi> <vi>The candy melts in your <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>He says something stupid <phrase>every time he opens his mouth</phrase>. [=every time he speaks]</vi> <vi>The experience <phrase>left a bad taste in my mouth</phrase>. [=the experience left me feeling bad or disgusted]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The medication is taken <phrase>by mouth</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an opening in something <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>the <it>mouth of</it> a cave/bottle</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>goal mouth</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where a river enters the ocean <vi>the <it>mouth</it> of the river = the river's <it>mouth</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an unpleasant or offensive way of talking <vi>That guy has quite a <it>mouth</it> on him.</vi> <vi>He has a loud <it>mouth</it>.</vi> <vi>He cursed and his mother angrily told him to <phrase>watch his mouth</phrase>. [=to not use offensive language]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>big mouth</dxt> <dxt>loudmouth</dxt> <dxt>smart-mouth</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>all mouth (and no trousers/action)</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe someone who talks a lot about doing something but never actually does it</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>born with a silver spoon in your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>butter wouldn't melt in someone's mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>butter</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>by word of mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>down in the mouth</dre> <def><dt>:unhappy or depressed <vi>I was surprised to see her looking so <it>down in the mouth</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>foam at the mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foam</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from the horse's mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>froth at the mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>froth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hand to mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>heart in your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your mouth shut</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not say anything <vi>When he starts talking about politics, I just <it>keep my mouth shut</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to not talk about something (such as a secret) <vi>She told me to <it>keep my mouth shut</it> about the news. [=she told me not to tell anyone about the news]</vi> <vi>I never tell him anything important because he doesn't know how to <it>keep his mouth shut</it>. [=he tells other people what he has been told]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>look a gift horse in the mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>melt in your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>melt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>mouth to feed</dre> <def><dt>:a person (such as a child) who needs to be fed <vi>They can't afford another child. They already have too many (hungry) <it>mouths to feed</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put words in/into someone's mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your foot in your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put your money where your mouth is</dre> <dx>see <dxt>money</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>run your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>run</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>shoot your mouth off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shoot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>shut your mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take the words right out of someone's mouth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="one[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">one</hw> <altpr>ˈwʌn</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:that person or thing <vi>“I'll have an iced tea, please.” “I'll have <it>one</it>, too.”</vi> <vi>Their dog died, but they plan to get another <it>one</it>.</vi> <vi>“You should wear the blue <it>one</it>.” “The <it>one</it> with the stripes?” “No, the other <it>one</it>.”</vi> <vi>I'd like to see the ring next to that <it>one</it>.</vi> <vi>Which <it>one</it> did you like better?</vi> <vi>He is the <it>one</it> who called the police.</vi> <vi>Have you heard <phrase>the one about</phrase> [=the joke about] the priest and the rabbi?</vi> <vi>That's one possible answer—but not the <phrase>only one</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He had <phrase>one too many</phrase> at the bar last night. [=he had too many alcoholic drinks at the bar]</vi> <snote>This sense of <it>one</it> can be used in the plural form <phrase>ones</phrase>. <vi>The <it>ones</it> on the team who are most successful practice every day.</vi> <vi>Those batteries are the <it>ones</it> that still work.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:someone or something that is a part of a particular group <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi>I met <it>one of</it> your friends at the party.</vi> <vi>She is <it>one of</it> the best players on the team.</vi> <vi><it>One of</it> the puppies has a brown patch around its eye.</vi> <vi>He'll come back <phrase>one of these days</phrase>. [=<it>someday</it>]</vi> <vi>Don't worry—he's <phrase>one of us</phrase>. [=he is part of our group and can be trusted]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:people in general :any person <vi><it>One</it> never knows [=(more commonly) you never know] what the weather will be.</vi> <vi>It is now possible to buy just about anything from the privacy of <it>one's</it> [=(more commonly) <it>your</it>] own home.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:I or we <vi>I would like to read more, but <it>one</it> doesn't have the time.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>one after another</dre> <dx>see <dxt>another</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>one and all</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:<sx>everyone</sx> <vi>Merry Christmas to <it>one and all</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one by one</dre> <def><dt>:separately in a series <vi>The performers took the stage <it>one by one</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one in a million</dre> <dx>see <dxt>million</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>there's one born every minute</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>no one</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
