<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bottom[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tom</hw> <sound><wav>bottom01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:təm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*toms</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the lowest part, point, or level of something <un>usually singular <vi>He's waiting at the <it>bottom</it> of the stairs.</vi> <vi>Our house is at the <it>bottom</it> of the hill.</vi> <vi>The top of the wall is painted and the <it>bottom</it> is covered in wood paneling.</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the page/screen/list</vi> <vi>Please fill out this form and sign your name at the <it>bottom</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of something that is below or under the other parts <un>usually singular <vi>the ship's <it>bottom</it> [=<it>underside</it>]</vi> <vi>The bowl was signed on the <it>bottom</it> [=<it>base</it>] by the artist.</vi> <vi>There's a small cut on the <it>bottom</it> [=<it>sole</it>] of his foot.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the lowest point or surface inside something :the part of something hollow that is furthest from the top <un>usually singular <vi>I think there is still a little sugar left in the <it>bottom</it> of the box/container.</vi> <vi>The pool is so deep I could not touch the <it>bottom</it>.</vi> <vi>One of the drawers has a <phrase>false bottom</phrase>. [=a panel that looks like the drawer's bottom but that can be removed to expose more space]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:the part of something that is furthest away <vi>We sailed to the <it>bottom</it> of the bay.</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the garden</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body on which you sit :<sx>buttocks</sx> <vi>The poor baby has a rash all over his little <it>bottom</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a position of little power in a company or organization <vi>The company's new CEO started at the <it>bottom</it> and worked her way up.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a low rank or position <vi>Why do I always find myself rooting for the team at the <it>bottom</it> of the league?</vi> <vi>She graduated <phrase>at the bottom of her/the class</phrase>. [=her grades were among the lowest in her graduating class]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the worst position, level, or condition <vi>at the <it>bottom</it> of the pay scale</vi> <vi>After weeks of losing value, the company's stocks have <phrase>hit bottom</phrase>. [=reached the bottom; lost all value]</vi> <vi>Jim has finally <phrase>scraped bottom</phrase>. [=has finally reached the worst possible condition]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rock bottom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the surface that is under a body of water <vi>the <it>bottom</it> of the ocean</vi> <vi>the sandy river/lake <it>bottom</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>bottoms</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the flat, low land along a river or stream :<sx>bottomland</sx> <vi>grazing in grassy river <it>bottoms</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of clothing that is worn on the lower part of the body <vi>a bikini <it>bottom</it></vi> <un>often plural <vi>pajama <it>bottoms</it></vi></un> <dx>see color picture on page C13</dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the second half of an inning in baseball <vi>They tied the score in the <it>bottom</it> of the ninth inning.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:the lowest gear of a car <vi>Stay in <it>bottom</it> [=<it>bottom gear</it>] until you reach the top of the hill.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at bottom</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:in reality :<sx>really</sx> <vi>The song is, <it>at bottom</it> [=<it>in truth</it>], a lullaby.</vi> <vi>He is very shy, <it>at bottom</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the bottom of the pile</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pile</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>be/lie at the bottom of</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to be the source or originator of (something) <vi>I think I know who's <it>at the bottom of</it> [=<it>behind</it>] these pranks.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bottoms up</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a toast or to tell people to finish their drinks <vi>Here's to the groom-to-be! <it>Bottoms up</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from the bottom of your heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from top to bottom</dre> <dx>see <dxt>top</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get to the bottom of</dre> <def><dt>:to find out the true reason for or cause of (something) <vi>Police are working furiously to <it>get to the bottom of</it> this recent string of violent crimes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the bottom drop/fall out</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>the bottom drops/falls out</it> of something, it suddenly fails or becomes unable to continue in a normal and effective way. <vi>Analysts warn that recent changes in the region may result in <it>the bottom dropping out</it> of the oil market. [=may cause the oil market to collapse]</vi> <vi>When the accident happened, she felt <it>the bottom drop out</it> of her world. [=she felt her world collapse]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the bottom of the barrel</dre> <def><dt>:the lowest possible condition, level, etc. <vi>After the divorce, Tim felt he had reached/hit <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>.</vi> <vi>The excessive coverage of the scandal signals that the news media may have finally hit/reached <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>.</vi> <vi>Salaries in the industry are scraping/hitting <it>the bottom of the barrel</it>. [=salaries in the industry are very low]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tomed</ure> <sound><wav>bottom02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:təmd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>flat <it>bottomed</it> boats</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bottom[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bottom</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:təm</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in the lowest position <vi>the <it>bottom</it> rung of the ladder</vi> <vi>the <it>bottom</it> drawer/shelf</vi> <vi>her <it>bottom</it> lip</vi> <vi>Somebody's fingerprints are all along the <it>bottom</it> edge of the photograph.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottom line</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:living at the lowest level of an ocean or lake <vi><it>bottom</it> fish</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bet your bottom dollar</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bet</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bottom[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bottom</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:təm</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bottoms</if></in> <in><if>bottomed</if></in> <in><if>bottom*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>bottom out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to reach a lowest or worst point usually before beginning to rise or improve <vi>Real estate prices seem to have <it>bottomed out</it>, and sellers can expect to get higher prices in coming months.</vi> <vi>The team <it>bottomed out</it> in last place.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bottom drawer"> <hw>bottom drawer</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>hope chest</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottom feeder"> <hw>bottom feeder</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a fish that feeds at the bottom of a lake, pond, etc.</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>disapproving</ssl> <dt>:someone who uses other people's troubles, weakness, etc., as an opportunity to make money <vi>After his daughter's tragic death, he was hounded by media <it>bottom feeders</it> who demanded exclusive interviews.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:someone or something that has a very low status or rank <vi>In a surprise upset, the all-star team lost to one of the league's <it>bottom feeders</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottom gear"> <hw>bottom gear</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:low gear :a vehicle's lowest gear</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottom line"> <hw>bottom line</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <bnote>the bottom line</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the most important part of something :the most important thing to consider <vi><it>The bottom line</it> [=all that matters] is that the product just wasn't practical.</vi> <vi>If our flight is late, we will miss our connection. That's <it>the bottom line</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the final result or outcome <vi>A student with special needs can stress a school's budget, but <it>the bottom line</it> is that the state must provide for the child's education.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a company's profits or losses <vi>How will these changes affect our <it>bottom line</it>?</vi> <vi>He's always got his eye on the <it>bottom line</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the least amount of money you are willing to consider for something <vi>He says his <it>bottom line</it> is $120,000.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottom-up"> <hw>bot*tom–up</hw> <sound><wav>botto05v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:təmˈʌp</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:progressing upward from the lowest levels :controlled or directed from the lower levels <vi><it>bottom-up</it> management</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>top-down</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Foggy Bottom"> <hw>Foggy Bottom</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the U.S. Department of State</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="rock bottom"> <hw>rock bottom</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the lowest possible level or point <vi>Prices have <phrase>hit/reached rock bottom</phrase>. [=have reached the lowest point they can reach]</vi> <vi>After years of heavy drug use, she has finally <it>reached rock bottom</it>.</vi> <vi>Their marriage has <it>hit rock bottom</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
