<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bottle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tle</hw> <sound><wav>bottle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*tles</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a glass or plastic container that has a narrow neck and usually has no handle <snote>Bottles are usually used to store liquid or tablets. <vi>Shall I open another <it>bottle</it> of wine?</vi> <vi>There's a <it>bottle</it> of aspirin in the cabinet.</vi> <vi>empty soda <it>bottles</it></vi> <vi>She kept a <it>bottle</it> [=a bottle of some strong alcoholic drink like whiskey] tucked away in the coat closet.</vi> <vi>Be sure to bring a <phrase>water bottle</phrase> [=bottle containing water] on your hike.</vi> <vi>Would you get me the <phrase>bottle opener</phrase> [=a tool used to remove metal tops from some bottles], please?</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount contained in a bottle <vi>We drank a <it>bottle</it> of wine.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the bottle</bnote> <dt>:alcoholic drink <vi>He says he's lost too many years to <it>the bottle</it>, and that he's giving up alcohol.</vi> <vi>Her struggles with <it>the bottle</it> affected her entire family.</vi> <vi>I hear he's <phrase>(gone) off the bottle</phrase>. [=stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>After his divorce he <phrase>took to the bottle</phrase>. [=began to drink a lot of alcohol]</vi> <vi>When she gets depressed she <phrase>hits the bottle</phrase>. [=begins drinking a lot of alcohol]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a special bottle for feeding babies that contains milk or a drink which contains milk <vi>Has the baby finished her <it>bottle</it> yet?</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) a baby <it>bottle</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a baby's <it>bottle</it></vi> <vi>raised on a <it>bottle</it> instead of breast milk</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottle-feed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:courage or strength of spirit <vi>I don't think he's got <it>bottle</it> [=<it>guts</it>] enough to confront them.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring your own bottle</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bring a bottle</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to tell the people who are invited to a party that they should bring their own alcoholic drinks</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch/capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tle*ful</ure> <sound><wav>bottle02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟ˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>singular</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bottleful</it> of water</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bottle[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bottle</hw> <altpr>ˈbɑ:tl̟</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bottles</if></in> <in><if>bot*tled</if></in> <in><if>bot*tling</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to put (something) into a bottle so that it can be sold or so that it is easier to use <vi>The restaurant <it>bottles</it> its own ginger ale.</vi> <vi>Near the top of the mountain, the climbers relied on <it>bottled</it> oxygen to breathe.</vi> <vi><it>bottled</it> water</vi> <vi><phrase>bottled gas</phrase> [=gas that is stored in containers for people to use in heating their homes or for cooking]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to put (fruit or vegetables) in a jar using a special procedure that preserves them <vi>At the end of summer we <it>bottle</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>can, preserve, put up</it>] tomatoes from the garden.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bottle out</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit slang</sl> <dt>:to become too afraid to do something :to lose your nerve <vi>I was going to ask him but then I <it>bottled out</it>. [=<it>chickened out</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bottle up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>bottle (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>bottle up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (a feeling or emotion) inside of you instead of expressing it :to hide (a feeling or emotion) <vi>She's kept her feelings about the accident <it>bottled up</it> for too long.</vi> <vi>I know he's angry, but he <it>bottles</it> it <it>up</it> inside instead of talking to someone about it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tler</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*tlers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>soft drink <it>bottlers</it></vi> <vi>the region's best known wine <it>bottler</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bottle bank"> <hw>bottle bank</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ banks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a large container that people put empty bottles in so that the glass or plastic the bottles are made from can be used again</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottle blond"> <hw>bottle blond</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ blonds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person whose hair has been made blond by using chemicals</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottle-feed"> <hw>bot*tle–feed</hw> <sound><wav>bottle06.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟ˌfi:d</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bot*tle–feeds</if></in> <in><if>bot*tle–fed</if></in> <in><if>bot*tle–feed*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to feed (a baby or young animal) with a bottle instead of from its mother's breast <vi>All her children were <it>bottle-fed</it>.</vi> <vi>We had to <it>bottle-feed</it> the kitten.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>breast-feed</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottle green"> <hw>bottle green</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a green color <snote>In the U.S., bottle green is usually a medium green color. In British English, it is usually a dark green color.</snote></dt></def> <uro><ure>bottle–green</ure> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="hot-water bottle"> <hw>hot–water bottle</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bottles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a rubber container that is filled with hot water and used to warm a bed or a part of your body</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="squeeze bottle"> <hw>squeeze bottle</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tles</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a plastic bottle that forces out its contents when it is squeezed :a squeezable bottle</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="capture[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cap*ture</hw> <sound><wav>captur01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæptʃɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cap*tures</if></in> <in><if>cap*tured</if></in> <in><if>cap*tur*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to take and hold (someone) as a prisoner especially by using force <vi>They were <it>captured</it> by enemy soldiers.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to catch (an animal) <vi>using traps to <it>capture</it> mice</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to get control of (a place) especially by using force <vi>The city was <it>captured</it> by the Romans.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to win or get (something) through effort <vi>She <it>captured</it> 60 percent of the vote in the last election.</vi> <vi>The company plans on <it>capturing</it> a larger segment of the market.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to get and hold (someone's attention, interest, etc.) <vi>The show has <it>captured</it> the attention/interest of teenagers.</vi> <vi>The story <phrase>captured our imaginations</phrase>. [=the story was very interesting and exciting]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to describe or show (someone or something) in a very accurate way by using writing, painting, film, etc. <vi>The story <it>captures</it> the essence of the holiday.</vi> <vi>The biography <it>captured</it> her perfectly.</vi> <vi>The beauty of the landscape was <it>captured</it> perfectly by the artist.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to record (something) in a picture, film, etc. <vi>The robbery was <it>captured</it> (on film) by the security cameras.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get and put (information) into a form that can be read or used by a computer <vi>The system is used to <it>capture</it> data relating to the buying habits of young people.</vi> <vi>a digital camera that <it>captures</it> 1.2 million pixels</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to take (something, such as a chess piece) by following the rules of a game <vi>In the game of chess, the goal is to <it>capture</it> your opponent's king.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="catch[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">catch</hw> <sound><wav>catch001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃ, ˈkɛtʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>catch*es</if></in> <in><if>caught</if> <sound><wav>catch002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>catch*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use your hands to stop and hold (an object that is moving through the air) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Catch</it> the ball and throw it to first base.</vi> <vi>She <it>caught</it> the ball with one hand.</vi> <vi>I dropped the book but managed to <it>catch</it> it before it hit the ground.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll throw you the keys. Ready? <it>Catch</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use your hands to grasp and hold onto (someone or something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>, <it>seized</it>] her by the wrist.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>caught hold of</phrase> her wrist.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to capture and not allow (a person, animal, or fish) to escape <vi>The police are working hard to <it>catch</it> the criminals and put them in jail.</vi> <vi>“I bet you can't <it>catch</it> me!” she yelled to her brother.</vi> <vi>I once <it>caught</it> 10 fish in a single day.</vi> <vi>In the summer, we would <it>catch</it> fireflies and put them in jars.</vi> <vi><it>catching</it> mice in traps</vi> <vi>lions <it>catching</it> their prey</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage to find, meet, or reach (someone) at a particular time or in a particular state or condition <vi>I <it>caught</it> her just as she was leaving for work.</vi> <vi>I'm afraid you've <it>caught</it> me at a bad time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find (someone who is doing something wrong) <vi>The police <it>caught</it> him trying to steal the painting.</vi> <vi>My teacher <it>caught</it> me cheating on a test.</vi> <vi>Her father <it>caught</it> her smoking in the basement.</vi> <vi>You'd never <it>catch</it> me doing that! [=I would never do that]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>caught him in the act</phrase> (of stealing the painting). = He was <phrase>caught red-handed</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to affect (someone) in a sudden and surprising way <vi>They were <phrase>caught unprepared</phrase> by the crisis. = The crisis <phrase>caught them unawares</phrase>. [=they were not prepared when the crisis occurred]</vi> <vi>The announcement <phrase>caught me by surprise</phrase>. [=I was surprised by the announcement]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to suddenly stop (yourself) before you do something <vi>Luckily, he <it>caught</it> himself before he gave away the secret.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suddenly become aware that you are doing something <vi>He <it>caught</it> himself staring at her.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be stopped, delayed, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be/get) caught</it> <vi>We <it>got caught</it> in a rain storm and had to find shelter.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I'm late. I <it>was caught</it> in traffic.</vi> <vi>We <phrase>got caught up in</phrase> traffic and were late for our flight.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>caught up in <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to become stuck and unable to move <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>caught</it> my sleeve on a nail.</vi> <vi>The kite got <it>caught</it> [=<it>tangled</it>] in the tree.</vi> <vi>She tried to stand up, but her foot was <it>caught</it> in the strap.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My sleeve <it>caught</it> on a nail.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the parts connect firmly <vi>I tried to lock the door, but the lock wouldn't <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop and hold (falling water) <vi>They kept a bucket outside to <it>catch</it> the rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become covered with (something that moves through the air) <vi>These curtains <it>catch</it> a lot of dust.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hit or touch (someone or something) <vi>The bullet <it>caught</it> him in the leg.</vi> <vi>His last punch <it>caught</it> me in the jaw.</vi> <vi>Isn't it beautiful the way the setting sun <it>catches</it> the tips of the trees?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be hit or touched by (something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> a bullet in the leg.</vi> <vi>The tips of the trees <it>catch</it> the light as the sun sets.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become affected with (a sickness or disease) <vi>We both <it>caught</it> [=<it>contracted</it>] the flu.</vi> <vi>I seem to <it>catch</it> a cold every winter.</vi> <vi>children <it>catching</it> colds from each other</vi> <snote>When people say that you will <phrase>catch your death (of cold)</phrase>, they mean that you will become sick or catch a very bad cold. <vi>It's freezing! You'll <it>catch your death</it> if you go out without a coat!</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to feel excitement or interest about something <vi>I haven't <it>caught</it> the holiday spirit yet this year.</vi> <vi>People are getting really interested in the sport. The whole country is starting to <phrase>catch the fever</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to attract and hold (someone's attention, interest, etc.) <vi>I tried to <it>catch</it> the waiter's attention, but I guess he didn't see me.</vi> <vi>The show is more likely to <it>catch</it> the interest of an older audience.</vi> <vi>Her books have <phrase>caught the imagination</phrase> of children from around the world. [=children find her books very exciting and enjoyable]</vi> <snote>If someone or something <phrase>catches your eye</phrase>, you notice that person or thing. <vi>There was one dress in particular that <it>caught my eye</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>eye-catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see, smell, or notice (something) <vi>I <it>caught</it> [=<it>got</it>] a faint whiff of her perfume.</vi> <vi>While you're in Hollywood, you might <phrase>catch a glimpse</phrase> of some movie stars.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>caught sight</phrase> of his red shirt and started calling to him.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to hear or understand (something) <vi>What was that again? I didn't quite <it>catch</it> [=<it>hear, get</it>] what you said.</vi> <vi>I didn't <it>catch</it> your name.</vi> <vi>Do you <phrase>catch my drift</phrase>? [=do you understand what I mean?]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become aware of (something, such as an illness) <vi>The disease is curable if <it>caught</it> [=<it>detected</it>] early.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or do (something) <vi>You can <it>catch</it> [=<it>take</it>] a quick nap on the train.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get (something) through effort <vi>I managed to <it>catch</it> [=<it>get</it>] a ride into town with some friends.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>“See you soon.” “Yup. <phrase>Catch you later</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move fast enough to be next to or in front of (someone) <vi>She <it>caught</it> [=<it>overtook</it>] the leader in the final meters of the race.</vi> <vi>He left before I did so I had to hurry to <it>catch</it> him. [=to catch up with him]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get on a bus, train, etc., before it leaves <vi>If you miss the first bus, you can <it>catch</it> the next one in 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>If you'll excuse me, I have a plane to <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see or hear (a show, game, etc.) <vi>I only <it>caught</it> the last few minutes of the game.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>catch</it> the show on Channel 4 last night?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to describe or show (someone or something) in an accurate way in art <vi>The new portrait <it>catches</it> her likeness perfectly.</vi> <vi>The novel successfully <it>catches</it> the atmosphere of 19th-century Paris.</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to play the position of catcher <vi>He <it>catches</it> for the New York Yankees.</vi> <vi>If you pitch, I'll <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>catch at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach for and try to hold (something) <vi>The baby <it>caught at</it> my dress as I walked past.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch fire</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or US</vl> <va>catch on fire</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to burn <vi>Newspaper <it>catches fire</it> [=<it>ignites</it>] easily.</vi> <vi>Their house <it>caught fire</it> and burned to the ground.</vi> <vi>Don't leave the towel on the stove. It could <it>catch fire</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become very popular or effective <vi>The idea failed to <it>catch fire</it>.</vi> <vi>The singer hasn't <it>caught fire</it> in this country yet.</vi> <vi>a new technology that has <it>caught fire</it> with the public</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch hell</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch it</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be punished or scolded <vi>He's really going to <it>catch it</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>catch hell</it>] (from his boss) if he comes in late again!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become popular <vi>This trend is <it>catching on</it> with/among college students.</vi> <vi>Soccer is finally starting to <it>catch on</it> in America.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn or understand something <vi>Once you start playing the game, the kids will <it>catch on</it> pretty quickly.</vi> <vi>It took her a while to <it>catch on</it>, but she eventually got the joke.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to show that (someone) does not know something or is doing something bad <vi>She loved <it>catching</it> teachers <it>out</it> by asking tough questions.</vi> <vi>The police tried to <it>catch</it> him <it>out</it> in a lie.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch (someone) dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move fast enough to join someone or something that is in front of you <vi>They went so fast we couldn't <it>catch up</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>Slow down so that I can <it>catch up with</it> you.</vi> <vi>She ran as fast as she could, but she couldn't <it>catch up with</it> her brother. = (<it>US</it>) She couldn't <it>catch up to</it> him.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>In order to <it>catch up with</it> its competitors in the industry, the company will need to start using more advanced technologies.</vi> <vi>She missed several months of school and may never <it>catch up with</it> the other children in her class. = (<it>US</it>) She may never <it>catch up to</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn about recent events <vi>We haven't seen each other in such a long time; we've got lots of <it>catching up</it> to do!</vi> <vi><it>catching up</it> with old friends</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He reads the newspaper on Sunday mornings to <it>catch up on</it> the news.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something) that you could have done earlier <vi>She has to <it>catch up on</it> her homework.</vi> <vi>I hope to <it>catch up on</it> some much-needed sleep this weekend.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to join someone who is ahead of you <vi>He was ahead of me for most of the race, but I <it>caught him up</it> [=I caught up with him] at the end.</vi> <vi>Go on ahead: I'll <it>catch you up</it> later.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to begin to affect (someone) usually in a bad way <vi>All those late nights are really starting to <it>catch up with</it> me!</vi> <vi>Old age <it>catches up with</it> everyone in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find and arrest (someone) <vi>The police eventually <it>caught up with</it> him in Texas.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>I've got to go. I'll <it>catch up with</it> you later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught in the middle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>middle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught short</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not having enough of something <vi>Don't be <it>caught short</it>! Make sure you stock up on supplies before you set out on your trip.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:having a sudden urge to use the toilet</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>caught up in</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:involved in (a difficult or confusing situation) <vi>Several members of Congress were <it>caught up in</it> the scandal.</vi> <vi>How did you get <it>caught up in</it> this mess?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>catch <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:excited about something and having trouble thinking about anything else <vi>Everyone was <it>caught up in</it> the excitement.</vi> <vi>Try not to get too <it>caught up in</it> the moment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>catch*able</ure> <sound><wav>catch003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃəbəl, ˈkɛtʃəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>catchable</it> ball</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
