<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="branch[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">branch</hw> <sound><wav>branch01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbræntʃ, <it>Brit</it> ˈbrɑ:ntʃ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>branch*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a part of a tree that grows out from the trunk <vi>birds singing from the <it>branches</it> of a tree</vi> <vi>A large (tree) <it>branch</it> fell into our yard during the storm.</vi> <dx>see color picture on page C6</dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a local office or shop of a company or organization <vi>The bank has a new <it>branch</it> in our area.</vi> <vi>She works at the <phrase>branch office</phrase> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a major part of a government <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the executive/legislative/judicial <it>branch of</it> the United States government</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a part of an area of knowledge or study <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>Pathology is a <it>branch of</it> medicine.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a part of a family that is descended from a particular family member in the past <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>We don't know much about that <it>branch of</it> the family.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:something that goes outward from a main line or source <vi>Some of the river's smaller <it>branches</it> flooded after the heavy rains.</vi> <vi>There was a problem with the railroad's <phrase>branch line</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>root and branch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>root</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>branched</ure> <sound><wav>branch02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbræntʃt, <it>Brit</it> ˈbrɑ:ntʃt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>

	<entry id="branch[2]"> <hw hindex="2">branch</hw> <altpr>ˈbræntʃ, <it>Brit</it> ˈbrɑ:ntʃ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>branch*es</if></in> <in><if>branched</if></in> <in><if>branch*ing</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <dt>:to divide into smaller parts :to separate into branches <vi>The stream <it>branches</it> from the river near their house.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>branch off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to separate from something and move in a different direction <vi>The stream <it>branched off</it> to the left.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The stream <it>branches off from</it> the river near their house.</vi> <vi>Streets <it>branch off from</it> both sides of the highway.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>branch out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to begin to do more different kinds of activities or work <vi>In the beginning the business was highly specialized, but it has since <it>branched out</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>The company specializes in casual clothing but it is <it>branching out into</it> formal wear.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="olive branch"> <hw>olive branch</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ branch*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something that is said or done to make peace or to show that you want peace :a symbol of peace <vi>The winner <phrase>extended/offered an olive branch</phrase> to his opponent by calling him a great player.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Special Branch"> <hw>Special Branch</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the department of the British police force that deals with political crimes and terrorism <vi>Officers from <it>Special Branch</it> are investigating the case.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="root[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">root</hw> <sound><wav>root0007.wav</wav><wav>root0006.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈru:t</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>roots</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of a plant that grows underground, gets water from the ground, and holds the plant in place <vi>Elm trees have shallow <it>roots</it>.</vi> <vi>Pull weeds up by the <it>roots</it> so that they don't grow back.</vi> <dx>see color picture on page C6</dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of a tooth, hair, fingernail, etc., that is attached to the body <vi>You can tell that she dyes her hair blonde because her dark <it>roots</it> are showing.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the cause or source of something <un>usually singular <vi>He believes that money is the <it>root</it> of all evil. [=money causes people to do bad things]</vi> <vi>We need to get to the <it>root</it> of the problem. = We need to get to the <phrase>root cause</phrase> of the problem.</vi> <vi>Simple greed was <phrase>at the root of</phrase> the robbery. [=was the reason for the robbery]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the origin of something <un>usually plural <vi>Rock-and-roll music has its <it>roots</it> in blues music. [=rock-and-roll music originated/developed from blues music]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>roots</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the family history of a person or a group of people <vi>They have traced their <it>roots</it> [=<it>ancestry</it>] back several generations.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a special connection to something <un>+ <it>in</it> <vi>She's a dedicated teacher with <it>roots in</it> the community.</vi> <vi>His family has <it>roots in</it> the New York theater scene.</vi> <vi>a novelist with <it>roots</it> deep <it>in</it> Southern life</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>grass roots</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt>:a number that is multiplied by itself a certain number of times to produce another number <vi>2 is the 4th <it>root</it> of 16. [=2 x 2 x 2 x 2 = 16]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cube root</dxt> <dxt>square root</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a word from which other words are formed <vi>“Butler” and “bottle” come from the same Latin <it>root</it>.</vi> <vi>“Hold” is the <it>root</it> of “holder.”</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>put down roots</dre> <def><dt>:to become a member of a community and begin to feel that it is your home :to settle and live in one place <vi>The family <it>put down roots</it> in New England. [=they made New England their home]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>root and branch</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:complete or thorough <vi>a <it>root and branch</it> overhaul of local schools</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:completely or thoroughly <vi>The laws were reformed <it>root and branch</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take root</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a plant</ssl> <dt>:to grow and develop roots <vi>There isn't enough time for the grass to <it>take root</it> before winter.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to begin to develop <vi>The classroom should be a place where creativity can <it>take root</it> and flourish.</vi> <vi>It was years before democratic ideals <it>took root</it> in that part of the world.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
