<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="breath"> <hw highlight="yes">breath</hw> <sound><wav>breath01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɛθ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>breaths</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the air that you take into your lungs and send out from your lungs when you breathe :air that is inhaled and exhaled in breathing <vi>gum that freshens your <it>breath</it></vi> <vi>His <it>breath</it> smells like garlic. = He has garlic <it>breath</it>.</vi> <vi>It's so cold outside that I can see my <it>breath</it>.</vi> <vi>We could smell the alcohol <phrase>on his breath</phrase>. [=his breath smelled of alcohol]</vi> <vi>He has <phrase>bad breath</phrase>. [=breath that smells unpleasant]</vi> <un>sometimes used before another noun <vi>Would you like a <it>breath</it> mint? [=a candy used to make breath smell better]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>breath test</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to breathe freely <vi>He was <phrase>fighting/struggling for breath</phrase>. [=he was having a lot of difficulty breathing]</vi> <vi>My mad dash for the bus left me <phrase>gasping for breath</phrase>.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>catch your breath</phrase> or (<it>Brit</it>) <phrase>get your breath back</phrase> is to rest until you are able to breathe normally. <vi>Give me a moment to <it>catch my breath</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you are <phrase>out of breath</phrase>, you are breathing very hard because you have been running or doing hard physical work. <vi>I'm a little <it>out of breath</it> from walking up all those stairs.</vi></snote> <snote>Someone who is <phrase>short of breath</phrase> or who has <phrase>shortness of breath</phrase> has difficulty breathing in enough air especially because of a physical or medical condition. <vi>The patient complains that he's <it>short of breath</it>.</vi> <vi>The doctor asked if I had been experiencing <it>shortness of breath</it> lately.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an amount of air that you take into your lungs <vi>I took/drew a long <it>breath</it> before speaking again.</vi> <vi>The patient was only able to take shallow <it>breaths</it>. [=only able to take in small amounts of air]</vi> <vi><phrase>Take a deep breath</phrase>. [=breathe deeply; take a lot of air into your lungs]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) I've barely had time to (stop and/to) <phrase>take a breath</phrase> since they got here. = (<it>Brit</it>) I've barely had time to <phrase>draw breath</phrase> since they got here. [=I have not been able to pause and rest]</vi> <vi>She recited the whole list <phrase>in one breath</phrase>. [=she recited it without stopping to breathe]</vi> <vi>her <phrase>last/dying breath</phrase> [=the breath that she took just before she died]</vi> <snote>If you say two different things <phrase>in the same breath</phrase>, or if you say one thing and then something else <phrase>in the next breath</phrase>, it means that you say these things very close together. <vi>It's unusual to hear “promotions” mentioned <it>in the same breath</it> as “layoffs.”</vi> <vi>She praises their work, then criticizes them <it>in the next breath</it>. [=then immediately criticizes them]</vi></snote> <snote>If someone says that you are <phrase>wasting your breath</phrase> or tells you to <phrase>save your breath</phrase> or to <phrase>not waste your breath</phrase>, it means that the things you say will not make someone behave or think differently and that you should not bother to try. <vi>He begged her to go with him, but she told him he was <it>wasting his breath</it>.</vi> <vi>You're not going to get him to stop drinking, so <it>don't waste your breath</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a slight breeze <un>usually singular <vi>a hot day with scarcely a <phrase>breath of wind</phrase></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a very small amount of something <vi>a faint <it>breath</it> [=<it>hint</it>] <it>of</it> scandal</vi> <vi>There was never even the slightest <it>breath</it> [=<it>suggestion</it>] <it>of</it> suspicion.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a breath of fresh air</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:clean or cool outside air after you have been in a building for a period of time <vi>We went outside to get <it>a breath of fresh air</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:someone or something that is different in a way that is interesting, exciting, enjoyable, etc. <vi>His unusual outlook is <it>a breath of fresh air</it>.</vi> <vi>After dealing for so long with a difficult boss, our new supervisor is <it>a breath of fresh air</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold your breath</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to keep the air that you have breathed in your lungs for a short time instead of breathing out <vi>How long can you <it>hold your breath</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not believe that something will happen soon or at all <vi>He says he'll do it, but <phrase>I'm not holding my breath</phrase>. [=I doubt he will do it]</vi> <vi>“She promised to pay me tomorrow.” “Well, <phrase>don't hold your breath</phrase>.” [=do not expect her to pay you tomorrow]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your breath away</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <it>takes your breath away</it> is extremely exciting, beautiful, or surprising. <vi>The acrobatic skill of the dancers <it>took my breath away</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>under your breath</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you say something <it>under your breath</it>, you say it quietly so that it is difficult to hear. <vi>We heard her mutter something <it>under her breath</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with bated breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bated</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="breath test"> <hw>breath test</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ tests</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a test that is used by the police to measure how much alcohol a person has drunk</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bated"> <hw>bat*ed</hw> <sound><wav>bated01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbeɪtəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <dro><dre>with bated breath</dre> <def><dt>:in a nervous and excited state because you do not know what will happen <vi>They waited for the answer <it>with bated breath</it>. [=they nervously waited for the answer]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="catch[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">catch</hw> <sound><wav>catch001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃ, ˈkɛtʃ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>catch*es</if></in> <in><if>caught</if> <sound><wav>catch002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:t</pr></in> <in><if>catch*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use your hands to stop and hold (an object that is moving through the air) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Catch</it> the ball and throw it to first base.</vi> <vi>She <it>caught</it> the ball with one hand.</vi> <vi>I dropped the book but managed to <it>catch</it> it before it hit the ground.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll throw you the keys. Ready? <it>Catch</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to use your hands to grasp and hold onto (someone or something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> [=<it>grabbed</it>, <it>seized</it>] her by the wrist.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>caught hold of</phrase> her wrist.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to capture and not allow (a person, animal, or fish) to escape <vi>The police are working hard to <it>catch</it> the criminals and put them in jail.</vi> <vi>“I bet you can't <it>catch</it> me!” she yelled to her brother.</vi> <vi>I once <it>caught</it> 10 fish in a single day.</vi> <vi>In the summer, we would <it>catch</it> fireflies and put them in jars.</vi> <vi><it>catching</it> mice in traps</vi> <vi>lions <it>catching</it> their prey</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage to find, meet, or reach (someone) at a particular time or in a particular state or condition <vi>I <it>caught</it> her just as she was leaving for work.</vi> <vi>I'm afraid you've <it>caught</it> me at a bad time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find (someone who is doing something wrong) <vi>The police <it>caught</it> him trying to steal the painting.</vi> <vi>My teacher <it>caught</it> me cheating on a test.</vi> <vi>Her father <it>caught</it> her smoking in the basement.</vi> <vi>You'd never <it>catch</it> me doing that! [=I would never do that]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>caught him in the act</phrase> (of stealing the painting). = He was <phrase>caught red-handed</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to affect (someone) in a sudden and surprising way <vi>They were <phrase>caught unprepared</phrase> by the crisis. = The crisis <phrase>caught them unawares</phrase>. [=they were not prepared when the crisis occurred]</vi> <vi>The announcement <phrase>caught me by surprise</phrase>. [=I was surprised by the announcement]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to suddenly stop (yourself) before you do something <vi>Luckily, he <it>caught</it> himself before he gave away the secret.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to suddenly become aware that you are doing something <vi>He <it>caught</it> himself staring at her.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be stopped, delayed, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be/get) caught</it> <vi>We <it>got caught</it> in a rain storm and had to find shelter.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I'm late. I <it>was caught</it> in traffic.</vi> <vi>We <phrase>got caught up in</phrase> traffic and were late for our flight.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>caught up in <dxn>1 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to become stuck and unable to move <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>caught</it> my sleeve on a nail.</vi> <vi>The kite got <it>caught</it> [=<it>tangled</it>] in the tree.</vi> <vi>She tried to stand up, but her foot was <it>caught</it> in the strap.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My sleeve <it>caught</it> on a nail.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have the parts connect firmly <vi>I tried to lock the door, but the lock wouldn't <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop and hold (falling water) <vi>They kept a bucket outside to <it>catch</it> the rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become covered with (something that moves through the air) <vi>These curtains <it>catch</it> a lot of dust.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hit or touch (someone or something) <vi>The bullet <it>caught</it> him in the leg.</vi> <vi>His last punch <it>caught</it> me in the jaw.</vi> <vi>Isn't it beautiful the way the setting sun <it>catches</it> the tips of the trees?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be hit or touched by (something) <vi>He <it>caught</it> a bullet in the leg.</vi> <vi>The tips of the trees <it>catch</it> the light as the sun sets.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become affected with (a sickness or disease) <vi>We both <it>caught</it> [=<it>contracted</it>] the flu.</vi> <vi>I seem to <it>catch</it> a cold every winter.</vi> <vi>children <it>catching</it> colds from each other</vi> <snote>When people say that you will <phrase>catch your death (of cold)</phrase>, they mean that you will become sick or catch a very bad cold. <vi>It's freezing! You'll <it>catch your death</it> if you go out without a coat!</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to feel excitement or interest about something <vi>I haven't <it>caught</it> the holiday spirit yet this year.</vi> <vi>People are getting really interested in the sport. The whole country is starting to <phrase>catch the fever</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to attract and hold (someone's attention, interest, etc.) <vi>I tried to <it>catch</it> the waiter's attention, but I guess he didn't see me.</vi> <vi>The show is more likely to <it>catch</it> the interest of an older audience.</vi> <vi>Her books have <phrase>caught the imagination</phrase> of children from around the world. [=children find her books very exciting and enjoyable]</vi> <snote>If someone or something <phrase>catches your eye</phrase>, you notice that person or thing. <vi>There was one dress in particular that <it>caught my eye</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>eye-catching</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see, smell, or notice (something) <vi>I <it>caught</it> [=<it>got</it>] a faint whiff of her perfume.</vi> <vi>While you're in Hollywood, you might <phrase>catch a glimpse</phrase> of some movie stars.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>caught sight</phrase> of his red shirt and started calling to him.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to hear or understand (something) <vi>What was that again? I didn't quite <it>catch</it> [=<it>hear, get</it>] what you said.</vi> <vi>I didn't <it>catch</it> your name.</vi> <vi>Do you <phrase>catch my drift</phrase>? [=do you understand what I mean?]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to become aware of (something, such as an illness) <vi>The disease is curable if <it>caught</it> [=<it>detected</it>] early.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or do (something) <vi>You can <it>catch</it> [=<it>take</it>] a quick nap on the train.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get (something) through effort <vi>I managed to <it>catch</it> [=<it>get</it>] a ride into town with some friends.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>“See you soon.” “Yup. <phrase>Catch you later</phrase>.”</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move fast enough to be next to or in front of (someone) <vi>She <it>caught</it> [=<it>overtook</it>] the leader in the final meters of the race.</vi> <vi>He left before I did so I had to hurry to <it>catch</it> him. [=to catch up with him]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get on a bus, train, etc., before it leaves <vi>If you miss the first bus, you can <it>catch</it> the next one in 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>If you'll excuse me, I have a plane to <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to see or hear (a show, game, etc.) <vi>I only <it>caught</it> the last few minutes of the game.</vi> <vi>Did you <it>catch</it> the show on Channel 4 last night?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to describe or show (someone or something) in an accurate way in art <vi>The new portrait <it>catches</it> her likeness perfectly.</vi> <vi>The novel successfully <it>catches</it> the atmosphere of 19th-century Paris.</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to play the position of catcher <vi>He <it>catches</it> for the New York Yankees.</vi> <vi>If you pitch, I'll <it>catch</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>catch at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reach for and try to hold (something) <vi>The baby <it>caught at</it> my dress as I walked past.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch fire</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or US</vl> <va>catch on fire</va></svr> <dt>:to begin to burn <vi>Newspaper <it>catches fire</it> [=<it>ignites</it>] easily.</vi> <vi>Their house <it>caught fire</it> and burned to the ground.</vi> <vi>Don't leave the towel on the stove. It could <it>catch fire</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become very popular or effective <vi>The idea failed to <it>catch fire</it>.</vi> <vi>The singer hasn't <it>caught fire</it> in this country yet.</vi> <vi>a new technology that has <it>caught fire</it> with the public</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch hell</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch it</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be punished or scolded <vi>He's really going to <it>catch it</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>catch hell</it>] (from his boss) if he comes in late again!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become popular <vi>This trend is <it>catching on</it> with/among college students.</vi> <vi>Soccer is finally starting to <it>catch on</it> in America.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn or understand something <vi>Once you start playing the game, the kids will <it>catch on</it> pretty quickly.</vi> <vi>It took her a while to <it>catch on</it>, but she eventually got the joke.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>catch (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to show that (someone) does not know something or is doing something bad <vi>She loved <it>catching</it> teachers <it>out</it> by asking tough questions.</vi> <vi>The police tried to <it>catch</it> him <it>out</it> in a lie.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch (someone) dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>catch up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move fast enough to join someone or something that is in front of you <vi>They went so fast we couldn't <it>catch up</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>Slow down so that I can <it>catch up with</it> you.</vi> <vi>She ran as fast as she could, but she couldn't <it>catch up with</it> her brother. = (<it>US</it>) She couldn't <it>catch up to</it> him.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>In order to <it>catch up with</it> its competitors in the industry, the company will need to start using more advanced technologies.</vi> <vi>She missed several months of school and may never <it>catch up with</it> the other children in her class. = (<it>US</it>) She may never <it>catch up to</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to learn about recent events <vi>We haven't seen each other in such a long time; we've got lots of <it>catching up</it> to do!</vi> <vi><it>catching up</it> with old friends</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He reads the newspaper on Sunday mornings to <it>catch up on</it> the news.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something) that you could have done earlier <vi>She has to <it>catch up on</it> her homework.</vi> <vi>I hope to <it>catch up on</it> some much-needed sleep this weekend.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to join someone who is ahead of you <vi>He was ahead of me for most of the race, but I <it>caught him up</it> [=I caught up with him] at the end.</vi> <vi>Go on ahead: I'll <it>catch you up</it> later.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>catch up with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to begin to affect (someone) usually in a bad way <vi>All those late nights are really starting to <it>catch up with</it> me!</vi> <vi>Old age <it>catches up with</it> everyone in the end.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to find and arrest (someone) <vi>The police eventually <it>caught up with</it> him in Texas.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to meet with (someone) <vi>I've got to go. I'll <it>catch up with</it> you later.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught in the middle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>middle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>caught short</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not having enough of something <vi>Don't be <it>caught short</it>! Make sure you stock up on supplies before you set out on your trip.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:having a sudden urge to use the toilet</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>caught up in</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:involved in (a difficult or confusing situation) <vi>Several members of Congress were <it>caught up in</it> the scandal.</vi> <vi>How did you get <it>caught up in</it> this mess?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>catch <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:excited about something and having trouble thinking about anything else <vi>Everyone was <it>caught up in</it> the excitement.</vi> <vi>Try not to get too <it>caught up in</it> the moment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>catch*able</ure> <sound><wav>catch003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkætʃəbəl, ˈkɛtʃəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>catchable</it> ball</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="fresh[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">fresh</hw> <sound><wav>fresh001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfrɛʃ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>fresh*er</if></in> <in><if>fresh*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:newly produced, made, gathered, etc. :not preserved by being frozen, canned, etc. <vi><it>fresh</it> vegetables = vegetables <it>fresh</it> from the farm = farm-<it>fresh</it> vegetables</vi> <vi>You can use either <it>fresh</it> or dried basil for this recipe.</vi> <vi><it>fresh</it> fish [=fish that were caught and killed very recently]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not old, spoiled, etc. <vi><it>fresh</it> bread = bread <it>fresh</it> from the oven = oven-<it>fresh</it> bread</vi> <vi>The meat was kept <it>fresh</it> in the refrigerator.</vi> <vi>a bouquet of <it>fresh</it> flowers</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:clean and pure <vi><it>fresh</it> air</vi> <vi><it>fresh</it> flavors</vi> <vi><it>fresh</it> colors</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not having an unpleasant smell, taste, etc. <vi><it>fresh</it> breath</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not worn or dirty <vi>He changed into a <it>fresh</it> shirt.</vi> <vi>She brought a <it>fresh</it> change of clothes.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:full of life and energy <vi>She rose <it>fresh</it> from a good night's sleep.</vi> <vi>She always seems to be (as) <phrase>fresh as a daisy</phrase>. [=very fresh; not at all tired]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:not containing salt <vi><it>fresh</it> water</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:newly made, experienced, or received <vi>a <it>fresh</it> wound</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:replacing something old or used <vi>Can I get you a <it>fresh</it> drink?</vi> <vi>I used a <it>fresh</it> piece of paper.</vi> <vi>Let's <phrase>make a fresh start</phrase>. [=let's start again]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:remaining clear :not faded <vi>I'd like to take the test soon, while the information is still <phrase>fresh in my mind</phrase>. [=while I still remember the information clearly]</vi> <vi>memories that remained <it>fresh</it></vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:new and original <vi>She offered <it>fresh</it> insight into the problem.</vi> <vi>a young writer with <it>fresh</it> ideas</vi> <vi>Let's try a <it>fresh</it> approach to this problem.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:behaving or talking in a rude or impolite way <vi>Don't be/get <it>fresh</it> with the teacher.</vi> <vi>a very <it>fresh</it> kid</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:behaving or talking in a way that shows sexual attraction to someone <vi>He tried to get <it>fresh</it> with me.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of wind</ssl> <dt>:fairly strong <vi>a <it>fresh</it> breeze</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a breath of fresh air</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fresh from</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>fresh out of</va></vr> <def><dt>:having recently left or come from (a place, such as a school) <vi>new employees <it>fresh out of</it> college</vi> <vi>a young doctor <it>fresh from</it> medical school</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fresh off the boat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>boat</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>fresh*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>freshly</it> baked pie</vi> <vi><it>freshly</it> polished boots</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>fresh*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>count, noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>The fruit had been shipped a great distance, and lacked flavor and <it>freshness</it>.</vi> <vi>Several critics praised the <it>freshness</it> of her style.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="hold[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">hold</hw> <sound><wav>hold0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhoʊld</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>holds</if></in> <in><if>held</if> <sound><wav>hold0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɛld</pr></in> <in><if>hold*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (something) in your hand, arms, etc. <vi><it>Hold</it> the rail so you won't fall.</vi> <vi>He was <it>holding</it> his hat (in his hand).</vi> <vi>He was <it>holding</it> a large package in his arms.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>hold</it> this for me?</vi> <vi>She showed him the correct way to <it>hold</it> the racket.</vi> <vi>She <it>held</it> his hand. = She <it>held</it> him by the hand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put your arms around (someone) :to embrace or hug (someone) <vi>Some people just don't like to be <it>held</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>held</it> her close/tight and kissed her.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put or keep (something or someone) in a specified place or position <vi>He <it>held</it> the pen in his mouth while he dialed the number.</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> the pen upright when you write.</vi> <vi>She picked up the trophy and <it>held</it> it over her head.</vi> <vi>You have to <it>hold</it> the button down for several seconds.</vi> <vi>I <it>held</it> the door open for her.</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> your arms at your sides.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to keep (something or someone) in the same place or position <vi>I need someone to <it>hold</it> this string while I finish tying the knot.</vi> <vi>She <it>held</it> the ladder steady while he climbed up it.</vi> <vi>It took six guards to <it>hold</it> him (down).</vi> <vi>The board was <it>held</it> in place/position by a couple of nails.</vi> <vi>The Federal Reserve has been <it>holding</it> interest rates down/up.</vi> <vi>The cover was <phrase>held on</phrase> by a piece of tape.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to remain in the same place or position <vi>The anchor <it>held</it>.</vi> <vi>The line of soldiers <it>held</it> under constant attack.</vi> <vi>Please <phrase>hold still</phrase> for a moment.</vi> <vi>His weight has <phrase>held steady</phrase> for several months now.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to be good <vi>We arrived late but our luck <it>held</it> and we were able to get tickets.</vi> <vi>We hope the weather <it>holds</it> through the weekend.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to own or possess (something) <vi>The bank <it>holds</it> (the) title to the car.</vi> <vi>Do you <it>hold</it> any shares/stock in the company?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (a job, a position, etc.) <vi>She has never before <it>held</it> public office.</vi> <vi>It's been a struggle for him to <it>hold</it> a job.</vi> <vi>In the last election the Democratic party managed to <it>hold</it> several seats but lost others.</vi> <vi>President Franklin Roosevelt <phrase>held office</phrase> for 12 years. = Franklin Roosevelt <it>held</it> the office of president for 12 years.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to succeed in keeping (something that is being attacked) <vi>The troops were able to <it>hold</it> the bridge.</vi> <vi>The line of soldiers <phrase>held their position/ground</phrase> and fought off the attack.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to have (something that you have achieved or earned) <vi>She <it>holds</it> a master's degree in chemistry.</vi> <vi>a swimmer who <it>holds</it> several world records</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to support the pressure or weight of (something or someone) <vi>The floor will <it>hold</it> 10 tons.</vi> <vi>I don't know if the roof can <it>hold</it> all that snow.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have or keep (a belief, a feeling, etc.) in your mind <vi>There's no need for him to <it>hold</it> [=<it>bear</it>] a grudge against me.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>hold</it> any resentment toward/against him.</vi> <vi>a belief <it>held</it> by many = a widely <it>held</it> belief</vi> <vi>I will always <it>hold</it> that memory in my heart.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to consider or judge (someone or something) in a specified way <vi>They <it>hold</it> me responsible.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>He should be <it>held</it> accountable <it>for</it> his actions.</vi> <vi>The store can't be <it>held</it> liable <it>for</it> damage to your vehicle.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>The court <it>held</it> his actions <it>to be</it> grounds for a lawsuit. [=the court said/ruled that his actions were grounds for a lawsuit]</vi> <vi>His latest book is generally/widely <it>held</it> [=<it>considered</it>] <it>to be</it> the best one.</vi> <vi>“We <it>hold</it> these truths <it>to be</it> self-evident…” <aq>U.S. Declaration of Independence (1776)</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to have or express (an opinion, belief, etc.) <un>+ <it>that</it> <vi>I <it>hold</it> [=<it>believe</it>] <it>that</it> such problems should be dealt with at the federal level.</vi> <vi>The Supreme Court <it>held</it> [=<it>ruled</it>] <it>that</it> the trial court had acted properly.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Tradition <it>holds that</it> [=it is traditional that] the oldest member of the family be seated first.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a meeting, class, sale, etc.) to take place <vi>A sale will be <it>held</it> next weekend.</vi> <vi>Free elections will be <it>held</it> next month.</vi> <vi>We will <it>hold</it> [=<it>have</it>] the meeting at 2 o'clock.</vi> <vi>The President has decided to <it>hold</it> [=<it>give</it>] a press conference.</vi> <vi>They're <it>holding</it> an art show at the gallery.</vi> <vi>The two sides will <it>hold</it> [=<it>have</it>] talks/discussions to resolve the dispute.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to contain (something) <vi>The box <it>holds</it> his collection of old photographs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to have enough room for (an amount) <vi>The disk can <it>hold</it> 1.44 megabytes of data.</vi> <vi>How much water can that bucket <it>hold</it>?</vi> <vi>The bottle <it>holds</it> two liters.</vi> <vi>The dining room <it>holds</it> 500 people.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue to have (someone's interest or attention) <vi>The speaker wasn't able to <it>hold</it> [=<it>keep</it>] our interest/attention for long.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (a specified quality, feature, etc.) <vi>His eyes <it>held</it> [=<it>had</it>] a quizzical look.</vi> <vi>She has always <it>held</it> a special place in my heart. [=I have always had special feelings for her]</vi> <vi>This hotel has long <it>held</it> [=<it>claimed</it>] a place among the world's finest. [=has long been considered one of the world's finest]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Music <it>holds</it> great appeal <it>for</it> many people. [=music appeals greatly to many people]</vi> <vi>His job <it>holds</it> no surprises <it>for</it> him. [=nothing about his job surprises him]</vi> <vi>Her paintings <it>hold</it> a real fascination <it>for</it> me. [=her paintings fascinate me]</vi> <vi>No one can know what the future <it>holds</it> (<it>for</it> us). [=no one can know what will happen (to us) in the future]</vi> <vi>These experiments <it>hold</it> great promise <it>for</it> future cancer research.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop doing (something) or wait to do (something) <vi>Tell the men to <phrase>hold their fire</phrase> [=not shoot] until I give the order.</vi> <vi><phrase>Hold everything</phrase>. [=wait; stop] We're not doing this right.</vi> <vi><phrase>Hold it</phrase> right there. [=stop right there] Where do you think you're going?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) available for later use <vi>A room at the hotel will be <it>held</it> for us for 24 hours.</vi> <vi>We will <it>hold</it> these flight reservations for you until tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to delay the handling of (something, such as a telephone call) for a time <vi>Please <it>hold</it> all my calls while I'm in the meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to prevent (something, such as a vehicle) from leaving <vi>The train was <it>held</it> until the track was cleared.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>hold</it> the elevator for me?</vi> <vi><it>Hold</it> that taxi!</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to not use or include (something) in preparing food <vi>I'd like a roast beef sandwich on rye, and <it>hold</it> the mustard please. [=do not put any mustard on the sandwich]</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to force (someone) to stay in a place (such as a prison) <vi>The police are <it>holding</it> him for questioning.</vi> <vi>Terrorists are <it>holding</it> the passengers hostage.</vi> <vi>They're being <it>held</it> hostage/captive/prisoner.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He was <it>held</it> captive by his own fears.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue moving on (a course) without change <vi>The ship continued to <it>hold</it> its course.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>of a vehicle</ssl> <dt>:to stay on (a road) in a safe and secure way when being driven at high speeds <vi>The car <it>holds</it> the road well when turning quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be true :to remain valid <vi>Her advice still <it>holds</it> [=<it>applies</it>] today.</vi> <vi>The general rule <it>holds</it> in most cases.</vi> <un>often used in the phrases <phrase>hold true</phrase> and (less commonly) <phrase>hold good</phrase> <vi>The general rule <it>holds true</it> in most cases.</vi> <vi>Their son needs support and understanding. The same <it>holds true</it> for all children.</vi> <vi>The advice she gave us 10 years ago still <it>holds good</it> today.</vi></un></dt> <sn>19</sn> <dt>:to wait to speak to someone on the telephone <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>All operators are currently busy. Please <it>hold</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>All operators are busy. Please <phrase>hold the line</phrase> for a minute.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>hold a candle to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>candle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold (something) against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something) as a reason to have a bad opinion of (someone) <vi>He lied to her once, and she still <it>holds it against him</it>.</vi> <vi>Nobody is going to <it>hold it against you</it> if you don't come. [=no one is going to be angry or upset with you if you don't come]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold a gun to someone's head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold all the aces</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold (all/all of) the cards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>card</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to stop yourself from doing something <vi>She wanted to introduce herself to him but she <it>held back</it> out of shyness.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a less than complete effort <vi>She could have beaten him in the race, but she <it>held back</it> and let him win. [=she did not run as fast as she could have so that he would win]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) back</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from doing something <vi>Once he starts talking, <phrase>there's no holding him back</phrase>. [=it's very hard to get him to stop talking]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not allow (something) to be seen or known by someone <vi>He was unable to <it>hold back</it> his tears. [=to keep from crying]</vi> <vi>The government <it>held back</it> [=<it>withheld</it>] some crucial information from the media.</vi> <vi>I know you're angry, so don't <it>hold</it> anything <it>back</it> (from me). [=tell me everything]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) <vi>He <it>held</it> several thousand dollars <it>back</it> in case of an emergency.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to delay (something) <vi>The company <it>held back</it> the first shipment of the new product until it was completely ready.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone or something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold back (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone or something) from moving forward :to stop (someone or something) from advancing to the next level, grade, or stage <vi>She might have been more successful, but bad health <it>held</it> her <it>back</it>.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held back</it> [=<it>kept back</it>] in first grade.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold court</dre> <dx>see <dxt>court</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from being or becoming too high <vi>Could you please <it>hold</it> the noise <it>down</it>? I'm trying to read.</vi> <vi>The company is trying to <it>hold down</it> costs/expenses/prices.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to have (a job) <vi>It's been a struggle for him to <it>hold down</it> [=<it>keep</it>] a job.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from doing something or advancing to a higher level, position, etc. <vi>We need to free ourselves of the unfair restrictions that are <it>holding</it> us <it>down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold firm</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to change what you have been doing or believing <vi>They are <it>holding firm</it> on their refusal to proceed.</vi> <vi>Despite opposition, she has <it>held firm</it> to her decision.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold forth</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to speak about something for a long time <vi>He <it>held forth</it> about/on the need for reform in his country.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold hands</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>hold someone's hand</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (an emotion) from being expressed <vi>Don't <it>hold</it> your feelings <it>in</it>. Let them out.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to wait to do something <vi>You need to decide now. You can't <it>hold off</it> any longer.</vi> <vi>He <it>held off</it> as long as he could.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>She decided to <it>hold off on</it> her vacation for a while longer.</vi></un> <snote>If you <phrase>hold off doing</phrase> something or <phrase>hold off on doing</phrase> something, you wait to do it at a later time. <vi>He <it>held off on</it> announcing his decision.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to not happen until later <vi>The rain <it>held off</it> until we got home. [=it didn't rain until we got home]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop (someone) from coming near someone or something <vi>Her bodyguard <it>held off</it> the crowd. [=kept the crowd away from her]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to defend against (something) successfully :<sx>withstand</sx> <vi>The soldiers <it>held off</it> the attack.</vi> <vi>Our team <it>held off</it> a late rally by the other team.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have or keep your hand, arms, etc., tightly around something <vi>He was <it>holding on</it> [=<it>hanging on</it>] for dear life.</vi> <vi><it>Hold on</it> (tight). It's going to get bumpy.</vi> <vi>The steps are slippery; you'd better <it>hold on</it> to the railing.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to succeed in keeping a position, condition, etc. <vi>I hope we can <it>hold on</it> until help arrives.</vi> <vi>They were able to <it>hold on</it> for a 10–9 victory.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to wait or stop briefly <vi>“Can we go now?” “<it>Hold on</it>, I'll be ready in just a minute.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold on to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep possession of (something) <vi>She's trying very hard to <it>hold on to</it> her money.</vi> <vi>He has managed to <it>hold on to</it> his lead in the polls.</vi> :to not lose or give up (something) <vi>Despite all his troubles, he has somehow <it>held on to</it> his faith in himself.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or be available <vi>I don't know how much longer our supply of food will <it>hold out</it>. [=<it>last</it>]</vi> <vi>You should do it while your courage is still <it>holding out</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm going to keep writing as long as my money <it>holds out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to work <vi>My old car is still <it>holding out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to continue to oppose someone or defend against something :to refuse to surrender or give in <vi>The troops were able to <it>hold out</it> until help arrived.</vi> <vi>Many of the strikers are still <it>holding out</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to reach outward with (something, such as your hand) <vi>He <it>held out</it> [=<it>extended</it>] his hand in greeting.</vi> <vi>She <it>held out</it> the car keys and asked him to drive.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>I <it>held out</it> the hand of friendship to my enemies. [=I offered friendship to my enemies]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to say that there is a good reason to have (something, such as hope) <vi>The doctor didn't <it>hold out</it> [=<it>offer</it>] much hope for her recovery. [=the doctor didn't say that there was much hope for her recovery]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to say that (a possibility) exists <vi>The mayor has <it>held out</it> the possibility that the library will be expanded in the future. [=has said that it is possible that the library will be expanded]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to refuse to accept or agree to something in order to get (something) <vi>The workers are <it>holding out for</it> higher pay.</vi> <vi>The wide receiver is <it>holding out for</it> a new contract.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold out on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to keep something (such as information) from (someone) <vi>She didn't tell me she was rich; she's been <it>holding out on</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold over (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something) over</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen later <vi>A vote on the proposal has been <it>held over</it> [=<it>delayed, postponed</it>] until tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something) to continue beyond a normal or planned time <vi>The movie is being <it>held over</it> for two more weeks. [=the movie will continue to be shown for two more weeks]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something or someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold over (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (something or someone) from an earlier time <vi>He is the only player to have been <it>held over</it> from their previous team.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) over (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use your knowledge of (something) to influence or control the behavior of (someone) <vi>She knows about his criminal past and has been <it>holding</it> it <it>over</it> him [=she has been threatening to tell other people about his criminal past] to force him to cooperate.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold the bag</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>hold the baby</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be given all of the blame or responsibility that should be shared with others <vi>His friends ran away and he was stuck/left <it>holding the bag</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold the fort</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fort</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold the line</dre> <dx>see <dxt>line</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to have or follow (a plan, purpose, etc.) <vi>He has <it>held to</it> his plan of exercising regularly.</vi> :to not change (a decision, belief, etc.) <vi>Despite opposition, she has <phrase>held to</phrase> her decision.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>You made a promise and I'm going to <it>hold</it> you <it>to</it> it.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held to</it> an impossible standard. [=he was required to meet very high expectations]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (someone) to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prevent (an opponent) from having or getting more than (a specified number of scores or shots) <vi>Our team <it>held</it> the other team <it>to</it> just three runs.</vi> <vi>The defense <it>held</it> him <it>to</it> only one shot attempt in the first half.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stay joined together or in one piece <vi>The empire <it>held together</it> for many decades.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) together</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold together (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to stay joined together or in one piece <vi>The coach hopes to <it>hold</it> the team <it>together</it> for at least one more season.</vi> <vi>The box was <it>held together</it> by a strong glue.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue in the same condition without failing or losing effectiveness or force <vi>The sales team was <it>holding up</it> well under the stress.</vi> <vi>The nurse came in to see how I was <it>holding up</it>.</vi> <vi>Their music still <it>holds up</it> 20 years later.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to raise (something) <vi>He <it>held up</it> his hand.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>hold up (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>hold (something or someone) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to delay, stop, or slow the movement, progress, or action of (something or someone) :<sx>delay</sx> <vi>Their decision was <it>held up</it> for months.</vi> <vi>A major accident <it>held</it> traffic <it>up</it> for hours.</vi> <vi>She was late for the meeting because she got <it>held up</it> in traffic.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use a gun to rob (a person, store, etc.) <vi>Someone <it>held up</it> the gas station.</vi> <vi>He was <it>held up</it> by a masked robber.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>holdup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be noticed for a particular reason <vi>His work has been <it>held up</it> to ridicule. [=his work has been ridiculed]</vi> <vi>Experts have been <it>holding</it> these programs <it>up</it> as examples of government waste.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>hold with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to agree with or approve of (something) <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I don't <it>hold with</it> all these newfangled notions!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your horses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>horse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your liquor</dre> <dx>see <dxt>liquor</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your nose</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold your own</dre> <def><dt>:to do well in a difficult situation <vi>It was a tough interview, but she managed to <it>hold her own</it>.</vi> <vi>She's been <it>holding her own</it> against cancer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold your tongue</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>hold your peace</va></vr> <def><dt>:to keep silent :to not say anything about something <vi>It was difficult, but he somehow managed to <it>hold his tongue</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="save[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">save</hw> <sound><wav>save0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈseɪv</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>saves</if></in> <in><if>saved</if></in> <in><if>sav*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (someone or something) safe :to stop (someone or something) from dying or being hurt, damaged, or lost <vi>He risked his life to <it>save</it> his friend (from drowning).</vi> <vi>The organization is dedicated to <it>saving</it> [=<it>protecting</it>] endangered animals.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>save</it> the rain forests (from destruction).</vi> <vi>He grabbed her arm to <it>save</it> her from falling. [=to stop/prevent her from falling so that she would not be hurt]</vi> <vi>The doctors managed to <it>save</it> the soldier's wounded leg. [=to keep the leg from having to be cut off]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop (something) from ending or failing :to make (something that is in danger of failing) successful <vi>He is trying to <it>save</it> his marriage by going to counseling for his drug addiction.</vi> <vi>The new CEO <it>saved</it> the company (from bankruptcy).</vi> <vi>She <it>saved</it> a tense situation by staying calm.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) from being lost or wasted <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>This new plan will help us <it>save</it> time. = The new plan will <it>save</it> us some time.</vi> <vi>Thinner computer monitors <it>save</it> space.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>on</it> <vi>A more efficient furnace will <it>save on</it> energy.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to keep money instead of spending it :to put money away especially in a bank so that you will have it in the future <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She would rather <it>save</it> than spend.</vi> <vi>He has been <it>saving</it> (up) for a new car.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Save</it> a little money for later.</vi> <vi>She <it>saves</it> part of her pay every week.</vi> <vi>I <it>saved</it> $20,000 for a down payment on the house.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to spend less money <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Buy now and <it>save</it>!</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><it>Save on</it> everything in the store!</vi> <vi>He <it>saved on</it> [=spent less money for] his car insurance by switching to a different insurance company.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>saved</it> $15 at the grocery store by using coupons.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're trying to <it>save</it> money <it>on</it> our electric bill.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) available for use in the future <vi>Be sure to <it>save</it> some cookies for your sister.</vi> <vi>You need to <it>save</it> (up) your energy for tomorrow.</vi> <vi>He <it>saves</it> his best jacket for special occasions. [=he only wears his best jacket on special occasions]</vi> <vi>The runners <it>saved</it> their energy for the last lap. = The runners <phrase>saved themselves</phrase> for the last lap.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) for someone to use or have <vi>She <it>saved</it> a seat for her friend.</vi> <vi>Please <it>save</it> the next dance for me. = Please <it>save</it> me the next dance. [=please don't plan to dance the next dance with anyone but me]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) unnecessary <vi>Check that you have everything before you leave. It will <it>save</it> your having to go back again.</vi> <vi>The shortcut <it>saves</it> an hour's driving.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to keep (someone) from doing something <vi>Thanks for sending out that package. It <it>saved</it> me a trip to the post office.</vi> <vi>I'll make the appointment for you to <phrase>save you the trouble/bother</phrase>. [=so that you don't have to do it yourself]</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>You should cut up the vegetables to <it>save</it> you <it>from</it> doing it later when the guests are here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to collect or keep (something) <vi>She <it>saved</it> all his letters.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to store (data) in a computer or on a storage device (such as a CD) so that it can be used later <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You should <it>save</it> your work on/to a disk.</vi> <vi><it>save</it> a file</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Don't forget to <it>save</it> before you close the file.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (an opponent's shot) from scoring a goal <vi>He <it>saved</it> the penalty kick/shot.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep (a game) from being lost to an opponent <vi>The relief pitcher <it>saved</it> the game.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>in Christianity</ssl> <dt>:to protect or free (someone) from sin or evil <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He believes that Jesus Christ will <it>save</it> him.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Jesus <it>saves</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a penny saved (is a penny earned)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>penny</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>save face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's bacon/hide/neck/skin</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to save someone :to help someone get out of a dangerous or difficult situation <vi>You really <it>saved my bacon</it> by helping out yesterday.</vi> <vi>He doesn't care what happens to us. All he's worried about is <it>saving his own skin/neck</it>. [=saving himself]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's life</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>save a life</va></svr> <dt>:to stop (someone) from dying or being killed :to rescue (someone) who is in terrible danger <vi>She thanked the firefighters who <it>saved her life</it>. [=rescued her]</vi> <vi>a surgical procedure that has <it>saved the lives</it> of thousands of people</vi> <vi>The use of seat belts can <it>save lives</it>.</vi> <vi>If you donate blood, you might <it>save a life</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help (someone) in an important way <un>often used to thank someone who helped you <vi>Thanks for covering for me. You really <it>saved my life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save the day</dre> <def><dt>:to make a bad situation end successfully <vi>Just when things looked hopeless, my brother came along and <it>saved the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to save your life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>cannot do something to save your life</phrase>, you are completely unable to do it. <vi>She <it>can't sing to save her life</it>. [=she is a very bad singer]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="short[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">short</hw> <sound><wav>short001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈʃoɚt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>short*er</if></in> <in><if>short*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:extending a small distance from one end to the other end :having little length :not long <vi>Her hair is <it>short</it>. = She has <it>short</it> hair.</vi> <vi>It's just a <it>short</it> distance from here. = It's just a <it>short</it> distance away.</vi> <vi>the <it>shortest</it> rope</vi> <vi>One of my legs is slightly <it>shorter</it> than the other.</vi> <vi>The coat is <it>short</it> on him. = The coat is too <it>short</it> for him. [=the coat should be longer in order to fit him correctly]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not great in distance <vi>a <it>short</it> walk/drive/trip</vi> <vi>This way is <it>shorter</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having little height :not tall <vi>He is <it>short</it> for his age.</vi> <vi>a <it>short</it> girl</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:lasting or continuing for a small amount of time :<sx>brief</sx> <vi>a <it>short</it> delay/vacation/speech</vi> <vi>the <it>shortest</it> day of the year</vi> <vi>Life's too <it>short</it> to worry about the past.</vi> <vi>The movie/meeting was very <it>short</it>.</vi> <vi>You have done a lot in a <it>short</it> space/period of time.</vi> <vi>a <it>short</it> burst of speed</vi> <vi>I've only lived here for a <it>short</it> time/while.</vi> <vi>It's just a <it>short</it> walk from here. [=you can walk there from here in a few minutes]</vi> <vi>She has a very <phrase>short memory</phrase>. [=she forgets about events, conversations, etc., soon after they happen]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:seeming to pass quickly <vi>She has made great progress in a few <it>short</it> years.</vi> <vi>He visited for two <it>short</it> weeks.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:having few pages, items, etc. <vi>a <it>short</it> book/poem</vi> <vi>I have a list of things I need to do before we go, but it's pretty <it>short</it>.</vi> <vi><it>short</it> sentences</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of clothing</ssl> <dt>:covering only part of the arms or legs <vi>boys in <it>short</it> pants</vi> <vi>a shirt with <it>short</it> sleeves [=sleeves that end at or above the elbows]</vi> <vi>a <it>short</it> skirt [=a skirt that ends above the knees and especially several inches above the knees]</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:existing in less than the usual or needed amount <vi>We should hurry. Time is <it>short</it>. [=we don't have much time]</vi> <vi>Money has been <it>short</it> lately. [=I haven't had enough money lately]</vi> <vi>Gasoline is <phrase>in short supply</phrase>. [=little gasoline is available]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) We can be ready <phrase>on short notice</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) We can be ready <phrase>at short notice</phrase>. [=very quickly]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Thank you for meeting with me <phrase>on such short notice</phrase>. = (<it>Brit</it>) Thank you for meeting with me <phrase>at such short notice</phrase>. [=even though you did not know that I wanted to meet with you until a short time ago]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:having less than what is needed :not having enough of something <vi>I can't pay the bill. I'm a little <it>short</it> (of money). [=I don't have enough money]</vi> <vi>The team was <it>short</it> (by) two players. = The team was two players <it>short</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><it>short on</it> time/food/money</vi> <vi>She's a little <it>short on</it> patience today. [=she is feeling somewhat impatient]</vi> <vi>He's not <it>short on</it> self-confidence. [=he has plenty of self-confidence]</vi> <vi>He was long on criticism but <it>short on</it> useful advice. [=he was very critical but did not give any useful advice]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:less than <un>used in the phrase <phrase>nothing short of</phrase> to give emphasis to a statement or description <vi>His recovery is <it>nothing short of</it> a miracle. = His recovery is <it>nothing short of</it> miraculous. [=his recovery is a miracle; his recovery is miraculous]</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:not reaching far enough <vi>The throw to first base was <it>short</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>short</it> throw</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:made smaller by having part removed <vi>a <it>short</it> tax form</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>“Doc” is <it>short for</it> “doctor.”</vi> <vi>“Ben” is <it>short for</it> “Benjamin.”</vi> <vi>“www” is <it>short for</it> “World Wide Web.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:talking to someone in a very brief and unfriendly way :rudely brief <vi>I'm sorry I was <it>short</it> [=<it>abrupt</it>, <it>curt</it>] with you.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>linguistics</ssl> <ssl>of a vowel</ssl> <dt><un>used to identify certain vowel sounds in English <vi>long and <it>short</it> vowels</vi> <vi>the <it>short</it> “a” in “bad”</vi> <vi>the <it>short</it> “e” in “bet”</vi> <vi>the <it>short</it> “i” in “sit”</vi> <vi>the <it>short</it> “o” in “hot”</vi> <vi>the <it>short</it> “u” in “but”</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>long <dxn>6</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a short fuse</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fuse</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>draw the short straw</dre> <dx>see <dxt>draw</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fall short</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fall</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in short order</dre> <def><dt>:quickly and without delay <vi><it>In short order</it> the group set up camp.</vi> <vi>The papers were organized <it>in short order</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make short work of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>work</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>short and sweet</dre> <def><dt>:pleasantly brief :not lasting a long time or requiring a lot of time <vi>That's the way we like the meetings—<it>short and sweet</it>.</vi> <vi>I've got a few announcements, but I'll keep it <it>short and sweet</it>. [=I will talk for only a few minutes]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>short of breath</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>short of breath</it>, it is difficult for you to breathe. <vi>He is overweight and gets <it>short of breath</it> [=<it>out of breath</it>] just walking to his car.</vi> <vi>She was <it>short of breath</it> and unable to talk after her run.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the short end of the stick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stick</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>short*ness</ure> <sound><wav>shortn01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈʃoɚtnəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>I was surprised by the <it>shortness</it> of the meeting.</vi> <vi>One symptom is <phrase>shortness of breath</phrase>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="waste[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">waste</hw> <altpr>ˈweɪst</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>wastes</if></in> <in><if>wast*ed</if></in> <in><if>wast*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use (something valuable) in a way that is not necessary or effective :to use more of (something) than is necessary <vi>Don't <it>waste</it> water during the summer drought.</vi> <vi>He always <it>wasted</it> his money on useless gadgets.</vi> <vi>Turn off the lights so we don't <it>waste</it> electricity.</vi> <vi>I think he's just <it>wasting</it> my time.</vi> <vi>We can't afford to <it>waste</it> so much food.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use (something or someone) in a way that does not produce a valuable result or effect :to fail to use (something or someone) in an appropriate or effective way <vi>We can't afford to <it>waste</it> this opportunity.</vi> <vi>She's a good writer but she's <it>wasting</it> her talent. [=she's not using her talent to do the things that she should be doing]</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) wasted</it> <vi>My efforts <it>were wasted</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>was wasted</it> in that job. [=his talents/skills were not being used in the job]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to kill or murder (someone) <vi>Someone <it>wasted</it> him.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>waste away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to become thinner and weaker because of illness or lack of food <vi>The disease caused her to <it>waste away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>waste no time</dre> <def><dt>:to do something quickly <vi>We <it>wasted no time</it> getting our tickets. [=we hurried to get our tickets]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>waste not, want not</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that if you never waste things you will always have what you need</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>waste your breath</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breath</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
