<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="brick[1]"> <hw hindex="1">brick</hw> <sound><wav>brick001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɪk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bricks</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small, hard block of baked clay that is used to build structures (such as houses) and sometimes to make streets, paths, etc. <vi>a pile of <it>bricks</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:blocks of baked clay used as building material <vi>a house made of <it>brick</it></vi> <vi>Most of the buildings in the town are (made of) <it>brick</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>brick</it> wall/building/oven</vi> <vi>a <it>brick</it> sidewalk</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a block of something <vi>a <it>brick</it> of ice cream</vi> <vi>a glass <it>brick</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a child's toy block <vi>children playing with wooden <it>bricks</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a helpful or dependable person <vi>He has been an absolute <it>brick</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bricks and mortar</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:houses and other buildings especially when people consider buying them because of their possible future value <vi>Market uncertainties have been driving the rush to invest in <it>bricks and mortar</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>brick-and-mortar</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop a brick</dre> <dx>see <dxt>drop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like a ton of bricks</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very hard or severely <vi>The loss of his job <phrase>hit him like a ton of bricks</phrase>. [=hit him very hard; made him very upset, unhappy, etc.]</vi> <vi>Our boss <phrase>came down on us like a ton of bricks</phrase> [=got very angry at us] when he found out we had missed the meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brick[2]"> <hw hindex="2">brick</hw> <altpr>ˈbrɪk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bricks</if></in> <in><if>bricked</if></in> <in><if>brick*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>brick up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>brick (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>brick up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cover or block (something) with bricks <vi>They <it>bricked up</it> the windows.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="brick-and-mortar"> <hw>brick–and–mortar</hw> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>bricks–and–mortar</va></vr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt><un>used to describe a traditional store or business that is in a building instead of on the Internet <vi>They have a Web site as well as several <it>brick-and-mortar</it> stores.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>bricks and mortar</tag> at <dxt>brick</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="brick red"> <hw>brick red</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a brownish-red color <dx>see color picture on page C3</dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>brick red</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>brick-red</it> scarf</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="drop[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">drop</hw> <altpr>ˈdrɑ:p</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>drops</if></in> <in><if>dropped</if></in> <in><if>drop*ping</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to let (something) fall <vi>Be careful not to <it>drop</it> the chair on your foot.</vi> <vi>She <it>dropped</it> the apple core into the trash can.</vi> <vi>They <it>dropped</it> bombs on the city.</vi> <vi>He <it>dropped</it> the vase and it shattered into pieces.</vi> <vi>The player <it>dropped</it> the ball.</vi> <vi>The trees <it>drop</it> their needles in the winter. [=the needles fall off the trees in the winter]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fall <vi>The pen rolled to the edge of the table and <it>dropped</it> to the floor.</vi> <vi>The book <it>dropped</it> from my hand.</vi> <vi>The ball <it>dropped</it> between the right and center fielders.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to lie down or fall down suddenly <vi>He <it>dropped</it> (down) to the floor and hid under the bed.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to lie down or become unconscious because you are sick or exhausted :<sx>collapse</sx> <vi>She was so tired she felt she would <it>drop</it>.</vi> <vi>He worked until he <it>dropped</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) We're going to the mall to <phrase>shop till we drop</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go down suddenly and form a steep slope <vi>The road <it>drops</it> into the valley.</vi> <vi>The cliff <it>drops</it> almost vertically.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change to a lower level, amount, position, etc. <vi>The temperature <it>dropped</it> (to 50 degrees).</vi> <vi>His voice <it>dropped</it> [=became quieter] as he told us the secret.</vi> <vi>Increased competition has caused prices to <it>drop</it>. [=<it>decline, go down</it>]</vi> <vi>Production has <it>dropped</it>. [=<it>decreased</it>]</vi> <vi>The team has <it>dropped</it> [=<it>fallen</it>] to third place.</vi> <vi>He <it>dropped</it> [=<it>fell</it>] behind the other runners when he hurt his ankle.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to lessen or decrease in level or amount <vi>He <it>dropped</it> [=<it>lowered</it>] his voice.</vi> <vi>She <it>dropped</it> [=<it>reduced</it>] her speed when she saw the patrol car.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to send (someone) a letter, note, etc. <vi>I'll <it>drop</it> you an e-mail when I know my schedule.</vi> <vi><phrase>Drop me a line</phrase> [=write me a letter] sometime.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop talking or thinking about (something) <vi>You can <it>drop</it> that idea right now.</vi> <vi>Let's just <phrase>drop the subject</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Just <phrase>drop it</phrase>. I don't want to talk about it any more.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop being talked about <vi>Please let the matter <it>drop</it>.</vi> <vi>Once he starts talking about a subject he just won't <phrase>let it drop</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop doing or continuing with (something) <vi>I'm going to <it>drop</it> my calculus class and take a biology course instead.</vi> <vi>New evidence was found and the case was <it>dropped</it>.</vi> <vi>The prosecutors <phrase>dropped the charges</phrase> against her.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>dropped everything</phrase> [=stopped what I was doing] and ran to the window to see what was going on.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to not include (someone or something) <vi>You should <it>drop</it> [=<it>cut, omit</it>] this sentence from your essay.</vi> <vi>The newspaper decided to <it>drop</it> the story.</vi> <vi>He was <it>dropped</it> from the team.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to suddenly end a relationship or connection with (someone) <vi>They dated for a while, but then she suddenly <it>dropped</it> him.</vi> <vi>She moved away and <it>dropped</it> her old friends.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to take (someone or something) to a place and then leave <vi>She <it>dropped</it> him in front of the library.</vi> <vi>He <it>dropped</it> the package at the post office this morning.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>I <it>drop</it> the kids <it>off</it> at school in the morning.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>drop off</it> the paperwork as soon as it's all filled out.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a brief social visit <un>usually + <it>by</it> or <it>in</it> or <it>over</it> <vi>His sister <it>dropped by</it> unexpectedly.</vi> <vi>They <it>dropped in</it> for a chat.</vi> <vi><it>Drop over</it> sometime!</vi> <vi>We were in the neighborhood and thought we would <phrase>drop in on</phrase> you.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>drop-in</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say (something) in an informal or casual way <vi>He casually <it>dropped</it> the news that they are getting married.</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>dropping names</phrase>. [=saying the names of famous people she knows to try to impress others]</vi> <vi>She has been <phrase>dropping hints</phrase> that she is looking for another job.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to lose (a game) <vi>They <it>dropped</it> the first game but won the next two.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to spend (an amount of money) <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>She <it>dropped</it> $300 <it>on</it> a new suit.</vi></un></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to lose (an amount of weight) <vi>Through diet and exercise, I managed to <it>drop</it> 20 pounds in a year.</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <dt>:to move down <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>When the teacher became angry at her, she <phrase>dropped her eyes/head</phrase>. [=she looked down]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His gaze <it>dropped</it> to the floor in embarrassment.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>knitting</ssl> <dt>:to let (a loop of yarn) fall off a knitting needle <vi>Count the stitches on the needle to make sure you didn't <it>drop</it> one.</vi> <vi>Be careful you don't <phrase>drop a stitch</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to not pronounce (a letter) when you speak <vi>When she spoke quickly, she <it>dropped</it> the “g” in “running.”</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to take (a drug) by swallowing it <vi>They <phrase>dropped acid</phrase>. [=they took LSD]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>drop a brick</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>drop a clanger</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to make a very bad or embarrassing mistake</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop back</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>American football</sl> <dt>:to move straight back from the line of scrimmage <vi>The quarterback <it>dropped back</it> and threw a long pass down the field.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop dead</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>drop in/into/on your lap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>drop off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to decrease in amount <vi>After the holidays, business usually <it>drops off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fall asleep <vi>The baby tends to <it>drop off</it> after he eats.</vi> <vi>She lay down and <phrase>dropped off to sleep</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>drop <dxn>10 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop attending a school or university before you have completed your studies <vi>He <it>dropped out</it> after 10th grade.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>He <it>dropped out of</it> [=<it>quit</it>] college/school and began working full-time.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop being part of a group <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>She was the first to <it>drop out of</it> the band.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being involved in regular society because you do not agree with or support its rules, customs, and values <vi>Back in the sixties he <it>dropped out</it> and lived as a hippie for several years.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dropout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop out of sight</dre> <def><dt>:to stop being seen <vi>The house <it>dropped out of sight</it> as we drove over the hill.</vi> <vi>a famous and successful actor who suddenly <it>dropped out of sight</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>jaw drops</dre> <dx>see <dxt>jaw</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the bottom drop out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bottom</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the penny drops</dre> <dx>see <dxt>penny</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>you could hear a pin drop</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
