<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bridge[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bridge</hw> <sound><wav>bridge01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbrɪʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bridg*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a structure built over something (such as a river) so that people or vehicles can get across <vi>a <it>bridge</it> connecting the island to the mainland</vi> <vi>the Brooklyn <it>Bridge</it></vi> <vi>a <phrase>railroad bridge</phrase> [=a bridge for trains]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>drawbridge</dxt> <dxt>footbridge</dxt> <dxt>suspension bridge</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that joins or connects different people or things <vi>Her work serves as a <it>bridge</it> between the past and the present.</vi> <vi>They hope to <phrase>build a bridge</phrase> between the two cultures. [=they hope to help the people in the two cultures understand each other]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the place on a ship where the ship is steered</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the upper part of the nose <vi>He broke <phrase>the bridge of his nose</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the part of a pair of eyeglasses that rests on a person's nose</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the part of a guitar, violin, or similar musical instrument that raises the strings away from the surface</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:part of a song that connects one section to the next section</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a false tooth or row of false teeth that fits between two real teeth</dt></def> <dro><dre>burn your bridges</dre> <dx>see <dxt>burn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cross that bridge when you come to it</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you say you will <it>cross that bridge when you come to it</it>, you mean that you will not worry about a possible problem until it actually happens. <vi>I don't know how we'll pay the bills if you quit your job, but <it>we'll cross that bridge when we come to it</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>water under the bridge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bridge</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bridge[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">bridge</hw> <altpr>ˈbrɪʤ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bridges</if></in> <in><if>bridged</if></in> <in><if>bridg*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to make a bridge over or across (something) <un>usually used figuratively <vi>We hope to <it>bridge</it> the divisions between the two groups.</vi></un> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>bridge the gap</phrase> <vi>styles that <it>bridge the gap</it> between fashion and practicality</vi> <vi>a book that attempts to <it>bridge the</it> generation <it>gap</it></vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bridge[3]"> <hw hindex="3">bridge</hw> <altpr>ˈbrɪʤ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a card game for four players in two teams</dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bridge</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="bridge loan"> <hw>bridge loan</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ loans</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:money that a bank lends you for a short period of time until you receive the money that you are getting from another source (such as from selling your house) <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>bridging loan</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="suspension bridge"> <hw>suspension bridge</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bridges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a bridge that is hung from two or more cables that are held up by towers</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="swing bridge"> <hw>swing bridge</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ bridges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a bridge that can be moved or raised so that tall boats can pass under it</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cross[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">cross</hw> <altpr>ˈkrɑ:s</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>crosses</if></in> <in><if>crossed</if></in> <in><if>cross*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go from one side of (something) to the other :to go across (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>We <it>crossed</it> the state border hours ago.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>crossed</it> the street.</vi> <vi>The highway <it>crosses</it> the entire state.</vi> <vi>He was the first runner to <it>cross</it> the finish line.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The train <it>crosses</it> through France.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or pass across each other <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>the point at which two lines <it>cross</it> [=<it>intersect</it>]</vi> <vi>Put a nail where the boards <it>cross</it>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>One line <it>crossed</it> the other.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to place one arm, leg, etc., over the other <vi><it>cross</it> your arms/legs/fingers</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>cross your fingers</phrase> or <phrase>keep your fingers crossed</phrase>, you hope that you will be lucky and that something you want to happen will happen. <vi>I <it>crossed my fingers</it> and hoped that I would be chosen.</vi> <vi><it>Keep your fingers crossed</it>. I just sent out my college applications.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to draw a line across (something) <vi>Remember to <it>cross</it> your <it>t</it>'s. [=to put a line across the top of the letter “t” when you write it]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>dot your i's and cross your t's</tag> at <dxt>dot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to pass in opposite directions <vi>Our letters <it>crossed</it> in the mail. [=my letter was going to you while your letter was coming to me]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to turn (your eyes) inward toward your nose <vi>He <it>crossed</it> his eyes.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to act against the wishes, plans, or orders of (someone) <vi>My boss is usually nice, but she has a terrible temper and you don't want to <it>cross</it> her.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>double-cross</dxt> <dxt>star-crossed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make two different kinds of animals breed together <vi>The breeders <it>crossed</it> [=<it>crossbred, interbred</it>] the bison with domestic cattle.</vi> <un>often used figuratively to describe someone or something that combines the qualities of two different people or things <vi>As our leader, she was like a drill sergeant <it>crossed</it> with a camp counselor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to mix two kinds of plants to form a new one <vi>The farmers <it>crossed</it> two different types of corn together.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>soccer</ssl> <dt>:to kick or hit the ball sideways across the field <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>crossed to</it> his teammate.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>cross my heart</dre> <def><dt><snote>The phrases <phrase>cross my heart</phrase> or <phrase>cross my heart and hope to die</phrase> are used in informal speech to stress that you are telling the truth and will do what you promise. <vi>I'll clean my room tomorrow—<it>cross my heart</it>. [=I promise that I'll clean my room tomorrow]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cross (someone or something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cross off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to draw a line through (a name or item on a list) <vi>They <it>crossed off</it> the names of the people who had already been invited.</vi> <vi>We can <it>cross</it> her <it>off</it> our list of potential donors.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cross (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cross out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to draw a line through (something) to show that it is wrong <vi><it>cross out</it> a mistake</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cross over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cross over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move or go from one side of (something) to the other <vi>The deer <it>crossed over</it> to the other side of the river.</vi> <vi>The bridge <it>crosses over</it> the river.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change from one type of character or condition to another <vi>People were <it>crossing over</it> to vote for the other party's candidate. [=people in one political party were voting for the other party's candidate]</vi> <vi>The singer <it>crossed over</it> from country to pop. [=the singer changed his style of music from country to pop]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>crossover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross paths</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people <phrase>cross paths</phrase> or when their <phrase>paths cross</phrase>, they meet each other at a time that was not planned or expected. <vi>After they left college, it was many years before they <it>crossed paths</it> again. = It was many years before their <it>paths crossed</it> again.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>crossed paths with</phrase> an old friend on a business trip.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross someone's face</dre> <def><dt>:to appear briefly on someone's face <vi>A smile <it>crossed her face</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross someone's mind</dre> <def><dt>:to come into someone's mind :to be thought of by someone <vi>Losing never <it>crossed her mind</it>. [=she was sure that she would win]</vi> <vi>Did it ever <it>cross your mind</it> that I could be right?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross swords</dre> <def><dt>:to fight or argue <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I didn't want to <it>cross swords with</it> him about who was right.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross that bridge when you come to it</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bridge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cross the line</dre> <def><dt>:to go beyond what is proper or acceptable <vi>Her criticism <it>crossed the line</it> from helpful to just plain hurtful.</vi> <vi>The magazine <it>crossed the line</it> when they printed the nude photos.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross up</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cross (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cross up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (someone) confused <vi>The team <it>crossed up</it> their opponent by throwing the ball instead of running it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cross (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cross up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to ruin (something) completely <vi>His failure to meet the deadline <it>crossed up</it> the deal.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cross yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to make the sign of the cross on your head and chest <vi>I <it>crossed myself</it> as I entered the church.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>cross*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cross*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="water[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">wa*ter</hw> <sound><wav>water002.wav</wav><wav>water001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɑ:tɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>wa*ters</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the clear liquid that has no color, taste, or smell, that falls from clouds as rain, that forms streams, lakes, and seas, and that is used for drinking, washing, etc. <vi>Would you like a glass of <it>water</it>?</vi> <vi>bottled/mineral/spring <it>water</it></vi> <vi>There's <it>water</it> dripping from the ceiling.</vi> <vi>Drink some <it>water</it>.</vi> <vi><phrase>drinking water</phrase> [=water that is safe for drinking]</vi> <vi>The house has hot and cold <phrase>running water</phrase>. [=water carried by pipes inside a building]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bathwater</dxt> <dxt>freshwater</dxt> <dxt>groundwater</dxt> <dxt>holy water</dxt> <dxt>ice water</dxt> <dxt>mineral water</dxt> <dxt>rainwater</dxt> <dxt>rose water</dxt> <dxt>saltwater</dxt> <dxt>seawater</dxt> <dxt>soda water</dxt> <dxt>tap water</dxt> <dxt>toilet water</dxt> <dxt>white water</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:an area of water (such as a lake, river, or ocean) <vi>deep/shallow <it>water</it></vi> <vi>The kids love playing in the <it>water</it>.</vi> <vi>A stick was floating on/in the <it>water</it>.</vi> <vi>They like to vacation near the <it>water</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>underwater</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>waters</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:a specific area of water</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:an area of seawater <vi>frigid northern <it>waters</it></vi> <vi>coastal/shallow <it>waters</it></vi> <vi>We are sailing in international <it>waters</it>.</vi> <vi>They were fishing in Canadian <it>waters</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We are entering into <phrase>dangerous waters</phrase> [=a difficult or complicated situation] whenever we discuss religion in public.</vi> <vi>He began studying the <phrase>murky waters</phrase> [=confusing details] of copyright law.</vi> <vi>The company is moving into <phrase>uncharted waters</phrase> [=new and unknown areas] with its Internet marketing campaign.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>headwaters</dxt> <dxt>territorial waters</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:methods of travel that involve boats and ships <vi>They came by <it>water</it>. [=by traveling on a boat or ship]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a fish out of water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fish</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>blood is thicker than water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come hell or high water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hell</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead in the water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold water</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be possible or believable <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>Her argument doesn't <it>hold water</it>. [=does not make sense]</vi> <vi>His theory cannot <it>hold water</it>. [=his theory is wrong]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in deep water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>deep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head above water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like a duck to water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>duck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>like water</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in large amounts <vi>He spends money <it>like water</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>muddy the waters</dre> <dx>see <dxt>muddy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pass water</dre> <def><sl>medical</sl> <dt>:to send urine out of the body :<sx>urinate</sx> <vi>a patient who is finding it difficult to <it>pass water</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pour/throw cold water on</dre> <def><dt>:to say that you do not like (an idea, suggestion, etc.) in a way that stops other people from doing it or from feeling enthusiastic about it <vi>He wanted to buy a new car, but I <it>poured/threw cold water on</it> that idea. [=I said he should not buy a new car]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>still waters run deep</dre> <dx>see <dxt>still</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>test the waters/water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>test</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>tread water</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tread</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>troubled waters</dre> <dx>see <dxt>troubled</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>water breaks</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>waters break</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to describe what happens when fluid suddenly comes from a pregnant woman's body because her baby will be born soon <vi>Her <it>water broke</it> early.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>water off a duck's back</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If something, such as criticism, advice, etc., is (<it>like</it>) <it>water off a duck's back</it>, it has no effect on someone. <vi>He tried to convince her to take the job, but his advice was <it>like water off a duck's back</it>. [=she completely ignored his advice]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>water under the bridge</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something happened in the past and is no longer important or worth arguing about <vi>We had our differences in the past, but that's all <it>water under the bridge</it> now.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
