<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bucket[1]"> <art><artref id="bucket_rev.tif"/><capt>bucket</capt><dim>50.6,79.8</dim></art> <hw hindex="1">buck*et</hw> <sound><wav>bucket01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌkət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>buck*ets</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an open container with a handle that is used especially to hold and carry water and other liquids <vi>a <it>bucket</it> and mop</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount contained in a bucket <vi>a <it>bucket</it> [=<it>bucketful</it>] of water</vi> <vi>We used two <it>buckets</it> of paint to paint the living room.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large container that is part of a machine (such as a tractor) and that is used for digging or carrying dirt, rocks, and other material</dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>buckets</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a large amount especially of a liquid <vi>The players were sweating <it>buckets</it>. [=were sweating very much]</vi> <vi>crying <it>buckets</it> of tears</vi> <vi>It's raining <it>buckets</it>. = The rain is coming down <phrase>in buckets</phrase>. [=it's raining very hard]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>basketball</ssl> <dt>:a successful shot :<sx>basket</sx> <vi>She scored/sank five <it>buckets</it> in the last five minutes of the game.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a drop in the bucket</dre> <dx>see <dxt>drop</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>kick the bucket</dre> <dx>see <dxt>kick</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>buck*et*ful</ure> <sound><wav>bucket02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌkətˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>buck*et*fuls</if> <pr>ˈbʌkətˌfʊlz</pr> <il>also</il> <if>buck*ets*ful</if> <sound><wav>bucket04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌkətsˌfʊl</pr></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bucketful</it> [=<it>bucket</it>] of nails</vi> <vi>She has <it>bucketfuls</it> [=<it>buckets</it>] of money.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="bucket[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bucket</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌkət</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>buckets</if></in> <in><if>bucket*ed</if></in> <in><if>bucket*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>bucket down</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to rain very heavily <vi>The rain is really <it>bucketing down</it>. = It's <it>bucketing down</it>. [=it's pouring]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bucket seat"> <hw>bucket seat</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ seats</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a low, separate seat for one person in a car or other vehicle</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bucket shop"> <hw>bucket shop</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ shops</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a company that sells cheap airplane tickets</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="drop[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">drop</hw> <sound><wav>drop0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdrɑ:p</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>drops</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a very small amount of liquid that falls in a rounded shape <vi>He squeezed the bottle until a few <it>drops</it> came out.</vi> <vi>She knew rain was coming when she felt a <it>drop</it> [=<it>raindrop</it>] land on her arm.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi><it>Drops of</it> water fell from the leaky faucet.</vi> <vi>a <it>drop of</it> blood</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>dewdrop</dxt> <dxt>raindrop</dxt> <dxt>teardrop</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a small amount of a drink <un>usually singular <vi>I didn't have a <it>drop</it> of your orange juice.</vi> <vi>I'd just like a <it>drop</it> of brandy, please.</vi> <vi>He used to have a drinking problem but he <phrase>hasn't touched a drop</phrase> [=hasn't drunk any alcohol] in years.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a small amount of something (such as a quality) <vi>She doesn't have a single <it>drop</it> of selfishness in her.</vi> <vi>The poet wrings the last <it>drop</it> of meaning from every word.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>drops</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:liquid medicine that is measured in drops and put into your eyes, ears, or nose <vi>The doctor prescribed daily <it>drops</it> for the child's ears.</vi> <vi><phrase>eye/ear drops</phrase></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a usually small, round piece of candy with a particular flavor <vi>We sucked on lemon <it>drops</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cough drop</dxt> <dxt>gumdrop</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the distance from a higher to a lower level <un>usually singular <vi>It is a 50-foot <it>drop</it> from the cliff to the ground below.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an area that goes downward suddenly <vi>A steep <it>drop</it> in the river forms a waterfall.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a decrease in amount or quality <un>usually singular <vi>His income took a sudden <it>drop</it>.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>He had a sudden <it>drop in</it> income.</vi> <vi>The patient experienced a sharp <it>drop in</it> blood pressure.</vi> <vi>a <it>drop</it> [=<it>decline</it>] <it>in</it> prices/sales</vi> <vi>a four percent <it>drop in</it> body weight</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of taking something (such as something secret or illegal) to a place and leaving it there <vi>He made the <it>drop</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a place where something is taken to and left to be picked up <vi>I left the package at the <it>drop</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>airdrop</dxt> <dxt>mail drop</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:a move back from the line of scrimmage <un>usually singular <vi>The quarterback made a quick three-step <it>drop</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a drop in the bucket</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>a drop in the ocean</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:an amount that is so small that it does not make an important difference or have much effect <vi>They need to raise thousands of dollars for this project, so our 20-dollar donation is just <it>a drop in the bucket</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the drop of a hat</dre> <def><dt>:very quickly and immediately <vi>He says he's ready to help us <it>at the drop of a hat</it>.</vi> <vi>She loses her temper <it>at the drop of a hat</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="kick[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">kick</hw> <sound><wav>kick0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>kicks</if></in> <in><if>kicked</if></in> <in><if>kick*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit (someone or something) with your foot <vi>The attacker <it>kicked</it> him in the stomach.</vi> <vi>She lost her temper and <it>kicked</it> over the box.</vi> <vi>He <it>kicked</it> the ball into the goal.</vi> <vi>She <it>kicked</it> the ball to me.</vi> <vi>The policeman <it>kicked</it> the door open.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move your leg or legs in the air or in water especially in a strong or forceful way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The baby <it>kicked</it> his legs in the air.</vi> <vi>The swimming instructor reminded the children to <it>kick</it> their legs as they swam.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The baby <it>kicked</it> with pleasure.</vi> <vi>The boy <phrase>kicked and screamed</phrase> as his mother carried him out of the room. = The boy was carried out of the room <phrase>kicking and screaming</phrase>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>They told him he needed a computer, but he had to be <phrase>dragged kicking and screaming</phrase> into the 21st century. [=he had to be forced to stop doing things the old way and use a computer]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to score (a goal) by kicking a ball <vi>He <it>kicked</it> the winning field goal.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to completely stop doing (something harmful to yourself) :to put an end to (a bad or dangerous habit) <vi>When he was 25, he <it>kicked</it> his cocaine habit and went back to school.</vi> <vi>I've been smoking for years, but this year I'm determined to <phrase>kick the habit</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be full of life and energy <un>always used as <it>(be) kicking</it> <vi>He's almost 90 years old, but he<it>'s</it> still <it>kicking</it>.</vi> <vi>The movement <it>is</it> still <phrase>alive and kicking</phrase>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>kick around</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick around (a place)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to spend time in (a place) without having a goal or purpose :to wander around (a place) <vi>After graduation, he <it>kicked around</it> Boston for a while, trying to decide what to do next. = After graduation, he <it>kicked around</it> for a while, trying to decide what to do next.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be lying somewhere within a general area or place <vi>I think I have a copy of that book <it>kicking around</it> [=lying around] somewhere in my house.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to be considered or discussed in an informal way over a period of time <vi>These ideas have been <it>kicking around</it> for years.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick around (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) around</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to consider or talk about (ideas, plans, etc.) in an informal way <vi>We should have a meeting to <it>kick around</it> some ideas about possible new products.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick (someone) around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick around (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to treat (someone) in a very bad or unfair way <vi>He gets <it>kicked around</it> by his older brother.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick ass</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal + impolite</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to succeed or win in a very impressive way <vi>a lawyer who <it>kicks ass</it> in the courtroom</vi> <vi>Our team <it>kicked ass</it> in the soccer tournament.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to use force to achieve some purpose <vi>If they don't start answering my questions, I'm going to go over there and <it>kick</it> some <it>ass</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>kick someone's ass</bnote> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to attack and injure someone severely <vi>Some drunk threatened to <it>kick his ass</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>got his ass kicked</phrase> by some drunk.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to defeat someone easily or completely <vi>We <it>got our asses kicked</it> [=we lost badly] in the last game.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>kick-ass</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick back</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to relax and enjoy yourself <vi>After work, he likes to <it>kick back</it> and watch some TV.</vi> <vi>I spent the weekend just <it>kicking back</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick butt</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal + sometimes impolite</sl> <dt><un>used in the same ways as <it>kick ass</it> (above) <vi>Our team <it>kicked butt</it> in the soccer tournament.</vi> <vi>I'm going to go over there and <it>kick</it> some <it>butt</it>.</vi> <vi>Some drunk threatened to <it>kick his butt</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin to work or to have an effect <vi>Once the heat <it>kicks in</it>, it will be a lot more comfortable in here.</vi> <vi>waiting for the new law to <it>kick in</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) in</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to give (an amount of money) as your share :<sx>contribute</sx> <vi>We each <it>kicked in</it> a few dollars for her gift.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start play in a game (such as American football or soccer) by kicking the ball <vi>Jones will <it>kick off</it> from the 30-yard line.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>kickoff</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin (something, such as a performance, an event, or a discussion) <vi>The chairman's speech will <it>kick off</it> the conference.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get started :<sx>begin</sx> <vi>The conference <it>kicked off</it> with a speech by the chairman.</vi> <vi>The game <it>kicks off</it> at 1:00.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to leave (a team or group) <vi>The coach threatened to <it>kick</it> him <it>off</it> the team if he continued to be late for practice.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick off (your shoes)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (your shoes) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (your shoes) by making a kicking motion <vi>She <it>kicked off</it> her shoes and started to dance.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to die <vi>I was so sick that I felt like I might <it>kick off</it> at any time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>kick (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone) to leave a place, group, school, etc. <vi>He was/got <it>kicked out</it> [=<it>thrown out</it>] of the school when he was caught cheating again.</vi> <vi>They threatened to <it>kick</it> him <it>out</it> (of the bar) if he didn't stop annoying people.</vi> <vi>She <it>kicked</it> her husband <it>out</it> (of the house).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick (someone) upstairs</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to promote (someone) to a higher but less powerful or important position <vi>He was <it>kicked upstairs</it>, given a fancy title, and stripped of most of his power.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick the bucket</dre> <def><sl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to die <vi>He inherited the house after his uncle <it>kicked the bucket</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to rise upward <vi>The car sped away, <it>kicking up</it> dirt and gravel.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to become stronger <vi>The praise <it>kicked up</it> her confidence.</vi> <vi>The intensity of the game got <it>kicked up</it> a notch when a fight broke out.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become stronger <vi>The wind suddenly <it>kicked up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>kick up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>kick (something) up</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen <vi>The high winds <it>kicked up</it> huge waves.</vi> <vi>The service in the restaurant wasn't very good, but we decided not to <phrase>kick up a fuss/stink</phrase> [=<it>complain</it>] about it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick up your heels</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to relax and enjoy yourself :to have a good and lively time <vi>After exams were over, the students had a little time to <it>kick up their heels</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>kick yourself</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to blame or criticize yourself for something you have done <vi>You've got to stop <it>kicking yourself</it>. It wasn't your fault that the project failed.</vi> <vi>He was <it>kicking himself</it> for having forgotten the meeting.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>could have kicked himself</phrase> [=he was very angry at himself] when he realized that he had forgotten the meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
