<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="build[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">build</hw> <sound><wav>build001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪld</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>builds</if></in> <in><if>built</if> <sound><wav>built001.wav</wav><wav>build002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪlt</pr></in> <in><if>build*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make (something) by putting together parts or materials <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The house is <it>built</it> (out) of brick/logs.</vi> <vi>The bridge was <it>built</it> in the 1890s.</vi> <vi>The planes were <it>built</it> in Germany.</vi> <vi>The organization helps <it>build</it> houses for poor families.</vi> <vi><it>building</it> more powerful machines/computers/weapons</vi> <vi>A family of birds has <it>built</it> a nest on our roof.</vi> <vi>She started <it>building</it> a fire in the fireplace.</vi> <vi>He <it>built</it> a model airplane from a kit.</vi> <vi>He <it>built</it> a dollhouse for the children. = He <it>built</it> the children a dollhouse.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You will need permission to <it>build</it> on your property.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to develop or form (something) gradually <vi>I've started <it>building</it> a collection of rare books. [=I've started collecting rare books]</vi> <vi>They <it>built</it> the organization from scratch. = They <it>built</it> the organization from the ground/bottom up.</vi> <vi>They are <it>building</it> a legal case against the tobacco industry.</vi> <vi>scientists <it>building</it> theories about how the universe began</vi> <vi>At college, you'll <it>build</it> friendships that will last a lifetime.</vi> <vi>She <it>built</it> a successful career in advertising.</vi> <vi>He has <it>built</it> a reputation as a talented artist.</vi> <vi><it>building</it> a more peaceful world [=making the world more peaceful]</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi><it>Building up</it> a successful business can take many years.</vi> <vi>She has <it>built up</it> a large collection of awards.</vi> <vi>We've been <it>building up</it> a savings account.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>build up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to increase the amount of (something) <vi>Lifting weights helps <it>build</it> muscle and increase strength.</vi> <vi>These programs are designed to help <it>build</it> confidence in young women.</vi> <vi>The advertisements are aimed at <it>building</it> support for political candidates.</vi> <vi>They thought the army would <it>build</it> character in their son. [=would make their son become a better person]</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>She runs a little farther every day to <it>build up</it> (her) endurance.</vi> <vi><it>building up</it> momentum/stamina/energy</vi> <vi>He's been trying to <it>build up</it> the courage/confidence to talk to her.</vi> <vi>These exercises will help you <it>build up</it> your strength.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>build up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to grow or increase to a high point, level, number, etc. <vi>The excitement was beginning to <it>build</it> before the game.</vi> <vi>A crowd was <it>building</it> around the accident.</vi> <vi>The story slowly <it>builds</it> to a climax. [=the story slowly reaches a climax]</vi> <vi>Chemicals in the lake are <it>building</it> to dangerous levels.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>As the water temperature rises, the pressure inside the pot begins to <it>build up</it>.</vi> <vi>Their passion/anger/fear/hatred has been <it>building up</it> for years.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>build up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>build around</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>build (something) around (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to develop or organize (something) by using (something, such as an idea) as its main or central part <vi>We <it>built</it> our program <it>around</it> the idea that people need love and support.</vi> <vi>Their lives are <it>built around</it> their children. [=their children are the most important things in their lives]</vi> <vi>The textbook <it>builds</it> lessons <it>around</it> grammar topics.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>build in/into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>build in (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>build (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>build (something) in/into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (something) a part of (something else) <vi>Carmakers are beginning to <it>build in</it> these new safety features as standard equipment. = Carmakers are <it>building</it> these new safety features <it>into</it> new cars as standard equipment.</vi> <vi>We've <it>built</it> bookshelves <it>into</it> the wall.</vi> <vi>These ideas are <it>built into</it> the program/system/design.</vi> <vi>There are special provisions for bonuses <it>built into</it> the contract.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>built-in</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>build on/upon</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>build on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to use (something that has been done in the past) as a basis for further work, development, etc. <vi>Each president <it>builds on/upon</it> the success of each past president.</vi> <vi>These classes will help students <it>build on</it> what they already know.</vi> <vi><it>building upon</it> past experiences/successes</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>build (something) on/upon (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to develop or create (something) by using (something else) as its basis <vi>He <it>built</it> [=<it>based</it>] his theory <it>on</it> recent studies.</vi> <vi>She has <it>built</it> her reputation as a talented artist <it>on</it> the strength of her earlier paintings.</vi> <vi>Their theory is <it>built upon</it> her research.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>build onto</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>build onto (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>build (something) onto (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (a new room) to a structure that already exists <vi>They <it>built</it> a new garage <it>onto</it> their house.</vi> <vi>They <it>built onto</it> their house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>build up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to increase gradually in amount as time passes :<sx>accumulate</sx> <vi>They pick up the garbage that <it>builds up</it> [=<it>collects</it>] along the highway.</vi> <vi>Dust has begun <it>building up</it> on his piano.</vi> <vi>These dangerous chemicals are <it>building up</it> in our lakes and ponds.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>build (something or someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>build up (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to say many good things about (something or someone) <vi>Political candidates are trying to <it>build</it> themselves <it>up</it> [=promote themselves] with public speeches and TV commercials.</vi> <vi>The movie was <it>built up</it> so much [=we heard so many good things about the movie] that we were disappointed when we actually saw it.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>build <dxn>2</dxn></dxt> <dxt><dxn>3, 4 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>buildup</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="build[2]"> <hw hindex="2">build</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪld</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>builds</if></in> <def><dt>:the shape and size of a person's body <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>people with thin/slender/slight <it>builds</it></vi> <vi>He has a strong, muscular <it>build</it>. [=<it>physique</it>]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He is strong and muscular in <it>build</it>.</vi> <vi>a man of average <it>build</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
