<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bunch[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bunch</hw> <sound><wav>bunch001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʌntʃ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bunch*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of things of the same kind that are held or tied together or that grow together <vi>a <it>bunch</it> of flowers/grapes</vi> <vi>He always had a <it>bunch</it> of keys on his belt.</vi> <vi>Dried herbs hung in <it>bunches</it> from the kitchen rafters.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:a group of people or things that are together or are associated with each other in some way <un>usually singular <vi>a nice <it>bunch</it> of people</vi> <vi>A <it>bunch</it> of us are going out for lunch.</vi> <vi>They're a pretty wild <it>bunch</it> (of people).</vi> <vi>All his books are good, but this one is the best/pick of the <it>bunch</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:a large amount :<sx>lot</sx> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>Thanks a <it>bunch</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>We spent a <it>bunch of</it> money on our vacation.</vi> <vi>having a (whole) <it>bunch of</it> problems</vi> <vi>What a <it>bunch of</it> nonsense!</vi></un> <wsgram>plural</wsgram> <vi>They make <it>bunches</it> [=<it>lots</it>] <it>of</it> money.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>bunches</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a way of arranging hair by separating it into two sections and tying these at each side of the head <vi>She wore her hair in <it>bunches</it>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>ponytails</it>]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bunch[2]"> <hw hindex="2">bunch</hw> <altpr>ˈbʌntʃ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bunches</if></in> <in><if>bunched</if></in> <in><if>bunch*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put (things or people) together in a group or bunch <un>usually + <it>together</it> or <it>up</it> <vi>They <it>bunched</it> [=<it>grouped</it>] the rest <it>together</it> under the category of “Miscellaneous.”</vi> <vi>She had <it>bunched</it> [=<it>gathered</it>] her curly hair <it>up</it> into a messy ponytail.</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) bunched</it> <vi>The flowers <it>are bunched together</it> in one corner of the yard.</vi> <vi>The words <it>were</it> all <it>bunched together</it> at the bottom of the page.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to form a group <un>usually + <it>together</it> <vi>The baby birds <it>bunch</it> [=(more commonly) <it>huddle</it>] <it>together</it> for warmth.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of clothing</ssl> <dt>:to form a group of tight folds on or around part of your body <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The child's tights <it>bunched</it> at the ankles.</vi> <un>usually + <it>up</it> or <it>together</it> <vi>The sweater's long sleeves kept <it>bunching up</it> around her wrists.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>up</it> or <it>together</it>; usually used as <it>(be) bunched</it> <vi>The tights <it>were bunched together</it> at the ankles.</vi> <vi>The sweater's long sleeves kept getting all <it>bunched up</it> around her wrists.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="thanks"> <hw highlight="yes">thanks</hw> <sound><wav>thanks01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈθæŋks</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a good feeling that you have towards someone who has helped you, given something to you, etc. <vi>I brought you a gift as a way of showing my <it>thanks</it> for all you've done.</vi> <vi>I want express my <it>thanks</it> [=<it>gratitude</it>] (to you) for your kindness and generosity.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something done or said to express thanks <vi>A simple bouquet of flowers can be a nice way to say <it>thanks</it>.</vi> <vi>We should <phrase>give thanks</phrase> (to God) for all the good things in our lives.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used as a less formal way to say “thank you” <vi>“Here's your change.” “<it>Thanks</it>.” “You're welcome.”</vi> <vi><it>Thanks</it>! I appreciate it.</vi> <vi>“How's your mother doing?” “She's doing well, <it>thanks</it>.” [=thank you for asking]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi><it>Thanks for</it> coming.</vi> <vi><it>Thanks</it> so much <it>for</it> your kind letter. = Many <it>thanks for</it> the kind letter.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used like “thank you” as a polite way of accepting or refusing an offer <vi>“Do you want another one?” “<it>Thanks</it>.” [=<it>yes, please</it>]</vi> <vi>“Do you want another one?” “<phrase>Yes, thanks</phrase>.” [=<it>yes, please</it>]</vi> <vi>“Do you want another one?” “<phrase>No, thanks</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>“Can I help you find something?” “<it>No thanks</it>, I'm just looking.”</vi> <vi>“Would you like a ride?” “<phrase>Thanks, but no thanks</phrase>. I'll walk.”</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>no thanks to</dre> <def><dt>:without the help of (someone or something) :despite (someone or something) <vi>The vote passed, <it>no thanks to</it> the mayor. [=the vote passed even though the mayor did not help or want it to pass]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>owe a debt of thanks to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>debt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>thanks a bunch/lot/million</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:thank you very much <vi>Wow, this is great! <it>Thanks a million</it>!</vi> <un>often used in an ironic way to say that you are not pleased that someone has done or said something <vi>“I'm boring? <it>Thanks a lot</it>!”</vi> <vi><it>Thanks a million</it> for leaving the door open. There are flies everywhere now.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>thanks to</dre> <def><dt>:with the help of (someone or something) :because of (someone or something) <vi>I'm a lot happier these days <it>thanks to</it> my new girlfriend.</vi> <vi><it>Thanks to</it> a new technique, patients typically recover from the surgery in only a few days.</vi> <un>often used in an ironic way <vi><it>Thanks to</it> you we have to do the whole thing over again.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
