<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="bury"> <hw highlight="yes">bury</hw> <sound><wav>bury0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈberi</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bur*ies</if></in> <in><if>bur*ied</if></in> <in><if>bury*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to put (a dead person or animal) in a grave <vi>He was <it>buried</it> with full military honors.</vi> <vi>Their ancestors are <it>buried</it> in the local cemetery.</vi> <vi>cultures that <it>bury</it> their dead</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have someone that you love or are related to die <vi>He had three children by two wives and <it>buried</it> [=<it>outlived</it>] them all.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to hide (something) in the ground <vi>The dog <it>buried</it> her bone.</vi> <vi>He <it>buried</it> the money in the backyard.</vi> <vi>the search for <it>buried</it> treasure</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hide (something) so that it cannot be seen or is difficult to see <vi>He has learned to <it>bury</it> his feelings.</vi> <vi>She <it>buried</it> her face in her hands.</vi> <vi>The disclaimer was <it>buried</it> in the fine print.</vi> <vi>The newspaper covered the story, but it was <it>buried</it> in the back of section C.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to cover (someone or something) with something <vi>A blanket of snow had <it>buried</it> the first few flowers of spring.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) buried</it> <vi>Three skiers were <phrase>buried alive</phrase> in a massive avalanche on Tuesday.</vi></un> <un>usually + <it>under</it> or <it>beneath</it> <vi>The car <it>was buried under</it> the snow.</vi> <vi>My shoes <it>were buried beneath</it> a pile of clothes.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to push (something) <it>in</it> or <it>into</it> something <vi>He <it>buried</it> his face/head <it>in</it> the pillow.</vi> <vi>The splinter <it>buried</it> itself <it>in</it> my thumb.</vi> <snote>When you <phrase>bury yourself in something</phrase>, you give it all of your attention and ignore everything else. <vi>He <it>buried himself in</it> his studies.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to stop being angry or upset about (something) <vi>We've decided to <it>bury</it> our differences and start working together.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make (a shot) in a very impressive way <vi>He <it>buried</it> the jumper. [=he made the jump shot]</vi> <vi>She <it>buried</it> [=<it>holed</it>] the putt.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to defeat (a competitor) easily or completely <vi>They <it>buried</it> the other team (by a score of) 15–2.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bury the hatchet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hatchet</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>dead and buried</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dead</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="hatchet"> <hw>hatch*et</hw> <sound><wav>hatche03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhætʃət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>hatch*ets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small ax that has a short handle</dt></def> <dro><dre>bury the hatchet</dre> <def><dt>:to agree to stop arguing or fighting :to end a disagreement and become friendly <vi>After all these years, they've finally <it>buried the hatchet</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
