<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="business"> <hw highlight="yes">busi*ness</hw> <sound><wav>busine07.wav</wav><wav>busine01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪznəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>busi*ness*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the activity of making, buying, or selling goods or providing services in exchange for money <vi>The store will be open for <it>business</it> next week. [=the store will be ready for customers next week]</vi> <vi>The store has lost a significant amount of <it>business</it> since the factory closed.</vi> <vi>Allowing customers to leave your store unsatisfied is bad (for) <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>The new Web site has been good for (attracting) <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>What line of <it>business</it> [=<it>work</it>] are you in?</vi> <vi>She works in the publishing <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>the fashion/music/restaurant <it>business</it></vi> <vi>We <phrase>do business with</phrase> [=sell to or buy from] companies overseas.</vi> <vi>David has decided to <phrase>go into business</phrase> with his brother.</vi> <vi>Remember that your customers can <phrase>take their business elsewhere</phrase>. [=your customers can go to another place to do business]</vi> <vi>Their publishing company is <phrase>the best in the business</phrase>.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>place of business</phrase> [=a place, such as a store, bank, etc., where business is done]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>business</it> opportunities/contacts/interests</vi> <vi>The <it>business</it> world is responding to changes in technology. [=businesses are responding to changes in technology]</vi> <vi>Someone will be available to answer your call during regular <phrase>business hours</phrase>. [=the hours that the office is open to do business]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>business meeting</phrase> [=a meeting at which matters of business are discussed]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>agribusiness</dxt> <dxt>big business</dxt> <dxt>in business <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>out of business <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>show business</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:work that is part of a job <vi>Is your trip to Miami (for) <it>business</it> or pleasure?</vi> <vi>I have to go to New York City on/for <it>business</it> next week.</vi> <un>sometimes used before another noun <vi>a <phrase>business trip</phrase> [=a trip that is made in order to do business]</vi> <vi>I am flying <phrase>business class</phrase> [=in a seating section of an airplane that is more expensive than the main section but less expensive than first class] from Tokyo to New York.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the amount of activity that is done by a store, company, factory, etc. <vi><it>Business</it> has been slow/bad lately. [=there have been few customers, sales, etc., lately]</vi> <vi><it>Business</it> was good/booming.</vi> <vi>They advertised to increase <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>How is <it>business</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an organization (such as a store, company, or factory) that makes, buys, or sells goods or provides services in exchange for money <vi>He has the skills necessary to run/operate/start a <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>The town is trying to attract new <it>businesses</it>.</vi> <vi>local <it>businesses</it></vi> <vi>She joined the <phrase>family business</phrase> [=the business owned or operated by her family] after graduating from college.</vi> <un>sometimes used before another noun <vi>I had lunch with some <it>business</it> associates.</vi> <vi>In addition to being married, the two are also <it>business</it> partners.</vi> <vi>The restaurant is in the <phrase>business district</phrase>. [=the part of a city or town where there are many businesses]</vi> <vi>the <phrase>business community</phrase> [=people involved in the upper levels of businesses]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that concerns a particular person, group, etc. :something that needs to be considered or dealt with <vi>Do we have any other <it>business</it> we need to discuss?</vi> <vi>Air quality is a serious <it>business</it>. [=air quality is something people should think about seriously]</vi> <vi>What's this <it>business</it> [=<it>news</it>] I hear about you moving away?</vi> <vi>Educating students is the <it>business</it> [=<it>responsibility</it>] of schools.</vi> <vi>No, I didn't ask him what he wanted the car for. That's his <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>I won't answer that question. Who I choose to vote for is my <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>He's decided to <phrase>make it his business</phrase> [=make it his goal] to bring more affordable housing to the city.</vi> <vi>“Who did you vote for?” “That's <phrase>none of your business</phrase>.” [=that's private information that you should not be asking about]</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>no business of yours</phrase> who I voted for.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>mind your own business</phrase> is used as an informal and often somewhat impolite way to tell someone to stop watching or asking about something that is private. <vi><it>Mind your own business</it> and let them talk alone.</vi></snote> <snote>To say that you were <phrase>minding your own business</phrase> when something happened means that you were doing what you normally do and were not bothering anyone. <vi>I was walking down the street, <it>minding my own business</it>, when all of a sudden some man started yelling at me.</vi></snote> <snote>If you say something is <phrase>nobody's business</phrase>, you mean that it is private and other people do not need to know about it. <vi>It's <it>nobody's business</it> what we were talking about.</vi></snote> <snote>Someone who <phrase>has no business doing something</phrase> has no right to do it. <vi>You <it>have no business telling me</it> what I can and cannot wear! I'll wear whatever I like!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:something that must be done <vi>I have some <it>business</it> in town Friday afternoon. [=I have to do something in town Friday afternoon]</vi> <vi>He had to leave the meeting early because he had to attend to some <phrase>unfinished business</phrase>. [=something not done that needs to be done]</vi> <vi>Now that we've all introduced ourselves, let's <phrase>get down to business</phrase>. [=start doing what needs to be done, start working]</vi> <vi>I was just <phrase>going about my business</phrase> [=doing what I usually do], when I heard a big crash.</vi> <vi>Sarah is good at <phrase>taking care of business</phrase> [=doing what needs to be done], so she's been put in charge of organizing the event.</vi> <vi>The church has hired someone to take care of the bills and <phrase>all that business</phrase>. [=everything else that needs to be done]</vi> <vi>A public library is <phrase>in the business of</phrase> providing information to the public. [=the job/purpose of a public library is to provide information]</vi> <vi>I'm not <it>in the business of</it> lending money to people I hardly know. [=I don't lend money to people I hardly know]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a matter, event, or situation <un>usually used after an adjective <vi>Divorce can be such a messy <it>business</it>. [=<it>affair</it>]</vi> <vi>The earthquake was a terrible <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>Predicting how people will react to something is a tricky <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>Investing all your money in one stock is (a) very risky <it>business</it>.</vi> <vi>“How long did the ceremony take?” “Oh, the whole <it>business</it> was over in less than an hour.”</vi> <vi>Let's just forget about that <it>business</it> of me being unhappy with my job.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>monkey business</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>business as usual</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is working or continuing in the normal or usual way <vi>Much of the town lost electricity in the storm, but for people with generators it was <it>business as usual</it>.</vi> <vi>As the election nears, both political parties continue to blame each other for all the city's problems. In other words, it's <it>business as usual</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>business is business</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that in order for a business to be successful it is necessary to do things that may hurt or upset people <vi>I'm sorry I have to let you go, but understand that <it>business is business</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in business</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:operating as a business <vi>The hotel has been <it>in business</it> for over 150 years.</vi> <vi>Customer satisfaction is important if you want to stay <it>in business</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:ready to begin doing or using something <vi>Just plug in the computer and you're <it>in business</it>! [=you will be able to use the computer]</vi> <vi>All the musicians have finally arrived, so we're <it>in business</it>!</vi> <vi>He quickly changed the tire, and was <phrase>back in business</phrase> [=ready to drive again] in 10 minutes.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>like nobody's business</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very well or quickly or in very large amounts <vi>She can design computer programs <it>like nobody's business</it>.</vi> <vi>It's been raining <it>like nobody's business</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>mean business</dre> <def><dt>:to be serious about doing something <vi>We thought he was joking at first, but then we saw that he really <it>meant business</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of business</dre> <def><dt>:closed down :no longer in business <vi>My favorite flower shop is <it>out of business</it>.</vi> <vi>Small grocery stores are being driven/forced/put <it>out of business</it> by large stores. [=small grocery stores cannot compete with large stores and so are closing permanently]</vi> <vi>The store has <phrase>gone out of business</phrase>. [=has closed]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the business</dre> <def><sl>Brit slang</sl> <dt>:a very good or impressive person or thing <vi>Since he's won the tournament, he thinks he's <it>the business</it>. [=<it>the best</it>]</vi> <vi>You should see their new flat. It's <it>the business</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="business administration"> <hw>business administration</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a program of studies in a college or university that teaches students how to run a business <vi>a degree in <it>business administration</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="business card"> <hw>business card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small card printed with a person's name and information about that person's company and job <snote>People give business cards to anyone who they think might want to contact them about their business.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="business end"> <hw>business end</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the business end</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:the part of a tool, weapon, or instrument that is used most directly for the object's purpose <vi>the <it>business end</it> of a rifle [=the end where the bullets come out]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="business suit"> <hw>business suit</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ suits</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a type of suit that is worn by some people who work in offices and that includes a matching coat and pants or skirt</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="big business"> <hw>big business</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:large companies considered together as a powerful group <vi>The tax proposal will be of most benefit to <it>big business</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an activity or product that makes a large amount of money <vi>Tourism is <it>big business</it> in the region.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="monkey business"> <hw>monkey business</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:playful tricks or jokes <vi>Our teacher warned us not to try any <it>monkey business</it> while she was out of the room.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:illegal or improper activity or behavior <vi>political <it>monkey business</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="order of business"> <hw>order of business</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a job that must be done or an issue that must be discussed <vi>The first <it>order of business</it> at the committee meeting was the budget.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="show business"> <hw>show business</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the entertainment industry involved in making movies, television shows, plays, etc. <vi>She has been in <it>show business</it> for over 30 years.</vi> <vi>actors trying to break into <it>show business</it></vi> <vi><it>show business</it> executives</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="mean[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">mean</hw> <sound><wav>mean0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmi:n</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>means</if></in> <in><if>meant</if> <sound><wav>mean0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>mean*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (a particular meaning) <vi>What does this word <it>mean</it> in English? = What is <it>meant</it> in English by this word?</vi> <vi>The word <it>meant</it> one thing in Shakespeare's day, but it <it>means</it> something else now.</vi> <vi>The abbreviation “U.S.” <it>means</it> [=<it>stands for</it>] “United States.”</vi> <vi>Red <it>means</it> “stop” and green <it>means</it> “go.”</vi> <vi>Can you tell me what my dream <it>means</it>?</vi> <vi>“Bonjour” is a French word <it>meaning</it> “hello.” = “Bonjour” is a French word that <it>means</it> “hello.”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to want or intend to express (a particular idea or meaning) <vi>I <it>meant</it> what I said. [=I was sincere when I said it]</vi> <vi>What was <it>meant</it> by the poet?</vi> <vi>Don't distort what she <it>meant</it> by taking her words out of context.</vi> <vi>When she says the play was “interesting,” she <it>means</it> (that) it wasn't very good.</vi> <vi>He's very ambitious, and I <it>mean</it> that as a compliment.</vi> <vi>It's a very easy question. Anyone, and I <it>mean</it> anyone, should be able to answer it.</vi> <vi>You hold it like this. (<phrase>Do you</phrase>) <phrase>See what I mean</phrase>? [=do you understand what I'm showing you?]</vi> <vi>She's not getting any thinner, <phrase>if you know/get what I mean</phrase>.</vi> <vi>“He can be a little difficult. (<phrase>Do you</phrase>) <phrase>Know what I mean</phrase>?”</vi> <vi>“He can be a little difficult.” “<phrase>What/How do you mean</phrase>?” = “<phrase>Meaning?</phrase>” [=what exactly do you mean when you say that?]</vi> <vi>“He can be a little difficult.” “<phrase>I know what you mean</phrase>.” [=I agree]</vi> <vi>“He can be a little difficult.” “<phrase>What's that supposed to mean</phrase>?” [=I am surprised that you would say that; I don't agree with what you are saying]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) in your mind as a purpose or goal <vi>Just what do you <it>mean</it> (by) coming into my room without knocking? [=what is your reason for coming into my room without knocking?]</vi> <vi>She says she didn't <it>mean</it> anything by what she did.</vi> <vi>She didn't <it>mean</it> (you) any harm. = She <it>meant</it> no harm (to you). [=she did not intend to cause any harm (to you)]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry if I hurt your feelings. I <it>meant</it> (you) no offense/disrespect.</vi> <vi>I don't trust him. He <it>means</it> no good.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>He didn't <it>mean</it> [=<it>intend</it>] <it>to do</it> any harm.</vi> <vi>She <it>means to win</it>.</vi> <vi>I keep <it>meaning to visit</it> you—I just never seem to get around to it.</vi> <vi>He says he never <it>meant to hurt</it> her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to plan for or want (someone or something) to do or to be something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>His comment was <it>meant</it> [=<it>intended</it>] <it>as</it> a joke.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>We <it>meant</it> her <it>to come</it> with us.</vi> <vi>She <it>meant</it> her remarks <it>to be</it> funny.</vi> <vi>“What you said hurt his feelings!” “Well, I <it>meant</it> it <it>to</it>!”</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> (<it>chiefly US</it>) <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>We <it>meant for</it> her to come with us.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to want (something that you control, provide, or have made) to be used for a particular purpose or by a particular person <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>I <it>meant</it> [=<it>intended</it>] the flowers <it>for</it> you, not for your sister.</vi> <vi>The book was <it>meant for</it> children, but it is popular with adults too.</vi> <vi>His criticism is <it>meant for</it> all of us.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>They <it>meant</it> the book <it>to be</it> a present.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>as</it> <vi>They <it>meant</it> the book <it>as</it> a present.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a statement to or about (someone) <vi>“Hey, you!” “I'm sorry: do you <it>mean</it> me?” [=are you talking to me?]</vi> <vi>“Some people here are too bossy!” “Do you <it>mean</it> me?” [=are you referring to me?]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to indicate or show (something that is going to happen) <vi>Those clouds <it>mean</it> rain. = Those clouds <it>mean</it> (that) it's going to rain.</vi> <vi>When he gets that angry look in his eyes, you know it <it>means</it> trouble. [=you know that there will be trouble]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause or result in (something) <vi>The bad weather could <it>mean</it> further delays.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to involve or require (something) as a necessary part <vi>Becoming a concert pianist <it>means</it> practicing a lot. [=if you're going to become a concert pianist you have to practice a lot]</vi> <vi>I'll get the work done today even if it <it>means</it> staying late.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to say or ask how important something is to someone</un> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>How much does your health <it>mean to</it> you? [=how important is your health to you?]</vi> <vi>It <it>means</it> a lot <it>to</it> me to know that you believe me.</vi> <vi>“I believe you.” “Thank you. You don't know how much that <it>means to</it> me.”</vi> <vi>Your good opinion <it>means</it> a great deal <it>to</it> me.</vi> <vi>He claims that money <phrase>means nothing to</phrase> him. [=that he does not care at all about money]</vi> <vi>Her words <it>meant nothing to</it> me. [=I did not care what she said]</vi> <vi>I thought our friendship <phrase>meant something to</phrase> you. [=I thought that you cared about our friendship]</vi> <vi>His wife <phrase>means everything to</phrase> him. = His wife <phrase>means the world to</phrase> him. [=he loves his wife very much]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>I mean</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to emphasize a statement <vi>He has to stop drinking. <it>I mean</it>, he's going to kill himself if he keeps it up.</vi> <vi>He throws, <it>I mean</it>, really hard!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to correct a previous statement <vi>We met in Toronto—<it>I mean</it> Montreal.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used when you are unsure of what to say or how to say it <vi>I'm not mad. It's just that, <it>I mean</it>, I think you've been acting a little selfishly.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>know what it means</dre> <def><dt>:to understand what it is like to do or be something <vi>I <it>know what it means</it> to be poor.</vi> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>You don't <it>know what it means</it> to be truly alone.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in an exaggerated way to make a forceful statement <vi>I don't <it>know what it means</it> to surrender! [=I will never surrender]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>mean business</dre> <dx>see <dxt>business</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>meant for (someone)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:perfectly suited for (someone) <vi>You were <it>meant for</it> me and I was <it>meant for</it> you.</vi> <vi>I'm not surprised that they have such a happy marriage. I always knew that they were <phrase>meant for each other</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mean <dxn>4b (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>meant to be/do something</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:intended to do or be something <vi>I was never <it>meant to</it> teach.</vi> <vi>They knew as soon as they met that they were <it>meant to</it> be together.</vi> <vi>I thought we could be friends, but I guess it just wasn't <phrase>meant to be</phrase>. [=it was not destined to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:supposed to be or do something <vi>The buses are <it>meant</it> [=<it>expected</it>] <it>to</it> arrive every 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>Brighton is <it>meant to</it> be very beautiful at this time of year. [=people say that Brighton is very beautiful at this time of year]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>mean well</dre> <def><dt>:to want to do good or helpful things :to have good intentions <vi>He <it>means well</it>, but he's not really helping anyone.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>well-meaning</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
