<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="busy[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">busy</hw> <sound><wav>busy0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪzi</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bus*i*er</if></in> <in><if>bus*i*est</if></in> <def><gram>also more busy; most busy</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:actively doing something <vi>She's <it>busy</it> preparing for her test.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>busy</it>? Can I talk to you for a minute?</vi> <vi>I will be <it>busy</it> cleaning the house.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I haven't called. I've been so <it>busy</it>.</vi> <vi><it>busy</it> people who don't have time to cook</vi> <vi>I got enough work to keep me <it>busy</it> for a while.</vi> <vi>He is a very <it>busy</it> person.</vi> <vi>He's been <it>busy</it> in the kitchen all afternoon.</vi> <vi>She's <phrase>as busy as a bee</phrase>. [=she's very busy]</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The actress is <it>busy with</it> a new film. [=is working on a new film]</vi> <vi>He keeps himself <it>busy with</it> volunteer work.</vi> <vi>She is <it>busy with</it> wedding plans.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:full of activity or work <vi>My week has been so <it>busy</it>!</vi> <vi>They live/lead <it>busy</it> lives.</vi> <vi>Is there any time in your <it>busy</it> schedule for us to have lunch next week?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:full of people or things <vi>a <it>busy</it> street</vi> <vi>a <it>busy</it> store</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>of a telephone or telephone line</ssl> <dt>:being used <vi>I tried calling her, but her line/phone is <it>busy</it>. [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>engaged</it>]</vi> <snote>When you dial a telephone line that is already in use, you hear a sound that is called a <phrase>busy signal</phrase>.</snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:full of many details <vi>I like the fabric, but I think the pattern is too <it>busy</it> for this dress.</vi> <vi><it>busy</it> wallpaper</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get busy</dre> <def><dt>:to start doing work <vi>We need to finish by 5 o'clock, so we'd better <it>get busy</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>busi*ly</ure> <sound><wav>busy0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪzəli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>She is <it>busily</it> preparing for her test.</vi> <vi>He is working <it>busily</it> in the kitchen.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>busy*ness</ure> <sound><wav>busy0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪzinəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>I don't like the <it>busyness</it> of stores around the holidays.</vi> <vi>the <it>busyness</it> of the pattern</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="busy[2]"> <hw hindex="2">busy</hw> <altpr>ˈbɪzi</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>bus*ies</if></in> <in><if>bus*ied</if></in> <in><if>busy*ing</if></in> <dro><dre>busy yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to make or keep yourself busy :to occupy (yourself) with work or an activity <vi>The children <it>busied themselves</it> with puzzles all day.</vi> <vi>He <it>busied himself</it> in the workshop building things.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="bee[1]"> <hw hindex="1">bee</hw> <sound><wav>bee00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbi:</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bees</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a black and yellow flying insect that can sting and that is often kept in hives for the honey that it produces <vi>flowers pollinated by <it>bees</it> and other insects</vi> <vi>a swarm of buzzing/humming <it>bees</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>My mom is a real <phrase>busy bee</phrase> around Christmastime. [=she is very busy and active]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>bumblebee</dxt> <dxt>honeybee</dxt> <dxt>killer bee</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) busy as a bee</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very busy and active <vi>My mom is (<it>as</it>) <it>busy as a bee</it> around Christmastime.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a bee in your bonnet</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to talk and think a lot about something <vi>He always <it>has a bee in his bonnet</it> about safety.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the birds and the bees</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bird</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>bee</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="signal[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">sig*nal</hw> <sound><wav>signal01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɪgnl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>sig*nals</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an event or act which shows that something exists or that gives information about something :<sx>sign</sx> <vi>The change in his behavior is clearly a <it>signal</it> [=<it>indication</it>] that there is a problem.</vi> <vi>He likes her but he is sending the wrong <it>signals</it> with his constant teasing.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>Inflammation is a <it>signal of</it> infection.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something (such as a sound, a movement of part of the body, or an object) that gives information about something or that tells someone to do something <vi>Don't start until I give the <it>signal</it>. [=<it>sign</it>]</vi> <vi>The teacher gave us the <it>signal</it> to finish what we were working on and hand in our tests.</vi> <vi>The pilot sent out a <phrase>distress signal</phrase> [=a message that the airplane was in danger] before the plane crashed.</vi> <vi>They communicated with each other by using <phrase>hand signals</phrase>. [=movements of a person's hands that mean something]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a piece of equipment with colored lights that is used on railways and roads to tell people when to go, to slow down, or to stop <vi>Faulty wiring in the train station caused a <it>signal</it> to malfunction.</vi> <vi>The <phrase>traffic signal</phrase> [=<it>traffic light</it>] was not working.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a message, sound, or image that is carried by waves of light or sound <vi>The video/TV <it>signal</it> is scrambled.</vi> <vi>Satellite dishes receive television <it>signals</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>digital</it> signal</vi> <vi>The transmitter beams radio <it>signals</it> into space.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a wave of light or sound that carries a message, sound, or image <vi>We'll need better equipment to generate a 50 Hz <it>signal</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>busy signal</dre> <dx>see <dxt>busy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>mixed signals</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mixed</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
