<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cap[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cap</hw> <sound><wav>cap00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a small, soft hat that often has a hard curved part (called a visor) that extends out over your eyes <vi>a Harvard University <it>cap</it> [=a cap that has the name or symbol of Harvard University on it]</vi> <vi>a knit/knitted <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>his wool/tweed <it>cap</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>baseball cap</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a covering for a person's head that is worn for a special purpose <vi>a <phrase>shower/bathing cap</phrase> [=a head covering that people wear to keep their hair dry when they are showering/swimming]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>thinking cap</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a hat that people with particular jobs wear while working <vi>a painter's <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>a surgeon's <it>cap</it>, gown, and gloves</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a part or object that covers the end or top of something <vi>a bottle <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>a lens <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>a pill bottle with a childproof <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>Put the <it>cap</it> back on the marker when you are done using it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a part that forms the top of something <vi>a bird with a black <it>cap</it> [=a black section of feathers on the top of its head]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>mushroom cap</phrase> [=the top part of a mushroom]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a limit on the amount of money that can be spent, given, charged, etc., for something <vi>a spending <it>cap</it></vi> <vi>a <it>cap</it> on political donations</vi> <vi>a <it>cap</it> on doctor's fees</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a paper or metal container that holds an explosive substance <vi>a blasting <it>cap</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a capital letter <un>usually plural <vi>e-mails written in all <it>caps</it></vi> <vi>She signed the letter with her name in <it>caps</it>: KIM.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a hard substance that is shaped to look like a healthy tooth and used to cover a damaged tooth</dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an opportunity to play for your school or country <vi>He won his first <it>cap</it> against Columbia when he was 22.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a player chosen to play for a country's team</dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>diaphragm <sxn>3</sxn></sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>a feather in your cap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>feather</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cap in hand</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if the cap fits</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>if the cap fits, wear it</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something said about a person is true and the person should accept it as true <vi>They may not like being called careless, but <it>if the cap fits, wear it</it>. [=(<it>US</it>) <it>if the shoe fits, wear it</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>tip your cap</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tip</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cap[2]"> <hw hindex="2">cap</hw> <altpr>ˈkæp</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>caps</if></in> <in><if>capped</if></in> <in><if>cap*ping</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cover the top or end of (something) <vi>a pipe <it>capped</it> at one end</vi> <vi>a mountain <it>capped</it> with snow = a snow-<it>capped</it> mountain</vi> :to put a cap on (something) <vi>Be sure to <it>cap</it> the pen/marker when you are done using it.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to end (something) in usually an exciting or impressive way <vi>The report <it>caps</it> a ten-year study of lung cancer among nonsmokers.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> in U.S. English <vi>The band <it>capped off</it> the show with an extended version of their classic hit.</vi> <vi>The victory <it>caps off</it> the career of a coach who's brought her team to the championships five times.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to follow (something) with something that is better, worse, etc. <vi>a concert <it>capped</it> by a fantastic fireworks display</vi> <vi>The car was filthy when he returned it to me, and <phrase>to cap it off</phrase> [=<it>to top it off</it>], there was almost no fuel left in the tank.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to prevent (something) from increasing :to put an upper limit on (something) <vi>If the teams don't <it>cap</it> player salaries, the league won't survive.</vi> <vi><it>capping</it> interest rates</vi> <vi>The law would <it>cap</it> legal immigration.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to put a limit on the amount of money that can be spent by (a group) <vi>The government wants to <it>cap</it> councils that spend too much.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to cover (a tooth) with a hard material that is shaped to look like a healthy tooth :to put a cap on (a tooth) <vi>He had two of his teeth <it>capped</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to choose (someone) to play for a national team <un>usually used as <it>(be) capped</it> <vi>He <it>was</it> first <it>capped</it> for Ireland at age 22.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="baseball cap"> <hw>baseball cap</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a rounded cap that fits close to the head and that has a long visor <snote>Baseball caps were originally worn only by baseball players as part of their uniform but are now worn by many people.</snote> <dx>see picture at <dxt>hat</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ice cap"> <hw>ice cap</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a very large and thick sheet of ice that covers the North Pole, the South Pole, or another region <vi>the polar <it>ice cap</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="stocking cap"> <hw>stocking cap</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a knitted close-fitting cap that sometimes has a decorative part (called a tassel or pom-pom) at the top</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="swimming cap"> <hw>swimming cap</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:a tight rubber cap that you wear while you swim to keep your hair dry</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="thinking cap"> <hw>thinking cap</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ caps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to refer to the act of trying to solve a problem by thinking carefully about it <vi>The students weren't wearing their <it>thinking caps</it> this morning. [=they weren't thinking very well]</vi> <vi>It's time to <phrase>put your thinking cap on</phrase>. [=it's time to start trying to think of what should be done]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="doff"> <hw>doff</hw> <sound><wav>doff0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɑ:f</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>doffs</if></in> <in><if>doffed</if></in> <in><if>doff*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to take off or remove (a hat or a piece of clothing) <vi>He <it>doffed</it> his cap as he introduced himself.</vi> <vi>They <it>doffed</it> their coats when they came inside.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="feather[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">feath*er</hw> <sound><wav>feathe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɛðɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>feath*ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:any one of the light growths that make up the outer covering of the body of a bird <vi>duck <it>feathers</it></vi> <vi>tail/wing <it>feathers</it></vi> <vi>downy <it>feathers</it></vi> <vi>a tuft of <it>feathers</it></vi> <vi>a <it>feather</it> pillow = a pillow filled with <it>feathers</it></vi> <vi>Her suitcase felt <phrase>as light as a feather</phrase>. [=extremely light]</vi> <vi>When I found out I had won, <phrase>you could have knocked me over with a feather</phrase>. [=I was extremely surprised or astonished]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a feather in your cap</dre> <def><dt>:an achievement or honor that you can be proud of <vi>The promotion was <it>a feather in his cap</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of a feather</dre> <def><dt>:of the same kind or nature <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>birds of a feather</phrase> <vi>Those two guys are <it>birds of a feather</it>. [=they are very much alike]</vi></un> <snote>The expression <phrase>birds of a feather flock together</phrase> means that people who are alike tend to do things together.</snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ruffle feathers</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ruffle</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>feath*ered</ure> <sound><wav>feathe02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɛðɚd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>She likes to refer to birds as “our <it>feathered</it> friends.”</vi> <vi>a <it>feathered</it> hat</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>feath*er*less</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a bird with <it>featherless</it> legs</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="fit[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">fit</hw> <altpr>ˈfɪt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>fits</if></in> <in><if>fit*ted</if> <il>or chiefly US</il> <if>fit</if></in> <in><if>fit*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be the right size and shape for (someone or something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The suit <it>fits</it> him perfectly.</vi> <vi>I hope this key <it>fits</it> the lock.</vi> <vi>The two pieces <it>fit</it> each other perfectly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>These shoes <it>fit</it> perfectly.</vi> <vi>This calculator will <it>fit</it> nicely/neatly in your shirt pocket.</vi> <vi>pants that <it>fit</it> tightly/loosely = tight-<it>fitting</it>/loose-<it>fitting</it> pants</vi> <vi>The two pieces <it>fit</it> together perfectly.</vi> <snote>Something that <phrase>fits (you) like a glove</phrase> fits (you) very well. <vi>That suit <it>fits him like a glove</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>The phrase <phrase>one size fits all</phrase> describes a hat, piece of clothing, etc., that is made in a size that is supposed to fit everyone. This phrase is commonly used figuratively. <vi>The school recognizes that a <it>one size fits all</it> approach won't work for these children. [=these children need to be taught in a way that considers the needs and abilities of each child]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go into or through a particular space <vi>All these groceries won't <it>fit</it> in the trunk of my car. = These groceries won't all <it>fit</it> in the trunk of my car.</vi> <vi>How many people can <it>fit</it> in a phone booth?</vi> <vi>The box was too large to <it>fit</it> through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to go into or through a particular space <vi>I can't <it>fit</it> all these groceries into the trunk of my car.</vi> <vi>We weren't able to <it>fit</it> the box through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sin><il>past tense and past participle</il> <if>fitted</if></sin> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to measure (someone) in order to choose clothes that are the right size and shape for that person <un>usually used as <it>(be) fitted</it> <vi>I'm <it>being fitted</it> [=<it>measured</it>] for a new suit tomorrow.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change the shape or form of (a piece of clothing) for a particular person <vi><it>fitting</it> the jacket to the customer</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find time to meet with (someone) or do (something) <un>usually + <it>in</it> or <it>into</it> <vi>I'll try to <it>fit</it> you <it>into</it> my schedule.</vi> <vi>The doctor can <it>fit</it> you <it>in</it> this afternoon. [=the doctor can meet with you this afternoon]</vi> <vi>She's got a lot of meetings to <it>fit in</it> this morning.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to belong in a particular situation, place, or group <vi>It's a good school, but I feel like I just don't <it>fit</it> here.</vi> <un>usually + <it>in</it> <vi>I was looking for a group that I could <it>fit in</it> with.</vi> <vi>No matter how hard she tried, she just didn't <it>fit in</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>fit</it> right <it>in</it> at school.</vi> <vi>That chair <it>fits in</it> well with the rest of the office.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be suitable or appropriate for (someone or something) <vi>The nickname <it>fits</it> [=<it>suits</it>] him very well.</vi> <vi>The punishment should <it>fit</it> the crime.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (someone or something) suitable or appropriate <it>for</it> or <it>to</it> something <vi>Her previous experience <it>fitted</it> [=<it>qualified</it>] her <it>for</it> the job.</vi> <vi>Let us <it>fit</it> the punishment <it>to</it> the crime.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in agreement with (something or someone) <vi>Their story doesn't <it>fit</it> the facts.</vi> <vi>He <it>fits</it> [=<it>matches</it>] the description perfectly. = The description <it>fits</it> him perfectly.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sin><il>past tense and past participle</il> <if>fitted</if></sin> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to supply equipment for (something) <vi>a lab <it>fitted</it> with the latest equipment</vi> <vi>The camera can be <it>fitted</it> with many different lenses.</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> or <it>up</it> <vi><it>fit out</it> an expedition</vi> <vi>an old ocean liner <it>fitted up</it> as a hospital ship</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>fit the bill</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bill</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if the cap fits</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cap</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>if the shoe fits</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shoe</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>fit*ter</ure> <pr>ˈfɪɾɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>fit*ters</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>a shoe/boot <it>fitter</it> [=a person whose job is to help you find a shoe/boot that fits]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pipe fitter</dxt></dx></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
