<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="capture[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cap*ture</hw> <sound><wav>captur01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæptʃɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cap*tures</if></in> <in><if>cap*tured</if></in> <in><if>cap*tur*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to take and hold (someone) as a prisoner especially by using force <vi>They were <it>captured</it> by enemy soldiers.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to catch (an animal) <vi>using traps to <it>capture</it> mice</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to get control of (a place) especially by using force <vi>The city was <it>captured</it> by the Romans.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to win or get (something) through effort <vi>She <it>captured</it> 60 percent of the vote in the last election.</vi> <vi>The company plans on <it>capturing</it> a larger segment of the market.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to get and hold (someone's attention, interest, etc.) <vi>The show has <it>captured</it> the attention/interest of teenagers.</vi> <vi>The story <phrase>captured our imaginations</phrase>. [=the story was very interesting and exciting]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to describe or show (someone or something) in a very accurate way by using writing, painting, film, etc. <vi>The story <it>captures</it> the essence of the holiday.</vi> <vi>The biography <it>captured</it> her perfectly.</vi> <vi>The beauty of the landscape was <it>captured</it> perfectly by the artist.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to record (something) in a picture, film, etc. <vi>The robbery was <it>captured</it> (on film) by the security cameras.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get and put (information) into a form that can be read or used by a computer <vi>The system is used to <it>capture</it> data relating to the buying habits of young people.</vi> <vi>a digital camera that <it>captures</it> 1.2 million pixels</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to take (something, such as a chess piece) by following the rules of a game <vi>In the game of chess, the goal is to <it>capture</it> your opponent's king.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="capture[2]"> <hw hindex="2">capture</hw> <altpr>ˈkæptʃɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the act of capturing someone or something: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act of taking and holding someone as a prisoner or of being taken as a prisoner <vi>They avoided/eluded/escaped <it>capture</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the act of getting control of something <vi>the <it>capture</it> of the city by enemy forces</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the act of putting information in a form that a computer can use or read <vi>data/image <it>capture</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bottle[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">bot*tle</hw> <sound><wav>bottle01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>bot*tles</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a glass or plastic container that has a narrow neck and usually has no handle <snote>Bottles are usually used to store liquid or tablets. <vi>Shall I open another <it>bottle</it> of wine?</vi> <vi>There's a <it>bottle</it> of aspirin in the cabinet.</vi> <vi>empty soda <it>bottles</it></vi> <vi>She kept a <it>bottle</it> [=a bottle of some strong alcoholic drink like whiskey] tucked away in the coat closet.</vi> <vi>Be sure to bring a <phrase>water bottle</phrase> [=bottle containing water] on your hike.</vi> <vi>Would you get me the <phrase>bottle opener</phrase> [=a tool used to remove metal tops from some bottles], please?</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount contained in a bottle <vi>We drank a <it>bottle</it> of wine.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the bottle</bnote> <dt>:alcoholic drink <vi>He says he's lost too many years to <it>the bottle</it>, and that he's giving up alcohol.</vi> <vi>Her struggles with <it>the bottle</it> affected her entire family.</vi> <vi>I hear he's <phrase>(gone) off the bottle</phrase>. [=stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>After his divorce he <phrase>took to the bottle</phrase>. [=began to drink a lot of alcohol]</vi> <vi>When she gets depressed she <phrase>hits the bottle</phrase>. [=begins drinking a lot of alcohol]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a special bottle for feeding babies that contains milk or a drink which contains milk <vi>Has the baby finished her <it>bottle</it> yet?</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) a baby <it>bottle</it> = (<it>Brit</it>) a baby's <it>bottle</it></vi> <vi>raised on a <it>bottle</it> instead of breast milk</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>bottle-feed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit slang</ssl> <dt>:courage or strength of spirit <vi>I don't think he's got <it>bottle</it> [=<it>guts</it>] enough to confront them.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>bring your own bottle</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>bring a bottle</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to tell the people who are invited to a party that they should bring their own alcoholic drinks</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch/capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lightning</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>bot*tle*ful</ure> <sound><wav>bottle02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:tl̟ˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>singular</gram> <utxt><vi>a <it>bottleful</it> of water</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="imagination"> <hw highlight="yes">imag*i*na*tion</hw> <sound><wav>imagin09.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ɪˌmæʤəˈneɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>imag*i*na*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the ability to imagine things that are not real :the ability to form a picture in your mind of something that you have not seen or experienced <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>You can find a solution if you use a little <it>imagination</it>.</vi> <vi>His plans to build a new stadium are the product of pure <it>imagination</it>. [=they are not based on reality; they are not likely to happen]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>children with vivid/fertile/overactive <it>imaginations</it></vi> <vi>The author does not tell us what happens to the characters. We have to use our <it>imagination</it>.</vi> <vi>He insists that these dangers are real and not just <phrase>a figment of his imagination</phrase>. [=something that he has imagined]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to think of new things <vi>Her painting shows a great deal of <it>imagination</it>. [=<it>creativity</it>]</vi> <vi>He's a competent writer, but he lacks <it>imagination</it>.</vi> <vi>He has no <it>imagination</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:something that only exists or happens in your mind <vi>Is it just my <it>imagination</it>, or is it getting warm in here?</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by any/no stretch of the imagination</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stretch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>capture/catch someone's imagination</dre> <def><dt>:to make someone very interested or excited <vi>Her books have <it>captured the imaginations</it> of children from around the world.</vi> <vi>The story <it>caught the public imagination</it>. [=the public became very interested in the story]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave (something) to the imagination</dre> <def><dt>:to not show or describe all of the parts or details of (something) <vi>Try to <it>leave something to the imagination</it>.</vi> <vi>The movie's sex scenes <it>leave nothing to the imagination</it>. [=they show everything]</vi> <vi>His explicit description of the crime scene <it>left little to the imagination</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="lightning[1]"> <hw hindex="1">light*ning</hw> <sound><wav>lightn02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪtnɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the flashes of light that are produced in the sky during a storm <vi>a bolt of <it>lightning</it> = a <it>lightning</it> bolt</vi> <vi>a flash of <it>lightning</it></vi> <vi>The tree was hit/struck by <it>lightning</it>. = The tree was hit by a <phrase>lightning strike</phrase>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>thunder</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>heat lightning</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>catch/capture lightning in a bottle</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:to succeed in a way that is very lucky or unlikely <vi>He <it>caught lightning in a bottle</it> with the success of his very first book.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lightning never strikes (the same place) twice</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a very unusual event is not likely to happen again to the same person or in the same place</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>like (greased) lightning</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very quickly <vi>The news traveled across the country <it>like lightning</it>.</vi> <vi>moving <it>like greased lightning</it></vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
