<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="card[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">card</hw> <sound><wav>card0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑɚd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cards</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small piece of stiff paper that is marked with symbols or pictures to show its value, comes in a set, and is used for playing games (such as poker) <vi>Each player is dealt five <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi>Shuffle the <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi><it>card</it> tricks</vi> <vi>He bought a deck/pack of <it>cards</it>.</vi> <vi>poker and other <phrase>card games</phrase> [=games that use a deck of cards]</vi> <ca>called also <cat>playing card</cat></ca> <dx>see also <dxt>cardsharp</dxt> <dxt>card table</dxt> <dxt>face card</dxt> <dxt>house of cards</dxt> <dxt>picture card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>cards</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:a game played with a deck of cards :a card game <vi>Do you want to play (a game of) <it>cards</it>?</vi> <vi>We played <it>cards</it> until midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used figuratively to refer to something that gives you an advantage when you are trying to make a deal or reach an agreement <vi>The fact that he was supported by big firms was his strongest/best <it>card</it> during the negotiations.</vi></un></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt><un>used figuratively to refer to an emotional issue (such as race) that is mentioned in a particular situation in order to give you an advantage <vi>She used/played the gender <it>card</it> and said we didn't hire her because she's a woman.</vi> <vi>She was accused of <phrase>playing the race card</phrase> to defend her client. [=she was accused of saying that her client was treated unfairly because of his race]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a thick piece of paper that is usually folded in half and decorated on one side and that contains a greeting, an invitation, etc. <vi>He sent me a <it>card</it> for my birthday. = He sent me a birthday <it>card</it>.</vi> <vi>a get well <it>card</it></vi> <vi>a <it>card</it> shop/store</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>christmas card</dxt> <dxt>greeting card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>postcard</sx> <vi>She sent us a <it>card</it> from Japan.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a rectangular piece of plastic that is used to buy goods or services or to get money from a bank or a machine <vi>“Will you be paying cash?” “No, please put it on my <it>card</it>.” [=I will pay for it using my credit/debit card]</vi> <vi>an ATM <it>card</it></vi> <vi>Insert your <it>card</it> into the machine. = Swipe/Pass your <it>card</it> through the machine.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a rectangular piece of paper or plastic with information about a person written on it <vi>a membership/library/appointment <it>card</it></vi> <vi>Let me give you my <it>card</it>. [=<it>business card</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a small piece of paper that is used for writing down information <vi>He wrote his notes on 3 x 5 <it>cards</it>. [=cards that are 3 inches tall and 5 inches wide]</vi> <vi>You may use <phrase>note cards</phrase> [=cards with notes on them] during your speech.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>trading card</sx> <vi>a collection of baseball/football/basketball <it>cards</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a thin, hard board that has small electronic devices on it and that can be added to the inside of a computer to make the computer perform different tasks <vi>a memory/sound/video <it>card</it></vi> <vi>an <phrase>expansion card</phrase> [=a device that allows a computer to do more things than it originally could]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a list of the individual competitions that will happen at a sports event :a sports program <vi>a racing <it>card</it> [=a list of races]</vi> <vi>a boxing <it>card</it> [=a list of boxing matches]</vi> <vi>Three fights are <phrase>on the card</phrase> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a funny or amusing person <vi>He's such a <it>card</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>cardboard</sx> <vi>a piece of <it>card</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>get your card</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>be given your card</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be told that you no longer have a job <vi>Thousands of factory workers have <it>been given their cards</it> [=have been laid off; have lost their jobs] in recent months.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hold (all/all of) the cards</dre> <def><dt>:to be in control of a situation and have the power to make decisions <vi>It's your decision. You're <it>holding all the cards</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the cards</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>on the cards</va></vr> <def><dt>:certain or likely to happen in the future <vi>No one knows what's <it>in the cards</it> for the economy next year. [=what will happen to the economy next year]</vi> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>It's not <it>in the cards</it> for him to win the election. [=he's not going to win the election]</vi> <vi>Success just wasn't <it>in the cards</it> for her. [=she wasn't meant/supposed to succeed]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/put (all/all of) your cards on the table</dre> <def><dt>:to be honest with other people and to tell them your thoughts, plans, etc., in a very open way <vi>Before we can talk further, you need to <it>put all your cards on the table</it>. [=you need to tell me what you are really thinking]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>overplay your cards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>overplay</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>play/hold/keep your cards close to the/your chest/vest</dre> <def><dt>:to keep your plans, ideas, etc., hidden from other people <vi>No one knows if he's going to run for reelection. He's still <it>playing his cards close to his chest</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play your cards right</dre> <def><dt>:to do things in an intelligent and well-planned way <vi>If I <it>play my cards right</it>, I'll be able to graduate next year.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="card[2]"> <hw hindex="2">card</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑɚd</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cards</if></in> <in><if>card*ed</if></in> <in><if>card*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to ask (someone) to show a form of identification (such as a driver's license) in order to prove that the person is old enough to do something (such as to drink alcohol) <vi>We all got <it>carded</it>. [=someone asked to see our IDs]</vi> <vi>He <it>carded</it> me when I bought cigarettes/beer.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to achieve (a score) in golf <vi>She <it>carded</it> [=<it>scored</it>] a 75.</vi> <vi>He <it>carded</it> a birdie on the second hole.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="card-carrying"> <hw>card–car*ry*ing</hw> <sound><wav>card_c01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑɚdˌkerijɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:known as an active member of a group or organization <vi>a <it>card-carrying</it> liberal/conservative</vi> <vi>a <it>card-carrying</it> union member</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="card catalog"> <hw>card catalog</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -logs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a set of cards in a library that have information about books, journals, etc., written on them and are arranged in alphabetical order <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>card index</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="card index"> <hw>card index</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dexes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:a set of cards that have information written on them and are arranged in alphabetical order</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:<sx>card catalog</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="card table"> <hw>card table</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ tables</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small table that is used for playing card games and that often has legs that fold up</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bank card"> <hw>bank card</hw> <sound><wav>bankca01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbæŋkˌkɑɚd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a card (such as a credit card or debit card) that you get from your bank and that you use to pay for things or to get money from an ATM</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>cheque card</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="banker's card"> <hw>banker's card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>cheque card</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="business card"> <hw>business card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small card printed with a person's name and information about that person's company and job <snote>People give business cards to anyone who they think might want to contact them about their business.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="calling card"> <hw>calling card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a plastic card that allows a person to charge telephone calls to an account <ca>called also <cat>phone card</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a small card presented when making a formal visit to someone that has the name and sometimes the address of the visitor <un>often used figuratively to describe something that identifies a particular person or group <vi>The young actor's bright smile is his <it>calling card</it>.</vi></un> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>visiting card</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
