<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="care[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">care</hw> <sound><wav>care0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cares</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:effort made to do something correctly, safely, or without causing damage <vi>She used <it>care</it> in selecting a doctor for her son.</vi> <vi>a box marked “Handle With <it>Care</it>” [=handle carefully]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:things that are done to keep someone healthy, safe, etc. <vi>The children have inadequate medical <it>care</it> and little formal education.</vi> <vi>We need to provide poor people with better dental <it>care</it>.</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>under a doctor's care</phrase>. [=is being treated by a doctor]</vi> <vi>The boys were <phrase>in the care of</phrase> [=being looked after by] their grandparents.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>day care</dxt> <dxt>health care</dxt> <dxt>intensive care</dxt> <dxt>primary care</dxt> <tag>acute care</tag> at <dxt>acute</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:things that are done to keep something in good condition <vi>She wrote a book about car <it>care</it>.</vi> <vi>With proper <it>care</it>, the machine should last a decade or more.</vi> <vi>She is an expert on skin/hair <it>care</it>.</vi> <vi>She knows a lot about the <phrase>care and feeding</phrase> of horses.</vi> <vi>These machines don't need a lot of <it>care and feeding</it>. [=<it>maintenance</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that causes you to feel worried or unhappy <vi>He acts as if he doesn't have a <it>care</it> in the world. [=as if he has no worries]</vi> <vi>She looks as if all the <it>cares</it> of the world are on her shoulders.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>care of</dre> <def><dt>:at the address of <vi>You can write to him <it>care of</it> his fan club. [=you can write to him by sending a letter to his fan club]</vi> <un>abbr. <it>c/o</it></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in/into care</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt><un>used to describe children who are being cared for by a government organization because their parents have died or are unable to care for them properly <vi>The children had to be taken <it>into care</it> because of parental failure.</vi> <vi>The youngest child was <it>in care</it> for several years.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take care</dre> <def><dt>:to be careful :to use caution <vi>He <it>took care</it> not to upset anyone.</vi> <vi><it>Take care</it> when you cross the street.</vi> <un>often used informally to express good wishes when someone is leaving or at the end of a letter <vi>I'll see you next week. <it>Take care</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take care of</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do the things that are needed to help or protect (someone) or to keep (something) in good condition :to care for (someone or something) <vi>He <it>takes care of</it> [=<it>looks after</it>] his brother after school.</vi> <vi>They <it>took care of</it> a ten-room house without help.</vi> <vi>He is home <it>taking care of</it> a sick child.</vi> <vi>Each worker <it>takes care of</it> [=is responsible for] three machines.</vi> <vi>Their family doctor has been <it>taking care of</it> them for 20 years.</vi> <vi>You really ought to <it>take</it> better <it>care of</it> yourself. If you don't get some rest and start eating better, you are bound to get sick.</vi> <vi>I'm old enough to <it>take care of</it> [=<it>look out for</it>] myself.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to deal with or do (something that requires effort or attention) <vi>My assistant <it>takes care of</it> [=<it>makes</it>] all our travel arrangements.</vi> <vi>Don't worry about that mess. I'll <it>take care of</it> it. [=I'll clean it up]</vi> <vi>He offered to <it>take care of</it> [=<it>pay</it>] the bill.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="care[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">care</hw> <altpr>ˈkeɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cares</if></in> <in><if>cared</if></in> <in><if>car*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to feel interest in something :to be interested in or concerned about something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He doesn't <it>care</it> if he gets fired.</vi> <un>often + <it>about</it> <vi>I don't <it>care about</it> your little problems.</vi> <vi>He <it>cares</it> deeply <it>about</it> religion.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I <it>care</it> what happens to her.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to feel affection for someone <vi>On Valentine's Day, send her flowers to show that you <it>care</it>.</vi> <vi>I didn't know you <it>cared</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to want <it>to do</it> something or <it>to be</it> something <vi>I wouldn't <it>care</it> [=<it>like</it>] <it>to have</it> to make that decision.</vi> <vi>I wouldn't <it>care to be</it> in your shoes right now.</vi> <vi>I'm going for a walk. Would you <it>care to join</it> me?</vi> <vi>He'll show the photos to anyone who <it>cares to see</it> them.</vi> <vi>More factors influenced her decision than she <it>cares to admit</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as if I cared</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used in angry speech to say that you do not care at all about something <vi>“She says she doesn't want to talk to you.” “<it>As if I cared</it>!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>care a damn</dre> <dx>see <dxt>damn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>care for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>care for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do the things that are needed to help and protect (a person or animal) :to look after (someone or something) <vi>She <it>cares for</it> [=<it>takes care of</it>] elderly patients.</vi> <vi>Who is <it>caring for</it> your son while you are at work?</vi> <vi>I <it>cared for</it> his cat while he was away.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>care for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to feel affection for (someone) <vi>He sent flowers to show that he <it>cares for</it> you.</vi> <vi>I got the feeling he never really <it>cared for</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>care for (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to like or enjoy (something) <un>often used in negative statements <vi>I don't <it>care for</it> [=<it>like</it>] jelly beans.</vi> <vi>He doesn't <it>care for</it> sports.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>care for</it> your tone of voice.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to want (something) <vi>Would you <it>care for</it> some pie?</vi> <vi>I don't <it>care for</it> any more coffee.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>could/couldn't care less</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If you <it>could care less</it> (<it>US</it>) or <it>couldn't care less</it>, you are not at all concerned about or interested in something. <vi>I <it>could care less</it> what happens. [=I don't care what happens]</vi> <vi>He says he <it>couldn't care less</it> if he gets fired.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for all (someone) cares</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that someone does not care at all about something <vi><it>For all I care</it>, he can leave today. [=I don't care if he leaves today]</vi> <vi>She could quit the whole thing, <it>for all he cares</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see if I care</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used in angry speech to say that you do not care at all about something <vi>Go ahead and call her. <it>See if I care</it>!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what does (someone) care?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you do not think someone should have any interest in something <vi>“She said we should go.” “Well, <it>what does she care</it>?”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>who cares?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to stress that something is not important. <vi>He can't carry a tune, but <it>who cares</it>? He's having fun and that's what matters.</vi> <vi><it>Who cares</it> what she says? [=what she says is not important]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="care package"> <hw>care package</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ages</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a package of useful or enjoyable items (such as candy or baked goods) that is sent or given as a gift to someone who is away from home</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="care worker"> <hw>care worker</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a person whose job is to give care to people who are ill, disabled, etc.</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="day care"> <hw>day care</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a place, program, or organization that takes care of children or sick adults during the day usually while their family members are at work <vi>She left work early to pick up her son from <it>day care</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>He works for/at a <it>day care</it> center.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="devil-may-care"> <hw>dev*il–may–care</hw> <sound><wav>devil_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌdɛvl̟ˌmeɪˈkeɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more dev*il–may–care; most dev*il–may–care</gram> <dt>:relaxed and without worry <vi>He has a <it>devil-may-care</it> attitude about life.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="elder care"> <hw>elder care</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:the care of old people <vi>an <it>elder care</it> facility [=a place that provides care for elderly people]</vi> :the care of elderly parents by their children <vi>resources for childcare and <it>elder care</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="health care"> <hw>health care</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the prevention or treatment of illness by doctors, dentists, psychologists, etc.</dt></def> <uro><ure>health–care</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi><it>health-care</it> workers</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="intensive care"> <hw>intensive care</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a section of a hospital where special medical equipment and services are provided for patients who are seriously injured or ill <vi>patients in <it>intensive care</it> = patients in the <phrase>intensive care unit</phrase> [=<it>ICU</it>]</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the medical care provided in such a section <vi>Her condition will require <it>intensive care</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="primary care"> <hw>primary care</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:medical care from the doctor who sees a patient first and provides basic treatment or decides that the patient should see another doctor <vi>He provides <it>primary care</it> to inner-city patients.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) a <it>primary care</it> physician/provider</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
