<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="carry[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">car*ry</hw> <sound><wav>carry001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeri</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>car*ries</if></in> <in><if>car*ried</if></in> <in><if>car*ry*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (something) while holding and supporting it <vi>She helped me <it>carry</it> [=<it>transport</it>] the boxes out to my car.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>carry</it> your luggage to your room.</vi> <vi>He was <it>carrying</it> his baby daughter in his arms.</vi> <vi>For two months, I <it>carried</it> the book around with me everywhere I went.</vi> <vi>The waitress <it>carried</it> away our empty dinner plates.</vi> <vi>The wind <it>carried</it> the smoke away from the campsite.</vi> <vi>These planes can <it>carry</it> up to 300 passengers.</vi> <vi>a ship <it>carrying</it> thousands of gallons of oil</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>Your talent will <it>carry</it> you far. [=it will make you very successful]</vi> <vi>She intended the play to <it>carry</it> audiences toward a sense of peace and understanding.</vi> <vi>She still <it>carries</it> the memories of an unhappy childhood.</vi> <vi>The song <phrase>carries me back to</phrase> [=it makes me remember] my first year of college.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to contain and direct the flow of (water, electricity, etc.) <vi>Oil is <it>carried</it> to the factory through these pipes.</vi> <vi>We installed gutters that will <it>carry</it> water away from the house.</vi> <vi>blood vessels that <it>carry</it> blood to the heart</vi> <vi>These cables <it>carry</it> electricity to hundreds of homes.</vi> <vi>The bridge <it>carries</it> traffic in two directions.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) with you or on your body <vi>Do police officers <it>carry</it> guns when they're off duty?</vi> <vi>This bus driver doesn't <it>carry</it> change, so please have the exact fare ready.</vi> <vi>I always <it>carry</it> $20 in case of an emergency.</vi> <vi>tourists <it>carrying</it> cameras</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be able to give (a disease or a gene) to others even though you may not be affected by it <vi>One percent of the population now <it>carries</it> the virus, and one in three will suffer symptoms of the disease.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be pregnant with (a baby) <vi>She's <it>carrying</it> her second child.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to hold (your body or your head) in a particular way <vi>He's over 80 years old and still <it>carries</it> himself erect/upright like a soldier.</vi> <vi>Be proud of yourself. Walk tall and <it>carry</it> your head high!</vi> <vi>She always <it>carries</it> [=(more formally) <it>comports</it>] herself with dignity and grace.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) in a store and ready to be sold :to keep (something) in stock <vi>Our grocery store <it>carries</it> a good selection of wines.</vi> <vi>We no longer <it>carry</it> that brand.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have (someone or something) on a list or record <vi>The company <it>carries</it> nearly 200 employees on its payroll.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) as a quality or characteristic <vi>All of our products <it>carry</it> a lifetime guarantee.</vi> <vi>Your promises would <phrase>carry more weight</phrase> [=they would be more meaningful] if you didn't break them so often.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be marked or labeled with (something) <vi>Cigarettes are required to <it>carry</it> a government health warning.</vi> <vi>men who <it>carry</it> the physical scars of war</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a result or consequence <vi>Such crimes <it>carry</it> [=<it>entail</it>, <it>involve</it>] a heavy penalty.</vi> <vi>The surgery does <it>carry</it> certain risks.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>You must understand that the job <it>carries with</it> it <it>g</it>reat responsibility.</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) as a duty or responsibility <vi>I'm <it>carrying</it> a full course load this semester.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>carries the weight of the world on his shoulders</phrase>. [=he feels much pressure because he has great responsibilities]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be responsible for the success of (something or someone) <vi>He's a player that's capable of <it>carrying</it> a team on his own.</vi> <vi>Her spectacular performance as Carmen <it>carried</it> the opera.</vi></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) continue <vi>They <it>carried</it> [=<it>took, extended</it>] the game into the 10th inning.</vi> <vi>The newspaper <it>carried</it> the story over to the following page.</vi> <vi>The design calls for the columns to be <it>carried</it> all the way up to the top of the building.</vi> <vi><it>carrying</it> the war to another continent</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to travel a long distance <vi>His deep voice <it>carries</it> well.</vi> <vi>Baseballs don't <it>carry</it> well in cold weather.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue (something) beyond a normal or acceptable limit <vi>He realized that he had <it>carried</it> the joke too far and hurt her feelings.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>carry (something) to extremes</tag> at <dxt>extreme</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to sing (a tune) correctly <vi>I've never been able to <it>carry</it> a tune.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to present (a story, sports event, TV show, etc.) to the public <vi>Channel 9 will <it>carry</it> the game.</vi> <vi>Every local newspaper <it>carried</it> [=<it>ran</it>] the photograph.</vi> <vi>The trial was <it>carried</it> live [=broadcast as it was happening] on television.</vi></dt> <sn>16 a</sn> <dt>:to cause (a bill or an official proposal) to be passed or adopted <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <un>often used as <it>(be) carried</it> <vi>The bill <it>was carried</it> in the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>He called for a motion to stop debate, but the motion did not <it>carry</it>.</vi> <vi>The motion <it>carried</it> unanimously. [=everyone voted to pass it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to win a majority of votes in (a state, legislature, etc.) <vi>The bill <it>carried</it> the Senate by a vote of 75–25.</vi> <vi>In the presidential election of 1936, Franklin D. Roosevelt <it>carried</it> [=<it>won, took</it>] all the states except Maine and Vermont.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to move (a number) from one column to another when you are adding numbers together <vi>When you added these two numbers, you forgot to <it>carry</it> the 1.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be/get carried away</dre> <def><dt>:to be so excited that you are no longer in control of your behavior <vi>I shouldn't have behaved like that. I just <it>got carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>Just relax! There's no need to <it>get carried away</it>.</vi> <vi>They allowed themselves to <it>be carried away</it> by fear.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry all/everything before you</dre> <def><sl>literary</sl> <dt>:to be completely successful <vi>This young boxer has the talent to <it>carry all before him</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry a torch for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry coals to Newcastle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coal</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry into effect</dre> <dx>see <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry (something) off</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do (something difficult) successfully :to achieve or accomplish (something) <vi>He tried to look cool but couldn't <it>carry it off</it>. [=<it>pull it off</it>]</vi> <vi>She's the only actress I know with enough talent to <it>carry this off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to win (something) <vi>We <it>carried off</it> the prize.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to do what you have been doing <vi>I didn't mean to interrupt you—please <it>carry on</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>carried on</it> as if nothing had happened.</vi> :to continue despite problems <vi>I know it's difficult, but you need to <it>carry on</it> as best you can.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to behave or speak in an excited or foolish way <vi>They laughed and <it>carried on</it> like they were old friends.</vi> <vi>We were embarrassed by the way he was <it>carrying on</it>.</vi> <vi>She's always <it>carrying on</it> [=talking in an excited way] about her neighbors.</vi> <vi>screaming, crying, and <it>carrying on</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryings-on</dxt> <dxt>carry-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to manage or participate in (an activity) <vi>She <it>carried on</it> an affair with her boss.</vi> <vi>It's too noisy in here to <it>carry on</it> a conversation.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>carrying on</it> [=<it>conducting</it>] an investigation into his murder.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> a campaign against illegal drug use</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi>The money allows us to <it>carry on</it> our research.</vi> <vi>Although the teacher spoke to them, they just <it>carried on</it> [=<it>went on</it>, <it>kept on</it>] talking.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause (something, such as a tradition) to continue <vi>We were the only ones left to <it>carry on</it> the tradition.</vi> <vi><it>carrying on</it> the family name</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing or participating in (an activity) <vi>Please <it>carry on with</it> what you were doing.</vi> <vi>They <it>carried on with</it> their conversation.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry on with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have an often immoral sexual relationship with (someone) <vi>I found out that he had been <it>carrying on with</it> [=(more commonly) <it>fooling around with</it>] my sister.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>carry (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do and complete (something) <vi>We <it>carried out</it> several experiments to test the theory.</vi> <vi>An investigation <it>carried out</it> several years ago revealed no new information.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to act on (a promise, plan, etc.) :to do something that you said you would do or that someone has asked you to do <vi>She failed to <it>carry out</it> [=<it>fulfill</it>] her promise.</vi> <vi>The town has plans to build a new school, but it currently lacks the money to <it>carry</it> them <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>You'll be paid when you've <it>carried out</it> [=<it>executed</it>] your instructions/orders/duties.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or be seen in another place or situation <vi>His unhappiness at home <it>carried over</it> into/to his work.</vi> <vi>Her abilities in singing didn't <it>carry over</it> to acting.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>carry over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause or allow (something) to continue in another place or situation <vi>People can <it>carry</it> bad eating habits learned in childhood <it>over</it> to/into adulthood.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carryover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the can</dre> <dx>see <dxt>can</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>day</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry the torch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>torch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to continue to exist or happen <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>The yellow and blue theme in the kitchen <it>carries through to</it> the rest of the house.</vi> <vi>Our conversation <it>carried through to</it> dessert.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue to do something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Though extremely tired, she managed to <it>carry through to</it> the finish.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry through with/on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to do (something that you said you would do) <vi>The mayor <it>carried through</it> [=<it>followed through</it>] <it>on</it> her promise to clean up the city.</vi> <vi>We're beginning to <it>carry through with</it> [=<it>carry out</it>] our plans.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (something) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to successfully finish or complete (something that you have begun or said you will do) <vi>Whatever project you begin, you must <it>carry it through</it> to completion.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> (until spring).</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>carry (someone) through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help or allow (someone) to survive or continue during (a period of time) <vi>We had enough supplies to <it>carry us through</it> the winter.</vi> <vi>His faith <it>carried him through</it> a difficult time in his life.</vi> <vi>I borrowed a few more books to <it>carry me through</it> the summer.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fetch and carry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fetch</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="carry[2]"> <hw hindex="2">carry</hw> <altpr>ˈkeri</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>carries</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>American football</sl> <dt>:the act of running with the ball <vi>He averaged four yards per <it>carry</it> this season.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="carry-cot"> <hw>car*ry–cot</hw> <sound><wav>carry_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeriˌkɑ:t</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>car*ry–cots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a small bed that is used for carrying a young baby</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="carry-on[1]"> <hw hindex="1">car*ry–on</hw> <sound><wav>carry_02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeriˌɑ:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>car*ry–ons</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a small piece of luggage that a passenger can carry onto an airplane <vi>I packed the book in my <it>carry-on</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a moment of excitement or silly behavior <vi>She makes such a big <it>carry-on</it> [=<it>fuss, stir</it>] about everything.</vi> <vi>What a <it>carry-on</it>!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>carry on</tag> at <dxt>carry</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="carry-on[2]"> <hw hindex="2">carry–on</hw> <altpr>ˈkeriˌɑ:n</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:small enough to be carried onto an airplane by a passenger <vi><it>carry-on</it> baggage/luggage</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cash-and-carry"> <hw>cash–and–car*ry</hw> <sound><wav>cash_a01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkæʃn̩ˈkeri</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cash–and–car*ries</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a store where businesses and other customers can pay cash for goods at low prices and take them away instead of having them delivered</dt></def> <uro><ure>cash–and–carry</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>items sold on a <it>cash-and-carry</it> basis</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="ball[1]"> <art><artref id="ball_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,288</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ball</hw> <sound><wav>ball0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɑ:l</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>balls</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a usually round object that is used in a game or sport or as a toy <vi>a tennis/soccer <it>ball</it></vi> <vi>golf/billiard/bowling <it>balls</it></vi> <vi>a toy rubber <it>ball</it></vi> <vi>kick/throw/hit/catch/bounce/dribble the <it>ball</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that has a round shape <vi>a <it>ball</it> of string</vi> <vi>She uses cotton <it>balls</it> to clean her face.</vi> <vi>eating rice/melon <it>balls</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a round bullet shot out of an old-fashioned gun</dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the rounded part of the human foot that is at the bottom of the foot and behind the toes <un>usually plural <vi>He stood on the <it>balls</it> of his feet.</vi></un> <dx>see picture at <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal + often offensive</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>testicle</sx> <un>usually plural <vi>She kicked him in the <it>balls</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>balls</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the courage that is needed to do something <vi>You don't have the/enough <it>balls</it> [=<it>guts</it>, <it>nerve</it>] to fight me.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>balls</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>nonsense</sx> <un>often used as an interjection to express disapproval or annoyance</un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:a ball that is thrown or hit <vi>She hit a high arching <it>ball</it> over the net.</vi> <vi>I thought the <it>ball</it> [=serve] was good, but my opponent said it was out.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>air ball</dxt> <dxt>curveball</dxt> <dxt>fastball</dxt> <dxt>fly ball</dxt> <dxt>ground ball</dxt> <tag>fair ball</tag> at <dxt>fair</dxt> <tag>foul ball</tag> at <dxt>foul</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:a pitch that does not go through the proper area and that the batter does not swing at <vi>The first pitch was a <it>ball</it> but the next two pitches were strikes.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>carry the ball</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to have the responsibility for doing something <vi>No one else is available to make the arrangements, so it's up to you to <it>carry the ball</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>drop the ball</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to make a mistake especially by not doing something important <vi>I think the mayor <it>dropped the ball</it> by not hiring more police officers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get/set/start the ball rolling</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to begin an activity or process <vi>She tried to <it>get the ball rolling</it> by asking him a few questions.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep the ball rolling</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to cause an activity or process to continue <vi>I've started the preparations for the party, but it's up to you to <it>keep the ball rolling</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eye on the ball</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to continue thinking about or giving attention to something important that you want to do or achieve <vi>She really needs to <it>keep her eye on the ball</it> [=stay focused] if she wants to win the election.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the ball</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:mentally prepared :aware of what is happening and ready to do what is needed or wanted <vi>With so many intelligent students, the teacher must always be <it>on the ball</it>.</vi> <vi>Their lawyer was really <it>on the ball</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>play ball</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin or continue to play a game with a ball (such as baseball) <vi>“Let's <it>play ball</it>!” shouted the umpire.</vi> <vi>We went outside to <it>play</it> some <it>ball</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do what other people want you to do :to cooperate or work with other people <vi>He refused to <it>play ball</it> with the police.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the ball is in your court</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>the ball is in your court</it>, you are the person who is expected or required to do something. <vi>What do you think we should do now? <it>The ball is in your court</it>.</vi> <vi>She's waiting for <it>the ball to be in her court</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>ball</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="can[2]"> <art><artref id="can.tif"/><capt>can</capt><dim>37.5,72.5</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">can</hw> <sound><wav>can_2_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cans</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a closed metal container that is usually shaped like a cylinder and that holds food or drink <vi>Open a <it>can</it> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>tin</it>] of beans.</vi> <vi>a <it>can</it> of tomatoes</vi> <vi>a soda/beer <it>can</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the food or drink that is in a can <vi>He ate the whole <it>can</it> of beans.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a metal or plastic container that has a removable top and that is used for holding liquid, trash, etc. <vi>a <it>can</it> of oil = an oil <it>can</it></vi> <vi>a garbage <it>can</it></vi> <vi>a trash <it>can</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>spray can</sx> <vi>a <it>can</it> of deodorant</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>can of worms</dre> <def><dt>:a complicated situation in which doing something to correct a problem leads to many more problems <vi>We thought the project would be simple, but it turned out to be a real <it>can of worms</it>.</vi> <vi>Our boss is reluctant to change the policy now because she doesn't want to <phrase>open a can of worms</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>carry the can</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to accept blame or responsibility for something that you did not cause <vi>He made the error, but she was left to <it>carry the can</it>.</vi> <vi>Taxpayers will <it>carry the can</it> for the renovations.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the can</dre> <def><sl>of a film, recording, etc.</sl> <dt>:completed and ready to be released <vi>a movie that is <it>in the can</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the can</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the part of the body that you sit on :<sx>buttocks</sx> <vi>If you ask me, what he needs is a good kick in <it>the can</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a room with a toilet :<sx>bathroom</sx> <vi>He locked himself in <it>the can</it> and wouldn't come out.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>toilet</sx> <vi>sitting on <it>the can</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a prison or jail <vi>The cops threw him in <it>the can</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>can*ful</ure> <sound><wav>can_2_02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkænˌfʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>can*fuls</if></in> <utxt><vi>a <it>canful</it> of beans</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="coal"> <hw highlight="yes">coal</hw> <sound><wav>coal0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoʊl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>coals</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a black or brownish-black hard substance within the earth that is used as a fuel <vi>a bin of <it>coal</it></vi> <vi>The furnace burns <it>coal</it>.</vi> <vi>a lump of <it>coal</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>coal</it> bin/mine/bed/stove</vi> <vi>the <it>coal</it> industry</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a piece of coal or charcoal especially when burning <vi>When the <it>coals</it> are red, they are very hot.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a glowing piece of wood from a fire :<sx>ember</sx> <vi>I toasted one last marshmallow over the <it>coals</it> of the campfire.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>carry/take coals to Newcastle</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to take something to a place where it is not needed because a large amount of it is already there</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>haul/rake (someone) over the coals</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) very severely <vi>I arrived late for the meeting and was immediately <it>hauled over the coals</it> by my boss.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="day"> <hw highlight="yes">day</hw> <sound><wav>day00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdeɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>days</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a period of 24 hours beginning at midnight :one of the seven time periods that make up a week <vi>We're open seven <it>days</it> a week, 365 <it>days</it> a year.</vi> <vi>Payment is due on the first <it>day</it> of every month.</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> is (it) today?” “Tuesday.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> [=<it>date</it>] is Friday?” “It's the 28th.”</vi> <vi>“What <it>day</it> of the week is the 28th?” “It's a Friday.”</vi> <vi>He spent five <it>days</it> in the hospital.</vi> <vi>She left on Thursday and came back four <it>days</it> later.</vi> <vi>The baby is due (to be born) in three <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>That was the happiest <it>day</it> of my life.</vi> <vi>Parenthood gets better every <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>We'll be finished in a <it>day</it> or two. = We'll be finished in a couple of <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It rained for a <it>day</it> and a half. [=it rained for about 36 hours]</vi> <vi>The office is closed for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I call him every (single) <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow is another <it>day</it>. [=there will be more opportunities to do things tomorrow]</vi> <vi>a <it>day</it> of celebration/mourning [=a day for people to celebrate/mourn]</vi> <vi>Take one pill two times <phrase>a day</phrase>. [=each day]</vi> <vi>She works eight hours <it>a day</it>.</vi> <vi>It costs 10 dollars <it>a day</it> to park there.</vi> <vi>The party is <phrase>the day after tomorrow</phrase>. = The party is in two <it>days</it>.</vi> <vi>It happened <phrase>the day before yesterday</phrase>. = It happened two <it>days</it> ago.</vi> <vi>Sometimes they didn't speak to each other for <phrase>days on end</phrase>. [=several days]</vi> <vi><phrase>From that day forth/forward</phrase> [=(less formally) <it>from then on</it>], I was determined to do better.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>do not look a day over</phrase> a particular age, you appear to be that age. <vi>“Today's my 50th birthday.” “Really? I'm surprised. You <it>don't look a day over</it> 40.” [=you don't look any older than 40 years old]</vi></snote> <snote>If you say that someone is a particular age <phrase>if he/she is a day</phrase>, you mean that the person is that age or older. <vi>The man she's dating is 60 <it>if he's a day</it>. [=he is at least sixty years old]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the time of light between one night and the next :the part of the day when light from the sun can be seen <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What a beautiful summer <it>day</it>!</vi> <vi>a cold/wet/rainy <it>day</it></vi> <vi>The shortest <it>day</it> of the year is usually December 22, and June 22 is usually the longest.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He sleeps during the <it>day</it> [=<it>daytime</it>] and works at night.</vi> <vi>You can call me any time, <it>day</it> or night.</vi> <vi>These animals are mostly active during the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>I work during the <it>day</it>. [=I work days]</vi> <vi>She's a student <phrase>by day</phrase> [=during the day] and a waitress by night.</vi> <vi>I woke at (the) <phrase>break of day</phrase>. [=(more commonly) <it>dawn, daybreak, sunrise</it>]</vi> <vi><phrase>day workers</phrase> [=people who work during the day]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>night</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the part of the day when people are usually most active and when most businesses are open <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>I like to start my <it>day</it> with a cup of coffee. [=I like to drink a cup of coffee as soon as I wake up]</vi> <vi>We decided to rent a car for the <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>How was your <it>day</it>?</vi> <vi>By the end of the <it>day</it>, we were all exhausted.</vi> <vi>Our neighbors play their loud music <phrase>at all hours of the day</phrase>. [=throughout the day]</vi> <vi>Let's go to bed. We have an <phrase>early day</phrase> [=we will get out of bed early] tomorrow.</vi> <vi>I needed to relax after a <phrase>long day</phrase> at work/school. [=after working/being at school for a long time]</vi> <vi>“Thank you, ma'am. <phrase>Have a nice day</phrase>!”</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I'll be gone <phrase>all day</phrase>.</vi> <vi>It rained <phrase>all day long</phrase>.</vi> <snote>People sometimes say that they <phrase>can't wait all day</phrase> or <phrase>don't have all day</phrase> when they are in a hurry and need someone to move or act more quickly. These phrases are usually used in a rude way. <vi>Hurry up! I <it>can't wait all day</it>! = I <it>don't have all day</it>. = I <it>haven't got all day</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hours during a day when a person works or goes to school or when a company does business <vi>I put in four twelve-hour <it>days</it> [=<it>workdays</it>] this week.</vi> <vi>She makes about 50 dollars a/per <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>He was late for his first <it>day</it> on the job.</vi> <vi>They collected a full <it>day</it>'s pay for half a <it>day</it>'s work.</vi> <vi>We had a busy couple of <it>days</it> at the store.</vi> <vi>We have a short <it>day</it> tomorrow. [=we have to work fewer hours tomorrow than usual]</vi> <vi>The school committee is pushing for a longer school <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow's our last <it>day</it> of school (for the school year).</vi> <vi>Please allow 14 <phrase>business days</phrase> [=days when most businesses are open; weekdays that are not holidays] for delivery.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>all in a day's work</phrase> for someone, it is part of a person's typical work. <vi>Solving violent crimes is <it>all in a day's work</it> for these police detectives.</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>take a/the day off</phrase> is to decide not to work on a particular day. <vi>He <it>took the day off</it> to go fishing.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the day on which something specified happens or is expected to happen <vi>It rained on their wedding <it>day</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>day</it> of his birth</vi> <vi>This Sunday is <phrase>family day</phrase> [=a day for families especially with young children] at the amusement park.</vi> <vi>If you've been waiting for the perfect skiing conditions, <phrase>today's the day</phrase>. [=the conditions are perfect today]</vi> <vi>So, when's <phrase>the big day</phrase>? When are you getting married?</vi> <vi>Did you ever think you'd <phrase>see the day</phrase> when he would apologize? [=did you believe he would ever apologize?]</vi> <vi>I never thought I would <phrase>live to see the day</phrase> when you would graduate from college. [=I did not think I would live long enough to see you graduate]</vi> <vi>Let her have her <phrase>day in court</phrase> [=let her defend herself in a court of law] before you pass judgment on her.</vi> <vi>This is <phrase>your lucky day</phrase>. [=a day when something good happens to you]</vi> <snote>If a day <phrase>is your day</phrase>, something good will happen to you on that day. <vi>You never know. Maybe today will <it>be my day</it>. [=maybe I will succeed, win, etc., today]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry you lost. I guess it just <it>wasn't your day</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>People sometimes use the phrase <phrase>that'll be the day</phrase> to say that they think something will not happen. <vi>“Do you think he'll ever admit he made a mistake?” “<it>That'll be the day</it>!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular period of time <vi>She was the most talented actress of her <it>day</it>. [=during the time when she lived and worked as an actress]</vi> <vi><phrase>In my day</phrase> [=when I was young], boys asked girls out on dates, not the other way around.</vi> <vi>Life was simpler <it>in my grandmother's day</it>, but it wasn't easier.</vi> <vi>We sell books dating from 1875 to <phrase>the present day</phrase>. [=<it>today</it>]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He often spoke about his <it>days</it> as a soldier.</vi> <vi>I was quite an athlete in my younger <it>days</it>. [=when I was young]</vi> <vi>The practice dates back to the <it>days</it> of ancient Rome.</vi> <vi>the olden <it>days</it></vi> <vi>my college <it>days</it> [=when I was in college]</vi> <vi>the <it>days</it> of stagecoaches [=when stagecoaches were used]</vi> <vi>In those <it>days</it> many factory workers were children.</vi></un> <snote>The saying <phrase>those were the days</phrase> is sometimes used to say that a period of time in the past was pleasant and often better than the present time. <vi>When I was a kid, we spent our summers at the beach. <it>Those were the days</it>!</vi> <vi>In the 1960s, everything seemed possible. Those were <phrase>the good old days</phrase>.</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>(all) the livelong day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>livelong</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>any day now</dre> <def><dt>:within the next few days :<sx>soon</sx> <vi>We're expecting a phone call from him <it>any day now</it>. [=in the near future]</vi> <vi><it>Any day now</it>, the decision could be made.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>at the end of the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>end</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>call it a day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>call</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>carry/win the day</dre> <def><dt>:to win or be successful <vi>The “no” vote <it>carried the day</it>. [=<it>prevailed</it>]</vi> <vi>We believe that truth and justice will <it>carry/win the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day after day</dre> <def><dt>:for several days without stopping or changing <vi>She wore the same pants <it>day after day</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Day after day</it>, we hear the same complaints from our customers.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day and night</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>night and day</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:all the time :without stopping <vi>We've been working on it <it>day and night</it>. = We've been working on it <it>night and day</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:complete or total <vi>The difference between them is <it>day and night</it>. = The difference between them is <it>night and day</it>. [=they are completely different]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day by day</dre> <def><dt>:in small amounts every day <vi><it>Day by day</it>, the situation is becoming more complex.</vi> <vi>She felt herself growing stronger <it>day by day</it>. [=every day]</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>take it/things day by day</phrase>, you make progress in a slow and careful way by dealing with each day as it comes. <vi>He hopes to make a full recovery after his surgery, but right now he's just <it>taking it day by day</it>. [=<it>taking it one day at a time</it>, <it>taking each day as it comes</it>]</vi> <vi>I don't know if our relationship is going to work out. I'm <it>taking things day by day</it> at this point.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>day in, day out</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>day in and day out</va></vr> <def><dt>:every day for many days :for a long time without stopping or changing <vi>She does the same thing at her job <it>day in</it>, <it>day out</it>.</vi> <vi>It can be difficult to spend all of your time with one person <it>day in and day out</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>days are numbered</dre> <dx>see <dxt>number</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>early days (yet)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>early</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every dog has its day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for a rainy day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rainy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>from day to day</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>His opinions seem to change <it>from day to day</it>. [=<it>from one day to the next</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>day-to-day</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from one day to the next</dre> <def><dt>:every day <vi>She changes her mind <it>from one day to the next</it>. [=<it>from day to day</it>]</vi> :as one day becomes another day <vi>You never know <it>from one day to the next</it> what's going to happen to you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the time of day</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to pay attention to someone <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>No one would <it>give us the time of day</it>.</vi> <vi>I needed their help, but they wouldn't <it>give me the time of day</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>glory days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>glory</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have seen/known better days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>better</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in all your born days</dre> <dx>see <dxt>born</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the cold light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in this day and age</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time in history <vi>Computers are essential to getting work done <it>in this day and age</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>It's unbelievable that <it>in this day and age</it> people are still dying from hunger.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>it is not every day</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something happens very rarely <vi><it>It's not every day</it> that I get to meet the President.</vi> <vi>Go ahead and spend the extra money. <it>It's not every day</it> that you get married.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>late in the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>late</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's day</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's day to be pleasant or happy <vi>Thanks for the compliment. You've really <it>made my day</it>!</vi> <vi>It <it>made my day</it> to see his smiling face.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of the day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:served in a restaurant as a special item on a particular day <vi>What's the fish/vegetable <it>of the day</it>?</vi> <vi>Our soup <it>of the day</it> [=<it>du jour</it>] is vegetable beef.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:of a particular period of time <vi>What were some of the popular movies <it>of the day</it>? [=that were popular during that time]</vi> <vi>the important issues <it>of the day</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one day</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:at some time in the future <vi><it>One day</it>, it'll happen. You'll see.</vi> <vi>People may <it>one day</it> [=<it>someday</it>] be able to take vacations to the moon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:on a day in the past <vi>I went to her house <it>one day</it> and had lunch with her.</vi> <vi><it>One day</it>, we had a terrible argument.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the day</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:on the day that an event happens <vi>I know we seem a bit disorganized now, but we'll be all right <it>on the day</it>.</vi> <vi>Whether we win or not depends on which players are healthy <it>on the day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save the day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>see the light of day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>some day</dre> <def><dt>:at some time in the future :<sx>someday</sx> <vi><it>Some day</it> I may be rich enough to own two houses.</vi> <vi>I'd like to return there <it>some day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take each day as it comes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>take one day at a time</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>take it/things one day at a time</va></vr> <def><dt>:to deal with each day's problems as they come instead of worrying about the future <vi>There's no way to know what the future will bring, so just <it>take each day as it comes</it> and hope for the best.</vi> <vi><it>Take one day at a time</it> and don't expect things to change overnight.</vi> <vi>It's important to <it>take things one day at a time</it> so you don't feel too overwhelmed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the other day</dre> <dx>see <dxt>other</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>these days</dre> <def><dt>:at the present time <vi>It seems that everyone has a cell phone <it>these days</it>. [=<it>nowadays</it>]</vi> <vi>What kind of music are you listening to <it>these days</it>?</vi> <vi><it>These days</it>, she has a very busy social life.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>one of these days</phrase> means at some time in the future. <vi><it>One of these days</it>, [=<it>one day</it>] I'm going to buy myself a boat.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>those days</dre> <def><dt>:a period of time in the past <vi>Remember when we were kids and life was easy? Well, <it>those days</it> are gone.</vi> <vi><phrase>In those days</phrase>, women weren't allowed to own property.</vi> <vi>No one knew <it>in those days</it> what caused the disease.</vi> <snote>If it is (<phrase>just) one of those days</phrase>, it is a day in which many bad or unpleasant things happen. <vi>It's <it>just one of those days</it> when everything seems to go wrong.</vi> <vi>I missed the bus and sprained my ankle; it was <it>one of those days</it> when nothing was going right.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the day</dre> <def><dt>:to exactly a specified number of years <vi>It's been 100 years <it>to the day</it> since their great discovery.</vi> <vi>Soon after their wedding, almost a year <it>to the day</it>, they got divorced.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to this day</dre> <def><dt>:up to now :continuing until today <vi><it>To this day</it>, I still don't know what happened.</vi> <vi>The belief persists <it>to this day</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
