<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="case[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">case</hw> <sound><wav>case0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkeɪs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cas*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a situation or occurrence that is an instance or example of something <vi>That was true in all three <it>cases</it>. [=<it>instances</it>]</vi> <vi>We usually ask for a 100-dollar deposit, but <phrase>in this case</phrase> we'll make an exception.</vi> <vi>They might not let you buy the tickets yet, <phrase>in which case</phrase> [=and if that is true] you should try again tomorrow.</vi> <vi>It was a <phrase>case of mistaken identity</phrase>. [=a situation in which someone or something is mistakenly thought to be someone or something else]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>classic case</phrase> [=a typical example] of sibling rivalry</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a situation that is being investigated or managed by someone (such as a police officer or social worker) in an official way <vi>Her disappearance is a <it>case</it> for the police.</vi> <vi>Detectives are on the <it>case</it>.</vi> <vi>a murder/rape/kidnapping <it>case</it></vi> <vi>The abused child's <it>case</it> was turned over to state authorities.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>grammar</ssl> <dt>:a form of a noun, pronoun, or adjective showing its relationship to other words in a sentence <vi>The word “child's” in “a child's shirt” is in the possessive <it>case</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>the case</bnote> <dt>:what actually exists or happens <vi>A lot of people have had trouble working with him, and that was certainly <it>the case</it> with me. [=I also had trouble working with him]</vi> <vi>She had expected him to come home, but that was not to be <it>the case</it>. [=but that didn't happen]</vi> <vi>The doctor may or may not have been at fault, but <phrase>whatever the case (may be)</phrase> [=either way] the patient almost died.</vi> <vi><phrase>Is it not the case</phrase> [=isn't it true] that she took the car without permission?</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:a situation that will be talked about and decided in court <vi>a court <it>case</it></vi> <vi>a civil/criminal <it>case</it></vi> <vi>The lawyer agreed to take/handle the <it>case</it>.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>I rest my case</phrase> can be used to say that you have finished an argument or to suggest that something proves that what you are saying is true. <vi>I said that it wouldn't work and it didn't. <it>I rest my case</it>.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>test case</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a convincing argument <vi>He makes a good <it>case</it> for cutting expenses.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an occurrence of a disease or an injury <vi>an AIDS <it>case</it></vi> <vi>He has a bad/severe/slight <it>case</it> of the flu.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an occurrence of discomfort, fear, etc. <vi>She had a bad <it>case</it> of the nerves/jitters/butterflies [=she was very nervous] before she gave her report.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a particular person and his or her condition or character <vi>You are a sad <it>case</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>basket case</dxt> <dxt>head case</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>in any case</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that something is true or certain regardless of what else has happened or been said <vi>I'm not sure if I'll be at the next meeting, but I'll see you Sunday <it>in any case</it>. [=I may or may not see you at the next meeting, but I'll definitely see you Sunday]</vi> <vi><it>In any case</it>, you still owe me five dollars.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in case</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:for the purpose of being ready for something that might happen <vi>Bring an umbrella <it>in case</it> it rains.</vi> <vi>We brought extra money <phrase>just in case</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about something that might have happened or that might be true <vi>Today is our anniversary, <it>in case</it> you've forgotten.</vi> <vi><it>In case</it> [=<it>if</it>] you're wondering, I'm looking for my glasses.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in case of</dre> <def><dt>:if (something) happens <vi>That door is for use <it>in case of</it> [=<it>in the event of</it>] fire.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in that case</dre> <def><dt>:when that is considered :because of that <vi>“The traffic could be heavy tomorrow.” “<it>In that case</it>, we better leave early.”</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on/off your case</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>Someone who is always or frequently criticizing you or telling you what to do is <it>on your case</it> and won't <phrase>get off your case</phrase>. <vi>Her brother is always <it>on her case</it> about the clothes she wears.</vi> <vi><it>Get off my case</it>! I'm working as hard as I can!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>case</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="case[2]"> <hw hindex="2">case</hw> <altpr>ˈkeɪs</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a box or container to hold something <vi>a cigarette/pencil <it>case</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>carrying case</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the contents of a box <vi>They drank a <it>case</it> [=four six-packs; 24 bottles] of beer.</vi></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>case</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="case[3]"> <hw hindex="3">case</hw> <altpr>ˈkeɪs</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cases</if></in> <in><if>cased</if></in> <in><if>cas*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to study or watch (a house, store, etc.) with plans to rob it <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>case the joint</phrase> <vi>A couple of robbers decided to <it>case the joint</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="case history"> <hw>case history</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ries</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a record that shows a person's past illnesses, treatments, and other information for use by doctors, social workers, etc. <vi>The patient's <it>case history</it> showed recurring fits of depression.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="case in point"> <hw>case in point</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:a specific example used to show that something you have said is true <vi>He spends a lot of money on unnecessary things. A <it>case in point</it> is his collection of rare sports cars.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="case law"> <hw>case law</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:law that is based on decisions that judges have made in past cases <vi><it>Case law</it> says that a person has a right to privacy.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="case study"> <hw>case study</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ies</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a published report about a person, group, or situation that has been studied over time <vi>a <it>case study</it> of prisoners</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a situation in real life that can be looked at or studied to learn about something <vi>The company's recent history is a <it>case study</it> in bad management.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="attache case"> <hw>attaché case</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small, thin suitcase that is used especially for carrying papers and documents</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="basket case"> <hw>basket case</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a person who is very nervous, tired, etc., and is not able to think or act normally <vi>I was so worried about losing my job that I was a complete <it>basket case</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something (such as a company or a government) that is in very bad condition and close to failure <vi>a business that was once very successful but is now a financial <it>basket case</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="carrying case"> <hw>carrying case</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a container that usually has a handle and that is made for carrying something with your hand <vi>The guitar had a plastic <it>carrying case</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
