<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cast[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cast</hw> <sound><wav>cast0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈkɑ:st</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>casts</if></in> <in><if>cast</if></in> <in><if>cast*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to throw or move (something) in a forceful way <vi><it>cast</it> [=<it>throw, toss</it>] a stone</vi> <vi>Seaweed was <it>cast</it> up by the waves.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to throw (a fishing line, hook, etc.) into the water by using a fishing pole</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to send or direct (something) in the direction of someone or something <vi>He <it>cast</it> a glance toward the door. [=he glanced at the door]</vi> <vi>The witch <it>cast</it> [=<it>put</it>] a spell on him.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to send (something) out or forward <vi>The fire <it>casts</it> [=<it>gives off</it>] a warm glow.</vi> <vi>The tree <it>cast</it> a long shadow on the lawn.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>The trial <it>casts</it> a harsh light on [=reveals bad things about] the banking industry.</vi> <vi>Their argument <phrase>cast a pall</phrase> on the party. [=gave the party an unhappy mood]</vi> <vi>The incident <phrase>casts doubt</phrase> on her honesty.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (a vote) formally <vi>How many votes were <it>cast</it>?</vi> <vi><it>cast</it> a ballot</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to assign roles for (a play, movie, etc.) to actors <vi><it>cast</it> a play</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to assign (an actor or actress) a role in a film, play, etc. <vi>She was <it>cast</it> as a college professor who becomes a spy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>typecast</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to shape (a substance) by pouring it into a mold and letting it harden <vi>The metal was <it>cast</it> into candlesticks.</vi> <vi>molds used for <it>casting</it> steel</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form (something, such as a sculpture) by casting metal, plaster, etc. <vi>The statue will be <it>cast</it> in bronze.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to arrange (something) into parts or into a proper form <vi>He <it>cast</it> the story in the form of a diary.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think of (someone or something) in a particular way <vi>The war was <it>cast</it> as a battle against terrorism.</vi> <vi>Health care issues are often <it>cast</it> in economic terms.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cast about/around for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast about/around for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look in many places for (something) <vi>They <it>cast about for</it> new ways to make money on the farm.</vi> <vi>She is still <it>casting around for</it> [=<it>seeking</it>] someone to watch her son while she is at work.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast a (dark) cloud</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloud</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast adrift</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (a boat) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (a boat) to float on the water without being tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>a small lifeboat <it>cast adrift</it> in the open sea</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast (someone) adrift</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to float on the water in a boat that is not tied to anything or controlled by anyone <un>often used as <it>(be) cast adrift</it> <vi>They <it>were cast adrift</it> in a small, leaky boat.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>I <it>was cast adrift</it> in a sea of confusion.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast aside (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) aside</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop thinking about (something) <vi>She tried to <it>cast aside</it> her worries and enjoy the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast aspersions</dre> <dx>see <dxt>aspersions</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast away (someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone) away</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (someone) alone somewhere (such as on an island) as a result of a storm, shipwreck, etc. <un>usually used as <it>(be) cast away</it> <vi>The crew <it>was cast away</it> on a desert island.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>castaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast caution to the wind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>caution</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast light on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast lots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>cast off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get rid of (something) <vi>The snake <it>casts off</it> [=<it>sheds</it>] its skin.</vi> <vi>They wanted to <it>cast off</it> their fears.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>castoff</dxt> <dxt>cast-off</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to untie the rope that is holding a boat near the land <vi>We decided to <it>cast off</it> and head out to sea.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to remove stitches from a knitting needle in a way that does not cause them to become loose <vi>When I finish this row, can you show me how to <it>cast off</it>?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to place stitches on a knitting needle <vi>I was having trouble <it>casting on</it>, but I think I have it now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cast out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cast (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force (someone or something) to go away <vi>He was <it>cast out</it> of [=expelled from] the tribe.</vi> <vi>They tried to <it>cast out</it> the spirits from the haunted house.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cast pearls before swine</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pearl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your eye over</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your lot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your mind back</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast your net wide</dre> <dx>see <dxt>net</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the die is cast</dre> <dx>see <dxt>die</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cast[2]"> <art><artref id="cast.tif"/><capt>cast</capt><dim>62.6,65.3</dim></art> <hw hindex="2">cast</hw> <altpr>ˈkæst, <it>Brit</it> ˈkɑ:st</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>casts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the actors in a play, film, or television show <vi>members of the <it>cast</it> = <it>cast</it> members</vi> <vi>The show features <phrase>an all-star cast</phrase>. [=a cast that includes many famous actors]</vi> <vi>a strong <phrase>supporting cast</phrase> [=the actors other than the main stars]</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>cast of characters</phrase> is sometimes used to refer to a group of people who have important roles in a book, story, or event. <vi>The <it>cast of characters</it> includes President Johnson and his top advisers during the Vietnam War.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a hard covering that is put on an arm, leg, etc., so that a broken bone can heal <vi>She has a <it>cast</it> on her arm.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>plaster cast</cat></ca></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a container that is used to give its form or shape to something that is poured or pressed into it :<sx>mold</sx></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:an object that is made by using such a container <vi>They made a mask from a wax <it>cast</it> of her face.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:the shape or appearance of something <vi>His face had a rugged <it>cast</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a slight bit of color <vi>old photographs with a reddish <it>cast</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a characteristic of a person or thing :a distinctive quality <vi>She has a skeptical <phrase>cast of mind</phrase>. [=she tends to be skeptical]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of throwing a fishing line into water with a pole</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cast iron"> <hw>cast iron</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a very hard type of metal that is made into different shapes by being melted and poured into special containers (called casts or molds) <vi>The fence is made of <it>cast iron</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cast-iron"> <hw>cast–iron</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:made of cast iron <vi>a <it>cast-iron</it> stove</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:very strong or tough <vi>I have a <it>cast-iron</it> stomach. [=I can eat anything spicy, hot, etc.]</vi> <vi>a <it>cast-iron</it> will</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:not likely to fail or be broken <vi>You had better have a <it>cast-iron</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>airtight</it>] excuse for missing the meeting.</vi> <vi>a <it>cast-iron</it> promise</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cast-off"> <hw>cast–off</hw> <sound><wav>cast_o01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkæstˌɑ:f, <it>Brit</it> ˈkɑ:stˌɒf</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:thrown or given away <vi>She had to wear her sister's <it>cast-off</it> clothes.</vi> <vi><it>cast-off</it> players</vi> <dx>see also <tag>cast off</tag> 1 at <dxt>cast</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="plaster cast"> <hw>plaster cast</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ casts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>cast <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <vi>She had a <it>plaster cast</it> on her leg.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a copy of something made of plaster of paris <vi>The mask was made from a <it>plaster cast</it> of his face.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="aspersions"> <hw>as*per*sions</hw> <sound><wav>asper01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>əˈspɚʒənz</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>cast aspersions</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to say critical things about (someone or someone's character) :to criticize (someone) harshly or unfairly <vi>He tried to discuss his political opponents respectfully, without <it>casting aspersions</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>He tried to avoid <it>casting aspersions on</it> (the motives/integrity of) his political opponents.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="caution[1]"> <hw hindex="1">cau*tion</hw> <sound><wav>cautio01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:ʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cau*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:care taken to avoid danger or risk :a careful attitude or way of behaving <vi>You should use <it>caution</it> when operating the electric saw.</vi> <vi>He injected a note/word of <it>caution</it> in his talk.</vi> <vi>Her financial adviser urged <it>caution</it> before investing in the project.</vi> <vi>Investors should exercise <it>caution</it>.</vi> <vi>The roads are slippery: drive with extreme <it>caution</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a warning telling someone to be careful <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Her comments were intended as a <it>caution</it> to us to protect our property.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>A <phrase>note/word of caution</phrase>: be sure that the electricity is off before you install the ceiling fan.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:a spoken official warning given to someone who has done something illegal but has not committed a serious crime <vi>She was given a <it>caution</it> by the magistrate.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>throw/fling/cast caution to the wind</dre> <def><dt>:to stop being careful and do something that is dangerous or that might result in failure <vi>After thinking about it for years, he finally <it>threw/flung/cast caution to the wind</it>, quit his job, and started his own company.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cloud[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cloud</hw> <sound><wav>cloud001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklaʊd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clouds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a white or gray mass in the sky that is made of many very small drops of water <vi>The sun is shining and there's not a <it>cloud</it> in the sky.</vi> <vi>a rain <it>cloud</it></vi> <vi>flying high above the <it>clouds</it></vi> <vi>It stopped raining and the sun poked through the <it>clouds</it>.</vi> <vi>Thick <phrase>cloud cover</phrase> [=a large number of clouds in the sky] hid the moon.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mushroom cloud</dxt> <dxt>storm cloud</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a large amount of smoke, dust, etc., that hangs in the air <vi>a <it>cloud</it> of cigarette smoke</vi> <vi><it>clouds</it> of steam/gas</vi> <vi>dust <it>clouds</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a large number of things (such as insects) that move together through the air in a group <vi>a <it>cloud</it> [=<it>swarm</it>] of bees</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a feeling or belief that a person or organization has done something wrong <vi>The company remains <phrase>under a cloud of suspicion</phrase>. [=people believe the company did something wrong]</vi> <vi>The team has been <phrase>under a cloud</phrase> since its members were caught cheating.</vi> <vi>There's <phrase>a cloud of controversy/uncertainty/doubt</phrase> hanging over the election.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cast a (dark) cloud</dre> <def><dt>:to cause people to stop trusting something <vi>The scandal <it>cast a cloud</it> over his presidency. [=people thought the President did something wrong]</vi> <vi>Several problems have <it>cast a cloud</it> on the program's future.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cloud on the horizon</dre> <def><dt>:a problem that could appear in the future <vi>The only <it>cloud on the horizon</it> for the team is the age of its key players.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>every cloud has a silver lining</dre> <dx>see <dxt>silver lining</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the clouds</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you are <it>in the clouds</it> or you <phrase>have your head in the clouds</phrase>, you spend too much time thinking about love or about ideas that are not practical. <vi>Since he met Sara, he's been walking around <it>with his head in the clouds</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on cloud nine</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very happy <vi>He's been <it>on cloud nine</it> ever since she agreed to marry him.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cold[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cold</hw> <sound><wav>cold0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoʊld</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>cold*er</if></in> <in><if>cold*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a very low temperature <vi>The water was too <it>cold</it> for swimming.</vi> <vi>The weather has been unusually <it>cold</it> this spring.</vi> <vi>a country with a <it>cold</it> climate</vi> <vi>It was a long, <it>cold</it> winter.</vi> <vi>It's <it>cold</it> outside, but the wind makes it feel even <it>colder</it>.</vi> <vi>It's bitterly/freezing <it>cold</it> out there!</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it>, rainy day</vi> <vi>metal that is <it>cold</it> to the touch</vi> <vi>Her hands were icy <it>cold</it>. = They were as <it>cold</it> as ice.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a feeling of low body heat <vi>Are you <it>cold</it>? I could turn up the temperature if you'd like.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:not heated <vi>a bowl of <it>cold</it> cereal</vi> <vi>He ate <it>cold</it> pizza for breakfast.</vi> <vi>We were happy to eat a hot meal rather than <it>cold</it> sandwiches.</vi> <vi><it>cold</it> meats</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of drinks</ssl> <dt>:served at a very low temperature or with ice <vi>They're serving coffee, tea, and <it>cold</it> drinks.</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it> glass of milk</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it> beer</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:not appealing or pleasant :causing a cold or unhappy feeling <vi>the <it>cold</it> gray sky</vi> <vi>the harsh <it>cold</it> lights of the hospital</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:not friendly or emotional :lacking emotional warmth <vi>Why is he so <it>cold</it> and distant toward me?</vi> <vi>She gave me a <it>cold</it> stare and turned away.</vi> <vi>I got a <it>cold</it> reception when I came home.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:not changed or affected by personal feelings or emotions <vi>Like them or not, these are the <it>cold</it> facts!</vi> <vi>It's time they took a <it>cold</it>, hard look at the situation.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:learned or memorized exactly <un>used with <it>have</it> <vi>Keep repeating the lines until you <it>have</it> them (down) <it>cold</it>. [=until you have memorized them perfectly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:unconscious or sleeping very deeply <vi>He passed out <it>cold</it>.</vi> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>out cold</phrase> <vi>She was <it>out cold</it> by eight o'clock.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>knock cold</tag> at <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:not fresh or strong :no longer easy to follow <vi>The dogs picked up a <it>cold</it> scent.</vi> <vi>The police had been hot on the trail of the escaped prisoners, but then the trail went <it>cold</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:not close to finding something or solving a puzzle <un>used especially in children's games <vi>You're getting warmer! You're getting hot! Oh, now you're getting <it>colder</it>!</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:not having success or good luck <vi>The team was hot in the first half, but their shooting turned <it>cold</it> in the second half. [=they missed a lot of shots in the second half]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blow hot and cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast a cold eye on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in cold blood</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the cold light of day</dre> <def><dt>:in the day when things can be seen clearly rather than at night <vi>The house that had looked so sinister at night seemed much less frightening <it>in the cold light of day</it>.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She forced me to look at myself <it>in the cold light of day</it>, and I didn't like what I saw.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave you cold</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <it>leaves you cold</it> does not interest or excite you. <vi>His movies <it>leave me cold</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood run cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pour/throw cold water on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>cold*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>“Your application has been denied,” he said <it>coldly</it>.</vi> <vi>She looked at me <it>coldly</it> and turned away.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>cold*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the icy <it>coldness</it> of winter</vi> <vi>Why does he treat me with such <it>coldness</it> and reserve?</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
