<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cause[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cause</hw> <sound><wav>cause001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:z</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>caus*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something or someone that produces an effect, result, or condition :something or someone that makes something happen or exist <vi>His symptoms had no apparent physical <it>causes</it>.</vi> <vi>She is the <it>cause</it> of all their problems.</vi> <vi>He died of/from <phrase>natural causes</phrase>. [=he died because of old age or an illness]</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The doctor determined the <it>cause of</it> death.</vi> <vi>The exact <it>cause of</it> the accident/fire is not known.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a reason for doing or feeling something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The medicine was prescribed without good <it>cause</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>There is some <it>cause for</it> concern. [=some reason to be concerned/worried]</vi></un> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>Their marriage was a <it>cause for</it> celebration.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>probable cause</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something (such as an organization, belief, idea, or goal) that a group or people support or fight for <vi>I can support a <it>cause</it> that means something to me.</vi> <vi>I'm willing to donate money as long as it's for a good/worthy <it>cause</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>lost cause</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is certain to fail <vi>She decided her acting career was a <it>lost cause</it>.</vi> <vi>I'm a <it>lost cause</it> when it comes to anything technical.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make/find common cause</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to join together with someone in order to achieve a shared goal <vi>He has <it>made common cause</it> with political rivals to defeat the proposed new law.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cause[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">cause</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:z</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>causes</if></in> <in><if>caused</if></in> <in><if>caus*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make (something) happen or exist :to be the cause of (something) <vi>He swerved and <it>caused</it> an accident.</vi> <vi>The flood <it>caused</it> great hardship.</vi> <vi>The illness is <it>caused</it> by a virus.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) feel, have, or do something <vi>The flood <it>caused</it> the town great hardship.</vi> <vi>You <it>caused</it> us a lot of extra work.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>His boss <it>caused</it> him <it>to resign</it>. [=his boss made him resign]</vi> <vi>His nervous behavior <it>caused</it> me <it>to question</it> his innocence.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cause celebre"> <hw>cause cé*lè*bre</hw> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>cause ce*le*bre</va> <sound><wav>cause_01.wav</wav><wav>cause_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkɑ:zsəˈlɛbrə</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>causes cé*lè*bres</if> <sound><wav>cause_01.wav</wav></sound> <il>also</il> <if>causes ce*le*bres</if> <sound><wav>cause_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkɑz:səˈlɛbrə</pr></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:a legal case or an event that a lot of people become interested in <un>usually singular <vi>The case became a <it>cause célèbre</it> for/among environmentalists.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="'cause"> <hw>'cause</hw> <sound><wav>cause004.wav</wav><wav>cause001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:z, kəz</pr> <fl>conjunction</fl> <def><dt>:<sx>because</sx> <un>used in informal speech <vi>“Why did he do that?” “<it>'Cause</it> I told him to.”</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="probable cause"> <hw>probable cause</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>law</sl> <dt>:evidence that gives someone a reason to think that a crime has been or is being committed <vi>The lawyer argued that there was a lack of <it>probable cause</it> for a search warrant.</vi> <vi>The police had <it>probable cause</it> to arrest him.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="find[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">find</hw> <sound><wav>find0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfaɪnd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>finds</if></in> <in><if>found</if> <sound><wav>found001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfaʊnd</pr></in> <in><if>find*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to discover (something or someone) without planning or trying to :to discover (something or someone) by chance <vi>He <it>found</it> a dollar on the ground.</vi> <vi>The well diggers <it>found</it> a number of Native American artifacts.</vi> <vi>She <it>finds</it> [=<it>meets</it>] interesting people wherever she goes.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote>Something or someone that <phrase>is found</phrase> in a specified place exists there or lives there. <vi>Many artifacts can <it>be found</it> in this area. [=there are many artifacts in this area]</vi> <vi>Polar bears <it>are found</it> in the Northern Hemisphere.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to get or discover (something or someone that you are looking for) <vi>After an hour of searching, I finally <it>found</it> my glasses.</vi> <vi><it>find</it> a missing person</vi> <vi>We need to <it>find</it> a suitable person for the job.</vi> <vi>I <it>found</it> a job for him. = I <it>found</it> him a job.</vi> <vi>My glasses are <phrase>nowhere to be found</phrase>. = I can't <it>find</it> my glasses.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to discover or learn (something) by studying about it <vi>She <it>found</it> the answer at last.</vi> <vi>They claim to have <it>found</it> a more efficient way to run the business.</vi> <vi>researchers trying to <it>find</it> a cure for cancer</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get (something needed or wanted) by effort <vi>You must <it>find</it> time to do it.</vi> <vi>I <it>found</it> a way to pay for college without taking out any loans.</vi> <vi>She <it>found</it> the courage to address the crowd.</vi> <vi>I hope you can <phrase>find it in your heart</phrase> to forgive me. = I hope you can <phrase>find it in yourself</phrase> to forgive me. [=I hope you can forgive me]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to regard (someone or something you have met, seen, experienced, etc.) in a specified way <vi>I <it>found</it> him (to be) a very sensible man. = I <it>found</it> him very sensible.</vi> <vi>Students often <it>find</it> this book (to be) useful.</vi> <vi>I <it>find</it> it hard to concentrate [=it is hard for me to concentrate] with that music playing.</vi> <vi>The travel arrangements were <phrase>found wanting</phrase>. [=the travel arrangements were criticized]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be affected by (something) in a specified way <vi>He <it>finds</it> laughing/laughter painful. = He <it>finds</it> it painful to laugh.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to feel (a pleasing emotion) <vi>He <it>finds</it> pleasure in her company.</vi> <vi>They didn't win, but the team <it>found</it> some satisfaction in having played so well.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to discover (someone) in a specified state <vi>He <it>found</it> them waiting for him.</vi> <vi>I <it>found</it> her relaxing by the pool.</vi> <vi>He was <it>found</it> dead the next morning.</vi> <vi>The crisis <it>found</it> them unprepared. [=they were unprepared when the crisis occurred]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become aware that you are doing something or that you are in a particular place or situation <vi>I often <it>find</it> myself thinking about her.</vi> <vi>When he awoke, he <it>found</it> himself in an unfamiliar room. [=he saw that he was in an unfamiliar room]</vi> <vi>I <it>found</it> myself agreeing with him. [=I found that I agreed with him]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to begin to have (something) <vi>The new product <it>found</it> few buyers. [=few people bought it]</vi> <vi>It took a while before his unusual brand of comedy <it>found</it> an audience.</vi> <vi>These ideas have <phrase>found approval/favor</phrase> [=been accepted; become well-liked] among many young people.</vi> <vi>His doctrines <phrase>found acceptance</phrase> [=were accepted] among scholars.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a decision about the guilt or innocence of (someone) <vi>The jury <it>found</it> her guilty.</vi> <vi>She was <it>found</it> innocent.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to decide the result of a court case <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The jury <it>found</it> a verdict of guilty.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The jury <it>found</it> for the defendant. [=the jury's decision was in favor of the defendant]</vi> <vi>The jury <it>found</it> against her.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>find common cause</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cause</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>find fault</dre> <def><dt>:to criticize someone or something <vi>No matter what she did, her husband was always <it>finding fault</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>Her husband <it>found fault with</it> everything she did.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>faultfinder</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find its mark/target</dre> <def><dt>:to hit a target that was aimed for <vi>The bullet <it>found its mark</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Her angry reaction showed that his criticisms had <it>found their mark</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>find out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to learn (something) by making an effort <vi>I'd like to <it>find out</it> more about the school's psychology program.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>find out</it> where the meeting is being held.</vi> <vi>I don't know when the game starts, but I'll <it>find out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>find out about (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become aware of (something) <vi>Her mother <it>found out about</it> her smoking habit.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>find (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to learn the unpleasant truth about (someone) <vi>He pretended to be a respectable citizen, but we <it>found</it> him <it>out</it> at last.</vi> <vi>Luckily, he was <it>found out</it> before he could do any harm.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>find yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to learn what you truly value and want in life <vi>He left school and traveled to Europe, saying that he wanted to <it>find himself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find your voice</dre> <def><dt>:to begin speaking or expressing your thoughts :to be able to speak or to express yourself as a writer <vi>I couldn't speak for a moment, but then I <it>found my voice</it>.</vi> <vi>a young novelist who has <it>found her voice</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>find your way</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to look for and find where you need to go in order to get somewhere <vi>I <it>found my way</it> home without any problems.</vi> <vi>She got lost trying to <it>find her way</it> back to the hotel.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>He's still <it>finding his way</it> as an actor. [=he's still learning what he needs to do to succeed as an actor]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or arrive somewhere by chance or after a time of wandering <vi>The settlers eventually <it>found their way</it> to California.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="make[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">make</hw> <sound><wav>make0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>makes</if></in> <in><if>made</if> <sound><wav>made0001.wav</wav><wav>make0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeɪd</pr></in> <in><if>mak*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to build, create, or produce (something) by work or effort <vi><it>make</it> a box/chair/suit</vi> <vi><it>make</it> someone a dress = <it>make</it> a dress for someone</vi> <vi>He works in a factory that <it>makes</it> jet engines.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> the curtains herself.</vi> <vi>He collected wood to <it>make</it> a fire.</vi> <vi>She used cheese and a mixture of other ingredients to <it>make</it> a delicious sauce.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>with</it> to describe the things that are used to produce something <vi>She <it>made</it> the sauce <it>with</it> cheese and other ingredients.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>of</it> to describe the material that forms something <vi>The box is <it>made of</it> wood. [=it is a wood/wooden box; the material used to produce the box was wood]</vi> <vi>The topping is <it>made</it> entirely <it>of</it> cheese. [=the topping consists entirely of cheese]</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>from</it> to describe the source of a product <vi>Cheese is <it>made from</it> milk.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to use (something) to create a product <un>+ <it>into</it> <vi>She <it>made</it> the material <it>into</it> a dress.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a mixture of ingredients <it>into</it> a delicious sauce.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to exist, happen, or appear <vi>Someone was <it>making</it> a disturbance.</vi> <vi>The car's engine has been <it>making</it> a strange noise lately.</vi> <vi>The rock <it>made</it> a dent in the car's fender.</vi> <vi>I'm not trying to <it>make</it> trouble.</vi> <vi>The typist <it>made</it> a mistake.</vi> <vi>I called the doctor's office to <it>make</it> an appointment.</vi> <vi>They moved over and <it>made</it> room for her.</vi> <vi>I want to <it>make</it> a good home for my children.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to create or write (something) in an official or legal way <vi>The government should <it>make</it> laws to protect poor people.</vi> <vi>I don't <it>make</it> the rules; I just follow them.</vi> <vi>You should <it>make</it> a will.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce, direct, or act in (something, such as a movie) <vi>a director who has <it>made</it> some classic films</vi> <vi>That actor has <it>made</it> many films.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to be changed in a specified way <vi>They adapted a Russian play and <it>made</it> the setting Dublin rather than Moscow.</vi> <vi>We originally planned on a one-week vacation, but we decided to <it>make</it> it two weeks instead.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>made</it> him a cynic. = The experience <it>made</it> a cynic (out) of him. = The experience <it>made</it> [=<it>changed, turned</it>] him into a cynic.</vi> <vi>I'd like a hamburger. No, wait—<it>make</it> that a cheeseburger.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something or someone) to have a specified quality, feeling, etc. <vi>A good teacher <it>makes</it> learning enjoyable.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> what she wanted clear to us. = She <it>made</it> (it) clear to us what she wanted. [=she said or showed clearly what she wanted]</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> it understood/known that he expected us to help.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>made</it> him cynical.</vi> <vi>Working in the garden <it>makes</it> me very tired.</vi> <vi>It <it>makes</it> me sad to think that the summer is ending.</vi> <vi>The photograph <it>makes</it> me seem/look fat.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>make yourself useful</phrase> means to do something useful. <vi>Why don't you <it>make yourself useful</it> by washing the dishes?</vi></snote> <snote>To <phrase>make yourself heard/understood (etc.)</phrase> means to do what is necessary to be sure that people hear you, understand you, etc. <vi>The music was so loud that she could hardly <it>make herself heard</it>.</vi> <vi>She doesn't speak French well, but she can <it>make herself understood</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to be or become something <vi>A good teacher <it>makes</it> learning a pleasure. = A good teacher <it>makes</it> it a pleasure to learn.</vi> <vi>Yes, you can leave work early today, but don't <it>make</it> it a habit.</vi> <vi>The bright paint really <it>makes</it> the room come alive!</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to do something <vi>He yelled at her and <it>made</it> her cry.</vi> <vi>How can I <it>make</it> you understand that I love you?!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to force (someone) to do something <vi>We have to find a way to <it>make</it> them work faster.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> me wait for an hour.</vi> <vi>If he doesn't want to do it, we can't <it>make</it> him (do it).</vi> <vi>They used threats to <it>make</it> her do it. = She was <it>made</it> to do it by the use of threats.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give a particular job, title, status, etc., to (someone) <vi>They <it>made</it> him (the) Emperor.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> her a member of their club. = She was <it>made</it> a member of their club.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to perform (a particular action) <vi>He <it>made</it> a bow. [=he bowed]</vi> <vi>We <it>made</it> [=<it>took</it>] a detour to avoid traffic.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> [=<it>got</it>] an early start. [=they started early]</vi> <vi>I have to <it>make</it> a (telephone) call to my boss. [=I have to call/telephone my boss]</vi> <vi>May I <it>make</it> a suggestion? [=may I suggest something?]</vi> <vi>“<it>Make</it> love, not war!” shouted the demonstrators.</vi> <vi>I'm not used to <it>making</it> [=<it>giving</it>] speeches.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> a bet [=they bet] that she would win.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> any sudden movements.</vi> <vi>They <it>made</it> a contribution. [=they contributed]</vi> <vi>We should <it>make</it> a distinction between them.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a promise to him. = She <it>made</it> him a promise.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> note of her address.</vi> <vi>Time is running out. You'll have to <it>make</it> a decision soon.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to form (a plan) in your mind <vi>Have you <it>made</it> any plans for your vacation?</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrange the blankets and sheets on (a bed) so that the mattress is covered <vi>She always <it>makes</it> the bed after she gets up in the morning.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to prepare (food or drink) <vi>Let me <it>make</it> dinner for you. = Let me <it>make</it> you dinner.</vi> <vi>Can I <it>make</it> you a drink?</vi> <vi>I'll <it>make</it> the pasta if you <it>make</it> the salad.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> a cake for her daughter's birthday.</vi></dt> <sn>14 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to indicate a total <vi>That <it>makes</it> the third time you've said the same thing!</vi> <vi>I've lost again! That <it>makes</it> $3 I owe you.</vi> <vi>“I'm hungry.” “<phrase>That makes two of us</phrase>.” [=I'm hungry too]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be equal to (an amount) <vi>Three plus two <it>make/makes</it> [=<it>equals, totals</it>] five.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to calculate (an amount, total, etc.) <vi>“What do you <it>make</it> the time?” [=what do you think the time is?] “(I <it>make</it> it) About half past three.”</vi> <vi>I <it>make</it> the distance back to camp about four miles. = I <it>make</it> it about four miles back to camp.</vi></dt> <sn>15 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be used to produce (something) <vi>Rags <it>make</it> the best paper.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to be suited for use as (something) <vi>This new building would <it>make</it> [=<it>be</it>] a fine school.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to be or become (something) <vi>She and her boyfriend <it>make</it> [=<it>are</it>] a lovely couple.</vi> <vi>She will <it>make</it> a fine judge one day.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> [=<it>was</it>] a loving wife to him. = She <it>made</it> him a loving wife.</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to arrive at (a place) <vi>The ship <it>made</it> port today.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to earn or gain (money, a profit, etc.) <vi>He <it>makes</it> $50,000 a year.</vi> <vi>She <it>makes</it> a good salary.</vi> <vi>Their products are so inexpensive I don't know how they <it>make</it> a profit.</vi> <vi>She <it>made</it> $100 on the deal. = The deal <it>made</it> $100 for her. = The deal <it>made</it> her $100.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>makes a/his living</phrase> by doing small jobs.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made a/his fortune in</phrase> the stock market.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be accepted as a member of (a group, team, etc.) <vi>She's finally <it>made</it> the team.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to appear on or in (a newspaper, a headline, etc.) <vi>The story of his accident <it>made</it> the front page of the paper.</vi> <vi>The story <it>made</it> headlines all across the country.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to be promoted to (a level or rank) <vi>My uncle is in the army. He <it>made</it> major last year.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to succeed in doing (something that you attempt) <vi>I missed the first foul shot but <it>made</it> the second one.</vi> <vi>He has to <it>make</it> this putt to win the tournament.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce (a particular score) <vi>She <it>made</it> a 6 on the second hole.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> a birdie/bogey.</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not be too late for (something) <vi>They (just/barely) <it>made</it> the deadline.</vi> <vi>We got to the station just in time to <it>make</it> the train.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reach or go to (a place) <vi>We <it>made</it> [=<it>reached</it>] Atlanta in just under two hours.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to succeed in reaching or going to (something) <vi>The team <it>made</it> [=qualified for] the play-offs last year.</vi> <vi>I don't know if I'll be able to <it>make</it> that meeting.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to act in a way that causes someone to be your friend, enemy, etc. <vi>She <it>makes</it> friends easily.</vi> <vi>He <it>made</it> a few enemies when he worked here.</vi></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause the success of (someone or something) <vi>This film could <phrase>make or break</phrase> her career. [=the success or failure of her career could depend on the success or failure of this film]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>make-or-break</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to be enjoyable, attractive, etc. <vi>The bright paint really <it>makes</it> the room!</vi> <vi>Meeting the star of the show really <phrase>made our day</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>old-fashioned + literary</ssl> <dt>:to seem to begin an action <vi>She <it>made</it> to go. = She <it>made</it> as if to go. [=she moved in a way that suggested she was going]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>make a face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make away with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>make away with (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>literary</ssl> <dt>:to steal and take away (something) <vi>Someone had <it>made away with</it> [=<it>made off with</it>] all the money.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make believe</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make do</dre> <def><dt>:to proceed or do what you can with the things that you have even though you do not have what you want <vi>They didn't have much money but they somehow managed to <it>make do</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>If we can't get what we want, we'll just have to <it>make do with</it> what we've got.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>without</it> <vi>If we don't have carrots for the soup, we'll just have to <it>make do without</it> them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>make for (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go toward (a place) quickly <vi>Everyone <it>made for</it> [=<it>headed for</it>] the exit as soon as the show was over.</vi> <vi>After he left the office he <it>made</it> straight <it>for</it> home.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause (something) to happen or to be more likely <vi>Courtesy <it>makes for</it> safer driving.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make friends</dre> <dx>see <dxt>friend</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make it</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to reach a particular place, goal, etc. <vi>The ship <it>made it</it> to port.</vi> <vi>You'll never <it>make it</it> that far.</vi> <vi>The climbers finally <it>made it</it> to the top of the mountain.</vi> <vi>Welcome to the party. I'm glad you could <it>make it</it>! = Welcome! I'm glad you could <it>make it</it> to the party!</vi> <vi>The story <it>made it</it> to the front page. [=the story appeared on the front page]</vi> <vi>She's finally <it>made it</it> onto the team. [=she finally was accepted on the team]</vi> <vi>If we hurry, we can still <it>make it</it> home before dark.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to not fail, die, etc. :<sx>survive</sx> <vi>Many new businesses don't <it>make it</it> through their first year.</vi> <vi>He's very sick. The doctor doesn't think he's going to <it>make it</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to become successful <vi>It's tough to succeed in this business, but if you work hard I know you'll <it>make it</it> eventually.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>made it big</phrase> [=became very successful] in real estate.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have sex <vi>His girlfriend caught him <it>making it</it> with another girl.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make like</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to pretend to be (someone or something) <vi>He <it>made like</it> a rooster and strutted across the stage.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to act in a way that does not show your true feelings <vi>He <it>made like</it> [=<it>acted like</it>] he didn't care.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make love</dre> <dx>see <dxt>love</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make merry</dre> <dx>see <dxt>merry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make much of</dre> <def><dt>:to treat (something) as very important <vi>In talking about his past, the book <it>makes much of</it> the influence of his brother. [=the book says that his brother's influence was very important]</vi> <vi>She tends to <it>make</it> far too <it>much of</it> her problems.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't <it>make</it> too <it>much of</it> what he said—he was only joking.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make nice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) of (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have or form an opinion about (something or someone) <vi>What do you <it>make of</it> this? [=what is your opinion about this?]</vi> <vi>I can't <it>make</it> anything <it>of</it> it at all.</vi> <vi>I don't know what to <it>make of</it> her behavior. [=I don't understand her behavior]</vi> <vi>He's a strange guy. I don't know quite what to <it>make of</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (a day, night, etc.) of it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue with an enjoyable activity during all of (a day, night, etc.) <vi>Since we're going out to dinner anyway, let's <it>make an evening of it</it> and go to a movie afterward.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make something of (yourself or your life)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to become successful <vi>She has worked very hard to <it>make something of herself</it>.</vi> <vi>He wants to <it>make something of his life</it>. [=to have a successful and productive life]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make something of it</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to treat something as a reason for arguing or being angry <un>used in speech as an angry way of telling someone that you are prepared to fight or argue about something <vi>Yes, I got home late last night. Do you want to <it>make something of it</it>? [=do you want to argue/fight about it?]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>make much of <dxn>(above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to leave quickly especially in order to escape <vi>After taking the money, the thieves <it>made off</it> toward the main highway.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take or steal (something) and go away <vi>Someone broke into the office and <it>made off with</it> some valuable equipment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to write down the required information on (something, such as a check) <vi>He <it>made out</it> a check for $100 to cover the cost of the repairs.</vi> <vi><it>make out</it> [=<it>fill out</it>] a form</vi> <vi>The doctor will <it>make out</it> a prescription for you. = The doctor will <it>make</it> you <it>out</it> a prescription.</vi> <vi>She <it>made out</it> a shopping list before going to the grocery store.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to see and identify (something) <vi>We could just <it>make out</it> a ship approaching through the fog.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to hear and understand (something) <vi>I couldn't quite <it>make out</it> what she said.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to learn or understand (something) by studying, searching, etc. <vi>I can't quite <it>make out</it> [=<it>tell</it>] whether he's drunk or sober.</vi> <vi>We're still trying to <it>make out</it> [=<it>find out, figure out</it>] what really happened.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (someone) out</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to understand the behavior of (someone) <un>used in negative statements <vi>I just <it>can't make</it> him <it>out</it> [=figure him out]—he's so contradictory.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (someone or something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to describe (someone or something) in a specified and usually false way <vi>The book <it>makes</it> them <it>out</it> to be criminals.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>make</it> them <it>out</it> as worse than they are.</vi> <vi>He's not as bad as he's <it>made out</it> (to be). = He's not as bad as people <it>make</it> him <it>out</it> (to be).</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to ask about or describe the success or progress of someone or something <vi>“How are you <it>making out</it> [=<it>doing, getting along</it>] in your new job?” “Just fine, thank you!”</vi> <vi>“How did the team <it>make out</it> yesterday?” “They won.”</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) He <phrase>made out like a bandit</phrase> [=he made a lot of money] when he sold the company.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to kiss and touch for a long time in a sexual way <vi>She was <it>making out</it> [=(<it>old-fashioned</it>) <it>necking</it>] with her boyfriend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something or someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make over (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to change the appearance of (something or someone) <vi>We <it>made</it> the whole house <it>over</it> so it looked more modern.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>makeover</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make over (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (property) to another person in an official or legal way <vi>He <it>made</it> the ranch/shares <it>over</it> to his eldest son.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to create or invent (a story, a lie, etc.) <vi>He entertained the children by <it>making up</it> a funny story about a cat that lived on a sailboat.</vi> <vi>He <it>made up</it> some excuse about having problems with his car, but no one believed him.</vi> <vi>It never happened: you <it>made</it> it all <it>up</it>!</vi> <vi>He didn't have a prepared speech. He just <it>made</it> it <it>up</it> as he went along.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>made-up</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to combine to produce (something) <vi>Ten chapters <it>make up</it> this volume. = This volume is <it>made up</it> [=<it>composed</it>] of 10 chapters.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce or create (something) by putting together different parts <vi>They're going to <it>make up</it> a list of requirements for us. = They're going to <it>make</it> us <it>up</it> a list of requirements.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to prepare (something) so that it is ready to be used <vi>I'll <it>make up</it> a bed for you. = I'll <it>make</it> you <it>up</it> a bed. [=I'll prepare a bed for you to sleep in]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to supply (something) according to directions <vi><it>make up</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>fill</it>] a prescription</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>make (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to provide an amount of time, money, etc., that is needed <vi>The total cost of the repairs is $200. If you can pay half of that, I'll <it>make up</it> the rest.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>make up</it> the difference.</vi> <vi>I have to leave work early today, but I'll <phrase>make up the time</phrase> by working late tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>make (someone or something) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to put makeup on (someone or someone's face) <vi>She <it>made</it> herself <it>up</it> for the party.</vi> <vi>Her face was heavily <it>made up</it>. [=there was a lot of makeup on her face]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>made-up</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change the appearance of (someone or something) by using costumes, decorations, etc. <vi>The actor was <it>made up</it> to look like George Washington.</vi> <vi>The room was <it>made up</it> to look like a disco.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become friendly again after being angry <vi>They quarreled but later <it>made up</it> (with each other).</vi> <vi>He <it>made up</it> with his girlfriend.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) She's trying to <phrase>make it up</phrase> with him.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do or have something as a way of correcting or improving (something else) <vi>He wanted to <it>make up for</it> [=<it>atone for</it>] neglecting his children by spending more time with them.</vi> <vi>She tried to <it>make up for</it> lost time by working extra hard.</vi> <vi>What the movie lacks in plot it <it>makes up for</it> in special effects.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>make up to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to treat (someone) in a very friendly or helpful way in order to get something for yourself <vi>an employee who's always <it>making up to</it> [=(<it>US, informal</it>) <it>sucking up to</it>] the boss</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>make it up to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do something helpful or good for (someone you have hurt or treated wrongly) <vi>He'd neglected his children and wanted to <it>make it up to</it> them by spending more time with them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make up your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make your way, make way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>made</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
