<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="certain[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cer*tain</hw> <sound><wav>certai01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɚtn̩</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <sgram>more cer*tain; most cer*tain</sgram> <dt>:not having any doubt about something :convinced or sure <vi>Are you <it>certain</it> [=<it>sure</it>] you want to leave today?</vi> <vi>I feel less than <it>certain</it> about it. [=I am not sure about it]</vi> <vi>She's <it>certain</it> (that) she can do the job despite her lack of experience.</vi> <vi>I'm fairly <it>certain</it> that I'll be on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used with <it>it</it> to say that something is known to be true or correct <vi>Although little is known about these ancient people, <it>it</it> is <it>certain</it> that they grew a number of crops.</vi> <vi><it>It</it>'s not <it>certain</it> [=<it>definite</it>] that the company will lay off workers. [=the company may lay off workers, but it also may not]</vi> <vi><it>It</it> seems <it>certain</it> that the jury will convict him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something will definitely happen or that someone will definitely do something <vi>Before the game was half over our team's defeat was nearly <it>certain</it>.</vi> <vi>Contact with the poison means <it>certain</it> death.</vi> <vi>Her victory seems <it>certain</it>.</vi></un> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>As technology develops, the rates of success with the procedure are <it>certain to improve</it>.</vi> <vi>Health-care costs are <it>certain</it> [=<it>sure</it>] <it>to increase</it> in coming years.</vi> <vi>She is almost <it>certain to win</it>.</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>all but certain</phrase> <it>to say</it> no. [=he will almost surely say no]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt><un>used to refer to something or someone that is not named specifically <vi>Each employee will receive a <it>certain</it> share of the profits.</vi> <vi>Building even a simple bookcase takes a <it>certain</it> amount of skill. [=takes some skill]</vi> <vi><it>Certain</it> people are always late for dinner.</vi> <vi>On <it>certain</it> days there is no parking on the street.</vi> <vi>The new technology has <it>certain</it> limitations.</vi> <vi>Students must fulfill <it>certain</it> requirements to graduate.</vi> <vi>She's allergic to <it>certain</it> [=<it>particular</it>] foods.</vi> <vi>The contract can be extended <phrase>under certain circumstances</phrase>. [=in some special cases]</vi> <vi><phrase>To a certain extent</phrase> [=up to a point] he's right.</vi> <vi>The movie will appeal to people <phrase>of a certain age</phrase>. [=people who are no longer young]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a certain</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to refer to a quality that is noticed but that is difficult to explain or describe <vi>She has <it>a certain</it> elegance about her.</vi> <vi>The house has <it>a certain</it> charm.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt><un>used with the name of a person you do not know <vi>In 1889, <it>a certain</it> Mr. Kelly made a large donation to the church.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for certain</dre> <def><dt>:without a doubt :definitely or certainly <vi>No one knows <it>for certain</it> what the outcome will be.</vi> <vi>We'll need more than an hour to get there <it>for certain</it>. [=<it>for sure</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make certain</dre> <def><dt>:to do something or find out something so that you have no doubt about whether something is true, correct, will happen, etc. <vi><it>Make certain</it> (that) you lock the door when you leave. = <it>Make certain</it> to lock the door when you leave.</vi> <vi>We must <it>make certain</it> [=<it>make sure</it>] this doesn't happen again.</vi> <vi>She <it>made certain</it> she thanked each of them for coming.</vi> <un>sometimes + <it>of</it> <vi><it>Make certain of</it> your flight times [=be sure that you definitely know your flight times] before you leave for the airport.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="certain[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">certain</hw> <altpr>ˈsɚtn̩</altpr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt>:certain ones :particular members of a group :<sx>some</sx> <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi><it>Certain of</it> his assumptions are simply not true.</vi> <vi>We know that <it>certain of</it> his classmates walk to school every day.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="degree"> <hw highlight="yes">de*gree</hw> <sound><wav>degree01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>dɪˈgri:</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>de*grees</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a unit for measuring temperature <vi>Bake the bread at 350 <it>degrees</it> (Fahrenheit) for 35 minutes.</vi> <vi>20 <it>degrees</it> Fahrenheit/Celsius [=20° F/C]</vi> <un>abbr. <it>deg</it>.</un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a unit for measuring the size of an angle <vi>There are 360 <it>degrees</it> in a circle.</vi> <vi>47 <it>degrees</it> latitude/longitude</vi> <vi>a 15 <it>degree</it> angle [=a 15° angle]</vi> <un>abbr. <it>deg</it>.</un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an amount or level that can be measured or compared to another amount or level <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>These trees will thrive, to a greater or lesser <it>degree</it>, in a number of climates.</vi> <vi><phrase>To what degree</phrase> [=how much] is she interested in finance?</vi> <vi>We don't yet know <phrase>the degree to which</phrase> [=how much] the roof is damaged.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>a high <it>degree of</it> difficulty/skill</vi> <vi>They have had varying <it>degrees of</it> success.</vi> <vi>We can now predict the weather with a greater <it>degree of</it> accuracy. [=with more accuracy]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a measure of how severe or serious something is <vi>He was accused of murder in the first <it>degree</it>. = He was accused of first-<it>degree</it> murder. [=the most serious kind of murder]</vi> <vi>a second-<it>degree</it> burn</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>first-degree</dxt> <dxt>second-degree</dxt> <dxt>third-degree</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an official document and title that is given to someone who has successfully completed a series of classes at a college or university <vi>She has a <it>degree</it> in engineering.</vi> <vi>a four-year <it>degree</it> [=a degree that is given to someone who has completed four years of study]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>bachelor's/master's degree</phrase></vi> <vi>She received an <phrase>honorary degree</phrase>. [=a degree given by a college or university to someone who is not a student but who has done something important]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by degrees</dre> <def><dt>:very slowly :by a series of small changes <vi>The tomatoes changed <it>by degrees</it> from green to red.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to some degree</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>to a (certain) degree</va></vr> <def><dt>:not completely but partly <vi><it>To some degree</it>, they're right.</vi> <vi>We simplified the process <it>to a certain degree</it>. [=<it>somewhat</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the nth degree</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nth</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
