<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="challenge[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chal*lenge</hw> <sound><wav>challe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃælənʤ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chal*leng*es</if></in> <in><if>chal*lenged</if></in> <in><if>chal*leng*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say or show that (something) may not be true, correct, or legal :<sx>dispute</sx> <vi>A number of doctors are <it>challenging</it> the study's claims.</vi> <vi>The new lawsuit <it>challenges</it> the lower court's decision.</vi> <vi>The new data <it>challenges</it> many old assumptions. [=the new data gives people reasons to doubt many old assumptions]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to question the action or authority of (someone) <vi>She's been <it>challenged</it> on her handling of the problem.</vi> <vi>None of them were willing to <it>challenge</it> the referee on the call.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to question whether (someone) should serve on a jury <vi><it>challenge</it> a juror</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to test the ability, skill, or strength of (someone or something) :to be difficult enough to be interesting to (someone) <vi>It's a game that will <it>challenge</it> a child's imagination.</vi> <vi>The work doesn't <it>challenge</it> him anymore, and he's often bored.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to invite (someone) to compete in a game, fight, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>I <it>challenge</it> you <it>to</it> a game of chess.</vi> <vi>The duke <it>challenged</it> him <it>to</it> a duel.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to order (someone) to stop and prove who he or she is <vi>The sentry <it>challenged</it> the stranger at the gate.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>chal*leng*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chal*leng*ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>He hopes to be the governor's <it>challenger</it> in the next election. [=the candidate running against the governor]</vi> <vi>The boxing match pitted the two-time champion against his <it>challenger</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="challenge[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">challenge</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃælənʤ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>challenges</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a difficult task or problem :something that is hard to do <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The next major <it>challenge</it> for the company is to improve its distribution capabilities.</vi> <vi>Teaching adolescents can be quite a <it>challenge</it>.</vi> <vi>The band feels ready for new <it>challenges</it>.</vi> <vi>If he takes on the new project he will face the greatest <it>challenge</it> of his career.</vi> <vi>Passing the test was hardly a <it>challenge</it> [=was very easy] for her.</vi> <vi>The coach is confident that you will <phrase>rise to the challenge</phrase>. [=the coach is confident that you will succeed]</vi> <vi>Management is seeking ways to better <phrase>meet the challenge</phrase> of future growth.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The ski slope offers a high degree of <it>challenge</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an action, statement, etc., that is against something :a refusal to accept something as true, correct, or legal <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The lawsuit is a <it>challenge to</it> the lower court's decision.</vi> <vi>Both teachers have had to deal with many <it>challenges to</it> their authority.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an invitation to compete in a game, fight, etc. <vi>Do you accept my <it>challenge</it> to a game of chess?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an attempt to defeat someone in a competition <vi>The senator may face a <it>challenge</it> from within her own party.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an order to someone to stop and say who he or she is <vi>The intruder fled at the sentry's <it>challenge</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="rise[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">rise</hw> <sound><wav>rise0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈraɪz</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>ris*es</if></in> <in><if>rose</if> <sound><wav>rise0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈroʊz</pr></in> <in><if>ris*en</if> <sound><wav>rise0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈrɪzn̩</pr></in> <in><if>ris*ing</if> <sound><wav>rise0004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈraɪzɪŋ</pr></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move upward <vi>Smoke was <it>rising</it> into the air.</vi> <vi>Bubbles <it>rose</it> to the surface of water.</vi> <vi>The airplane <it>rose</it> [=(more formally) <it>ascended</it>] into the sky.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>Smoke was <it>rising up</it> into the air.</vi> <vi>The airplane <it>rose up</it> from the runway.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>His <phrase>spirits rose</phrase> [=he began to feel happier] when he heard the good news.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become higher <vi>The tide <it>rose</it> and fell.</vi> <vi>The river is <it>rising</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to slope or extend upward <vi>The land <it>rises</it> as you move away from the coast.</vi> <vi>The road <it>rose</it> gently/steeply.</vi> <vi>a tower <it>rising</it> above the little town</vi> <vi>steeply/sharply <it>rising</it> mountain peaks</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>The mountains <it>rose up</it> before us.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to advance to a higher level or position :to become more popular, successful, etc. <vi>a politician who <it>rose</it> to fame/power/prominence very quickly</vi> <vi>Empires <it>rise</it> [=become powerful, important, etc.] and fall.</vi> <vi>The book has <it>risen</it> to the top of best-seller lists.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>rose through the ranks</phrase> of the company to become president. [=she began her career with the company with little power or authority and gradually gained more power and authority until she had become president]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>has risen in my estimation</phrase>. [=I think more highly of her; I respect/admire her more]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to increase in amount, number, level, etc. :to become more <vi>Sales have <it>risen</it> [=<it>increased</it>] in recent months.</vi> <vi>People are angry about <it>rising</it> gasoline prices.</vi> <vi>The population has been <it>rising</it> [=<it>growing</it>] dramatically/sharply/markedly.</vi> <vi>Stocks <it>rose</it> (by) several points in early trading today.</vi> <vi>The market is continuing to <it>rise</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become stronger :to increase in strength <vi>The wind <it>rose</it> in the afternoon.</vi> <vi>My anger <it>rose</it> as I thought about what she had said.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to become louder :to increase in volume <vi>The music <it>rose</it> and fell.</vi> <vi>Her voice <it>rose</it> to an angry shout.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to stand up <vi>He <it>rose</it> slowly (to his feet).</vi> <vi>She quickly <it>rose</it> from the chair and began to walk away.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get up from sleeping in a bed <vi>He <it>rose</it> refreshed after a good night's sleep.</vi> <vi><phrase>Rise and shine</phrase>! [=wake up and get out of bed]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to appear above the horizon <vi>The sun <it>rises</it> [=<it>comes up</it>] in the morning and sets at night.</vi> <vi>We watched as the moon <it>rose</it> in the eastern sky.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>set <dxn>11</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>of bread, cake, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to become bigger because of being filled with air bubbles made through a chemical process <vi>Yeast will make the dough <it>rise</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to begin to fight in order to remove a ruler or government <vi>The people <it>rose</it> in rebellion/revolt.</vi> <un>often + <it>up</it> <vi>He told the people that they should <it>rise up</it> and overthrow the corrupt government.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to live again after dying :to come back to life <vi>a belief that the dead will <phrase>rise again</phrase> [=will live again]</vi> <vi>Christians believe that Jesus Christ <phrase>rose from the dead</phrase>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>rise above</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>rise above (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not allow yourself to be hurt or controlled by (something bad or harmful) <vi>We need to <it>rise above</it> our anger/frustration and find a way to get along with each other.</vi> <vi>She <it>rose above</it> the prejudice of her time to become a great civil rights leader.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>rise above</it> petty bickering/politics.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be or become better than (something) <vi>The quality of the food never <it>rises above</it> average.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>rise to the occasion/challenge</dre> <def><dt>:to make the special effort that is required to successfully deal with a difficult situation <vi>No one was sure if he could handle the pressure of making a speech, but he <it>rose to the occasion</it> and did an excellent job.</vi> <vi>When the company needed to increase its sales, its employees <it>rose to the challenge</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your gorge rises</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gorge</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
