<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="channel[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chan*nel</hw> <sound><wav>channe01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃænl̟</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chan*nels</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a television or radio station <vi>The TV program airs at 8:00 p.m. on <it>Channel</it> 5.</vi> <vi>Change the <it>channel</it>, please.</vi> <vi>What is your favorite radio <it>channel</it>?</vi> <vi>a movie/news/sports <it>channel</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a system used for sending something (such as information or supplies) from one place or person to another <vi>E-mail is a <it>channel</it> of communication.</vi> <un>often plural <vi>To make a complaint, you will need to go through (the) official/proper <it>channels</it>.</vi> <vi>the ordinary <it>channels</it> of trade</vi> <vi>the army's distribution/supply <it>channels</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a way of expressing your ideas, feelings, etc., to other people <vi>Art provides a <it>channel</it> for creativity.</vi> <vi>Music became a <it>channel</it> for her emotions.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a path, tube, or long narrow place where water flows <vi>A system of irrigation <it>channels</it> brings water to the fields.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a deep part of a river, harbor, or other body of water where ships can go <vi>a narrow <it>channel</it> of the Mississippi River</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a narrow area of the sea between two large areas of land that are close together <vi>We took a ferryboat across the English <it>Channel</it> to France.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="channel[2]"> <hw hindex="2">channel</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃænl̟</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>channels</if></in> <in><il>US</il> <if>channeled</if> <il>or British</il> <if>channelled</if></in> <in><il>US</il> <if>channel*ing</if> <il>or British</il> <if>channel*ling</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to express (your ideas, thoughts, feelings, energy, etc.) through a particular behavior or action <vi>She's started <it>channeling</it> her anger towards me.</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>His aggression was <it>channeled into</it> playing football.</vi> <vi>Actors learn how to <it>channel</it> their own emotions <it>into</it> their characters.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to send (food, money, etc.) to someone or something <vi>He <it>channeled</it> millions of dollars into/to the program.</vi> <un>often + <it>through</it> <vi>Food, clothes, and money were <it>channeled through</it> churches to the poor people of the village.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to carry and move (something, such as water) in or through a tube, passage, etc. <vi>Their irrigation system <it>channels</it> water to the corn fields.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to allow (the spirit of a dead person) to enter your body in order to talk with living people <vi>She said that she was <it>channeling</it> my father and that he had a message for me.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="channel surfing"> <hw>channel surfing</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the activity of using a remote control to change television stations quickly as you look for something to watch <ca>called also <cat>channel-hopping</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="English Channel"> <hw>English Channel</hw> <fl>geographical name</fl> <dro><dre>the English Channel</dre> <dt>:part of the Atlantic Ocean between France and the United Kingdom</dt></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
