<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="chap"> <hw>chap</hw> <sound><wav>chap0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃæp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chaps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal + somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:a man <vi>He's a friendly sort of <it>chap</it>. [=<it>fellow</it>, <it>guy</it>]</vi> <vi>Don't worry old <it>chap</it>. It'll be all right.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>chaps</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="old[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">old</hw> <sound><wav>old00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈoʊld</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>old*er</if></in> <in><if>old*est</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:having lived for many years :not young <vi>He's an <it>old</it> man now.</vi> <vi>a little <it>old</it> lady</vi> <vi>She was helping an <it>old</it> [=(more politely) <it>elderly</it>] woman cross the street.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to talk about or ask about a person's age <vi>He looks <it>old</it> for his age. [=he looks older than he really is]</vi> <vi>She's <it>older</it> than she looks. [=she has a young appearance]</vi> <vi>He's dating an <it>older</it> woman. [=a woman who is older than he is]</vi> <vi>I wasn't <it>old</it> enough [=I was too young] to vote in the last election.</vi> <vi>“How <it>old</it> is your daughter?” “She's almost six.”</vi> <vi>Their <it>oldest</it> [=<it>eldest</it>] child is 18 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>My sister's three years <it>older</it> than me.</vi> <vi>She lived to the <phrase>ripe old age</phrase> of 85.</vi> <vi>He joked that he was <phrase>as old as the hills</phrase>. [=very old]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a specified age <vi>He's 30 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>a nine-month-<it>old</it> baby</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:having existed or been in use for a long time :not new <vi>We rented an <it>old</it> black-and-white movie.</vi> <vi><it>old</it> newspapers/magazines</vi> <vi>a beautiful <it>old</it> house</vi> <vi>There's an <it>old</it> saying that good fences make good neighbors.</vi> <vi>an <it>old</it> family tradition</vi> <vi>a new approach to an <it>old</it> problem</vi> <vi>She wore a T-shirt and an <it>old</it> pair of jeans.</vi> <vi>I wish you would stop wearing that dirty <it>old</it> hat!</vi> <vi>The hotel was <it>old</it> and dingy.</vi> <vi>the <it>oldest</it> known civilization in the region</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having existed for a specified amount of time <vi>The house we live in is 50 years <it>old</it>.</vi> <vi>a 400-year-<it>old</it> castle</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:belonging to, used by, or known by someone in the past <vi>We went back to visit our <it>old</it> neighborhood.</vi> <vi>I met one of my <it>old</it> [=<it>former</it>] professors at the library.</vi> <vi>one of his <it>old</it> cars</vi> <vi>I made a lot less money at my <it>old</it> job.</vi> <vi>That's their <it>old</it> number. The new number is 555-4397.</vi> <vi>She is now just a shadow of her <it>old</it> self. [=she is not the person she was in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has been your friend, enemy, etc., for a long time <vi>I had lunch with an <it>old</it> friend of mine. [=a friend I have known for a very long time]</vi> <vi>They're <it>old</it> enemies.</vi> <vi>Spaghetti is an <it>old</it> favorite in our home.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:done or experienced many times <vi>Do we have to go through that <it>old</it> routine again?</vi> <vi>Grandpa tells the <phrase>same old</phrase> stories over and over again.</vi> <vi>When she brought up the <it>same old</it> argument, I just stopped listening.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used for emphasis after adjectives like <it>big, good</it>, etc. <vi>We had a big <it>old</it> party in her honor.</vi> <vi>You poor <it>old</it> thing. You must be exhausted!</vi> <vi><phrase>Good old</phrase> Joe. He's always helping people in need.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>any old</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to describe someone or something that is not special or specific <vi>I don't care where I sleep. <it>Any old</it> couch will do.</vi> <vi>She won't drink <it>any old</it> tea; it has to be her favorite kind.</vi> <vi>You'll have to park <it>any old</it> way [=any way] you can.</vi> <vi>Give me beer over champagne <phrase>any old day</phrase> (of the week).</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chip off the old block</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for old times' sake</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>old boy/chap/man/etc.</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt><un>used to address a man <vi>Don't worry, <it>old chap</it>, it'll be all right.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>old boy</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>good old boy</dxt></dxnl> <syns><sc>old</sc>, <sc>ancient</sc>, <sc>antique</sc>, and <sc>archaic</sc> describe things that existed or were used in the past. <sc>old</sc> is the most common and general of these words and can refer to either the recent past or to the distant past. <vi>This is one of my <it>old</it> sweaters.</vi> <vi>The neighborhood has many <it>old</it> houses that were built more than 200 years ago.</vi> <sc>ancient</sc> refers to things that happened or existed in the very distant past and that may or may not exist today. <vi>an <it>ancient</it> custom</vi> <vi>the <it>ancient</it> pyramids of Egypt</vi> <sc>antique</sc> refers to things, such as toys, machines, and pieces of furniture, that have been kept from the past and that are often valuable. <vi>She collects <it>antique</it> furniture.</vi> <sc>archaic</sc> refers to things, such as words or ways of behaving, that belong to a much earlier time and that are no longer used. <vi>The play used <it>archaic</it> language to convey a sense of the past.</vi> <vi>an <it>archaic</it> tradition</vi></syns></entry>

</entry_list>
