<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="character"> <hw highlight="yes">char*ac*ter</hw> <sound><wav>charac02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkerɪktɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>char*ac*ters</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the way someone thinks, feels, and behaves :someone's personality <un>usually singular <vi>He rarely shows his true <it>character</it>—that of a kind and sensitive person.</vi> <vi>This is a side of her <it>character</it> that few people have seen.</vi> <vi>the different aspects/facets of her <it>character</it></vi></un> <un>often used before another noun <vi>Certain <it>character</it> traits are helpful in the teaching profession.</vi> <vi>Pride, his one <it>character</it> flaw, caused his downfall.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of qualities that are shared by many people in a group, country, etc. <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>character</it> of the American people</vi> <vi>the <it>character</it> of a nation</vi> <vi>the French/Japanese/Mexican national <it>character</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a set of qualities that make a place or thing different from other places or things <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>the wine's distinctive <it>character</it></vi> <vi>the unique <it>character</it> of the town/city/region</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The building is very simple in <it>character</it>.</vi> <snote>If something is <phrase>in character with something else</phrase>, it has the same qualities or characteristics as something else. <vi>This room is not really <it>in character with</it> the rest of the house.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the qualities or characteristics that make something interesting or special <vi>The room lacks <it>character</it>. [=there's nothing special about the room]</vi> <vi>Their house has a lot of <it>character</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who appears in a story, book, play, movie, or television show <vi>The film's main <it>characters</it> are a woman in her late 30s and her elderly neighbor.</vi> <vi>She plays the film's lead/main/central <it>character</it>.</vi> <vi>a fictional <it>character</it> [=a character in a work of fiction]</vi> <vi>a popular cartoon <it>character</it></vi> <vi>the <phrase>title character</phrase> of the book <it>Tom Sawyer</it> [=the character named Tom Sawyer]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>cast of characters</tag> at <dxt>cast</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a particular type of person <vi>He's a strange/interesting <it>character</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person who says or does funny or unusual things <vi>That husband of yours is a real <it>character</it>!</vi> <vi>She's quite a <it>character</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the good qualities of a person that usually include moral or emotional strength, honesty, and fairness <vi>She's a kind and honest person of good <it>character</it>.</vi> <vi>They believe that going to church will improve the moral <it>character</it> of their children.</vi> <vi>He is admired for his <phrase>strength of character</phrase> in stressful situations.</vi> <vi>Playing sports is seen as a way to <phrase>build character</phrase> in young people. = Playing sports is seen as <phrase>character-building</phrase> for young people.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>test of (your) character</phrase> is something that is difficult and that requires you to show that you are a good and emotionally strong person. <vi>These past few days have been a real <it>test of my character</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the usually good beliefs or opinions that most people have about a particular person <vi>They defended the <it>character</it> [=<it>reputation</it>] of their friend.</vi> <vi>an attack on his <it>character</it></vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a symbol (such as a letter or number) that is used in writing or printing <vi>the Chinese <it>character</it> for “water”</vi> <vi>The line is 30 <it>characters</it> long.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in character, out of character</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that some action or behavior is or is not like someone's usual way of behaving <vi>It was entirely <it>in character</it> for a generous person like her to give him the money.</vi> <vi>His rudeness was completely <it>out of character</it>. [=he is not usually rude]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="character actor"> <hw>character actor</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an actor who is known for playing many different and unusual characters</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="character assassination"> <hw>character assassination</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the act of saying false things about a person usually in order to make the public stop liking or trusting that person <vi>None of those rumors are true. She's been the victim of <it>character assassination</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="special character"> <hw>special character</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a symbol used in writing, typing, etc., that represents something other than a letter or number <vi>The symbol § is a <it>special character</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="characterless"> <hw>char*ac*ter*less</hw> <sound><wav>charac03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkerɪktɚləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more char*ac*ter*less; most char*ac*ter*less</gram> <dt>:not having any interesting or unusual qualities :lacking character <vi>rows of <it>characterless</it> houses</vi> <vi>Their food is bland and <it>characterless</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="test[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">test</hw> <sound><wav>test0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtɛst</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>tests</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a set of questions or problems that are designed to measure a person's knowledge, skills, or abilities <vi>She is studying for her math/spelling/history <it>test</it>.</vi> <vi>I passed/failed/flunked my biology <it>test</it>.</vi> <vi>The teacher sat at his desk grading <it>tests</it>.</vi> <vi>a driver's/driving <it>test</it> [=a test that is used to see if someone is able to safely drive a car]</vi> <vi>an IQ <it>test</it></vi> <vi><it>test</it> questions</vi> <vi>The <it>test</it> will be on [=the questions on the test will be about] the first three chapters of the book.</vi> <vi>We <phrase>took/had a test</phrase> on European capitals. = (<it>Brit</it>) We <phrase>did a test</phrase> on European capitals.</vi> <vi>The college relies on <phrase>test scores</phrase> in its admissions process.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>intelligence test</dxt> <dxt>rorschach test</dxt> <dxt>screen test</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a careful study of a part of the body or of a substance taken from the body <vi>The <it>test</it> showed/revealed a problem with your liver function.</vi> <vi>a vision/hearing <it>test</it> [=a test that shows how well you see/hear]</vi> <vi>a urine <it>test</it> [=a test that examines a person's urine for evidence of disease or illegal drugs]</vi> <vi>allergy <it>tests</it> [=tests that show what you are allergic to]</vi> <vi>All applicants must pass a <phrase>drug test</phrase>. [=a test that examines a person's blood or urine for evidence of illegal drugs]</vi> <vi>The doctor will call you with the <phrase>test results</phrase>.</vi> <vi>They went to the drug store to buy a <phrase>pregnancy test</phrase>. [=a device that reacts to a woman's urine in a way that shows whether or not she is pregnant]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>DNA test</phrase> [=a test that examines DNA and that is used to identify someone or to show that people are relatives]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>blood test</dxt> <dxt>breath test</dxt> <dxt>stress test</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a careful study of a small amount of water, soil, air, etc., in order to see if its quality is good, to find out if it contains a dangerous substance, etc. <vi>The <it>test</it> indicated high levels of lead in the soil.</vi> <vi>routine water <it>tests</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a planned and usually controlled act or series of acts that is done to learn something, to see if something works properly, etc. <vi>lab/laboratory <it>tests</it></vi> <vi>underground nuclear <it>tests</it></vi> <vi>a <it>test</it> of a new vaccine</vi> <vi><phrase>Taste tests</phrase> revealed that people prefer this brand of cola over that one.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>As participants in the sleep study, <phrase>test subjects</phrase> will be kept awake for 18 hours.</vi> <vi>The effects of the drug were clear when the <phrase>test group</phrase> was compared with the control group.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>road test</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:something (such as a difficult situation or task) that shows how strong or skilled someone or something is <vi>a <it>test</it> of will/strength/character</vi> <vi>The real/true <it>test</it> of your ability as a skier is whether you can ski well on very hard snow.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>acid test</dxt> <dxt>litmus test</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:<sx>test match</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>put (someone or something) to the test</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be in a situation that shows how strong, good, etc., that person or thing really is <vi>The team has been playing well so far, but tomorrow's game will really <it>put them to the test</it>. [=will really test them]</vi> <vi>A trip through the desert will <it>put</it> the truck <it>to the test</it>.</vi> <vi>We decided to <it>put</it> the idea/theory <it>to the test</it> [=to test the theory] with a little experiment.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stand the test of time</dre> <def><dt>:to continue to be important, respected, etc., for a long period of time <vi>Great art/literature/music can <it>stand the test of time</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>test of (your) character</dre> <dx>see <dxt>character</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>high-test</dxt> <dxt>means test</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
