<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="charge[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">charge</hw> <sound><wav>charge01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃɑɚʤ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>charg*es</if></in> <in><if>charged</if></in> <in><if>charg*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to give an amount of electricity to (something) :to put electricity into a battery so that a machine or device will run <vi>We tried to <it>charge</it> the car's battery.</vi> <vi>My cell phone needs to be <it>charged</it>. = The battery in my cell phone needs to be charged.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give a job or responsibility to (a person or group) :to make (a person or group) responsible for something <un>usually used as <it>(be) charged</it></un> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>The board <it>was charged with</it> deciding where to build a new school.</vi> <vi>the department <it>charged with</it> helping war veterans</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to formally accuse (someone) of a crime <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>They <it>charged</it> him <it>with</it> theft.</vi> <vi>She was <it>charged with</it> murder.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to say that someone has done something wrong <vi>The government <it>charged</it> that he had not paid taxes for five years.</vi> <vi>It is not clear if he violated the rules, as his critics have <it>charged</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to say that a player has broken the rules in a game <vi>The basketball player was <it>charged</it> with a foul.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to rush toward (a person, place, etc.) <vi>The bull <it>charged</it> the matador.</vi> <vi>Fans <it>charged</it> [=<it>rushed</it>] the stage but were stopped by the security guards.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to rush in a particular direction <vi>People <it>charged</it> toward the stage.</vi> <vi>She came <it>charging</it> into the room.</vi> <vi>The bull <it>charged</it> right at me.</vi> <vi>a <it>charging</it> rhinoceros</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to create a record of an amount of money that is owed <vi>The clerk <it>charged</it> the purchase to my account.</vi> <vi>The expenses were <it>charged</it> against the company's earnings.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:to ask for money in return for providing or doing something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Do you <it>charge</it> for fixing flat tires?</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>charge</it> a fee for late payment.</vi> <vi><it>charge</it> tuition</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to ask for (a specific amount of money) as a price, rate, or fee <vi>The shop <it>charged</it> $100 for repairs.</vi> <vi>The bank <it>charged</it> eight percent interest on the loan.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to ask for payment from (a customer, client, etc.) <vi>They <it>charged</it> me $500 to fix the engine.</vi> <vi>She <it>charged</it> the city thousands of dollars for her work.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="charge[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">charge</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃɑɚʤ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>charges</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an amount of electricity <vi>an electrical <it>charge</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the amount of an explosive material (such as dynamite) that is used in a single blast <vi>He set off a <it>charge</it> that destroyed the mountain.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>depth charge</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the responsibility of managing or watching over something <vi>He has <it>charge</it> of the building.</vi> <vi>He wanted to <phrase>take charge</phrase> [=<it>take control</it>] of the organization.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an amount of money that someone asks for in return for providing or doing something :the price charged for something <vi>There is no <it>charge</it> for fixing the tire.</vi> <vi>a delivery <it>charge</it> for the refrigerator</vi> <vi>a monthly <it>charge</it></vi> <vi>an admission <it>charge</it> at the fair</vi> <vi>The concert at the school is <phrase>free of charge</phrase>. [=costs nothing to attend]</vi> <vi>A second member of your family can join <phrase>at no charge</phrase>. [=without paying]</vi> <synref>price</synref></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:a formal accusation that someone committed a crime <vi>a <it>charge</it> of burglary</vi> <vi>They dropped the <it>charges</it> against him.</vi> <vi>She pleaded guilty to a lesser <it>charge</it>.</vi> <vi>He decided not to <phrase>bring/press charges</phrase>. [=to formally accuse someone of a crime]</vi> <vi>Will she <phrase>face charges</phrase>? [=will she be charged?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a statement that criticizes someone or says that someone has done something wrong :an accusation or criticism <vi>The senator rejects <it>charges</it> that he is too liberal.</vi> <vi>She responded to the <it>charges</it> of plagiarism.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:a person (such as a child) that another person must guard or take care of <vi>She loved to play with her young <it>charges</it> at the day-care center.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a judge's instructions to a jury before it begins deciding a verdict <vi>The judge delivered his <it>charge</it> to the jury.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an act of running or rushing forward especially in order to make an attack <vi>a cavalry <it>charge</it></vi> <vi>Tennyson's poem “The <it>Charge</it> of the Light Brigade”</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a feeling of joy or excitement <vi>The children <phrase>got a charge out of</phrase> [=were amused by] the juggler.</vi> <vi>He <it>gets a charge out of</it> teasing his sister.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in charge</dre> <def><dt>:having control of or responsibility for something <vi>She is <it>in charge</it> of hiring new employees.</vi> <vi>I am not sure who is <it>in charge</it> at the restaurant.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>reverse the charges</dre> <dx>see <dxt>reverse</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="charge account"> <hw>charge account</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -counts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:an arrangement in which a bank, store, etc., allows a customer to buy things with a credit card and pay for them later <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>credit account</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="charge card"> <hw>charge card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:<sx>credit card</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="charge nurse"> <hw>charge nurse</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ nurses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a nurse who is in charge of one section of a hospital</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="charge sheet"> <hw>charge sheet</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sheets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>rap sheet</sx> <vi>The suspect already has a long <it>charge sheet</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cover charge"> <hw>cover charge</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ charges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an amount of money that must be paid to go into a nightclub or restaurant in addition to the charge for food and drink <vi>The nightclub has a $5 <it>cover charge</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="depth charge"> <hw>depth charge</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ charges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a bomb that is made to explode under water at a particular depth in order to destroy submarines</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="reverse-charge"> <hw>reverse–charge</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>collect</sx> <vi>a <it>reverse-charge</it> phone call</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="service charge"> <hw>service charge</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ charges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an amount of money that is charged for a particular service in addition to a basic fee <vi>Tickets are $25 each plus a $3 <it>service charge</it> per ticket.</vi> <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>service fee</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:an amount of money that is paid to the owner of an apartment building for services (such as garbage collection)</dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a charge added to a bill in a restaurant to pay for the work of the waitress or waiter</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
