<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="chase[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chase</hw> <sound><wav>chase001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃeɪs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chas*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of following and trying to catch a person, animal, etc. <vi>Police caught the bank robbers after a high-speed <it>chase</it> on the highway.</vi> <vi>a car <it>chase</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:an eager attempt to get something <vi>Though she has repeatedly failed to capture the world record, she refuses to give up the <it>chase</it>. [=she keeps trying]</vi> <vi>He was always trying to find a new girlfriend and seemed to enjoy <phrase>the thrill of the chase</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>wild goose chase</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>steeplechase</sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut to the chase</dre> <def><dt>:to go directly to the important points of a story, argument, etc., <vi>She urged him to skip the details and <it>cut to the chase</it>. [=<it>get to the point</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give chase</dre> <def><dt>:to chase someone or something <vi>The officer saw the thief and <it>gave chase</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>Police <it>gave chase to</it> the suspect as he fled the scene.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chase[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">chase</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃeɪs</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chases</if></in> <in><if>chased</if></in> <in><if>chas*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to follow and try to catch (someone or something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The cops <it>chased</it> the thief.</vi> <vi>a child <it>chasing</it> a balloon</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>after</it> <vi>My dog <it>chases after</it> butterflies.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to try very hard to get (someone or something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>a journalist who is <it>chasing</it> a big story</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>after</it> <vi>He's been <it>chasing after</it> the world record all season.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to attract (someone) for a romantic or sexual relationship <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He was always <it>chasing</it> women half his age.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>after</it> <vi>He was always <it>chasing after</it> women half his age.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to go away <vi>She <it>chased</it> a dog off the lawn.</vi> <vi>He <it>chased</it> the kids away from his new car.</vi> <vi>She <it>chased</it> the cats out of her garden.</vi> <vi>Our last mayor was <it>chased</it> from office by political enemies.</vi> <vi>Her reassuring letter helped to <it>chase</it> away my fears.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>chase down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>chase (someone or something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chase down (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to follow and catch (someone or something) <vi>Police <it>chased down</it> the robber in an alley.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to search for and find (someone or something) <vi>I finally <it>chased down</it> [=<it>tracked down, found</it>, (<it>Brit</it>) <it>chased up</it>] that recipe I promised you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>chase up</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>chase (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chase up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to search for and find (someone or something) <vi>Can you <it>chase up</it> those files for me?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>chase (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chase up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to contact or find (someone) usually in order to get something <vi>His landlord had to <it>chase him up</it> for his rent.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="wild goose chase"> <hw>wild goose chase</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ chases</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a difficult and long search for something that is not important or that cannot be found <vi>The boss sent me on a <it>wild goose chase</it> that wasted half the day.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cut[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cut</hw> <sound><wav>cut00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cuts</if></in> <in><if>cut</if></in> <in><if>cut*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use a sharp tool (such as a knife) to open or divide (something, such as paper or wood) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Cut</it> the paper along/on the dotted line (with a pair of scissors).</vi> <vi><it>cutting</it> a piece of string</vi> <vi>He uses the ax to <it>cut</it> wood.</vi> <vi>The meat is so tender you can <it>cut</it> it with a fork.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The excitement/tension in the room was so thick <phrase>you could cut it with a knife</phrase>. [=there was a lot of excitement/tension in the room]</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Cut</it> along/on the dotted line.</vi> <vi>The saw easily <it>cuts</it> through metal.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> into the melon with a knife.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a hole or wound in (a person's skin) <vi>I <it>cut</it> myself while shaving.</vi> <vi>I <it>cut</it> my finger on a sharp piece of metal. = A sharp piece of metal <it>cut</it> me (on the finger).</vi> <vi>I had a <it>cut</it> finger.</vi> <vi>We were fighting, and he tried to <it>cut</it> me with his knife.</vi> <vi>Pieces of broken glass <it>cut</it> her face and arms.</vi> <vi>He fell and <it>cut</it> his head open on a sharp rock.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (a hole) in something by using a sharp tool <vi>They <it>cut</it> a hole in the wall for the new window.</vi> <vi>Doctors begin by <it>cutting</it> a small incision in the chest.</vi> <vi><it>Cut</it> several slits in the top of the crust to allow air to escape.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to divide or separate parts of (something) by using a sharp tool <vi>It's time to <it>cut</it> [=<it>slice</it>] the cake!</vi> <vi>I'll <it>cut</it> the apple in half so you both can have some.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>cut</it> me a slice of bread? = Would you <it>cut</it> a slice of bread for me?</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>Add one large onion that has been <it>cut into</it> one-inch pieces.</vi> <vi>The chicken is <it>cut into</it> long strips and served on top of the salad.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>Her walls were covered with pictures <it>cut from</it> magazines.</vi> <vi>a piece of meat that is <it>cut from</it> the hind end of the animal</vi></un> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>She was <it>cutting off</it> pieces of watermelon and giving them to the children.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to cut something <vi>This knife doesn't <it>cut</it> well.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be able to be cut <vi>Aluminum foil <it>cuts</it> easily with scissors.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (hair, grass, etc.) shorter by using a sharp tool (such as scissors) <vi>I <it>cut</it> my hair short for the summer.</vi> <vi>Where'd you get your hair <it>cut</it>?</vi> <vi>I need to <it>cut</it> [=<it>trim</it>] my nails; they're way too long.</vi> <vi>She keeps her nails <it>cut</it> short.</vi> <vi>The grass in our yard needs to be <it>cut</it>. [=<it>mowed</it>]</vi> <vi>the smell of fresh-<it>cut</it> grass</vi> <vi>The wood is already <phrase>cut to size/length</phrase>. [=it has already been cut so that it is the proper size/length]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give (hair or clothing) a certain style by cutting it <un>usually used as <it>(be) cut</it> <vi>Her hair is light brown and <it>cut</it> in a short bob.</vi> <vi>She was wearing a dress that <it>was cut</it> low at the neck. [=she was wearing a low-<it>cut</it> dress]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (something) a new shape by using a sharp tool <vi>a beautifully <it>cut</it> diamond</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make or form (something) by cutting or removing material <vi>We all <it>cut</it> [=<it>carved</it>] our names on/into the tree.</vi> <vi>The stream <it>cuts</it> a path through the woods.</vi> <vi>builders <it>cutting</it> new roads in the forest</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> <vi>At the center of the table was a statue <it>cut out</it> of ice.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make the amount of (something) smaller :<sx>reduce</sx> <vi>Our benefits were recently <it>cut</it> at work.</vi> <vi>The drug has been shown to <it>cut</it> the risk of heart attack by half.</vi> <vi>In just three years, the mayor has <it>cut</it> the city's crime in half.</vi> <vi>The President has promised to <it>cut</it> government spending.</vi> <vi><it>Cutting</it> taxes can have positive and negative effects on the economy.</vi> <vi>measures that are designed to <it>cut</it> costs = cost-<it>cutting</it> measures</vi> <vi>The company's expenses had been <phrase>cut to the bone</phrase>. [=reduced to their lowest possible amount]</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>This route can <it>cut</it> as much as five minutes <it>off</it> your driving time.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>cut</it> 20 years <it>off</it> (of) his life. [=shortened his life by 20 years]</vi> <vi>We've <it>cut</it> 20 percent <it>off</it> the regular retail price.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (a book, film, etc.) shorter by removing parts <vi>His article was <it>cut</it> [=<it>shortened</it>] by about 500 words.</vi> <vi>The movie had to be <it>cut</it> because it was too long.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) from a book, film, etc. <vi>The movie's director decided to <it>cut</it> [=<it>cut out</it>, <it>omit</it>] my part.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The director <it>cut</it> the scene <it>from</it> the final version of the film.</vi> <vi>They decided to <it>cut</it> her report <it>from</it> the newscast.</vi> <vi>About 500 words were <it>cut from</it> his article.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (something) from a computer document in a way that allows you to move it to another part of the document or to another document <vi>After you select the text with your mouse, you can <it>cut</it> it and then paste it at the beginning of the paragraph.</vi> <vi>You can <phrase>cut and paste</phrase> the picture into your file.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut-and-paste</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (a plant or part of a plant) by cutting it <vi>It's illegal to <it>cut</it> [=<it>cut down</it>] trees in this forest.</vi> <vi>We'll start <it>cutting</it> and harvesting the wheat next week.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>cut flower</phrase> is a flower that has been cut off the plant that it grew on. <vi>He brought her a bouquet of <it>cut flowers</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to no longer be connected <vi>The enemy has <it>cut</it> [=<it>severed</it>] our supply lines.</vi> <vi>He wanted to <it>cut</it> all ties with his past and start a new life.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to allow (someone or something) to be free, loose, etc., by cutting something that stops movement <vi>They were trapped inside the crushed car and had to be <phrase>cut free</phrase>. = They had to be <it>cut</it> from the car.</vi> <vi>The boat was <phrase>cut loose</phrase> from the pier and allowed to drift away.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>cut loose</tag> at <dxt>loose</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (someone) from a team, organization, etc. <vi>I was on the team for two weeks before I got <it>cut</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The coach <it>cut</it> two players <it>from</it> the team.</vi> <vi>The band was <it>cut from</it> the show at the last minute.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:to divide (a pack of cards) into two piles <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>cut</it> the deck and I'll deal.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>cut</it> and I'll deal.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to divide (an area of land) into two parts <vi>The river <it>cuts</it> the city in half.</vi> <vi>The mountain ridges are <it>cut</it> by deep valleys.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <it>across</it> or <it>through</it> something <vi>Let's take a shortcut and <it>cut across</it> this field.</vi> <vi>We <it>cut through</it> the park on our way home.</vi> <vi>The boundary line between the two countries <it>cuts</it> directly <it>through</it> the group's traditional homeland.</vi> <un>often used figuratively to describe something that is not limited in the usual way <vi>National security is an issue that <it>cuts across</it> party lines. [=an issue that is important to both political parties]</vi> <vi>Child abuse <it>cuts across</it> all economic and racial lines/boundaries. [=it occurs in all economic and racial groups]</vi> <vi>Her academic interests <it>cut across</it> [=involve or relate to] many disciplines.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move quickly <vi>a fast ship <it>cutting</it> through the waves</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move suddenly in a different direction <vi>The driver <it>cut</it> across three lanes of traffic to get to his exit and nearly caused an accident.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The runner <it>cut</it> to his left to avoid being tackled.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in front of other people in a line <vi>That guy <it>cut</it> to the head of the line.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> in front of us. = She <it>cut</it> ahead of us.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>Our friends let us <it>cut in</it> in front of them.</vi> <vi>Celebrities are allowed to <phrase>cut in line</phrase> at popular restaurants.</vi> <vi>Hey, no <it>cutting</it> (<it>in line</it>)!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to not go to (school or a class) when you should go to it <vi>We used to <it>cut</it> [=<it>skip</it>] school together and hang out at the beach.</vi> <vi>She would take notes for me when I <it>cut</it> class.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to record (a song, album, etc.) <vi>She's in the studio <it>cutting</it> a new track/song for her next album.</vi> <vi>Elvis Presley <it>cut</it> his first record in 1954.</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to suddenly move from one image or scene to another in a movie, television program, etc. <vi>The movie <it>cuts</it> quickly from one scene to the next.</vi> <vi>The camera <it>cut</it> back to the actor's face.</vi> <vi>To explain the present situation, the film <it>cuts</it> back to the hero's childhood.</vi> <un>often + <it>away</it> <vi>They quickly <it>cut away</it> to the announcer when he appeared on stage.</vi></un></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop filming a scene in a movie or television show <un>usually used as a command <vi>“<it>Cut</it>!” yelled the director.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop saying or doing (foolish or annoying things) <un>usually used in phrases like <phrase>cut the nonsense</phrase> and (less politely) <phrase>cut the crap</phrase> <vi>Let's <it>cut the nonsense</it> and get down to business.</vi> <vi><it>Cut the crap</it>, Jen! I know you're lying.</vi></un></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop (a motor) by moving a switch <vi>We <it>cut</it> the engine and drifted into shore.</vi> <vi>I parked and <it>cut</it> the ignition.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>The pilot <it>cut off</it> the engine after the plane had come to a stop.</vi></un></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go to or deal with something in a very direct way <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Her question <it>cut to</it> the heart of the issue.</vi> <vi>This research <it>cuts to</it> the very core of who we are as human beings.</vi> <vi>Let me <it>cut to</it> the real reason why I'm here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to cause painful feelings or emotions <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His words <it>cut</it> deeply.</vi> <vi>The disappointment <phrase>cut like a knife</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>His harsh words <it>cut</it> me very deeply.</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>cut to the quick</phrase> [=she was very badly hurt] by their insults.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to make (alcohol) less strong by adding water or another liquid <vi>They <it>cut</it> [=<it>diluted</it>] the wine with water.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (a drug, such as heroin) less strong by mixing it with another substance <vi>The substance is used to <it>cut</it> cocaine.</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (dirt, grease, etc.) to break apart and be removed <vi>soap that <it>cuts</it> grease and grime</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut a check</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to write a check and give it to someone <vi>The company <it>cut</it> him <it>a check</it> and he cashed it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a dash</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dash</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut a deal</dre> <def><dt>:to make an agreement usually about business :to make a deal <vi>The band <it>cut a deal</it> with a recording company.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a figure</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>cut a fine/dashing/heroic (etc.) figure</phrase>, you look very good and impressive. <vi>He <it>cut a fine figure</it> in his officer's uniform.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut and run</dre> <def><dt>:to leave quickly in order to avoid danger or trouble <vi>You can't just <it>cut and run</it> when your friends are in trouble.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a rug</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned slang</sl> <dt>:to dance in an energetic way <vi>He's not young anymore, but he can still <it>cut a rug</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a tooth</dre> <def><sl>of a baby</sl> <dt>:to have a tooth begin to come through the gums <vi>Their baby daughter <it>cut</it> her first <it>tooth</it> yesterday.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut away (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut (something) away</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something that is not needed) by cutting <vi>They <it>cut away</it> [=<it>cut off</it>] a few of the tree's lower branches.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>20 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use less or do less of something <vi>We've been spending too much money and we need to <it>cut back</it> [=we need to spend less money]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I've been trying to <it>cut back on</it> smoking.</vi> <vi>He's <it>cut back on</it> the time he spends in front of the TV.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (a plant) smaller or shorter by cutting its branches <vi><it>Cut back</it> [=<it>prune</it>] the shrub in the late fall.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reduce the size or amount of (something) <vi>We ran out of time and had to <it>cut back</it> our plans.</vi> <vi>They've <it>cut back</it> my hours at work.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cutback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut both ways</dre> <def><dt>:to have both good and bad results, effects, etc. <vi>He knows that his extreme competitiveness <it>cuts both ways</it>.</vi> <vi>These changes in the economy <it>cut both ways</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut corners</dre> <dx>see <dxt>corner</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use less or do less of something <vi>I haven't been able to quit smoking completely, but at least I've <it>cut down</it>. [=<it>cut back</it>]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I've had to <it>cut down on</it> [=<it>reduce</it>, <it>cut back on</it>] the amount of money I spend on clothes.</vi> <vi>She suggested he <it>cut down on</it> his drinking.</vi> <vi>a building material that helps <it>cut down on</it> noise</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove (a tree or bush) by cutting through its trunk or base <vi>Most of the tree was dead, so we had to <it>cut</it> it <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Much of the forest has been <it>cut down</it> for firewood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reduce the size or amount of (something) <vi>We used a shortcut that <it>cut down</it> our traveling time by 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>The machine significantly <it>cuts down</it> the amount of work necessary to harvest crops.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to kill or wound (someone) <vi>She was <it>cut down</it> by a stray bullet.</vi> <vi>The composer Schubert was <it>cut down</it> in his prime by illness. [=he died because of illness when he was in his prime]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut from the same cloth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut ice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to join a conversation suddenly :<sx>interrupt</sx> <vi>We were trying to have a conversation, but she kept <it>cutting in</it>.</vi> <vi>“What are you guys talking about?” he <it>cut in</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He's always <it>cutting in on</it> our conversations.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop two people who are dancing and take the place of one of them <vi>He went up to the dancing couple and said, “May I <it>cut in</it>?”</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work <vi>Once the heater <it>cuts in</it> [=<it>kicks in</it>], it'll be a lot more comfortable in here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to include (someone) in a group of people who are receiving money or other benefits <vi>They'll help you start your business provided that you <it>cut</it> them <it>in</it> when you start making a profit.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>They want you to <it>cut</it> them <it>in on</it> [=to give them some of] the profits.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (something, such as butter) to dry ingredients (such as flour) by making cutting motions with a knife or other sharp tool <vi>After sifting the flour into a mixing bowl, use two knives to <it>cut in</it> the butter.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>17 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reduce the amount of (something) <vi>Although it would <it>cut into</it> profits, we were forced to lower our prices.</vi> <vi>The extra time I was spending at work was <it>cutting into</it> my time with my family.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be able to do something well enough <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>After two weeks at the new job, he decided that he just couldn't <it>cut it</it>. [=that he couldn't do the job well enough to succeed]</vi> <vi>They didn't think that I would <it>cut it</it> as an actress.</vi> <vi>Everyone's using bold colors to decorate their homes. Plain white walls just don't <it>cut it</it> anymore. [=plain white walls are not acceptable anymore]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>People use the informal phrase <phrase>any way you cut it</phrase> to say that something is true no matter how you look at it or think about it. <vi><it>Any way you cut it</it>, it was a pretty good year for our company.</vi> <vi>She's one of the world's best tennis players <it>any way you cut it</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut it close</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>cut it fine</va></vr> <def><dt>:to almost not be able to do something :to almost fail, lose, etc. <vi>They ended up winning the game, but they really <it>cut it close</it> [=they almost lost the game] at the end</vi> <vi>It's <it>cutting it</it> a bit <it>fine</it> to get to the station at 9:45 when the train leaves at 9:50!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to stop working suddenly :to turn off <vi>The engine suddenly <it>cut off</it>. [=<it>cut out</it>]</vi> <vi>The air-conditioning <it>cut off</it>, and the room was silent.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) by cutting <vi><it>Cut off</it> dead flowers to promote new growth.</vi> <vi>I had very long hair, but I <it>cut</it> most of it <it>off</it> in college.</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>cut off</it> his beard.</vi> <vi>He was running around <phrase>like a chicken with its head cut off</phrase>. [=he was acting in a very excited and confused way]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop or end (something) <vi>They had a vote to <it>cut off</it> debate on the budget.</vi> <vi>The organization <it>cut off</it> its ties with the country's government.</vi> <vi>His family <it>cut off</it> all communication/contact with him after the incident.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop people from seeing or using (something) :to block (something) <vi>Their fence <it>cuts off</it> our view of the ocean.</vi> <vi>Many of the town's roads were <it>cut off</it> when the river overflowed.</vi> <vi>The army <it>cut off</it> all escape routes.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop the movement or supply of (something) <vi>The power was <it>cut off</it> to our apartment building.</vi> <vi>The earthquake <it>cut off</it> our water supply.</vi> <vi>They've decided to <it>cut off</it> funding/aid to the group.</vi> <vi>His main source of income had been <it>cut off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone or something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be separate or alone <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>an island nation geographically <it>cut off from</it> the rest of the world</vi> <vi>They are <it>cut off from</it> (contact with) the outside world.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> herself <it>off from</it> her family.</vi> <vi>He's emotionally <it>cut off from</it> his wife.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (someone) from talking <vi>I was in the middle of telling a story when she <it>cut</it> me <it>off</it> [=she interrupted me] to ask about dinner.</vi> <vi>He spoke for 12 minutes until his teacher finally <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>get cut off</phrase> when you are using the telephone, the telephone connection suddenly ends and you can no longer hear the other person. <vi>I called him, but we <it>got cut off</it> [=we got disconnected; the telephone connection ended] two minutes into our conversation.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to drive in front of (someone in another vehicle) in a sudden and dangerous way <vi>He shouted at a driver who <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>Hey, that guy/car just <it>cut</it> me <it>off</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move ahead and force (someone) to stop <vi>“Sheriff, they're getting away!” “Don't worry, we'll take a shortcut and <it>cut</it> them <it>off</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to decide not to give money or property to (someone) after your death <vi>In her will, she <it>cut off</it> her son without a cent/penny.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it> completely.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to refuse to allow (someone) to drink more alcohol <vi>He's had too much to drink. We'd better <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>1d</dxn> <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutoff</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut off your nose to spite your face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to stop working suddenly <vi>The plane's engines suddenly <it>cut out</it>. [=<it>cut off</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to leave quickly and suddenly <vi>We were in a hurry to get home, so we <it>cut out</it> before the performance ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to move out of a line of traffic <vi>The other car/driver <it>cut out</it> from behind and sped ahead of us.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to form (something) by cutting with a sharp tool <vi>He got a piece of red paper and <it>cut out</it> a big heart. = He <it>cut</it> a big heart <it>out</it> of a piece of red paper.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She <it>cut out</it> [=<it>carved out</it>] a place for herself in history. [=she caused herself to be important in history]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>5 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) by cutting <vi>I <it>cut out</it> the recipe from a magazine.</vi> <vi><it>cutting out</it> newspaper articles</vi> <vi>Doctors <it>cut out</it> the lump from her chest.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) from something <vi>Fortunately, they <it>cut</it> [=<it>took</it>] that scene <it>out</it> of the movie.</vi> <vi>He <it>cut out</it> sugar from his diet and began eating more fruits and vegetables.</vi> <vi>I focused on my work and <it>cut out</it> everything else in my life.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop doing (something) <vi>I've cut down on the number of cigarettes I smoke, but I'd like to <it>cut out</it> [=<it>give up</it>] smoking altogether.</vi> <vi>I told you to <phrase>cut that out</phrase>! [=I told you to stop that]</vi> <vi>That's enough, kids. I mean it! <phrase>Cut it out</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><snote>If your legs, feet, or knees are <phrase>cut out from under you</phrase>, you are knocked down by something that hits your legs very hard. This phrase is often used figuratively. <vi>When I learned that I was seriously ill, I felt like my feet were <it>cut out from under me</it>.</vi> <vi>The financial legs had been <it>cut out from under</it> the program. [=the program lost money and could not do what it needed to do]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to no longer be included in something <vi>She <it>cut</it> all of her children <it>out</it> of her will and left everything to her grandchildren.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>cut</it> me <it>out</it> of your life completely!</vi> <vi>We can save money by <phrase>cutting out the middleman</phrase> and ordering our supplies directly from the manufacturer.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you are <phrase>cut out for (something)</phrase> or <phrase>cut out to do/be (something)</phrase>, you are naturally able or suited to do or be something. <vi>Why do you think that you're <it>cut out for</it> this job? [=why would you be good at this job?]</vi> <vi>I'm really not <it>cut out for</it> this kind of work. [=I'm not naturally good at it]</vi> <vi>He's not <it>cut out to be</it> a teacher. = He's not <it>cut out to</it> teach.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <tag>have your work cut out for you</tag> at <dxt>work</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut short</dre> <dx>see <dxt>short</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut (someone) dead</dre> <def><dt>:to pretend not to see (someone you know) :to deliberately ignore (someone) <vi>When I saw her on the street yesterday, she <it>cut</it> me <it>dead</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut (someone) some slack</dre> <dx>see <dxt>slack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut the Gordian knot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gordian knot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut the mustard</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mustard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get through or past (something that blocks you or slows you down) quickly and directly <vi>We were able to start the project once she told us how to <it>cut through</it> the red tape.</vi> <vi>It took some time to <it>cut through</it> the lies and get to the truth.</vi> <vi><it>cutting through</it> all the nonsense</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi><it>cutting through to</it> the heart/essence of the problem</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>15 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut to the chase</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chase</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a silly or rude way <vi>I was sent to the principal's office for <it>cutting up</it> [=<it>clowning around</it>] in class.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cutup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cut (something) into parts or pieces <vi>He <it>cut up</it> the candy into little pieces and gave it to the child.</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>The area was <it>cut up</it> [=<it>divided</it>] <it>into</it> three separate farms.</vi> <vi>They <it>cut up</it> the wood <it>into</it> small pieces.</vi> <vi>We made sandwiches and <it>cut</it> them <it>up into</it> triangles.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone or something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut up (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or damage (someone or something) by cutting <vi>He got <it>cut up</it> pretty badly in the fight.</vi> <vi>His face and arms were all <it>cut up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone or something) in a harsh way <vi>The critics really <it>cut up</it> his last play.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><snote>In informal British English, to be <phrase>cut up about</phrase> something is to be very sad or upset about something. <vi>I was pretty <it>cut up about</it> the way the critics treated my last play.</vi> <vi>She's really <it>cut up about</it> losing her job.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut up rough</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in an angry or violent way <vi>He got drunk and started to <it>cut up rough</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut your losses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>loss</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut your own throat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>throat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut your teeth</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe the things that people do when they are starting their careers <vi>He <it>cut his teeth</it> performing at local bars and nightclubs.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut her</it> political <it>teeth</it> [=she began her political career] as a volunteer during the 1992 presidential elections.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>Many television and movie stars <it>cut their teeth on</it> soap operas.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fish or cut bait</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fish</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="give[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">give</hw> <sound><wav>give0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɪv</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>gives</if></in> <in><if>gave</if> <sound><wav>give0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgeɪv</pr></in> <in><if>giv*en</if> <sound><wav>give0003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɪvən</pr></in> <in><if>giv*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause or allow someone to have (something) as a present :to make a present of (something) <vi>She <it>gave</it> him a camera for Christmas.</vi> <vi>Someone <it>gave</it> me a present. = Someone <it>gave</it> a present to me. = I was <it>given</it> a present. = A present was <it>given</it> (to) me.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>giving</it> this to me or only lending it?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause or allow (something valued or needed) to go to another person, group, etc. :<sx>donate</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She has <it>given</it> money to many worthy/good causes.</vi> <vi>They're asking people to <it>give</it> money for a new hospital.</vi> <vi><it>give</it> blood</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>give</it> to our charity.</vi> <vi>We already <it>gave</it> at the office.</vi> <vi>It is better to <it>give</it> than to receive.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to put (something) into someone's hand <vi>He picked up the letter and <it>gave</it> [=<it>handed</it>] it to me.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> me the letter.</vi> :to cause someone to hold or possess (something) for a specified reason <vi>He <it>gave</it> me a letter to mail for him. = He <it>gave</it> a letter to me to mail for him.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her his coat to hold.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to provide someone with (something wanted or needed) <vi>She has <it>given</it> me a lot of help/support/encouragement. [=she has helped/supported/encouraged me a lot]</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> me a job. [=they hired me]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> me a head start.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>give</it> you a lift/ride to the station. [=I'll drive you to the station in my car]</vi> :to allow someone to have (something wanted or needed) <vi>I know I can do it if you'll just <it>give</it> me a chance.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> her another opportunity.</vi> <vi>Her boss has <it>given</it> her a lot of responsibility/authority.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> him the best room available.</vi> <vi>The law <it>gives</it> all citizens the right to vote. = The law <it>gives</it> the right to vote to all citizens.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to allow someone to have or take (an amount of time) <vi>Just <it>give</it> me a few more minutes and I'll be ready.</vi> <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him two weeks to pay his bill.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to treat or regard someone or something with (a particular attitude, feeling, etc.) <vi>She <it>gave</it> her friend her complete confidence. = She <it>gave</it> her complete confidence to her friend. [=she trusted her friend completely]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> the company his loyalty. [=he was loyal to the company]</vi> <vi>They've worked hard. You should <it>give</it> them some respect. [=you should respect them]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to direct (something) toward someone <vi>She <it>gave</it> him an angry look. [=she looked at him angrily]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her a smile. [=he smiled at her]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to tell (information) to someone <vi>Just <it>give</it> me the facts.</vi> <vi>They weren't able to <it>give</it> us the information we needed.</vi> <vi>The witness was reluctant to <it>give</it> evidence.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> his name as “John Smith.” [=he said his name was “John Smith”]</vi> <vi>The drawing <it>gives</it> [=<it>shows</it>] the dimensions of the room.</vi> <vi>The book <it>gives</it> [=<it>provides</it>] a brief history of the industry.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to express or say (something) to someone <vi>You have no right to <it>give</it> me orders.</vi> <vi>They <it>gave</it> him careful instructions on how to proceed.</vi> <vi><it>Give</it> them my regards. = <it>Give</it> my regards to them.</vi> <vi>His parents <it>gave</it> him a lecture about the importance of studying.</vi> <vi>The coach <it>gave</it> the team a pep talk.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>give you my word</phrase> [=I swear; I promise], I knew nothing about their plans.</vi> <vi>Just <phrase>give it to me straight</phrase>. [=just say what you are going to say to me in a direct way]</vi> <snote>The informal phrase <phrase>don't give me that</phrase> is used in speech to show annoyance when someone tells you something that you do not believe or accept. <vi>“It's not my fault that we're late.” “<it>Don't give me that</it>! You were the one who said we didn't have to leave early!”</vi></snote></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to show (something) <vi>a young artist who has <it>given</it> evidence/signs of real talent</vi> <vi>She <it>gave</it> (us) no hint/indication that she was upset or worried.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to offer (something) for consideration or acceptance <vi>He declined to <it>give</it> an opinion.</vi> <vi>Can you <it>give</it> an example?</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> no reason for his absence.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say that someone has or deserves (something) <vi>He <it>gives</it> the credit for his success to his wife. [=he credits his wife for his success]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to have or experience (something, such as an emotion, a problem, etc.) <vi>My car has been <it>giving</it> [=<it>causing</it>] me a lot of trouble lately.</vi> <vi>I like Mexican food, but it <it>gives</it> me indigestion.</vi> <vi>a book that <it>gives</it> pleasure to the reader</vi> <vi>All that noise is <it>giving</it> me a headache. [=I'm getting a headache from all that noise]</vi> <vi>It <it>gave</it> me a shock to see how sick he is.</vi> <vi>Her encouragement <it>gave</it> me a lot of self-confidence. [=made me feel very self-confident]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to become affected by (something, such as an illness) <vi>His sister <it>gave</it> him the measles. [=he got/caught the measles from his sister]</vi> <vi>Hearing the joke <it>gave</it> him the giggles. [=hearing the joke made him giggle]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to cause someone or something to have (a quality) <vi>His quiet manner <it>gives</it> him a mysterious air.</vi> <vi>The large windows <it>give</it> the room an open feeling.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to cause something to be affected by (something) <vi>He argues that the tax cuts would <it>give</it> a considerable stimulus/boost to the economy.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause someone to get or take (a medicine) <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> the patient a pill.</vi> <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him an injection.</vi> <vi>The drug is usually <it>given</it> intravenously.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to present (a show, speech, etc.) in public <vi><it>give</it> a concert/lecture/talk/speech/reading/performance</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to provide (something) as entertainment or as a social gathering <vi><it>give</it> [=<it>throw</it>] a party</vi> <vi><it>give</it> a formal dinner</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to do (an action) <vi>She <it>gave</it> the door a push. [=she pushed the door]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> her a hug. [=he hugged her]</vi> <vi>He <it>gave</it> a cynical smile. [=he smiled cynically]</vi> <vi>She picked up the package and <it>gave</it> it a shake. [=she shook the package]</vi> <vi>The referee <it>gave</it> [=<it>made</it>] the signal to start the game.</vi> <vi>The ship <it>gave</it> a sudden lurch. [=the ship lurched suddenly]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to experience or suffer (a form of punishment) <vi>His father <it>gave</it> the boy a whipping.</vi> <vi>The judge <it>gave</it> him life (imprisonment) for murder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause someone to undergo or do (something) <vi>The teacher <it>gave</it> the class a test.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>give something thought/consideration (etc.)</phrase> is to think about it. <vi>We've <it>given</it> your proposal a lot of thought and careful consideration. [=we've thought about your proposal a lot and considered it carefully]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt><snote>To <phrase>give someone a call/ring/buzz/bell</phrase> is to make a telephone call to someone. <vi>I'll <it>give you a call</it> later.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt><snote>If you try to do something, you <phrase>give it a try</phrase> or (informally) <phrase>give it a go/shot/stab</phrase>. <vi>I've never gone skiing before, but I'm willing to <it>give it a try</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>15</sn> <dt><snote>If you would <phrase>give anything</phrase> or <phrase>give your right hand/arm</phrase> to do or to have something, you want to do or have it very much. <vi>I'd <it>give anything</it> to be able to sing like that!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as your hand) available for someone <vi>She <it>gave</it> [=<it>offered</it>] her hand to him to shake/kiss. = She <it>gave</it> him her hand to shake/kiss. [=she held out her hand toward him so that he could shake/kiss it]</vi> <vi>She <it>gave</it> him her arm [=she linked her arm in his arm] and they walked together into the room.</vi> <snote>When a woman <phrase>gives her hand in marriage to</phrase> a man, she marries him. This is a formal and somewhat old-fashioned expression.</snote></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:<sx>pay</sx> <vi>I wouldn't <it>give</it> a penny for that old bike!</vi> <vi>If you have an extra ticket, I'll <it>give</it> you $20 for it.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>sell</sx> <vi>I'm willing to <it>give</it> you the ticket for $20.</vi></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say or judge that someone or something will last for (an amount of time) <vi>The doctor <it>gave</it> him only a few weeks to live. [=the doctor said that he would live for only a few weeks]</vi> <vi>Their marriage will never work. I <it>give</it> it/them six months—tops!</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to admit (something) to or about someone <vi>He made an effort, I'll <it>give</it> him that (much). [=I'll admit that he made an effort]</vi> <vi>I don't really like his movies, but he's a talented actor, <phrase>I'll give you that</phrase>. [=I admit that he is a talented actor]</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have or produce (something) as a product, result, or effect <vi>medical procedures that <it>give</it> better results</vi> <vi>Cows <it>give</it> milk.</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to cause someone to believe or think (something) <un>followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>They <it>gave</it> [=<it>led</it>] me <it>to understand</it> that they'd be arriving later.</vi></un> <snote>To <phrase>give someone an idea/impression (etc.)</phrase> is to cause someone to believe or think something. <vi>Whatever <it>gave you the idea</it> (that) he loved you?! [=whatever made you think that he loved you?]</vi> <vi>I'm sorry if I <it>gave you the wrong impression</it>. [=I'm sorry if I misled you; I'm sorry if you got the wrong impression from me]</vi> <vi>I don't know what <it>gave her the notion</it> that she could treat people that way.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bend because of force, pressure, or strain <vi>The branch <it>gave</it> [=<it>sagged</it>] under his weight, but it didn't break.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to break because of force, pressure, or strain <vi>The branch suddenly <it>gave</it> [=<it>gave way</it>] under his weight, and he fell to the ground.</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop trying to resist or oppose something :to give in or submit to pressure <vi>Both sides refuse to <it>give</it> [=refuse to accept or agree to the demands of the other side] in this dispute.</vi> <vi>For the strike to be settled, <phrase>something has (got) to give</phrase>! [=one side or the other has to give in]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to indicate a possible or assumed state or condition <vi><it>Give</it> him his books and his music and he's happy. [=he is happy if he has his books and his music]</vi> <vi>(If) <it>Given</it> better conditions, she'd do the work even better. = She'd do the work even better (if) <it>given</it> better conditions. = If she were <it>given</it> better conditions, she'd do the work even better.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what you want to have or would prefer to have <vi>“…<it>give</it> me liberty, or <it>give</it> me death!” [=I would rather die than live without liberty] <aq>Patrick Henry, Speech (1775)</aq></vi> <vi>The country's OK—but <it>give</it> me the city any day! [=I prefer the city]</vi></un></dt> <sn>25</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>give a damn</phrase> to say that you do not care at all about something <vi>He angrily told her that he didn't <it>give a damn</it> what she did.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>give as good as you get</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to be as forceful in fighting or arguing against others as they are in fighting or arguing against you <vi>She can <it>give as good as she gets</it> in an argument with just about anybody.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give away (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make a present of (something) <vi>For a limited time only our store is <it>giving away</it> [=<it>giving</it>] a free can of soda to each and every one of our customers!</vi> <vi>Our prices are so cheap we're practically <it>giving away</it> everything in our store!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to lose (something) in a careless way <vi>He virtually <it>gave</it> the election <it>away</it> when he made a racist remark.</vi> <vi>The pitcher <it>gave</it> the game <it>away</it> by walking four batters in a row.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to allow (something hidden or secret) to become known <vi>The way she looked at him <it>gave away</it> her real feelings for him.</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>give away</it> [=<it>reveal</it>] how the trick is done.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>giveaway</dxt> <dxt>giveaway price</dxt> <tag>give the game away</tag> at <dxt>game</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (someone) away</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>give away (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to bring (the bride) to the groom at a wedding <vi>Traditionally, it's the father of the bride who <it>gives</it> his daughter <it>away</it> at the wedding.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reveal the truth about (someone) <vi>His fellow conspirators <it>gave</it> him <it>away</it> to the police. [=they betrayed him to the police]</vi> <vi>His accent <it>gave</it> him <it>away</it> as a northerner. [=his accent showed that he was a northerner]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause someone to have (something) again :to return or restore (something) to someone <vi>He <it>gave back</it> the money he found to the person who'd lost it.</vi> <vi>Her encouragement helped to <it>give</it> me <it>back</it> my self-confidence. [=her encouragement helped me to get my self-confidence back]</vi> <vi>They agreed to <it>give</it> him his old job <it>back</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>giveback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give birth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>birth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give chase</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chase</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to fight or resist something :to agree to do or accept something that you have been resisting or opposing <vi>The strike has been going on for weeks, and neither side seems willing to <it>give in</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He refused to <it>give in to</it> their demands. [=he refused to do what they demanded that he do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give in (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to give (something) to a person who has authority to review or accept it <vi><it>give in</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>hand in</it>] an assignment</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give it a rest, give (something) a rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give me a break, give (someone) a break</dre> <dx>see <dxt>break</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give of</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give of yourself</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give of your time</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to use your time and effort to help others <vi>They freely <it>gave of their time</it> when their help was needed.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to send (light, energy, etc.) out from a source <vi>The telescope can detect light <it>given off</it> [=<it>emitted</it>] by distant galaxies.</vi> <vi>The garbage <it>gave off</it> an unpleasant smell.</vi> <vi>The chimneys <it>gave off</it> thick, black smoke.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give on to</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>give onto</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give on to (something)</pva> <pvl>also</pvl> <pva>give onto (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to provide a view of or a passage to (something) <vi>The door <it>gives</it> directly <it>on to</it> the garden.</vi> <vi>The rooms <it>give onto</it> a hall.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give or take</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate that the stated amount is approximate and might be increased or decreased by a specified amount <vi>He ran a mile, <it>give or take</it> a few yards.</vi> <vi>The movie lasted three hours, <it>give or take</it> a few minutes either way.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal)</it> He ran a mile, <it>give or take</it>. [=he ran about a mile]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The plane's engine sputtered and <it>gave out</it>, forcing an emergency landing.</vi> <vi>His voice <it>gave out</it>. [=he was unable to talk]</vi> <vi>His courage finally <it>gave out</it>. [=he lost his courage]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become used up <vi>Our supply of fuel had almost <it>given out</it> [=<it>run out</it>] entirely.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>give out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to produce (noise, light, etc.) <vi>The brakes <it>gave out</it> a loud squeal.</vi> <vi>The woodstove <it>gives out</it> a lot of heat.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give (something) to many people :to hand out (something) <vi>They <it>gave out</it> copies of the newsletter.</vi> <vi>He's always <it>giving out</it> unwanted advice.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop doing something that is annoying or unpleasant <vi>Oh, <it>give over</it>! I'm tired of your complaints!</vi> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>They eventually <it>gave over bothering</it> me [=stopped bothering me] and let me alone.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give over to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>give (something) over to (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to give (something) to (someone) to have, use, do, etc. <vi>She has <it>given</it> most of her work <it>over</it> to her assistant.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) over to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (yourself) to be fully affected by, controlled by, or involved in (something) <vi>He <it>gave himself over to</it> despair. [=he was overcome by despair]</vi> <vi>She <it>gave herself over</it> completely <it>to</it> her work. [=she devoted all of her attention and energy to her work]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><snote>Something that is <phrase>given over to</phrase> a specified purpose is used for that purpose. <vi>One of the upstairs rooms is <it>given over to</it> storage.</vi> <vi>Much of her time recently has been <it>given over to</it> researching her family history.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give place to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>place</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give rise to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rise</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stop an activity or effort :to admit that you cannot do something and stop trying :<sx>quit</sx> <vi>He vowed that he would never <it>give up</it>.</vi> <vi>I <it>give up</it>! I don't know what more I can do to please my girlfriend!</vi> <vi>“How many prime numbers are there between 1 and 100? Well, do you <it>give up</it>?” “OK, I <it>give up</it>!”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>give up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop having, doing, or using (something) <vi>He was forced to <it>give up</it> his job.</vi> <vi>She refused to <it>give up</it> trying.</vi> <vi>My doctor urged me to <it>give up</it> smoking/cigarettes.</vi> <vi>Rescuers have not yet <it>given up</it> hope that more survivors will be found.</vi> <vi>He <it>gave up</it> his seat to an elderly woman. [=he got out of his seat so that an elderly woman could sit there]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to do (something) <vi>We did our best to repair the engine, but in the end we had to <it>give</it> it <it>up</it> as impossible.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to allow (a score, a hit, etc.) by an opposing team or player <vi>The defense <it>gave up</it> two touchdowns in the first quarter.</vi> <vi>The pitcher didn't <it>give up</it> a hit till the ninth inning.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to surrender (yourself) as a prisoner <vi>The fugitive eventually <it>gave himself up</it> (to the police/authorities).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to improve the condition of (someone) because it seems hopeless <vi>The teacher <it>gave</it> him <it>up</it> as a hopeless case.</vi> <vi>The doctors <phrase>gave him up for dead</phrase>. [=the doctors said that he was certain to die]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having hope of seeing (someone) <vi>We'd <it>given</it> you <it>up</it> (for lost) hours ago!</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>give (yourself) up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to allow (yourself) to be fully affected by, controlled by, or involved in (something) <vi>He <it>gave himself up to</it> despair.</vi> <vi>She <it>gave herself up</it> completely <it>to</it> her work.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>give up on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop trying to improve the condition of (someone) <vi>He has gotten in trouble many times, but his parents have never <it>given up on</it> him.</vi> <vi>Please don't <it>give up on</it> me. I promise I'll do better.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop having hope of seeing (someone) <vi>We'd <it>given up on</it> you hours ago!</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <phrasev><pva>give up on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop trying to do or achieve (something) <vi>They have <it>given up on</it> their plan to build a new factory.</vi> <vi>She hasn't <it>given up on</it> trying to convince her husband to buy a new car.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give up the ghost</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ghost</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>What gives?</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to ask the reason for something <vi>You've been acting weird all week. <it>What gives</it>? [=why are you acting weird?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="lead[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">lead</hw> <sound><wav>lead0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈli:d</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>leads</if></in> <in><if>led</if> <sound><wav>lead0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlɛd</pr></in> <in><if>lead*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to guide someone to a place especially by going in front <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>lead</it> and we'll follow right behind you.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>led</it> [=<it>took</it>] me into a room in the back of the house.</vi> <vi>You <it>lead</it> us and we'll follow right behind you.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The teacher <it>led</it> the child by the hand <it>to</it> his seat. = The teacher took the child's hand and <it>led</it> him <it>to</it> his seat.</vi> <vi>Our hostess <it>led</it> us <it>to</it> the dinner table.</vi></un> <un>often used as <it>(be) led</it> <vi>The passengers <it>were led</it> onto/aboard the ship by the steward.</vi> <vi>The prisoner <it>was</it> <phrase>led off</phrase> to jail [=was taken to jail] in handcuffs.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>I gradually <it>led</it> the interview around/back to the subject of his failed marriage.</vi> <vi>He says that he will follow the evidence wherever it <it>leads</it> (him).</vi> <vi>This <it>leads</it> me to my next point, which is that the building needs a new roof.</vi> <vi>The painting's composition <phrase>leads the/your eye</phrase> to the figures in the foreground. [=causes you to look at the figures in the foreground]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go or be at the front part of (something) <vi>The veterans will <it>lead</it> a parade down Main Street.</vi> <vi><it>lead</it> a march</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to lie or go in a specified direction <vi>The path <it>leads</it> uphill.</vi> <vi>This road doesn't <it>lead</it> to the village as we thought it did.</vi> <vi>a set of stairs that <it>leads</it> down to the basement</vi> <vi>There was a path <it>leading</it> (off) from the meadow into the woods.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She realized that their relationship would never <it>lead</it> to marriage.</vi> <vi>The investigation into the murder was <phrase>leading nowhere</phrase>. [=the investigation was not solving the crime]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to guide the actions of a person or group :to be in charge of a person, group, activity, etc. <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>We need to elect someone who can <it>lead</it>.</vi> <vi>bosses who <phrase>lead by example</phrase> [=who show employees how they should act by acting that way themselves]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>leads</it> her employees by setting a good example for them.</vi> <vi>She <it>led</it> a successful boycott of the store.</vi> <vi><it>lead</it> an expedition</vi> <vi>A visiting professor will be <it>leading</it> the seminar.</vi> <vi><it>lead</it> [=<it>direct</it>] an orchestra</vi> <vi>She <it>led</it> the children in a song. [=she sang a song and the children sang with her]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (a person, group, etc.) to do something or to follow some course of action <vi>Her interest in art <it>led</it> her into the field of art history.</vi> <un>usually followed by <it>to</it> or <it>to + verb</it> <vi>His volunteer work in the hospital <it>led</it> him <it>to</it> a career in nursing. = His volunteer work in the hospital <it>led</it> [=<it>inspired</it>] him <it>to become</it> a nurse.</vi> <vi>Her experience with cancer <it>led</it> her <it>to consider</it> writing a book on the subject.</vi> <vi>The evidence <it>leads</it> me <it>to believe</it> [=makes me believe] that this disease is curable.</vi> <vi>We've been <it>led to believe</it> that the labels on food items disclose all ingredients, but it's becoming clear that this is not the case.</vi> <vi>I had been <it>led to expect</it> that someone would meet me at the airport, but no one came.</vi> <vi>He <it>led me to understand</it> [=he told me or caused me to think] that the deadline was January 7.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to be first, best, or ahead in a race or competition <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>the team that is currently <it>leading</it> in the pennant race</vi> <vi>At the end of the fourth inning, the Red Sox <it>led</it> by two runs.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>lead</it> a race</vi> <vi>They <it>led</it> their opponents by 20 points at the end of the third quarter.</vi> <vi>the team that is <it>leading</it> the league [=the team that is in first place]</vi> <vi>a batter who <it>leads</it> the league in home runs [=who has hit more home runs than any other batter]</vi> <vi>a runner who is <phrase>leading the pack/field</phrase> [=a runner who is ahead of the group of other runners]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their company <phrase>leads the world</phrase> [=is the most successful company in the world] in developing new technology to assist people with disabilities.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go through (life) in a certain way :to have (a specified kind of life) <vi>They chose to <it>lead</it> [=<it>live</it>] a quiet life.</vi> <vi>He <it>leads</it> a peaceful existence.</vi> <vi>It turned out that he had been <phrase>leading a double life</phrase>. [=deceiving people about his life, not telling the whole truth about his life]</vi> <vi>He has always <phrase>led a charmed life</phrase>. [=he has always been lucky]</vi> <vi>She needs to <phrase>lead her own life</phrase>. [=she needs to make her own decisions about her life]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to begin play in a card game with (a certain card or kind of card) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>lead</it> trumps</vi> <vi><it>led</it> a spade</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>lead</it> with a spade</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to guide a dance partner through the steps of a dance <vi>I don't know this dance, so I'd prefer it if you <it>lead</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to ask (a witness) a question in a way that suggests what the answer should be :to ask (a witness) a leading question <vi>The judge ruled that the lawyer was <it>leading</it> the witness.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>lead off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lead off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lead (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lead off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start something (such as an activity or performance) in a specified way <vi>She <it>led off</it> [=<it>started, kicked off</it>] the presentation with a brief overview of the project.</vi> <vi>She <it>led off</it> [=<it>began</it>] with a brief overview of the project.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:to be the first batter in an inning <vi>He <it>led off</it> with a walk. [=he was the first batter in his team's half of the inning and he was walked]</vi> <vi>He <it>led off</it> the inning with a home run.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>leadoff</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lead (someone) on</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to wrongly continue believing or doing something <vi>She was devastated when she found out that he didn't really love her, and had only been <it>leading</it> her <it>on</it>. [=he had been leading her to believe that he loved her]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead someone a merry chase</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>lead someone a (merry) dance</va></vr> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to cause a series of troubles or worries for (someone) <vi>He <it>led me a merry chase</it> before I finally got him to agree to a meeting.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead someone (around) by the nose</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lead someone down/up the garden path</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to deceive someone :to cause someone to go, think, or proceed wrongly <vi>He believes the average consumer is being <it>led down the garden path</it> by the promises in advertisements.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead the way</dre> <def><dt>:to be the first person to go somewhere <vi>You <it>lead the way</it>, and we'll follow.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their company <it>led the way</it> in developing this technology. [=was the first to have success developing the technology]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lead to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to result in (something) <vi>a course of study <it>leading to</it> a degree in agriculture</vi> <vi>Her investigations ultimately <it>led to</it> the discovery of the missing documents.</vi> <vi>His volunteer work in the hospital <it>led to</it> a career in nursing. = His volunteer work in the hospital <it>led to</it> him becoming a nurse.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>lead <dxn>1a, 4 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead up to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lead up to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to occur in the time that comes before (something) <vi>Many voters were still undecided in the days <it>leading up to</it> [=<it>approaching</it>] the election.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to come before and help to cause (something) <vi>There was a series of errors <it>leading up to</it> the accident.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to come before and help to introduce (something) <vi>a chapter <it>leading up to</it> the main topic of the book</vi> <vi>I had no idea what he was <it>leading up to</it> when he started talking about his father.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lead with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to begin something (such as a story or speech) with (something specified) <vi>The newspaper story <it>led</it> [=<it>opened, began</it>] <it>with</it> a long report on the funeral.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to begin a series of punches in boxing with (a punch thrown by a specified hand) <vi>The champion <it>led with</it> a left to the body, followed up quickly with a right to the jaw.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the blind leading the blind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="merry"> <hw highlight="yes">mer*ry</hw> <sound><wav>merry001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmeri</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>mer*ri*er</if></in> <in><if>mer*ri*est</if></in> <def><sl>somewhat old-fashioned</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:very happy and cheerful :feeling or showing joy and happiness <vi>Let's eat, drink, and be <it>merry</it>!</vi> <vi>They sang a <it>merry</it> little song.</vi> <vi>a <it>merry</it> man</vi> <vi><it>merry</it> laughter</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:causing joy and happiness <vi>a very <it>merry</it> occasion</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>go on your merry way</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>be on your merry way</va></svr> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>Soon I'll <it>be on my merry way</it>. [=soon I'll be leaving]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>often disapproving</ssl> <dt>:to continue doing what you have been doing <vi>She just <it>goes on her merry way</it>, loving men and then breaking their hearts.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lead (someone) a merry chase/dance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lead</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make merry</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:to have fun and enjoy yourself by eating, drinking, dancing, etc. <vi>They <it>made merry</it> throughout the night.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>Merry Christmas</dre> <def><dt><un>used to wish someone an enjoyable Christmas holiday <vi><it>Merry Christmas</it> to you and your family.</vi> <vi>We wish you a <it>Merry Christmas</it> and a happy New Year!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the more the merrier</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that more people are welcome or invited to do something <vi>“Can I bring my friends to the party?” “Of course, <it>the more the merrier</it>!”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>mer*ri*ly</ure> <sound><wav>merry002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmerəli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>laughing <it>merrily</it></vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>mer*ri*ness</ure> <sound><wav>merry003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmerinəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>merriness</it> of the occasion</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
