<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="check[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">check</hw> <sound><wav>check001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃɛk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>checks</if></in> <in><if>checked</if></in> <in><if>check*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to look at (something) carefully to find mistakes, problems, etc., or to make sure there is nothing wrong with it <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Make sure to <it>check</it> your spelling.</vi> <vi>She <it>checked</it> her makeup in the mirror.</vi> <vi>We should <it>check</it> the equipment to make sure that it's working properly.</vi> <vi>I <it>checked</it> the tires for wear. [=to see if they are worn down/out]</vi> <vi>The guards <it>checked</it> my passport.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>Be careful to <it>check for</it> any mistakes.</vi> <vi>The border guards <it>checked</it> in my luggage <it>for</it> contraband.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cross-check</dxt> <dxt>double-check</dxt> <dxt>spot-check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to get information by looking at something, asking about something, etc. <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>checked</it> his watch and saw that it was almost noon.</vi> <vi>I'll just <it>check</it> the map to see where we are.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>check</it> the newspaper to see when the movie starts.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>We were out of milk last time I <it>checked</it>. [=<it>looked</it>]</vi> <vi>“Do you have these shoes in a larger size?” “I don't know. Let me <it>check</it>.” [=<it>take a look</it>]</vi> <vi>I think the door is locked, but I'll have to <it>check</it> (to be sure).</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>Did you <it>check to see</it> where the movie was playing?</vi> <vi>I <it>checked to make sure</it> the door was locked.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look at or in (a place) in order to find or get something or someone <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>If you're looking for a spoon, <it>check</it> the top drawer.</vi> <vi>I <it>checked</it> his office but he wasn't there.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>If you're looking for the umbrella, <it>check</it> in the closet.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to find out if you have any (mail, messages, etc.) <vi>Did you <it>check</it> the mail yet today?</vi> <vi>She <it>checked</it> [=listened to] her phone messages when she got home.</vi> <vi>He logged on and <it>checked</it> [=<it>read</it>] his e-mail.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to talk <it>with</it> someone in order to get approval, information, etc., about something <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>I'll have to <it>check with</it> the manager before I can let you in.</vi> <vi><it>Check with</it> your doctor to find out which drugs are safe.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I'm not sure when you should arrive. I'll have to <it>check</it> that <it>with</it> my wife.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to slow or stop (something or someone) from doing something <vi>She started to speak but then <it>checked</it> [=<it>stopped</it>] herself.</vi> <vi>The batter <it>checked</it> his swing. [=the batter started to swing and then stopped]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>hockey</ssl> <dt>:to stop or hit (an opponent) in order to steal the ball or puck, defend the goal, etc. <vi>He was <it>checked</it> by the defender.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to leave (something you own) with a worker at a restaurant, hotel, etc., who keeps it in a special area or room (called a checkroom) while you are there <vi>I <it>checked</it> my hat and coat in the restaurant's checkroom.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (your bags, suitcases, etc.) to a worker so that they can be loaded onto a plane or train <vi>We <it>checked</it> our bags before boarding.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to take (someone's bags, suitcases, etc.) to load them onto a plane or train <vi>The airline <it>checked</it> our bags before we boarded.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>check in <dxn>3 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to mark (something) with a check (✓) to show that it has been done, approved, etc. <vi>You should <it>check</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>tick</it>] each item on the list after you've completed it.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>You should <it>check off</it> [=(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>tick off</it>] each item on the list after you've completed it.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be proven to be true, accurate, etc. <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>Her story didn't <it>check</it>. [=the evidence did not support her story]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>check out <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>check back</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to return to a place, person, etc., in order to try something again or to get additional information <vi>We are not hiring today, but <it>check back</it> next month.</vi> <vi>I'll <phrase>check back with you</phrase> [=talk to you again] in about a week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to report to someone when you arrive at a place (such as an airport or convention) to let them know you are there <vi>Passengers must <it>check in</it> one hour before the flight leaves.</vi> <vi>Where do I have to <it>check in</it>?</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to arrive at and be given a room in a hotel, motel, etc. <vi><it>check in</it> [=<it>register</it>] at a hotel</vi> <vi>Guests cannot <it>check in</it> before 4:00 PM.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>check-in</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to talk with someone in order to report or find out new information <vi>I'm just <it>checking in</it> to see how things are going.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>I have to go to a meeting now, but I'll <it>check in with</it> you later.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>check (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>check in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave or take bags, suitcases, etc., so that they can be loaded onto a plane or train <vi>We <it>checked</it> our bags <it>in</it> at the station.</vi> <vi>The airline <it>checked in</it> our luggage.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to arrive at and be given a room in (a hotel, motel, etc.) <vi>We <it>checked into</it> a hotel.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to look for information about (something) :to find out the truth about (something) by getting information <vi>The police are <it>checking into</it> [=<it>checking on, checking up on</it>] his activities. [=the police are investigating his activities]</vi> <vi>A problem like that should really be <it>checked into</it> carefully.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check off on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check off on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to give official approval for (something) <vi>My boss will have to <it>check off on</it> [=<it>authorize, approve</it>] my decision.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to look at or examine (someone or something) to see if there are any problems <vi>The nurse <it>checked on</it> the patients regularly.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to look for information about (someone or something) :to find out the truth about (someone or something) by getting information <vi>The police are <it>checking on</it> [=<it>checking up on</it>] him.</vi> <vi>I asked the waiter to <it>check on</it> [=find out what was happening with] my order.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave and pay for your room at a hotel, motel, etc. <vi>We <it>checked out</it> (of the hotel) early.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to die <vi>There are still a lot of things I want to accomplish in life before I finally <it>check out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be proven to be accurate, true, etc. <vi>I didn't believe her at first, but her story <it>checked out</it>.</vi> <vi>The description <it>checked out</it> when we compared it with the photograph. [=we saw that the description was accurate when we compared it with the photograph]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>check out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>check (something) out</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find out if (something) is true <vi>The police are still trying to <it>check out</it> [=<it>investigate, confirm</it>] his alibi.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>check out (something or someone)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>check (something or someone) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to look at (something or someone) in order to find problems, mistakes, etc. <vi>We carefully <it>checked out</it> the car for defects.</vi> <vi>He had problems with his computer and asked the technician to <it>check</it> it <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>He needs to get <it>checked out</it> by a doctor.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to look at (someone or something that is attractive or interesting) <vi>When she walked into the room, all the guys were <it>checking</it> her <it>out</it>.</vi> <vi>Just <it>check out</it> his new car!</vi> <vi>We're going to the mall to <it>check out</it> that new clothing store.</vi> <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>check it out</phrase> to direct someone's attention to something <vi><it>Check it out</it>—they've got that new book in stock.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>check out (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>check (something) out</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to borrow (something) from a library <vi>He <it>checked out</it> [=<it>took out, borrowed</it>] a book on farming.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to add up the cost of the goods that someone buys in a store (such as a supermarket) and accept payment for them <vi>She got a job <it>checking out</it> groceries at the supermarket.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:to pay for the goods that you buy in a store <vi>There was a long line of people waiting to <it>check out</it> their groceries.</vi> <vi>She was able to <it>check out</it> quickly using her debit card.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check (something or someone) over</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>check over (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look at (something or someone) in a careful way to find problems, mistakes, etc. <vi><it>checking</it> the new cars <it>over</it></vi> <vi>The doctors <it>checked</it> him <it>over</it> for bruises.</vi> <vi>Be sure to <it>check over</it> each item on the list for any mistakes.</vi> <vi>She <it>checked</it> herself <it>over</it> [=she looked at herself carefully] in the mirror before going to the party.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to look at the parts of (a group of things) <vi>I <it>checked through</it> all his letters but found nothing useful.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>check up on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>check up on (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to find or look for information about (someone or something) often in order to find out the truth <vi>My parents are always <it>checking up on</it> me.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>checking up on</it> his alibi.</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>check*able</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an easily <it>checkable</it> fact</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="check[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">check</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃɛk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>checks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act or process of looking at or examining something to find out information or see if there is anything wrong with it <vi>Please give the schedule a <it>check</it> to see if the times are correct.</vi> <vi>I gave the ingredients list a quick <it>check</it> to see if the cereal contained any sugar.</vi> <vi>She ran/did a quick <it>check</it> of the computer to make sure it was working properly.</vi> <vi>They did a <phrase>sound check</phrase> [=tested the sound equipment] before the concert.</vi> <vi>All government employees are subject to a <phrase>security check</phrase>. [=all government employees are investigated to see if they can be trusted]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>keep a close check on</phrase> your blood pressure. [=you should watch your blood pressure closely]</vi> <vi>The police <phrase>ran a check on</phrase> the license plate and found out that the car had been stolen.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something that stops or limits another thing <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>a system that acts/serves as a <it>check on</it> the governor's power [=a system that limits the governor's power]</vi> <vi>The store hired a guard to <phrase>put a check on</phrase> shoplifting. [=to reduce or stop shoplifting]</vi> <vi>The government has lowered interest rates in an attempt to <it>put a check on</it> inflation.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>checks and balances</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>hockey</ssl> <dt>:an act of hitting or stopping a player in order to steal the ball or puck, defend a goal, etc. <vi>He was penalized for an illegal <it>check</it>.</vi> <vi>a hip <it>check</it> [=an act of hitting by bumping with the hips]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>US</vl> <va>check</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>cheque</va></svr> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of paper that is used to make a payment to someone using the money in a bank account <vi>He made out the <it>check</it> to me and signed it, and I deposited it in my account.</vi> <vi>Do you want to pay in cash, by <it>check</it>, or by credit card?</vi> <vi>write/cash/draw a <it>check</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>money order</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>blank check</dxt> <dxt>traveler's check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a bill for the food and drinks that are served in a restaurant <vi>She asked the waiter for the <it>check</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a mark ✓ that is used to show that something (such as an item on a list) has been noted, done, etc. <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>check mark</cat> (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>tick</cat></ca></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to say that something has been noted, done, etc. <vi>“So you'll be here at 6 o'clock on the dot.” “<it>Check</it>.” [=yes, I will be here at 6 o'clock]</vi> <vi>“Do you have the camera?” “<it>Check</it>.” “The umbrella?” “<it>Check</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a room in a restaurant, theater, etc., where you can leave something that you do not want to carry or wear <vi>He left his coat at the <phrase>coat check</phrase>. [=<it>checkroom, coatroom</it>, (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>cloakroom</it>]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>hat check</phrase></vi> <vi>When she was younger she worked as a <phrase>coat-check/hat-check girl</phrase>. [=a woman whose job is to take and return the things that people leave in a checkroom]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a ticket that is given to you when you leave something (such as a hat or a coat) that you will return for later <vi>a baggage <it>check</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rain check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a situation in the game of chess in which a player's king can be captured on the opponent's next turn and must be protected or moved <vi>He moved his bishop and said, “<it>Check</it>!” to show that my king was in <it>check</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>checkmate</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut a check</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in check</dre> <def><dt>:under control <un>used with <it>keep</it> or <it>hold</it> <vi>He's trying to <it>hold</it> his emotions <it>in check</it>. [=he is trying to control his emotions]</vi> <vi>The government has lowered interest rates in an attempt to <it>keep</it> inflation <it>in check</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>check</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="check[3]"> <hw hindex="3">check</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃɛk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a pattern of squares in different colors <vi>a fabric with a blue and yellow <it>check</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>check</it> [=<it>checked, checkered</it>] fabric</vi> <vi>a tablecloth with a <it>check</it> [=<it>checked, checkered</it>] pattern</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>check</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="cheque"> <hw>cheque</hw> <cx><cl>Brit spelling of</cl> <ct>check <ctn>3</ctn></ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="check-in"> <hw>check–in</hw> <sound><wav>check_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃɛkˌɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>check–ins</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act or process of reporting that you have arrived at a hotel, an airport, etc. :the act or process of checking in <vi><it>Check-in</it> was delayed.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the time when people are allowed to check in <vi>When is <it>check-in</it>? = When is <it>check-in</it> time?</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the place where people go when they arrive at a hotel, airport, etc. <vi>When we got to the airport there was a long line at the <it>check-in</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the <it>check-in</it> desk/counter</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>check in</tag> at <dxt>check</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="check mark"> <hw>check mark</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ marks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>check <sxn>5</sxn></sx>a</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blank check"> <hw>blank check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>blank cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a signed check that does not have the amount of money written on it yet</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:complete control or freedom <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>give/hand (someone) a blank check</phrase> <vi>The director had a lot of creative freedom on this project; the film's backers essentially <it>handed him a blank check</it>. [=let him direct the film exactly the way he wanted to]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cashier's check"> <hw>cashier's check</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a check that is written by a bank and signed by a cashier <dx>compare <dxt>bank draft</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="certified check"> <hw>certified check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>certified cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a check that is guaranteed by a bank</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cross-check"> <hw>cross–check</hw> <sound><wav>cross_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkrɑ:sˌtʃɛk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cross–checks</if></in> <in><if>cross–checked</if></in> <in><if>cross–check*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to use a different source or method to check (something, such as information or calculations) <vi>I <it>cross-checked</it> the changes against the original copy. [=I looked at the original copy to make sure that the changes were correct]</vi> <vi>You should <it>cross-check</it> your answers with a calculator.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>cross–check</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cross–checks</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
