<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cheque"> <hw>cheque</hw> <cx><cl>Brit spelling of</cl> <ct>check <ctn>3</ctn></ct></cx></entry>

	<entry id="check[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">check</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃɛk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>checks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act or process of looking at or examining something to find out information or see if there is anything wrong with it <vi>Please give the schedule a <it>check</it> to see if the times are correct.</vi> <vi>I gave the ingredients list a quick <it>check</it> to see if the cereal contained any sugar.</vi> <vi>She ran/did a quick <it>check</it> of the computer to make sure it was working properly.</vi> <vi>They did a <phrase>sound check</phrase> [=tested the sound equipment] before the concert.</vi> <vi>All government employees are subject to a <phrase>security check</phrase>. [=all government employees are investigated to see if they can be trusted]</vi> <vi>You should <phrase>keep a close check on</phrase> your blood pressure. [=you should watch your blood pressure closely]</vi> <vi>The police <phrase>ran a check on</phrase> the license plate and found out that the car had been stolen.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something that stops or limits another thing <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>a system that acts/serves as a <it>check on</it> the governor's power [=a system that limits the governor's power]</vi> <vi>The store hired a guard to <phrase>put a check on</phrase> shoplifting. [=to reduce or stop shoplifting]</vi> <vi>The government has lowered interest rates in an attempt to <it>put a check on</it> inflation.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>checks and balances</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>hockey</ssl> <dt>:an act of hitting or stopping a player in order to steal the ball or puck, defend a goal, etc. <vi>He was penalized for an illegal <it>check</it>.</vi> <vi>a hip <it>check</it> [=an act of hitting by bumping with the hips]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>US</vl> <va>check</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>cheque</va></svr> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of paper that is used to make a payment to someone using the money in a bank account <vi>He made out the <it>check</it> to me and signed it, and I deposited it in my account.</vi> <vi>Do you want to pay in cash, by <it>check</it>, or by credit card?</vi> <vi>write/cash/draw a <it>check</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>money order</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>blank check</dxt> <dxt>traveler's check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a bill for the food and drinks that are served in a restaurant <vi>She asked the waiter for the <it>check</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a mark ✓ that is used to show that something (such as an item on a list) has been noted, done, etc. <ca>called also (<it>US</it>) <cat>check mark</cat> (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <cat>tick</cat></ca></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to say that something has been noted, done, etc. <vi>“So you'll be here at 6 o'clock on the dot.” “<it>Check</it>.” [=yes, I will be here at 6 o'clock]</vi> <vi>“Do you have the camera?” “<it>Check</it>.” “The umbrella?” “<it>Check</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a room in a restaurant, theater, etc., where you can leave something that you do not want to carry or wear <vi>He left his coat at the <phrase>coat check</phrase>. [=<it>checkroom, coatroom</it>, (<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>cloakroom</it>]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>hat check</phrase></vi> <vi>When she was younger she worked as a <phrase>coat-check/hat-check girl</phrase>. [=a woman whose job is to take and return the things that people leave in a checkroom]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a ticket that is given to you when you leave something (such as a hat or a coat) that you will return for later <vi>a baggage <it>check</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>rain check</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a situation in the game of chess in which a player's king can be captured on the opponent's next turn and must be protected or moved <vi>He moved his bishop and said, “<it>Check</it>!” to show that my king was in <it>check</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>checkmate</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut a check</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cut</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in check</dre> <def><dt>:under control <un>used with <it>keep</it> or <it>hold</it> <vi>He's trying to <it>hold</it> his emotions <it>in check</it>. [=he is trying to control his emotions]</vi> <vi>The government has lowered interest rates in an attempt to <it>keep</it> inflation <it>in check</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>check</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="cheque card"> <hw>cheque card</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cards</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a card that you show when you pay for something with a cheque to prove that the bank will pay the amount of the cheque</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blank check"> <hw>blank check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>blank cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a signed check that does not have the amount of money written on it yet</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:complete control or freedom <un>often used in the phrase <phrase>give/hand (someone) a blank check</phrase> <vi>The director had a lot of creative freedom on this project; the film's backers essentially <it>handed him a blank check</it>. [=let him direct the film exactly the way he wanted to]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="certified check"> <hw>certified check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>certified cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a check that is guaranteed by a bank</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="paycheck"> <hw>pay*check</hw> <sound><wav>payche01.wav</wav></sound> <hsl>US</hsl> <pr>ˈpeɪˌtʃɛk</pr> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>pay cheque</va> <pr>ˈpeɪˌtʃɛk</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>pay*checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a check that is used to pay an employee for his or her work <vi>I went to the office to pick up my <it>paycheck</it>.</vi> <vi>a big <it>paycheck</it> [=a paycheck for a large amount of money]</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) We are <phrase>living paycheck to paycheck</phrase> [=we spend all of the money from one paycheck before we receive the next paycheck] and have no money left over for savings.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:the money that you regularly earn :a wage or salary <vi>Your weekly <it>paycheck</it> will be almost $600 after taxes.</vi> <vi>When I was in college, I earned my first <phrase>steady paycheck</phrase> [=I was earning money regularly for the first time] as a waitress.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="traveler's check"> <hw>traveler's check</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>traveller's cheque</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ checks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a check that is paid for in advance and that may be exchanged for or used like cash</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
