<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="chip[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">chip</hw> <sound><wav>chip0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃɪp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chips</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small piece that has been broken off from something larger <vi>wood <it>chips</it></vi> <vi><it>chips</it> of stone</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a place where a small piece of something has broken off <vi>The cup has a <it>chip</it> in/on it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a small piece of candy or chocolate used in baking <vi>chocolate <it>chips</it></vi> <vi><phrase>chocolate chip cookies</phrase> [=cookies with small bits of chocolate in them]</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:a thin, hard, and usually salty piece of food <vi>tortilla <it>chips</it></vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:<sx>potato chip</sx> <vi>a bag of <it>chips</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>corn chip</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>french fry</sx> <dx>see also <dxt>fish and chips</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a small, flat, round piece of plastic that is used to represent an amount of money in gambling games like poker <dx>see also <dxt>bargaining chip</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a very small piece of hard material (called silicon) in a computer or other device that contains many electronic circuits <vi>computer/silicon <it>chips</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>microchip</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a piece of dried waste matter from an animal <vi>buffalo/cow <it>chips</it></vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:<sx>chip shot <sxn>1</sxn> <sxn>2</sxn></sx></dt></def> <dro><dre>chip off the old block</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:someone who looks or behaves like his or her parent <vi>His son is a real <it>chip off the old block</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a chip on your shoulder</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to have an angry or unpleasant attitude or way of behaving caused by a belief that you have been treated unfairly in the past <vi>He <it>has had a chip on his shoulder</it> ever since he didn't get the promotion he was expecting.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let the chips fall where they may</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to allow events to happen without trying to change them <snote>This phrase usually suggests that you are willing to accept a result, whatever it may be. <vi>I will run the best campaign I can, then <it>let the chips fall where they may</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>when the chips are down</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a difficult situation :when things are not good <vi>True friends will stand by you <it>when the chips are down</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chip[2]"> <hw hindex="2">chip</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃɪp</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>chips</if></in> <in><if>chipped</if></in> <in><if>chip*ping</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to break off a small piece from (something) <vi>I bit into something hard and <it>chipped</it> my tooth.</vi> <vi>He fell and <it>chipped</it> a bone in his knee.</vi> <vi>She <it>chipped</it> a nail. [=she broke a small piece of hardened nail polish off a fingernail]</vi> <vi>a <it>chipped</it> cup/tooth</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break or come off in small pieces <vi>China <it>chips</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The paint had <it>chipped</it> off/away.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to break off (something) especially with a tool <vi>He <it>chipped</it> away the ice from the car's windshield.</vi> <vi>The sculptor <it>chipped</it> away/off bits of stone.</vi> <vi>The geologist <it>chipped</it> [=<it>cut</it>] the specimen out of the rock face.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to hit something with a tool in order to break off small pieces <un>usually + <it>away</it> <vi>The sculptor <phrase>chipped away at</phrase> the stone/marble.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>There have been endless efforts to <it>chip away at</it> [=gradually reduce] social prejudice.</vi> <vi>His failures <it>chipped away at</it> his self-confidence.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to hit or kick (a ball) so that it goes a short distance :to hit or kick a chip shot <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The golfer <it>chipped</it> the ball onto the green.</vi> <vi>She <it>chipped</it> the soccer ball over the goalie's head.</vi> <vi>He <it>chipped</it> a pass to his teammate.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The golfer <it>chipped</it> onto the green.</vi> <vi>She <it>chipped</it> in for par. [=she made a par by hitting a chip shot that went into the hole]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>chip in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>chip in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>chip in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give something (such as money) to help a person, group, or cause <vi>We all <it>chipped in</it> [=<it>contributed</it>] to buy him a gift.</vi> <vi>If we all <it>chip in</it> [=<it>help</it> (<it>out</it>)], the work will get done quickly.</vi> <vi>We each <it>chipped in</it> 10 dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to add your comment or opinion to a conversation or discussion <vi>“He left hours ago,” Sue <it>chipped in</it>. [=<it>chimed in</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="chip shop"> <hw>chip shop</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ shops</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:a restaurant that sells fish and chips and other fried foods for people to take away and eat somewhere else</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="chip shot"> <hw>chip shot</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ shots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>golf</ssl> <dt>:a very short shot that is made from an area near the green <vi>She hit a <it>chip shot</it> onto the green.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>soccer + rugby</ssl> <dt>:a short kick that lifts a ball high in the air <vi>He kicked a <it>chip shot</it> over the goalie's head.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>American football</ssl> <dt>:a short and easy field goal</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="bargaining chip"> <hw>bargaining chip</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ chips</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something that can be used to gain an advantage when you are trying to make a deal or an agreement <vi>The workers used the threat of a strike as a <it>bargaining chip</it> in their negotiations for a new contract.</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>bargaining counter</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blue-chip"> <hw>blue–chip</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:valuable and likely to make a good profit :not likely to cause investors to lose money <vi><it>blue-chip</it> companies/stocks</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:very good :<sx>excellent</sx> <vi>a <it>blue-chip</it> [=<it>first-class, first-rate</it>] artist/athlete/wine</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="corn chip"> <hw>corn chip</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ chips</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small, flat piece of fried cornmeal that is eaten cold as a snack</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="potato chip"> <hw>potato chip</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ chips</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a thin slice of potato that is fried or sometimes baked and usually salted <vi>I had a sandwich and a bag of <it>potato chips</it> for lunch.</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>crisp</cat> (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>potato crisp</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="tortilla chip"> <hw>tortilla chip</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ chips</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a thin, hard piece of food (called a chip) that is made from corn and usually salted <vi>We had salsa and <it>tortilla chips</it> as an appetizer.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="block[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">block</hw> <sound><wav>bloc0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblɑ:k</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>blocks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a solid piece of material (such as rock or wood) that has flat sides and is usually square or rectangular in shape <vi>a <it>block</it> of ice/cheese</vi> <vi>a wall built out of concrete/cinder <it>blocks</it></vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) kids playing with wooden <it>blocks</it> [=(<it>Brit</it>) <it>bricks</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>building block</dxt> <dxt>chopping block</dxt> <dxt>starting block</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an area of land surrounded by four streets in a city <vi>We took a walk around the <it>block</it>.</vi> <vi>She lived on our <it>block</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:the length of one city block <vi>The store is three <it>blocks</it> down on the right.</vi> <vi>Our hotel is a <it>block</it> from the ocean.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large building divided into separate units (such as apartments or shops) <vi>an apartment <it>block</it></vi> <snote>This sense of <it>block</it> is more common in British English than in U.S. English. <vi>a high-rise office <it>block</it></vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>block of flats</dxt> <dxt>cellblock</dxt> <dxt>tower block</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that stops the progress or achievement of something <vi>They put a <it>block</it> on future development of the area.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:an action or movement that stops or slows down an opponent <vi>a shoulder <it>block</it></vi> <vi>(American football) The lineman <phrase>threw a block</phrase>. [=the lineman hit an opposing player to prevent him from making a tackle]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:something that stops a person from thinking about certain things <vi>a mental/emotional <it>block</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stumbling block</dxt> <dxt>writer's block</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a number of similar things that form a group <vi>We reserved a <it>block</it> of seats.</vi> <vi>She bought a large <it>block</it> of stock/shares in the company.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an amount or section of something <vi>They played a half-hour <it>block</it> of music.</vi> <vi>We set aside a big <it>block</it> of time for the project.</vi> <vi>a <it>block</it> of text</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>chip off the old block</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>knock someone's block off</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>new kid on the block</dre> <dx>see <dxt>kid</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the block</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>on the auction block</va></vr> <def><dt>:for sale at an auction <vi>Some valuable paintings went <it>on the block</it> today.</vi></dt> <sd>broadly</sd> <dt>:for sale <vi>Their business is now <it>on the block</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
