<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="choice[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">choice</hw> <sound><wav>choice01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtʃoɪs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>choic*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the act of choosing :the act of picking or deciding between two or more possibilities <vi>He knew he had to make a <it>choice</it>. [=choose one thing or another]</vi> <vi>He has some important <it>choices</it> to make.</vi> <vi>You made a good/bad <it>choice</it>.</vi> <vi>She was faced with a difficult <it>choice</it>.</vi> <vi>You can either accept the job or not. It's your <it>choice</it>.</vi> <vi>I read about the various options so that I could make an informed <it>choice</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the opportunity or power to choose between two or more possibilities :the opportunity or power to make a decision <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>Given the <it>choice</it>, I'd rather stay home tonight.</vi> <vi>He had no <it>choice</it> in the matter. = He did not have a <it>choice</it> in the matter.</vi> <vi>You leave me (with) no <it>choice</it>.</vi> <vi>They gave/offered me a <it>choice</it> between an automatic or standard transmission.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>A flexible health insurance plan gives patients more <it>choice</it> about doctors and coverage.</vi> <vi>He had little <it>choice</it> in the matter. = He did not have much <it>choice</it> in the matter.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hobson's choice</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a range of things that can be chosen <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>The plan has a wide <it>choice of</it> options. [=there are many options that can be chosen]</vi> <vi>You have the <it>choice of</it> coffee or tea.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The menu does not have much <it>choice</it>. [=<it>selection</it>]</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) Customers are <phrase>spoiled for choice</phrase> [=customers have a lot of choices] when buying a new car.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the things that you can choose <vi>She wanted pizza, but that wasn't a <it>choice</it>. [=<it>option</it>]</vi> <vi>There is a wide range of <it>choices</it>.</vi> <vi>Other <it>choices</it> on the menu looked equally tempting.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>multiple-choice</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the person or thing that someone chooses <vi>He is happy with his <it>choice</it>.</vi> <vi>She is my first <it>choice</it> for the job. [=she is the one I most want for the job]</vi> <vi>I don't like her <it>choice</it> of friends.</vi> <vi>Selling our car was the right <it>choice</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by choice</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>out of choice</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If you do something <it>by choice</it> or <it>out of choice</it>, you choose to do it. <vi>I live here <it>by choice</it>. [=I live here because I want to]</vi> <vi>No one forced them to do it. They acted <it>out of choice</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of choice</dre> <def><dt>:favorite or most liked :chosen most often <vi>Wine was his beverage <it>of choice</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of your choice</dre> <def><dt><snote>A person or thing <it>of your choice</it> is a person or thing that you have chosen. <vi>They said I could bring a guest <it>of my choice</it> to the party.</vi> <vi>The meal is served with a beverage <it>of your choice</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="choice[2]"> <hw hindex="2">choice</hw> <altpr>ˈtʃoɪs</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <in><if>choic*er</if></in> <in><if>choic*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:very good <vi>The store sells only the <it>choicest</it> [=<it>best</it>] fruits.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of meat</ssl> <dt>:of a quality that is good but not the best <vi><it>Choice</it> beef is not as expensive as prime beef.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of words or phrases</ssl> <dt>:carefully chosen especially for the purpose of expressing anger or disapproval <vi>I had a few <it>choice</it> words for him. [=I said a few angry words to him]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="Hobson's choice"> <hw>Hob*son's choice</hw> <sound><wav>hobson01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑ:bsənz-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ choices</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a situation in which you are supposed to make a choice but do not have a real choice because there is only one thing you can have or do <vi>He jokingly referred to dinner as a <it>Hobson's choice</it> between soup and salad or salad and soup.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="multiple-choice"> <hw>multiple–choice</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having several answers from which one is to be chosen <vi>a <it>multiple-choice</it> question</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:made up of multiple-choice questions <vi>a <it>multiple-choice</it> test</vi> <vi>The exam will be <it>multiple-choice</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="pro-choice"> <hw>pro–choice</hw> <sound><wav>procho01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>proʊˈtʃoɪs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:believing that pregnant women should have the right to choose to have an abortion <vi><it>pro-choice</it> supporters/groups</vi> <vi>The governor has taken a <it>pro-choice</it> position. = The governor is <it>pro-choice</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>pro-life</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
