<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="circumstance"> <hw highlight="yes">cir*cum*stance</hw> <sound><wav>circum29.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɚkəmˌstæns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cir*cum*stanc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a condition or fact that affects a situation <vi>I can't imagine a <it>circumstance</it> in/under which I would do that.</vi> <un>usually plural <vi>If our business is to survive, we must be able to adapt to changing <it>circumstances</it>.</vi> <vi>It is impossible <phrase>under these circumstances</phrase> to meet our deadline.</vi> <vi>Do not, <phrase>under any circumstances</phrase>, open that door. = <phrase>Under no circumstances</phrase> are you to open that door. [=no matter what happens, do not open that door]</vi> <vi>Due to <phrase>circumstances beyond our control</phrase> [=things that have happened that we cannot change or influence], the flight is canceled.</vi> <vi>There is nothing we can do <phrase>under the circumstances</phrase>. [=in this specific situation]</vi> <vi><phrase>Given the circumstances</phrase>, I think we did well. [=when you consider how everything went, I think we did well]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>circumstances</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the way something happens :the specific details of an event <vi>The <it>circumstances</it> of his death are suspicious.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an event or situation that you cannot control <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She says that her client is <phrase>a victim of circumstance</phrase> and should not be blamed for the accident.</vi> <wsgram>plural</wsgram> <vi>He was <phrase>a victim of circumstances</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>circumstances</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the conditions in which someone lives <vi>Their <it>circumstances</it> changed dramatically after she lost her job.</vi> <vi>I don't know anything about his <phrase>financial circumstances</phrase>. [=about how much money he has]</vi> <vi>They have been forced to live in <phrase>reduced circumstances</phrase>. [=to live with less money]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>pomp and circumstance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pomp</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="pomp"> <hw>pomp</hw> <sound><wav>pomp0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈpɑ:mp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the impressive decorations, music, clothing etc., that are part of some formal events <vi>the <it>pomp</it> [=<it>splendor</it>] of a royal ceremony</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>pomp and circumstance</dre> <def><dt>:impressive formal activities or ceremonies <vi>The prime minister was greeted with <it>pomp and circumstance</it>.</vi> <vi>the <it>pomp and circumstance</it> of a presidential inauguration</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
