<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="civil"> <hw highlight="yes">civ*il</hw> <sound><wav>civil001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɪvəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:of or relating to the people who live in a country <vi><it>civil</it> liberties/duties</vi> <vi>a period of <it>civil</it> unrest [=a time when groups of people in a country fight one another]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>civil disobedience</dxt> <dxt>civil war</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:of or relating to the regular business of the people in a city, town, state, etc. :not connected to the military or to a religion <vi>They got married in a <it>civil</it> ceremony at city hall.</vi> <vi><it>civil</it> institutions</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <sgram>more civ*il; most civ*il</sgram> <dt>:polite but not friendly :only as polite as a person needs to be in order to not be rude <vi>It was hard to be <it>civil</it> when I felt so angry.</vi> <vi>She was barely <it>civil</it> to me.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>uncivil</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>more civ*il; most civ*il</sgram> <dt>:caring about art, science, government, people's well-being, etc. <vi>She argues that a <it>civil</it> [=(more commonly) <it>civilized</it>] society takes care of its weakest members.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>uncivil</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:relating to laws that describe a person's rights rather than to laws about crime <vi>The couple filed a <it>civil</it> suit against the company that made the crib.</vi> <vi><it>civil</it> cases</vi> <vi>rules of <it>civil</it> procedure</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>criminal <dxn>2</dxn></dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>civil law</dxt> <dxt>civil liberty</dxt> <dxt>civil rights</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>civ*il*ly</ure> <sound><wav>civill01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsɪvəli</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>The couple couldn't even discuss things <it>civilly</it> [=<it>politely</it>] anymore.</vi> <vi>“Thank you for helping me, sir,” she said <it>civilly</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="civil defense"> <hw>civil defense</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>civil defence</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a group of people who are not part of the military but are trained to protect and help people if an enemy attacks their country or if there is a natural disaster (such as a flood or earthquake) <vi>She's in training to be part of the local <it>civil defense</it>.</vi> <vi>the head of <it>civil defense</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil disobedience"> <hw>civil disobedience</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:refusal to obey laws as a way of forcing the government to do or change something <vi>In an act of <it>civil disobedience</it>, the family sent its tax money to an antiwar organization.</vi> <vi>A student organization is encouraging <it>civil disobedience</it> as a way to get the university to change its policies.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil engineering"> <hw>civil engineering</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a type of engineering that deals with the science of designing and building roads, bridges, large buildings, etc. <vi>He has a degree in <it>civil engineering</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>civil engineer</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -neers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="civil law"> <hw>civil law</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:laws that deal with the rights of people rather than with crimes <dx>compare <dxt>criminal law</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil liberty"> <hw>civil liberty</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ties</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:the right of people to do or say things that are not illegal without being stopped or interrupted by the government <vi>Freedom of speech is a <it>civil liberty</it>.</vi> <un>usually plural <vi>Opponents said the law would threaten <it>civil liberties</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil marriage"> <hw>civil marriage</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -riages</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a marriage performed by a person (such as a justice of the peace) who is not a religious leader <vi>a mayor who has officiated at several <it>civil marriages</it> this year</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil rights"> <hw>civil rights</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <dt>:the rights that every person should have regardless of his or her sex, race, or religion <vi>Martin Luther King, Jr., fought for <it>civil rights</it>.</vi> <vi>The U.S. <it>civil rights</it> movement achieved equal rights legislation for African-Americans.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil servant"> <hw>civil servant</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -vants</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person who works for the government :a person who works in the civil service</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="civil service"> <hw>civil service</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the civil service</dre> <def><dt>:the part of a government that takes care of the government's basic business :the administrative part of a government <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>civil service</it> employee</vi> <vi>the <it>civil service</it> system</vi> <vi>I took the <it>civil service</it> exam. [=I took a test to get a job in the civil service]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
