<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="claim[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">claim</hw> <sound><wav>claim001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkleɪm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>claims</if></in> <in><if>claimed</if></in> <in><if>claim*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say that (something) is true when some people may say it is not true <vi>The man <it>claimed</it> (that) he was a long-lost relative.</vi> <vi>They <it>claim</it> (that) the drug prevents hair loss.</vi> <vi>She <it>claims</it> (that) the landlord owes her money.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>He <it>claims to know</it> nothing about the robbery.</vi> <vi>He <it>claims to be</it> an expert.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to say that you have (something) <vi>He <it>claims</it> a connection to British royalty.</vi> <vi>The organization <it>claims</it> 10,000 members.</vi> <vi>He <it>claimed</it> ignorance of the robbery. [=he said that he had no knowledge about the robbery]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to say that (something) belongs to you or that you deserve (something) <vi>The terrorist group <it>claimed</it> responsibility for the attack.</vi> <vi>New Yorkers proudly <it>claim</it> the artist as one of their own.</vi> <vi>Both of them <it>claimed</it> credit for the idea.</vi> <vi>No one ever <it>claimed</it> authorship for the poem.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to say that you have a legal right to be given (something) <vi>You should <it>claim</it> compensation for the hours you worked.</vi> <vi>No heirs came forward to <it>claim</it> the inheritance.</vi> <vi>They <it>claimed</it> asylum.</vi> <vi>You can <it>claim</it> these expenses as tax deductions. [=you can say that you should be able to pay less money in taxes because of these expenses]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to take (something that belongs to you or that you deserve) <vi>She <it>claimed</it> her baggage and left the airport.</vi> <vi>The exiled king returned to <it>claim</it> his rightful place on the throne.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone's attention, time, etc., is being given to something <vi>An urgent message <it>claimed</it> [=<it>required, demanded</it>] his attention.</vi> <vi>This issue has already <it>claimed</it> too much of our time. [=we have already spent too much time on this issue]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to cause the end of someone's life <vi>The accident <it>claimed</it> seven victims. [=seven people were killed in the accident]</vi> <vi>the fatal illness that <phrase>claimed her life</phrase> [=caused her death]</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>claim*able</ure> <sound><wav>claim002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkleɪməbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi><it>claimable</it> expenses</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="claim[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">claim</hw> <altpr>ˈkleɪm</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>claims</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a statement saying that something happened a certain way or will happen a certain way :a statement saying that something is true when some people may say it is not true <vi>She makes the <it>claim</it> that sea levels will actually go down.</vi> <vi>He made false <it>claims</it> about his past job experience.</vi> <vi>The book makes some extravagant <it>claims</it>. [=it includes statements that many people will not agree with]</vi> <vi>She disputes/denies the <it>claim</it> [=she says it isn't true] that she was unfaithful to her husband.</vi> <vi>I make no <it>claim</it> to be an expert. [=I don't say that I am an expert]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an official request for something (such as money) that is owed to you or that you believe is owed to you <vi>You'll need to file an insurance <it>claim</it> to pay for the damage.</vi> <vi>make a <it>claim</it> on your insurance policy</vi> <vi>All <it>claims</it> must be made in writing.</vi> <vi>Please fill out this <phrase>claim form</phrase>. [=a document with information about why you should be given money]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a right to have something <un>usually + <it>on</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>The bank has a <it>claim on/to</it> their house and land.</vi> <vi>The book would have little <it>claim on</it> our attention if not for the fact that its story is true.</vi> <vi>the family's <it>claim to</it> the name</vi></un> <snote>To <phrase>lay claim to (something)</phrase> is to say that it belongs to you or that you have a right to it. <vi>She <it>laid claim to</it> the ring.</vi> <vi>The community <it>lays claim to</it> (the honor of) being the oldest city in the country. [=it claims to be the oldest city in the country]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:an area of land that you take as your own often for a specified use <vi>a mining/timber <it>claim</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>baggage claim</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>baggage claim area</va></vr> <def><dt>:the area in an airport or bus station where you pick up your luggage after traveling <vi>Call when your plane gets in and I'll meet you at (the) <it>baggage claim</it>.</vi> <vi>at the <it>baggage claim area</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>claim to fame</dre> <def><dt>:something that someone or something is famous for or that makes someone or something important or interesting <vi>His <it>claim to fame</it> is the invention of the stapler.</vi> <vi>The restaurant's <it>claim to fame</it> is its barbecue sauce.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stake (out) a claim</dre> <dx>see <dxt>stake</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="fame"> <hw highlight="yes">fame</hw> <sound><wav>fame0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfeɪm</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the condition of being known or recognized by many people <vi>He died at the height of his <it>fame</it>.</vi> <vi>The book tells the story of her sudden rise to <it>fame</it>.</vi> <vi>He gained/found <it>fame</it> as an actor.</vi> <vi>The house was once occupied by Noah Webster of dictionary <it>fame</it>. [=Noah Webster, who was famous for his dictionary]</vi> <vi>achieving/earning/winning international/worldwide <it>fame</it></vi> <vi>She went to Hollywood seeking <it>fame</it> and fortune.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hall of fame</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>claim to fame</dre> <dx>see <dxt>claim</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="lay[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">lay</hw> <sound><wav>lay00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈleɪ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>lays</if></in> <in><if>laid</if> <sound><wav>lay00002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈleɪd</pr></in> <in><if>lay*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to place (someone or something) down gently in a flat position <vi><it>Lay</it> the fabric carefully on the table.</vi> <vi>He <it>laid</it> a gentle hand on her shoulder.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid</it> the baby in his crib for a nap.</vi> <vi>He says that he never <phrase>laid a finger/hand on</phrase> her. [=that he never touched her]</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi>He <it>laid</it> the newspaper <it>down</it> on the desk.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid</it> the baby down for his nap.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>lay down <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) into position on or along a surface :to build or set (something) on or in the ground or another surface <vi>When will they <it>lay</it> the foundation for the addition?</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> tracks for the new railroad</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> pipe/cable/lines</vi> <vi><it>laying</it> bricks</vi> <un>often + <it>down</it> <vi><it>laying down</it> a new road/carpet</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>We are <phrase>laying the groundwork/foundation</phrase> [=providing conditions] for additional research.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to spread (something) over a surface <vi><it>lay</it> plaster/paint</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> wallpaper</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:<sx>bury <sxn>1</sxn></sx>a <vi>They <it>laid</it> him in his grave.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be in a flat position on a surface :<sx>lie</sx> <vi>The book was <it>laying</it> on the table.</vi> <snote>The use of <it>lay</it> to mean “lie” occurs commonly in informal speech but it is regarded as an error by many people.</snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to beat or strike (something) down with force <vi>The wheat was <phrase>laid flat</phrase> by the wind and rain.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to change the condition of something in a specified way <vi>The mountainside has been <phrase>laid bare</phrase> by loggers. [=all the trees on the mountainside have been cut down by loggers]</vi> <vi>He <it>laid bare</it> his soul. = He <it>laid</it> his soul <it>bare</it>. [=he revealed his most private thoughts and feelings]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>laid himself open</phrase> to criticism [=he exposed himself to criticism] with his remarks.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>of a bird, insect, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to produce (an egg) outside of the body :to push (an egg) out of the body <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>birds that typically <it>lay</it> only two eggs per year</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>old chickens that no longer <it>lay</it></vi> <dx>see also <tag>lay an egg</tag> at <dxt>egg</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt><un>used like <it>make, place</it>, or <it>put</it> in various phrases <vi>She has <phrase>laid plans</phrase> [=she has made plans] to cut the staff down to just 15 people.</vi> <vi>Even the <phrase>best-laid plans</phrase> [=the most carefully made plans] sometimes go wrong.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>lays great stress/emphasis</phrase> on good manners. [=she stresses/emphasizes good manners very much]</vi> <vi>The author <phrase>lays the blame/responsibility</phrase> for the state of the environment squarely on the government. [=the author blames the government for the state of the environment]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something) ready :to prepare (something) <vi><it>lay</it> a trap</vi> <vi><it>lay</it> a fire in the fireplace</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Places were <it>laid</it> (at the table) for three people. [=silverware, glasses, and napkins were put on the table for three people who will be eating there]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) <it>lay</it> [=<it>set</it>] the table for a meal</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to risk losing (money) if your guess about what will happen is wrong :<sx>bet</sx> <vi><it>lay</it> money on a race</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal + offensive</ssl> <dt>:to have sex with someone <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>get laid</phrase> <vi>All he cares about is <it>getting laid</it>. [=having sex]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>lay aside</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) aside</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay aside (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to place (something) to one side <vi>She <it>laid aside</it> [=<it>put aside, set aside</it>] the book she had been reading and turned on the TV.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Plans for a new school have been <it>laid aside</it>. [=<it>put aside, set aside</it>]</vi> <vi>It's time for all of us to <it>lay aside</it> old prejudices.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>lay</it> our differences <it>aside</it> so that we can learn to work together.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep (something) for special or future use :to reserve or save (something) :to keep (something) for special or future use <vi>She has been able to <it>lay aside</it> [=<it>put aside</it>] a few dollars each week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay by (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (something) for special or future use <vi>She has been able to <it>lay by</it> [=<it>lay aside</it>] a few dollars each week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay charges</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to accuse someone officially of doing something illegal <vi>Police are deciding whether to <it>lay charges</it> (against her).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay claim to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>claim</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to clearly state (a rule, standard, guideline, etc.) <vi>The company has <it>laid down</it> strict new safety standards.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop using (something) <vi>At noon, we <it>laid down</it> the rakes and rested for a while.</vi> <vi>The strikers <it>laid down</it> their tools.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (a weapon) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay down (a weapon)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to put (a weapon) down and stop fighting <vi>The police ordered the criminals to <it>lay down</it> their weapons.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay down your life</pva></phrasev> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to give up your life for a good purpose :to die for a good cause <vi>heroes who <it>laid down their lives</it> to preserve our nation</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay down the law</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make a strong statement about what someone is or is not allowed to do <vi>The agreement <it>lays down the law</it> (to everyone) on what the group allows.</vi> <vi>When she came home after midnight, her father <it>laid down the law</it>: if she came home that late again, she would not be allowed to watch TV for a week.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>lay <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay hold of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get and store (a supply of something) for future use <vi>They <it>laid in</it> [=<it>laid up</it>] canned goods for the winter.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>lay into (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to angrily attack or criticize (someone or something) <vi>The coach really <it>laid into</it> us for playing so carelessly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay it on the line</dre> <dx>see <dxt>line</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop employing (someone) because there is not enough work <vi>The company has had to <it>lay off</it> most of the staff.</vi> <vi>Costs have increased and many workers have been <it>laid off</it>. [=<it>let go</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>layoff</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay off (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop doing, using, eating, or drinking (something) <vi>You should <it>lay off</it> the late nights. [=you should stop staying up so late]</vi> <vi>My doctor advised me to <it>lay off</it> caffeine.</vi> <vi>He's a much nicer person since he <it>laid off</it> the booze. [=since he stopped drinking alcohol]</vi> <vi>I need to <it>lay off</it> fatty foods and lose some weight.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to leave someone alone :to stop annoying someone <vi>I wish you'd just <it>lay off</it>!</vi> <vi><it>Lay off</it> me! [=stop bothering me]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) on</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay on (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to spread (something) over a surface <vi>Try to <it>lay</it> the grout <it>on</it> the surface evenly.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>(<it>informal</it>) My parents have been <it>laying</it> a lot of guilt <it>on</it> me. [=have been saying things that make me feel guilty]</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) If you have something to tell me, just <it>lay</it> it <it>on</it> me. [=just tell me]</vi> <vi>He <it>laid</it> the flattery <it>on</it> pretty heavily.</vi> <vi>She <it>laid on</it> a fake southern accent. [=she spoke with a southern accent although she doesn't usually speak that way]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to provide (something) for someone <vi>If a lot of people want to come, more coaches will be <it>laid on</it> for them.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay it on (thick)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to speak in a way that is exaggerated and not sincere <vi>You should compliment her cooking but don't <it>lay it on too thick</it> or she'll know you don't mean it.</vi> <vi>He <it>laid it on</it> pretty heavily and pretended to be interested in what she said.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to place (something) on a surface in a carefully arranged way <vi>The wires were <it>laid out</it> along the floor.</vi> <vi>Brochures were <it>laid out</it> on a table.</vi> <vi>She was <it>laying out</it> the cheese and crackers for the guests.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to arrange (something) in a particular pattern or design <vi>The garden was <it>laid out</it> in a formal pattern.</vi> <vi>Much of Manhattan is <it>laid out</it> in the form of a grid.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>layout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to plan the details of (something) <vi>She's been hired to <it>lay out</it> [=<it>map out</it>] the election campaign.</vi> <vi>The work for tomorrow is all <it>laid out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to explain the details of (something) <vi>He <it>laid out</it> the reasons for his decision.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to spend (money) <vi>The city <it>laid out</it> millions of dollars for the new stadium.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>outlay</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone's body) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (someone's body)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prepare (someone's dead body) so that it can be seen by family and friends before it is buried <vi>They <it>laid</it> him <it>out</it> in a plain coffin.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make (someone) unconscious :to knock (someone) out <vi>He <it>laid</it> his opponent <it>out</it> with a hard right to the jaw.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay over</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to make a stop in the middle of a journey <vi>Our flight to Italy <it>laid over</it> in Madrid for several hours.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) over</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stop in the middle of a journey <un>usually used as <it>(be) laid over</it> <vi>We <it>were laid over</it> in Madrid for several hours.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>layover</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay siege to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>siege</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay (someone) to rest</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay to rest (something)</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>lay (something) to rest</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>rest</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to store (something) <vi><it>lay up</it> [=<it>lay in</it>] grain for the winter</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take (something) out of active use or service <vi>We <it>laid up</it> the boat for the winter.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>lay (someone) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>lay up (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to stay at home or in bed because of illness or injury <vi>The flu <it>laid him up</it> for two weeks.</vi> <un>usually used as <it>(be) laid up</it> <vi>He <it>was laid up</it> for six weeks with a bad back.</vi> <vi>He <it>was laid up</it> by the flu.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay waste to</dre> <def><dt>:to cause very bad damage to (something) <vi>The fire <it>laid waste to</it> the land. [=the fire caused great destruction to the land]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay your hands on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hand</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the goose that lays the golden egg</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goose</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="life[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">life</hw> <sound><wav>life0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪf</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>lives</if> <sound><wav>life0002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlaɪvz</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to grow, change, etc., that separates plants and animals from things like water or rocks <vi>He believes that God gives <it>life</it> to all creatures.</vi> <vi>the miracle of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>eternal/everlasting <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the period of time when a person is alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She knew what she wanted to do <phrase>early in life</phrase>. [=when she was young]</vi> <vi>He became famous relatively <phrase>late in life</phrase>. [=at a relatively old age]</vi> <vi>He became famous <phrase>later in life</phrase>. = He became famous <phrase>in later life</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She was happy and healthy for most of her <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>The people in her family tend to have long/short <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>I've known her all my <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>He is nearing the end of his <it>life</it>.</vi> <vi>They spent their whole/entire <it>lives</it> in one town. = They lived in one town all their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>People can expect to change jobs several times in their <it>life/lives</it>.</vi> <vi>They've been waiting their whole/entire <it>life/lives</it> for an opportunity like this.</vi> <vi>This is the financial opportunity <phrase>of his life</phrase>. [=<it>of his lifetime</it>; the best chance in his life to make money]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the experience of being alive <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want out of <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>He believes in living <it>life</it> to the fullest. [=in living a very full and rich life]</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>The details of everyday/ordinary <it>life</it> can be fascinating.</vi> <vi><it>life</it> in the city/country = city/country <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Sometimes <it>life</it> just isn't fair.</vi> <vi>We can laugh at things in movies that would scare us in <phrase>real life</phrase>. [=in a real situation; in actual existence]</vi> <vi>Oh well, <phrase>that's life</phrase>! [=bad things will happen, and you have to deal with them]</vi> <vi>Despite the political upheaval, for most people <phrase>life goes on</phrase> as usual. [=the activities of life continue in the usual way]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>What do you really want to do with your <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>Her children say that she has ruined their <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>She talked about the men in her <it>life</it>. [=the men she has had a romantic or close relationship with during her life]</vi> <vi>She has dedicated/devoted <it>her life</it> to helping other people.</vi> <vi>All this paperwork has made my <it>life</it> much more difficult.</vi> <vi>They're trying to <phrase>get/put their lives back together</phrase>. [=to begin living in a normal way after suffering loss, hardship, etc.]</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>the love of my life</phrase>. [=the person I loved more than any other person at any time in my life]</vi> <vi>I've never heard such a silly idea <phrase>in all my life</phrase>! [=at any time] = Never <phrase>in my life</phrase> have I heard such a silly idea!</vi> <vi>They're old enough to <phrase>run/live their own lives</phrase>. [=to make their own decisions about how to live]</vi> <vi>After all the problems they've had recently, they just want to <phrase>get/move on with their lives</phrase>. [=to continue living their lives in the usual way]</vi> <vi>I'm not surprised that I didn't get the job. That's <phrase>the story of my life</phrase>. [=that's the way things usually or always happen in my life]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>She told us her <phrase>life story</phrase>. [=she told us about many of the things that had happened to her in her life]</vi> <vi>a lack of <phrase>life experience</phrase> [=experience and knowledge gained through living]</vi></un> <snote>If your <phrase>life flashes/passes before your eyes</phrase> or if your <phrase>life flashes/passes before you</phrase>, many memories from different parts of your life quickly appear in your mind one after the other. <vi>Her <it>life flashed before her eyes</it> when her car was about to crash.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a specified part of a person's life <vi>He talked about his <it>life</it> as an artist.</vi> <vi>the social <it>lives</it> of college students</vi> <vi>How's your love/sex <it>life</it>?</vi> <vi>They had difficult home <it>lives</it> when they were children.</vi> <vi>They are trying to keep their personal/private <it>lives</it> separate from their public <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>the responsibilities of their family <it>life</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a specified way or manner of living <vi>He lived/led a <it>life</it> of crime. [=he was a criminal]</vi> <vi>They have lived/led sheltered <it>lives</it>.</vi> <vi>He is trying to make a better <it>life</it> for himself and his family.</vi> <snote>Your <phrase>way of life</phrase> is how you live your life. <vi>a fisherman's <it>way of life</it></vi> <vi>Most people don't approve of my <it>way of life</it>.</vi> <vi>a traditional <it>way of life</it></vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition of being alive <vi>They spared the horse's <it>life</it>. [=they did not kill the horse]</vi> <vi>She feels that her <it>life</it> is in danger. = She <phrase>fears for her life</phrase>. = She is <phrase>in fear for her life</phrase>. [=she feels that she is in danger of being killed]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>risked her life</phrase> [=she did something very dangerous that could have resulted in her death] to help him.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>gave/sacrificed her life</phrase> [=she did something that resulted in her death] for her country.</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>running for his life</phrase>. [=he was running to escape from great danger]</vi> <vi>He is <phrase>fighting for his life</phrase>. [=he is very sick or injured and may die]</vi> <vi>A would-be assassin <phrase>made an attempt on the President's life</phrase>. [=tried to kill the President]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:living things of a specified kind or in a specified place <vi>There may be a great deal of animal/plant <it>life</it> still to be discovered in this region.</vi> <vi>forest <it>life</it></vi> <vi>ocean <it>life</it></vi> <vi>Will we ever find intelligent <it>life</it> on other planets?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the time when something can be used :the period when something exists or is useful or effective <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>battery <it>life</it></vi> <vi>the <it>life</it> of an insurance policy</vi> <vi>They claim that using their product will extend the <it>life</it> of the car.</vi> <vi>a warranty that is good for the <it>life</it> of the product</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a product that extends the <it>lives</it> of the rugs/cars</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>half-life</dxt> <dxt>shelf life</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:energy and spirit <vi>eyes full of <it>life</it></vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) suck the <it>life</it> out of a room [=take all the fun and energy out of a group of people in a room]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:activity and movement <vi>The streets were humming with <it>life</it>. [=the streets were filled with people and activity]</vi> <vi>There were no signs of <it>life</it> in the deserted village.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a book that tells about the life of a person :<sx>biography</sx> <vi>She wrote a <it>life</it> of Napoleon.</vi> <vi>Boswell's <it>Life of Johnson</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the punishment of being kept in a prison for the rest of your life :<sx>life imprisonment</sx> <vi>He was found guilty and sentenced to <it>life</it>. = (<it>informal</it>) He got <it>life</it>. = He was given <it>life</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a dog's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a life of its own</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <phrase>takes on a life of its own</phrase> becomes very large, important, or hard to control. <vi>The project soon <it>took on a life of its own</it> and prevented us from getting any other work done.</vi> <vi>The story <it>took on a life of its own</it> and began to appear on news broadcasts everywhere.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>all walks of life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>every walk of life</va></vr> <dx>see <dxt>walk</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a matter of life and death</dre> <def><dt>:something that is extremely important and often involves decisions that will determine whether someone lives or dies <vi>Being prepared for severe weather can be <it>a matter of life and death</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>life-and-death</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a new lease on/of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lease</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(as) big as life</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>(as) large as life</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in person <un>used to describe the surprise of seeing someone <vi>I never expected her to come to the party, but there she was, <it>as big as life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bet/stake your life on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you would <it>bet/stake your life on</it> something, you are very sure that it will happen. <vi>“Will she keep her promise?” “I'd <it>bet/stake my life on</it> it!”</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>breathe (new) life into</dre> <def><dt>:to give new energy and excitement to (something) <vi>She is credited with <it>breathing new life into</it> contemporary art.</vi> <vi>The singer managed to <it>breathe life into</it> some tired old songs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring someone or something back to life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone or something that has died to begin living again <vi>The story is about a mad scientist who tries to <it>bring</it> dead people <it>back to life</it>.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>They're trying to <it>bring</it> the restaurant <it>back to life</it> by introducing a new menu.</vi> <vi>an old theory that is <it>being brought back to life</it></vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring something to life</dre> <def><dt>:to make something very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>She <it>brings</it> history <it>to life</it> with her books.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come to life</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become very interesting, appealing, or exciting <vi>The movie really <it>comes to life</it> when she appears on the screen.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a place</ssl> <dt>:to become filled with the energy and excitement of active people <vi>Downtown <it>comes to life</it> each night when the clubs open.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>sputter/roar (etc.) to life</va></svr> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to begin working <vi>The engine suddenly <it>roared to life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>depart this life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>depart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for dear life</dre> <def><dt>:very tightly or quickly because of fear or danger <vi>He was hanging/holding on to the rope <it>for dear life</it>.</vi> <vi>They were running <it>for dear life</it> to get away from the vicious dogs.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for life</dre> <def><dt>:for the whole of your life :for the rest of your life <vi>They met in college and have remained friends <it>for life</it>.</vi> <vi>He was sentenced to prison <it>for life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>for the life of me</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in any way at all <un>used to say that you are unable to remember or understand something <vi>I couldn't <it>for the life of me</it> remember what her name was.</vi> <vi><it>For the life of me</it>, I can't think of any reasons why you wouldn't want a computer at home.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>frighten/scare the life out of</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to frighten (someone) very badly <vi>You (nearly) <it>scared the life out of</it> me when you startled me like that!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>from life</dre> <def><sl>of a painting, drawing, etc.</sl> <dt>:from looking at an actual person, object, etc. <vi>drawings done <it>from life</it> rather than from photographs</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>get a life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to stop spending time doing or thinking about things that are not important or interesting :to begin to have a more interesting or exciting life <vi>My girlfriend's parents are nice people, but all they do is watch TV all day. They need to <it>get a life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>larger than life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>large</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay down your life</dre> <dx>see <tag>lay down</tag> at <dxt>lay</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>life depends on</dre> <def><dt><snote>If your <it>life depends on</it> something, then you must do it. <vi>His <it>life depends on</it> how he answers this question.</vi> <vi>He was studying as if his <it>life depended on</it> it.</vi></snote> <un>often used in negative statements <vi>I wouldn't eat that food if my <it>life depended on</it> it. [=I would never eat it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose your life</dre> <def><dt>:to die <vi>She nearly <it>lost her life</it> in a car accident.</vi> <vi>Many <it>lives were lost</it>. [=many people died]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>new life</dre> <def><dt><snote>When something <phrase>takes on (a) new life</phrase> or when you <phrase>give something new life</phrase> or <phrase>give new life to something</phrase>, it becomes more active, interesting, etc. <vi>Plain old mashed potatoes <it>take on a new life</it> in this recipe.</vi> <vi>Falling interest rates <it>gave new life to</it> the housing market.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not on your life</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used as a very forceful way of saying “no” or “never” <vi>Do the government's policies really help the average worker? <it>Not on your life</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>risk life and limb</dre> <def><dt>:to do something that is very dangerous <vi>They <it>risked life and limb</it> to pull the child from the river.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>save someone's life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>spring into/to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>spring</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>staff of life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>staff</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>such is life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>such</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>take/claim someone's life</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone's death <vi>Two years ago he was diagnosed with the illness that eventually <it>took his life</it>.</vi> <vi>The flood <it>claimed many lives</it>. [=caused the deaths of many people]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your own life</dre> <def><dt>:to kill yourself <vi>He threatened to <it>take his own life</it> [=<it>commit suicide</it>], but no one believed him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the life of the party</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>the life and soul of the party</va></vr> <def><dt>:someone who is very lively and amusing at a party or other social gathering</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the light of your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>light</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the next life</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>the life to come</va></vr> <def><dt>:a life that is believed by some people to come after death <vi>He believed that he would see his family again in <it>the next life</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the simple life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>simple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to save your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>save</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>true to life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>true</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>fact of life</dxt> <dxt>good life</dxt> <dxt>slice-of-life</dxt> <dxt>still life</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="stake[2]"> <hw hindex="2">stake</hw> <altpr>ˈsteɪk</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>stakes</if></in> <in><if>staked</if></in> <in><if>stak*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to risk the loss of (something, such as money) <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>She <it>staked</it> [=<it>bet, wagered</it>] all her money <it>on</it> the race.</vi> <vi>He <it>staked</it> [=<it>risked</it>] his reputation <it>on</it> the success of the new plan.</vi> <vi>The corporation <it>staked</it> billions of dollars <it>on</it> the deal.</vi> <vi>She <it>staked</it> everything <it>on</it> one last attempt.</vi> <vi>That's the man who robbed the bank. <phrase>I would stake my life on it</phrase>. [=I am absolutely sure]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to support (something, such as a plant) with stakes <vi>She <it>staked</it> the tomatoes to keep them from falling over.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>stake out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>stake (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>stake out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to mark the limits of (an area) with stakes <vi><it>stake out</it> a mining area</vi> <vi>We <it>staked out</it> the area where the pool will be installed.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to watch (a place) secretly especially because you are looking for illegal activity <vi>The police <it>staked out</it> the building until they caught the vandals.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>stakeout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to state (your opinion) in a very clear and definite way <vi>He <it>staked out</it> his position on this issue in a speech he gave last month.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>stake (out) a/your claim</dre> <def><dt>:to say or show that you believe you should have something or that you deserve something <vi>They <it>staked their claim</it> to the land.</vi> <vi>With her strong showing in the early rounds of the tournament, she has <it>staked her claim</it> to be considered one of the favorites.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
