<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="class[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">class</hw> <sound><wav>class001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklæs, <it>Brit</it> ˈklɑ:s</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>class*es</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of students who meet regularly to be taught a subject or activity <vi>There are 20 students in the <it>class</it>.</vi> <vi>Several people in the <it>class</it> are absent today.</vi> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>class</it> is used with a singular verb. <vi>The <it>class</it> is going on a field trip.</vi> In British English, <it>class</it> can also be used with a plural verb. <vi>The <it>class</it> are going on a field trip.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a series of meetings in which students are taught a particular subject or activity :a course of instruction <vi>This <it>class</it> is really difficult.</vi> <vi>He will be teaching an American history <it>class</it> next semester.</vi> <vi>The college offers <it>classes</it> in computer programming and engineering.</vi> <vi>She is <phrase>taking a class</phrase> on psychology.</vi> <vi><it>taking</it> dance <it>class</it></vi> <vi>What <it>classes</it> are you <it>taking</it> this semester?</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:one of the meetings in which students are taught a particular subject or activity <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I have an English <it>class</it> this morning.</vi> <vi>My <it>class</it> got out early today.</vi> <vi>I have already missed two <it>classes</it>.</vi> <vi>Read chapters 10 through 20 for the next <it>class</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>I'm late for <it>class</it>.</vi> <vi>Let's meet after <it>class</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Class</it> starts at 8:00 a.m.</vi> <vi>What did you learn in <it>class</it> today?</vi> <vi>He got in trouble for talking during/in <it>class</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a group of students who finish their education at a particular school at the same time :students who graduate together <vi>She's a member of the <it>class</it> of 2006.</vi> <vi>the freshman <it>class</it> [=the group of students who are freshmen this year and will eventually graduate together]</vi> <vi>She's running for <it>class</it> president.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people in a society who are at the same economic and social level <vi>the ruling/professional <it>class</it></vi> <vi>the higher/lower social <it>classes</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>class</it> distinctions</vi> <vi>a <it>class</it> struggle</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way people in a society are divided into different social and economic groups <vi>a discussion about <it>class</it> and race</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a quality that makes something or someone seem special and attractive <vi>The hotel has <it>class</it>. [=it is very elegant]</vi> <vi>The candles on the table added a <phrase>touch of class</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>first-class</dxt> <dxt>high-class</dxt> <dxt>world-class</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a quality that makes someone seem very good, kind, etc. <vi>She showed a lot of <it>class</it> by donating her prize money to charity.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>class act</dxt> <dxt>classy</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a group of people or things that are similar in some way <vi>Do you have a license to drive this <it>class</it> of vehicle?</vi> <vi>a new <it>class</it> [=<it>kind, type</it>] of nuclear submarine</vi> <vi>There are many good players here, but she is in a different <it>class</it> altogether. [=she is far better than the other good players]</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>in a class by yourself</phrase> or <phrase>in a class of your own</phrase>, you are very different from others in a good or bad way. <vi>There have been a lot of corporate scandals but this one is <it>in a class by itself</it>. [=worse than all the others]</vi> <vi>As an architect, she is <it>in a class by herself</it>. [=she has exceptional talent as an architect]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:one of the sections of seats on an airplane, train, etc. <vi>I am traveling <phrase>business class</phrase>. [=in a section of an airplane that is more comfortable and expensive than the main section but less comfortable and expensive than first class]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>first class</dxt> <dxt>second class</dxt> <dxt>third class</dxt> <dxt>tourist class</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:one of the levels of a university degree</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="class[2]"> <hw hindex="2">class</hw> <altpr>ˈklæs, <it>Brit</it> ˈklɑ:s</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>classes</if></in> <in><if>classed</if></in> <in><if>class*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to decide that (someone or something) belongs to a particular group :<sx>classify</sx> <un>usually used as <it>(be) classed</it></un> <un>often + <it>as</it> <vi>The animal has <it>been classed as</it> a fish by some scientists and as a reptile by others.</vi> <vi>He <it>was classed as</it> a part-time worker.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="class act"> <hw>class act</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ acts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:someone who is admirable and usually very fair or polite <vi>She's a real <it>class act</it> on and off the soccer field.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="class action"> <hw>class action</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -tions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sl>law</sl> <dt>:a lawsuit in which many people join together to sue because they all say they were harmed by the same person or group</dt></def> <uro><ure>class–action</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>a <it>class-action</it> suit against a car company</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="class-conscious"> <hw>class–conscious</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more class–conscious; most class–conscious</gram> <dt>:having or showing a lot of awareness about which economic or social level a person is in :thinking that a person's economic or social class is important <vi>She was never very <it>class-conscious</it>, so it surprised her when her classmates talked about the “rich kids” and “poor kids” on campus.</vi> <vi>We live in a <it>class-conscious</it> society.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>class–consciousness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="first class"> <hw>first class</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:the best or highest group or class: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the best of usually three kinds of service you can have when you travel <vi>flying in <it>first class</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a class of mail in the U.S. that includes letters and postcards</dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a class of mail in the U.K. that includes letters and packages which are delivered sooner than ordinary second-class mail but cost more to send</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="first-class"> <hw>first–class</hw> <sound><wav>first_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfɚstˈklæs, <it>Brit</it> ˈfə:stˈklɑ:s</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:of or relating to first class <vi>passengers in the <it>first-class</it> cabin</vi> <vi>raising the rates for <it>first-class</it> mail</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:of the best quality :of the highest excellence <vi>a <it>first-class</it> telescope/meal</vi> <vi><it>first-class</it> [=<it>excellent, superior</it>] work</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>first–class</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>They insist on flying <it>first-class</it>.</vi> <vi>I'd like to send this package <it>first-class</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="high-class"> <hw>high–class</hw> <sound><wav>highcl01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhaɪˈklæs, <it>Brit</it> ˈhaɪˈklɑ:s</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>high*er–class</if></in> <in><if>high*est–class</if></in> <def><gram>also more high–class; most high–class</gram> <dt>:very fancy, wealthy, or expensive <vi>I felt out of place at such a <it>high-class</it> party.</vi> <vi>a <it>high-class</it> neighborhood</vi> <vi>The restaurant is trying to attract a <it>higher-class</it> clientele.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>lower-class</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="low-class"> <hw>low–class</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>low*er–class</if></in> <in><if>low*est–class</if></in> <def><gram>also more low–class; most low–class</gram> <dt>:<sx>lower-class</sx> <vi>a <it>low-class</it> neighborhood</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="lower class"> <hw>lower class</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ classes</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a social class that is below the middle class and that has the lowest status in a society <vi>a member of the <it>lower class/classes</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>middle class</dxt> <dxt>underclass</dxt> <dxt>upper class</dxt> <dxt>working class</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
