<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="classic[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clas*sic</hw> <sound><wav>classi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklæsɪk</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more clas*sic; most clas*sic</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something has come to be considered one of the best of its kind <vi><it>classic</it> novels/movies</vi> <vi>a <it>classic</it> case study on hysteria</vi> <vi>He collects <it>classic</it> cars.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is an example of excellence <vi>His winning goal was <it>classic</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that has been popular for a long time <vi><it>classic</it> board games</vi> <vi>The recipe is a new version of a <it>classic</it> dish.</vi> <vi>a radio station that plays <it>classic</it> rock [=rock music from the past that is still popular]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a graceful design with simple lines <vi>She prefers <it>classic</it> furniture designs.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>classic</it> suit that won't go out of style.</vi> <vi>I like the car's <it>classic</it> contours.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:very typical <vi>The battle was a <it>classic</it> example/case of poor planning.</vi> <vi>a <it>classic</it> error</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) She lost the tickets? How <it>classic</it>. [=it is not surprising that she lost the tickets; she often loses things]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="classic[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">classic</hw> <altpr>ˈklæsɪk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>classics</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that has been considered to be excellent for a long time <vi>That car is a <it>classic</it>.</vi> <vi>film/literary <it>classics</it></vi> <vi>I like to read <phrase>the classics</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Their latest album is <phrase>destined to become a classic</phrase>. [=it is very good and will still be admired many years from now]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>classics</bnote> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the study of the literature, language, and culture of ancient Greece and Rome <vi>He teaches <it>classics</it> at the local university.</vi> <vi>She studied <it>classics</it> in college.</vi> <vi>an interest in the <it>classics</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a traditional event <vi>The football game is a Thanksgiving <it>classic</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
