<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="clear[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clear</hw> <sound><wav>clear001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkliɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>clear*er</if></in> <in><if>clear*est</if></in> <def><gram>also more clear; most clear</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:very obvious :not causing or allowing doubt <vi>The show was a <it>clear</it> failure. [=it was clearly a failure; there is no doubt that the show was a failure]</vi> <vi>There are <it>clear</it> differences between the two candidates.</vi> <vi>She's the <it>clear</it> favorite to win the election.</vi> <vi>I'm not completely happy with the plan, but I see no <it>clear</it> alternative.</vi> <vi>He was the <it>clear</it> winner.</vi> <vi>It has become <it>clear</it> [=<it>evident</it>] to me that changes are necessary.</vi> <vi>She has made it abundantly/painfully/very <it>clear</it> that she does not support us.</vi> <vi>It's not <it>clear</it> how much longer we'll have to wait.</vi> <vi>She made (it) <it>clear</it> to me that she was unhappy. [=she told/showed me in a very definite way that she was unhappy]</vi> <vi>“Changes will have to be made.” “Yes, that's <it>clear</it>.”</vi> <vi>The sign said/read “Keep Out” <phrase>as clear as day/daylight/anything</phrase>. [=the sign very clearly said “Keep Out”]</vi> <un>sometimes used in spoken phrases that express anger <vi>I want this work finished by this afternoon. <phrase>Do I make myself clear</phrase>? [=do you understand me?]</vi> <vi>The work needs to be finished by this afternoon. <phrase>Is that clear</phrase>?</vi> <vi><phrase>Let's get one thing perfectly clear</phrase>: I want this work finished by this afternoon.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:easily understood <vi>She's a <it>clear</it> writer. [=she writes clearly]</vi> <vi>Her writing has a <it>clear</it> style.</vi> <vi>a <it>clear</it> definition/explanation</vi> <vi>a <it>clear</it> message</vi> <vi>The instructions weren't very <it>clear</it> about when we were supposed to begin.</vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) The explanation was <phrase>as clear as mud</phrase>. [=extremely unclear]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:free from doubt or confusion <vi>I think I have a <it>clear</it> understanding of the problem.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>clear</it> on/about what you need to do? [=do you understand what you need to do?]</vi> <vi>He has <it>clear</it> ideas about what he hopes to accomplish.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:able to think in an accurate way without confusion <vi>She's a <it>clear</it> thinker.</vi> <vi>This job requires someone with a <phrase>clear head</phrase>. [=someone who can think clearly]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clearheaded</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:easily seen :having small parts and details that can be easily seen and identified <vi>This picture is blurry, but that one is <it>clear</it>.</vi> <vi>Our TV has a beautifully <it>clear</it> picture/image.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:easily heard <vi>a very <it>clear</it> sound</vi> :easily heard and understood <vi><it>clear</it> pronunciation</vi> <vi>The teacher has a very <it>clear</it> speaking voice.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:easily seen through <vi><it>clear</it> [=<it>transparent</it>] glass</vi> <vi>a <it>clear</it> liquid</vi> <vi>a glass of cool, <it>clear</it> water</vi> <vi><it>clear</it> plastic bags</vi> <vi><it>clear</it> soup/broth</vi> <vi><it>clear</it> air</vi> <vi>The water in the lake is <phrase>crystal clear</phrase>. = The water in the lake is (as) <phrase>clear as crystal</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:not blocked by anything <vi>I had a <it>clear</it> view of the accident. [=I was able to see the accident clearly]</vi> <vi>The aisles must be kept <it>clear</it> during the show. [=no people or things can be in the aisles during the show]</vi> <vi>a <it>clear</it> path</vi> :not covered by anything <vi>You should keep your work area <it>clear</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>You should keep your work area <it>clear of</it> clutter.</vi> <vi>Don't try to cross the street until it's <it>clear of</it> traffic. [=until there is no traffic on the street]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>clear of <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt> <tag>the coast is clear</tag> at <dxt>coast</dxt> <tag>clear sailing</tag> at <dxt>sailing</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>of weather or the sky</ssl> <dt>:not having any clouds, fog, etc. <vi>It was a beautifully <it>clear</it>, sunny day.</vi> <vi>a <it>clear</it> blue sky</vi> <vi>You can see thousands of stars on a <it>clear</it> night.</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <dt>:free of marks or spots <vi>an actress with beautifully/perfectly <it>clear</it> healthy skin</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a distinct and bright color <vi>She has <it>clear</it> blue eyes.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>medical</ssl> <dt>:free of abnormal signs or symptoms <vi>After treatment, all his tests were <it>clear</it>. [=his tests did not show any problems]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:free from feelings of guilt or blame <un>used with <it>conscience</it> <vi>The accident wasn't my fault. My <it>conscience</it> is <it>clear</it>. = I have a <it>clear conscience</it>.</vi></un> <snote>If your conscience is <it>clear</it>, you do not feel guilty because you do not believe that you have done anything wrong.</snote></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>finance</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe the amount that remains after costs, taxes, etc., have been paid <vi>We made a <it>clear</it> [=<it>net</it>] profit of $500.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:not having any planned or scheduled activities <vi>Wednesday afternoon is <it>clear</it> [=<it>free</it>], so let's meet then.</vi> <vi>I like to keep my schedule <it>clear</it> on Friday afternoons.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>(as) clear as a bell</dre> <def><dt>:very clear <vi>It was <it>clear as a bell</it> that morning—not a cloud in the sky.</vi> <vi>The water was <it>as clear as a bell</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Clear as bell</it>, I heard him say my name.</vi> <vi>a sound <it>as clear as a bell</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clear of</dre> <def><dt>:away from (something dangerous, harmful, etc.) <vi>Keep/Stay <it>clear of</it> [=<it>out of</it>] trouble!</vi> <vi>Stand <it>clear of</it> the closing doors!</vi> <vi>We'll pick up speed once we get <it>clear of</it> the heavy traffic.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clear <dxn>7 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see your way clear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>see</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>steer clear (of)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>steer</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>clear*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>I was impressed by the <it>clearness</it> [=(more commonly) <it>clarity</it>] of his explanation.</vi> <vi>the <it>clearness</it> of the water</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="clear[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">clear</hw> <altpr>ˈkliɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clears</if></in> <in><if>cleared</if></in> <in><if>clear*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to become clear: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of weather or the sky</ssl> <dt>:to change so that there are no clouds, fog, etc. <vi>The sky <it>cleared</it> after the rain.</vi> <vi>The weather is cloudy now, but it's <it>clearing</it> gradually.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clear up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of clouds, fog, smoke, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to go away <vi>The clouds <it>cleared</it> (from the sky) after the rain.</vi> <vi>The morning fog gradually <it>cleared</it>.</vi> <vi>When the smoke <it>cleared</it>, we could see that the building had been completely destroyed.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of a liquid</ssl> <dt>:to change by becoming easier to see through :to become transparent or more transparent <vi>The water <it>cleared</it> after the mud had settled.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>of the skin</ssl> <dt>:to become free of marks or spots <vi>My skin <it>cleared</it> when I started using the cream.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clear up <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><snote>When your <phrase>head clears</phrase> or when something <phrase>clears your head</phrase>, you become more awake or alert and are able to think in a normal way without confusion. <vi>My <it>head cleared</it> after a good night's sleep. = A good night's sleep <it>cleared my head</it>. [=I was able to think clearly again after a good night's sleep]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt><snote>When your <phrase>vision/eyesight clears</phrase> you become able to see things correctly. <vi>When I woke up everything was blurry at first, but then my <it>vision</it> gradually <it>cleared</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove something entirely from an area or place <vi>He used a shovel to <it>clear</it> the snow off/from the driveway. = He used a shovel to <it>clear</it> the driveway of snow.</vi> <vi>They <it>cleared</it> timber from/off the land.</vi> <vi>She <it>cleared</it> everything out of the closet.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>clear</it> those books out of the/your way.</vi> <vi>She <it>cleared</it> [=<it>removed</it>] the dishes from the table. = She <phrase>cleared the table</phrase> (of dishes).</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the people in an area or place to leave <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>clear</it> a room of unwanted visitors = <it>clear</it> unwanted visitors from a room</vi> <vi>The alarm <it>cleared</it> [=<it>emptied</it>] the room (of people).</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The room <it>cleared</it> quickly when the alarm sounded. [=the people in the room left quickly when the alarm sounded]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to leave (an area or place) so that it is empty <vi>The police ordered the crowd to <it>clear</it> the area.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (a path, road, open space, etc.) by removing things that block or cover an area or surface <vi>The guide <it>cleared</it> a path for us through the jungle.</vi> <vi>I <it>cleared</it> a space on the desk for my new computer.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to go over, under, or past (something) without touching <vi>The horse <it>cleared</it> [=jumped over] the fence easily.</vi> <vi>The pole-vaulter <it>cleared</it> 15 feet on his first try.</vi> <vi>The boat's sail just/narrowly <it>cleared</it> [=passed under] the bottom of the bridge.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to prove that (someone) is not guilty of a crime <vi>The investigation <it>cleared</it> him officially of all the charges against him.</vi> <vi>He says he's innocent and he wants an opportunity to <phrase>clear himself</phrase>. = He wants an opportunity to <phrase>clear his name</phrase>. [=to prove that he is innocent]</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to get approval for (something) <vi>You should <it>clear</it> the article with your boss before trying to get it published.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give approval for (something) <vi>Her boss <it>cleared</it> [=<it>approved</it>] the article for publication.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to say that (someone) has official permission to do something <vi>The head of the agency has <it>cleared</it> her to see classified information.</vi> <vi>The flight/plane/pilot was <it>cleared</it> to land. = The flight/plane/pilot was <it>cleared</it> for landing. [=the flight/plane/pilot was given official permission/clearance to land]</vi> <vi>We were <it>cleared</it> (to go) through customs. = We <phrase>cleared customs</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to be passed or officially approved by (a group) <vi>The bill has finally <it>cleared</it> the Senate. [=the Senate has finally passed the bill]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>finance</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to pay all the money that is owed for (a debt or loan) <vi><it>clear</it> a debt</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to gain (an amount of money) after paying all costs, taxes, etc. <vi>After paying our expenses we <it>cleared</it> almost 1,000 dollars on the deal.</vi> <vi><it>clear</it> a profit</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><snote>When a <phrase>check clears</phrase> or <phrase>is cleared</phrase>, it goes through the process of being reviewed and accepted by a bank, and the money for the check is taken from the bank's account. <vi>Checks can take up to four days to <it>clear</it>. = Checks can take up to four days to <it>be cleared</it>.</vi> <vi>The check failed to <it>clear</it>. [=the check bounced]</vi></snote></dt></def> <dro><dre>clear away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>clear (something) away</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear away (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something) from an area or surface <vi>Just give me a moment to <it>clear away</it> all these papers, then we can sit down at the table.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>They had a long talk and were able to <it>clear away</it> [=<it>clear up, resolve</it>] all their misunderstandings.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clear off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>clear off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear (something) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove things from (an area or surface) <vi>It took her a few minutes to <it>clear off</it> the dinner table.</vi> <vi>It took her a few minutes to <it>clear</it> the dishes <it>off</it> the dinner table.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>clear off</it> my desk so that you can use it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to go away or run away :to leave quickly <vi>When we heard the night watchman, we <it>cleared off</it> as quickly as we could.</vi> <vi>I told him to <it>clear off</it> [=<it>get lost</it>] and leave me alone.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>clear off (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (a place) quickly <vi>I ordered the hikers to <it>clear off</it> [=<it>get off</it>] my land at once.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clear out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave quickly <vi>He <it>cleared out</it> without paying his rent.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>clear (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove unwanted things from (an area or place) <vi><it>clear out</it> a cluttered closet</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clearout</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clear the air</dre> <dx>see <dxt>air</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>clear the deck/decks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>deck</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>clear up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become clear: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of weather or the sky</ssl> <dt>:to change so that there are no clouds, fog, etc. <vi>The sky <it>cleared up</it> after the rain.</vi> <vi>It's cloudy now, but it's <it>clearing up</it> gradually.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of the skin</ssl> <dt>:to become free of marks or spots <vi>My skin <it>cleared up</it> when I started using the cream.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>clear up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go away or cause (something) to go away <vi>My symptoms <it>cleared up</it> once I started using the cream.</vi> <vi>The cream has <it>cleared up</it> my symptoms.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>clear (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>clear up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (something) clear by explaining it <vi><it>clear up</it> a mystery</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause the end of (something) by talking about it or dealing with it <vi>We need to <it>clear up</it> [=<it>resolve</it>] these misunderstandings.</vi> <vi>If we try I'm sure we can <it>clear up</it> these problems quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to make an area clean or tidy <vi>Let's <it>clear up</it> [=<it>clean up</it>, <it>tidy up</it>] before we leave.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clear your throat</dre> <def><dt>:to make a noise in your throat for attention or to be able to speak more clearly <vi>He <it>cleared his throat</it> and began to speak.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clear[3]"> <hw hindex="3">clear</hw> <altpr>ˈkliɚ</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a clear manner <un>used in the phrase <phrase>loud and clear</phrase> <vi>“Can you hear me now?” “<it>Loud and clear</it>.” [=I can hear you very clearly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:all the way :completely or entirely <vi>We drove <it>clear</it> across the state.</vi> <vi>The ball rolled <it>clear</it> across the street.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>free and clear</dre> <dx>see <dxt>free</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clear[4]"> <hw hindex="4">clear</hw> <altpr>ˈkliɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>in the clear</dre> <def><dt>:free from guilt or suspicion <vi>The investigation/jury considered all the charges against him and concluded that he was <it>in the clear</it>. [=that he was not guilty]</vi> <vi>He's not <it>in the clear</it> yet. The police still consider him a suspect.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clear-cut[1]"> <hw hindex="1">clear–cut</hw> <sound><wav>clear_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkliɚˈkʌt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more clear–cut; most clear–cut</gram> <dt>:very obvious and sharp <vi>a <it>clear-cut</it> distinction</vi> :free from doubt or uncertainty :very definite <vi>a <it>clear-cut</it> victory/decision</vi> <vi>The difference between their views on this issue is not <it>clear-cut</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="clear-cut[2]"> <hw hindex="2">clear–cut</hw> <sound><wav>clear_02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkliɚˌkʌt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clear–cuts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:an area of land in which all the trees have been cut down <vi>The law limits the size of <it>clear-cuts</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="clear-cut[3]"> <hw hindex="3">clear–cut</hw> <altpr>ˈkliɚˌkʌt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clear–cuts</if></in> <in><if>clear–cut</if></in> <in><if>clear–cut*ting</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:to cut down all the trees in (an area) <vi>Ten years ago the lumber company <it>clear-cut</it> this hillside.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>clear–cutting</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi><it>Clear-cutting</it> has led to mudslides in many regions.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="clear-eyed"> <hw>clear–eyed</hw> <sound><wav>clear_04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkliɚˌaɪd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more clear–eyed; most clear–eyed</gram> <dt>:having or showing an ability to think clearly <vi>She provided a <it>clear-eyed</it> [=<it>clear-sighted, clearheaded</it>] assessment of the problem.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="clear-sighted"> <hw>clear–sight*ed</hw> <sound><wav>clear_05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkliɚˌsaɪtəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more clear–sight*ed; most clear–sight*ed</gram> <dt>:having or showing an ability to think clearly <vi>He provided a <it>clear-sighted</it> [=<it>clear-eyed, clearheaded</it>] appraisal of the problem.</vi> <vi>a <it>clear-sighted</it> commentator</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>clear–sight*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="all clear"> <hw>all clear</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the all clear</dre> <def><dt>:a signal telling you that a situation is no longer dangerous <vi>“How will we know when it's safe to leave?” “I'll give you <it>the all clear</it> by blowing a whistle.”</vi> <vi>Doctors have given her <it>the all clear</it> [=have told her that she is healthy] and she should be back at work next week.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
