<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cleaner"> <hw>clean*er</hw> <sound><wav>cleane01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkli:nɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clean*ers</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person whose job is to clean something <vi>street/window <it>cleaners</it></vi> <vi>They have hired a <phrase>house cleaner</phrase>. [=a person whose job is to keep the rooms in a house or apartment clean]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a substance used for cleaning things <vi>He recommends using baking soda as a general household <it>cleaner</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a device or machine used for cleaning things <vi>an air <it>cleaner</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>pipe cleaner</dxt> <dxt>vacuum cleaner</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>the cleaners</bnote> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>the cleaner's</va></svr> <dt>:a shop where clothes are cleaned :<sx>dry cleaner</sx> <vi>I took my suit to <it>the cleaners</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>take (someone) to the cleaners</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to get all or most of someone's money or possessions usually in a dishonest or unfair way <vi>I heard that his ex-wife really <it>took him to the cleaners</it> [=<it>cleaned him out</it>] in the divorce.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clean[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clean</hw> <sound><wav>clean001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkli:n</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>clean*er</if></in> <in><if>clean*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:free from dirt, marks, etc. :not dirty <vi>a <it>clean</it> floor</vi> <vi>This table isn't <it>clean</it>. There's a sticky spot where something spilled.</vi> <vi>He keeps a very <it>clean</it> house.</vi> <vi>The janitor does a good job of keeping the office <it>clean</it>.</vi> <vi><it>clean</it> laundry/socks/towels/sheets</vi> <vi>I wiped the baby's face <it>clean</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:tending to keep clean <vi>He's a <it>clean</it> young man.</vi> <vi>Cats are very <it>clean</it> animals.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:free from pollution or other dangerous substances <vi><it>clean</it> air/water</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not causing pollution <vi>Solar power provides <it>clean</it> energy.</vi> <vi>a <it>clean</it> fuel</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not yet used <vi>a <it>clean</it> [=<it>blank, fresh</it>] piece/sheet of paper</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a document</ssl> <dt>:not having any mistakes <vi>We need a <phrase>clean copy</phrase> of the document.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:not infected <vi>a <it>clean</it> wound</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:pleasingly simple <vi>I like the <it>clean</it> simplicity of the chair's design.</vi> <vi>She wore a formal wool suit with <phrase>clean lines</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:having edges that are straight and smooth <vi>a <it>clean</it> cut</vi> <vi>The vase was broken, but it was a <it>clean</it> break and easily repaired with a little glue.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:completely and quickly done <vi>The bank robbers made a <it>clean</it> getaway.</vi> <vi>When he left home, he made a <phrase>clean break</phrase> with the past. [=he completely separated himself from everything that had been part of his life]</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:done in a skillful and impressive way without mistakes or awkwardness <vi>a <it>clean</it> dive/catch/hit</vi> <vi>The gymnast made a <it>clean</it> landing.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:not showing evidence of any broken rules or laws <vi>She has a <it>clean</it> driving record.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>clean slate <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt>:not connected with or involving anything illegal or morally wrong <vi>a <it>clean</it> candidate</vi> <vi>They believe in hard work and <it>clean</it> living.</vi> <vi>The party was good, <it>clean</it> fun.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not referring to anything sexual or offensive <vi>Only <it>clean</it> jokes, please. There are children here.</vi> <vi><it>clean</it> language</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:no longer using drugs :not addicted to drugs <vi>He's been <it>clean</it> for five years.</vi> <vi><it>clean</it> and sober</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:not carrying any weapons, drugs, etc. <vi>All visitors to the prison are searched to make sure they're <it>clean</it>.</vi> <vi>I checked her; she's <it>clean</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>clean as a whistle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>whistle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>clean slate</dre> <vr><vl>also Brit</vl> <va>clean sheet</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a person's record (as from a school or a job) that shows no evidence of any problems, broken rules, etc. :a clean record <vi>Everyone who comes to this school starts with a <it>clean slate</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>clean sheet</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a game in which the opposing team is prevented from scoring <vi>The team's star goalie has had five <it>clean sheets</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>shutouts</it>] this season. [=has prevented the other team from scoring in five games]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clean sweep</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a victory in which one side or team wins every game, contest, etc. <vi>The Red Sox won the series in a <it>clean sweep</it>.</vi> <vi>The election was a <it>clean sweep</it> for local Democratic candidates.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a complete change in something <vi>The new governor has made a <it>clean sweep</it> of the staff in the governor's mansion. [=the new governor completely replaced the former governor's staff]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come clean</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to tell the truth about what happened :to stop hiding the truth <vi>Eventually she <it>came clean</it> and helped the police recover the goods she'd stolen.</vi> <vi>He's finally <it>come clean</it> about his role in the scandal.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone or something) a clean bill of health</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bill</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your nose clean</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make a clean breast of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>breast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>wipe the slate clean</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wipe</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>clean*ness</ure> <sound><wav>clean002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkli:nnəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>cleanness</it> of the image</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="clean[3]"> <hw hindex="3">clean</hw> <altpr>ˈkli:n</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:all the way :completely or entirely <vi>Somehow, the top of the machine came <it>clean</it> off.</vi> <vi>The nail went <it>clean</it> through the wall.</vi> <vi>The fish were jumping <it>clean</it> out of the water.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="dry cleaner"> <hw>dry cleaner</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a shop where clothes and other cloth items are dry-cleaned <vi>I take my clothes to a local <it>dry cleaner</it>.</vi> <vi>My wool coat is still at <phrase>the dry cleaner's/cleaners</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="pipe cleaner"> <hw>pipe cleaner</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a piece of wire that is covered with soft cloth and used to clean the inside of a tobacco pipe</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="vacuum cleaner"> <art><artref id="vacuum_cleaner.tif"/><capt>vacuum cleaner</capt><dim>40.5,94.3</dim></art> <hw>vacuum cleaner</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an electrical machine that cleans floors, rugs, etc., by sucking up dirt, dust, etc.</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
