<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="clever"> <hw highlight="yes">clev*er</hw> <sound><wav>clever01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɛvɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>clev*er*er</if></in> <in><if>clev*er*est</if></in> <def><gram>also more clev*er; most clev*er</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:intelligent and able to learn things quickly <vi>A few <it>clever</it> [=<it>smart, bright</it>] students have started a business recycling old computers.</vi> <vi>Some cats are <it>clever</it> enough to figure out how to operate doorknobs.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:showing intelligent thinking <vi>a <it>clever</it> design/invention</vi> <vi>That's the <it>cleverest</it> idea I've heard yet!</vi> <vi>She found a <it>clever</it> hiding place for the letter.</vi> <un>often used in a joking or ironic way to describe a foolish idea, action, etc. <vi>Whose <it>clever</it> idea was it to leave the window open?</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:funny in a way that shows intelligence <vi>I enjoyed the play's <it>clever</it> [=<it>witty</it>] dialogue.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:talking in a rude way that is meant to show you are smart <vi>Don't you start getting <it>clever</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>fresh</it>] with me! [=don't speak to me in a disrespectful way]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:good at doing things with your hands :<sx>skillful</sx> <vi>Even as a little boy playing with blocks he was <it>clever</it> with his hands.</vi> <vi>a <it>clever</it> machinist</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used in various negative expressions to suggest that someone is not feeling well <vi>I'd had a few drinks and wasn't <phrase>feeling very clever</phrase>.</vi> <vi>For someone who hasn't been <phrase>feeling too clever</phrase> lately, he just played a great round of golf.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>too clever by half</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:clever in a way that is annoying or that causes problems <vi>an arrogant politician who is <it>too clever by half</it></vi> <vi>a complex computer program that is <it>too clever by half</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>clev*er*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>cleverly</it> designed gadget</vi> <vi><it>cleverly</it> written dialogue</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>clev*er*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>cleverness</it> of the idea</vi> <vi>a cat's <it>cleverness</it></vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="clever dick"> <hw>clever dick</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ dicks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal + disapproving</sl> <dt>:a person who is clever in a way that is annoying <ca>called also <cat>clever clogs</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
