<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="click[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">click</hw> <sound><wav>click001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɪk</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clicks</if></in> <in><if>clicked</if></in> <in><if>click*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to make a short, sharp sound <vi>He <it>clicked</it> his heels together and saluted the officer.</vi> <vi><it>click</it> your tongue/fingers</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a short, sharp sound :to make a click <vi>Her heels <it>clicked</it> on the marble floor.</vi> <vi>a <it>clicking</it> noise/sound</vi> <vi>Press the door until you hear the latch <it>click</it>.</vi> <vi>The last piece of the puzzle <it>clicked</it> [=<it>snapped</it>] into place.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>computers</ssl> <dt>:to press a button on a mouse or some other device in order to make something happen on a computer <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>To open the program, point at the icon and <it>click</it> the left mouse button.</vi> <vi><it>click</it> the icon</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Click</it> here to check spelling in the document.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><it>Click on</it> the icon to open the program.</vi> <vi>I got to the Web site by <it>clicking on</it> a link at another site.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>right-click</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to become friends :to like and understand each other <vi>They met at a party and <it>clicked</it> [=<it>hit it off</it>] right away.</vi> <vi>I know him fairly well, but we've never really <it>clicked</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to get the attention or interest of people <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>This is the issue that has really <it>clicked with</it> the voters this year.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to describe what happens when you suddenly understand or remember something <vi>I worked on the problem for days, until finally one day something <it>clicked</it> and I knew what I had to do.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>click*able</ure> <sound><wav>click01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɪkəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <sl>computers</sl> <utxt><vi>The names in the list are all <it>clickable</it>. [=you can click on the names with your mouse to cause something to happen]</vi> <vi>a <it>clickable</it> image on a Web page</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="click[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">click</hw> <altpr>ˈklɪk</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clicks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a short, sharp sound <vi>the <it>click</it> of her heels on marble</vi> <vi>There was a <it>click</it> as the door closed behind him.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of selecting something on a computer screen by pressing a button on a mouse or some other device <vi>You can order movie tickets on the Internet with just a few <it>clicks</it> of your mouse.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="double-click"> <hw>double–click</hw> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>double–clicks</if></in> <in><if>double–clicked</if></in> <in><if>double–click*ing</if></in> <def><dt>:to choose something on a computer screen by quickly pressing a button on a computer mouse or other device two times <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Double-click</it> the icon to start the program.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi><it>Double-click on</it> the icon.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>double click</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clicks</if></in> <gram>count</gram> <utxt><vi>A <it>double click</it> with the mouse will start the program.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="point-and-click"> <hw>point–and–click</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>computers</sl> <dt>:used by pointing to images on a computer screen and pressing a mouse or other device <vi><it>point-and-click</it> links</vi> <vi>a <it>point-and-click</it> interface</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="right-click"> <hw>right–click</hw> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>right–clicks</if></in> <in><if>right–clicked</if></in> <in><if>right–clicking</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sl>computers</sl> <dt>:to press the button on the right side of a mouse or similar device in order to make something happen on a computer <vi><it>Right-click</it> on the icon and select “Open” from the menu.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>click <dxn>2</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
