<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="clock[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clock</hw> <sound><wav>clock001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɑ:k</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clocks</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a device that shows what time it is and that is usually placed in a room or attached to a wall <vi>She looked/glanced at the <it>clock</it> on the wall. It was now 2:30.</vi> <vi>the hands/face of the <it>clock</it></vi> <vi>a digital <it>clock</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>clock</it> tower [=a tower with a clock on at least one of its sides]</vi> <vi>a <it>clock</it> face</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>watch</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>alarm clock</dxt> <dxt>atomic clock</dxt> <dxt>biological clock</dxt> <dxt>body clock</dxt> <dxt>cuckoo clock</dxt> <dxt>grandfather clock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <dt>:a clock that is used in sports and that shows how much time remains for a particular part of a game <vi>They were winning by 2 points with 10 seconds (left) on <it>the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>They stopped <it>the</it> (game) <it>clock</it> with eight seconds remaining.</vi> <snote>In U.S. English, to <phrase>eat up the clock</phrase> or <phrase>run out the clock</phrase> or <phrase>kill the clock</phrase> is to keep control of the ball or puck near the end of a game so that your opponent will not have a chance to score. <vi>We kept moving the ball to try to <it>eat up the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>If we can <it>run out the clock</it>, we can keep our lead and win.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>shot clock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <dt>:<sx>time clock</sx> <vi>I punched <it>the clock</it> at 8:45 and started working right away.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>the clock</bnote> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a device that shows how far a vehicle has traveled :<sx>odometer</sx> <vi>a car with 100,000 miles <phrase>on the clock</phrase></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>against the clock</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in order to do or finish something before a particular time <vi>On our last project, we were working/racing <it>against the clock</it>.</vi> <vi>It was a race <it>against the clock</it> to finish the job on time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>If a race is <it>against the clock</it>, the time of each racer is measured and the racer with the fastest time wins. <vi>One by one the skiers sped downhill, racing <it>against the clock</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>around the clock</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>round the clock</va></vr> <def><dt>:throughout the entire day and night :every hour of the day <vi>Our stores are now open <it>around the clock</it>. [=our stores are open 24 hours a day]</vi> <vi>Reporters worked <it>around the clock</it> to cover the story.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>beat the clock</dre> <def><dt>:to do or finish something quickly before a particular time <vi>In a desperate attempt to <it>beat the clock</it>, I raced to mail my tax return before midnight.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/turn back the clock</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>put/turn the clock back</va></vr> <def><dt>:to return to a condition that existed in the past <vi>This new decision has effectively <it>turned back the clock</it> on 20 years of progress.</vi> <vi>I wish that we could <it>turn back the clock</it> and start all over again.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clock[2]"> <hw hindex="2">clock</hw> <altpr>ˈklɑ:k</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clocks</if></in> <in><if>clocked</if></in> <in><if>clock*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to measure the amount of time it takes for (a person) to do something or for (something) to be completed <un>usually + <it>at</it> <vi>She <it>clocked</it> [=<it>timed</it>] her first mile <it>at</it> 5 minutes and 20 seconds.</vi> <vi>He <it>clocked</it> me <it>at</it> 30 seconds.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to finish a race in (an amount of time) <vi>He <it>clocked</it> 3 hours and 15 minutes in his last marathon.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to measure or show (the speed of something) with a measuring device <vi>His fastest pitch was <it>clocked</it> at 91 miles per hour.</vi> <vi>The cop said she <it>clocked</it> me going 95 miles per hour.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have a particular speed or to continue for a particular amount of time <un>+ <it>in</it> <vi>The movie <it>clocked in</it> at just under three hours. [=the movie was almost three hours long]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to hit (someone or something) very hard <vi>I was so angry I wanted to <it>clock</it> him.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to look at or notice (someone or something) <vi>Just <it>clock</it> [=<it>get a load of</it>] that new motor of his.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>clock in/on</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to record on a special card the time that you start working <vi>What time did you <it>clock on</it>?</vi> <vi>I <it>clocked in</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>punched in</it>] 10 minutes late.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clock off/out</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:to record on a special card the time that you stop working <vi>What time did you <it>clock off</it> yesterday?</vi> <vi>I <it>clocked off</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>punched out</it>] 10 minutes late.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>clock up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>clock up (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to gain or reach (a particular number or amount) <vi>Our company <it>clocked up</it> a record number of sales this year.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clock radio"> <hw>clock radio</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -dios</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a radio that includes a clock and that can be set so that the radio turns on at a particular time</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="alarm clock"> <hw>alarm clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a clock that can be set to sound an alarm at any desired time <vi>She set the <it>alarm clock</it> for six o'clock.</vi> <vi>The <it>alarm clock</it> went off at six o'clock.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="around-the-clock"> <hw>around–the–clock</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:happening or continuing all day and all night <vi>The prisoner requires <it>around-the-clock</it> [=<it>round-the-clock, constant</it>] surveillance.</vi> <vi><it>around-the-clock</it> care</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="atomic clock"> <hw>atomic clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a special kind of clock that is extremely exact</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="biological clock"> <hw>biological clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a system in the body that controls the occurrence of natural processes (such as waking, sleeping, and aging) <un>often used to describe a woman's desire to have children before she is too old <vi>She felt her <it>biological clock</it> ticking away and wanted to have a baby as soon as possible.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="body clock"> <hw>body clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a system in the body that controls when you need to sleep, eat, etc. <vi>It takes a while for my <it>body clock</it> to get adjusted when I fly from New York to London.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>biological clock</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cuckoo clock"> <hw>cuckoo clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a clock that has a toy bird inside of it that comes out and makes a sound like a cuckoo to tell what time it is</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="grandfather clock"> <hw>grandfather clock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clocks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a tall clock that stands on the floor</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
