<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="close[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">close</hw> <sound><wav>close002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>clos*er</if></in> <in><if>clos*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:near in space :not far away or distant <vi>We're not there yet, but we're getting <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>We stood <it>close</it> together to stay warm.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>New York is much <it>closer to</it> Chicago than it is <it>to</it> Los Angeles.</vi> <vi>Don't get too <it>close to</it> the fire.</vi> <vi>Stay <it>close to</it> me, children!</vi> <vi>Let's try to sit <it>close to</it> the front.</vi> <vi>The trees were planted <phrase>in close proximity to</phrase> [=<it>near</it>] the building.</vi> <vi>The gun is made for shooting <phrase>at close range</phrase>. [=from a short distance]</vi> <vi>We were able to observe their behavior <phrase>at close quarters</phrase>. [=from a short distance]</vi> <vi>Over 200 people lived <phrase>in close quarters</phrase> [=very close together] on the ship.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>close encounter</tag> at <dxt>encounter</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:near in time <vi>Christmas is getting <it>closer</it> and will soon be here.</vi> <vi>She had her two children very <it>close</it> together. [=her second child was born soon after her first]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>You shouldn't snack so <it>close to</it> dinnertime.</vi> <vi>It's getting <it>close to</it> midnight.</vi> <vi>My birthday is <it>close to</it> Thanksgiving.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:very similar :almost the same <vi>Their daughters are <it>close</it> in age.</vi> <vi><it>close</it> in size and shape</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a sound <it>close to</it> the sound of breaking glass</vi> <vi>He bears a <phrase>close resemblance to</phrase> his father. [=he looks very much like his father]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:almost correct <vi>“I'd guess that you're 29 years old.” “You're <it>close</it>. I'm 30.”</vi> <vi>It's not exactly right, but it's <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>You're way off! Not even <it>close</it>! [=you are completely wrong]</vi> <snote>The informal phrase <phrase>close but no cigar</phrase> is used to say that a guess was almost correct or that an effort was almost good enough. <vi>“Was I right?” “<it>Close</it>, <it>but no cigar</it>.”</vi> <vi>We were <it>close but no cigar</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has almost reached a particular condition</un> <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>He was <it>close to</it> death when they brought him to the hospital.</vi> <vi>These rare birds are <it>close to</it> extinction.</vi> <vi>His reply left her <it>close to</it> tears. [=his reply almost made her cry]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:almost <it>doing</it> something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She was <it>close to</it> crying.</vi> <vi>The bridge came dangerously <it>close to</it> collapsing. [=the bridge almost collapsed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something bad almost happened <vi>That was <it>close</it>! We almost missed our plane.</vi> <vi>That was a <phrase>close one</phrase>. [=<it>close call, close shave</it>]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>too close for comfort</tag> at <dxt>comfort</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the people you are most directly related to (such as your parents, children, sisters, brothers, etc.) <vi>She had no <it>close</it> relatives nearby.</vi> <vi>We're only inviting <it>close</it> family members to our wedding.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>distant</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe people who know each other very well and care about each other very much <vi>They were <it>close</it> friends in high school, but they've since grown apart.</vi> <vi>My sister and I have always been very <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>We have a very <it>close</it> relationship.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We've always felt very <it>close to</it> each other.</vi> <vi>He's very <it>close to</it> his grandparents.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:connected in a direct way <vi>Sources <it>close</it> to the president say that he is willing to make a deal.</vi> <vi>She stays in <it>close</it> touch/contact with her friends back home.</vi> <vi>Authorities claim he has <it>close</it> ties to terrorist organizations.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>This idea lies <it>close</it> to the heart of Democracy. [=it has an important connection to Democracy]</vi> <vi>Animal rights is a cause that is <phrase>close to my heart</phrase>. [=I care very much about animal rights]</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:very careful, complete, or precise <vi>It's important to pay <it>close</it> attention to the details.</vi> <vi>Take a <it>closer</it> look at the evidence.</vi> <vi>On <it>closer</it> examination, it appeared that something was missing.</vi> <vi>We worked under the <it>close</it> supervision of a trained professional.</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> study of the Greek classics</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> reading of a text</vi> <vi>Keep (a) <phrase>close watch</phrase> on the baby. = Keep a <phrase>close eye</phrase> on the baby. [=watch the baby closely]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a race, contest, game, etc., in which one person, group, or team defeats the other or is leading the other by only a small amount <vi>That was a <it>close</it> game. We only beat them by one point.</vi> <vi>It was the <it>closest</it> election in recent history.</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> race</vi> <vi>At this point, the election is <phrase>too close to call</phrase>. [=it is not clear who will win]</vi></un> <snote>When you are <phrase>a close second</phrase>, there is a small difference between you and the winner. <vi>Vanilla is the most popular flavor while chocolate is/finishes/runs <it>a close second</it>.</vi> <vi>She won the race while her teammate came in <it>a close second</it>. [=her teammate finished soon after her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:very short or near to the skin <vi>a <it>close</it> haircut/shave</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:fitting tightly :having no extra space <vi>I think there's enough room in the car for all of us, but it'll be a <it>close</it> [=<it>tight</it>] fit.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close-fitting</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:warm in an uncomfortable way :not having enough fresh air <vi>It's very <it>close</it> in here: let's open a window.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>close to home</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>close to home</it>, it affects you in a strong and personal way. <vi>I'm a teacher, so their criticisms of our educational system hit <it>close to home</it>.</vi> <vi>People are usually not concerned about crime until it comes <it>close to home</it>. [=until it affects them directly]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to the bone</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>close to the bone</it>, it is very honest and deals with sensitive issues that can shock people or hurt their feelings. <vi>His joke about racism in America cut pretty <it>close to the bone</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to the edge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>edge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close to the mark</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mark</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close to your chest</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>close to the vest</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If you hold, keep, or play something <it>close to your chest</it> or <it>close to the vest</it>, you do not tell other people about it. <vi>It's better to hold such information <it>close to the vest</it>.</vi> <vi>She tends to keep her opinions <it>close to her chest</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>close*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <gram>more close*ly; most close*ly</gram> <utxt><vi>Don't drive too <it>closely</it> behind the car in front of you.</vi> <vi>The houses on our street are crowded very <it>closely</it> together.</vi> <vi>She <it>closely</it> resembles her mother.</vi> <vi>The suspects were watched <it>closely</it> by the police.</vi> <vi>We've been studying their behavior very <it>closely</it>.</vi> <vi><it>closely</it> related family members</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>close*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>closeness</it> of the election results</vi> <vi>the <it>closeness</it> felt by a parent and child</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
