<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="closet[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">clos*et</hw> <sound><wav>closet01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɑ:zət</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clos*ets</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a usually small room that is used for storing things (such as clothing, towels, or dishes) <vi>The sheets and blankets are in the hall <it>closet</it>.</vi> <vi>He has a <it>closet</it> full of new clothes.</vi> <vi>broom/coat <it>closets</it></vi> <vi>a <phrase>walk-in closet</phrase> [=a large closet usually for clothes]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>water closet</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a state in which someone will not talk about something or admit something</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a state in which someone will not admit being a homosexual <un>usually used in the phrases <phrase>in the closet</phrase> or <phrase>out of the closet</phrase> <vi>He's still <it>in the closet</it>. [=he has not told people that he is gay]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>came out of the closet</phrase> in college.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>skeleton in the/your closet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>skeleton</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="closet[2]"> <hw hindex="2">closet</hw> <altpr>ˈklɑ:zət</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:hiding the fact that you are a particular type of person <vi>She's a <it>closet</it> racist. [=she does not want people to know that she is a racist]</vi> <vi>Some people think he's a <it>closet</it> homosexual.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="closet[3]"> <hw hindex="3">closet</hw> <altpr>ˈklɑ:zət</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>closets</if></in> <in><if>closet*ed</if></in> <in><if>closet*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to put (yourself) in a room in order to be alone <vi>He <it>closeted</it> himself in his apartment for several days.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to bring (someone) into a room in order to talk privately <un>usually used as <it>(be) closeted</it> <vi>The manager <it>was closeted</it> with one of her employees for several hours.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="water closet"> <hw>water closet</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ets</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:a room containing a toilet <un>abbr. <it>WC</it></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="skeleton[1]"> <hw hindex="1">skel*e*ton</hw> <sound><wav>skelet03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈskɛlətən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>skel*e*tons</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the structure of bones that supports the body of a person or animal <vi>They found the fossil <it>skeleton</it> of a mastodon.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a set or model of all the bones in the body of a person <vi>He hung a plastic <it>skeleton</it> on the door for Halloween.</vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>human</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a very thin person or animal <vi>She was a <it>skeleton</it> after her illness.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:the frame of a building <vi>Only the charred <it>skeleton</it> of the house remained after the fire.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a basic outline of a plan, piece of writing, etc. <vi>We saw a <it>skeleton</it> of the report before it was published.</vi> <vi>a <it>skeleton</it> draft</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>skeletons in the/your closet</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>skeletons in the/your cupboard</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:something bad or embarrassing that happened in your past and that is kept secret <vi>He asked if she had any <it>skeletons in her closet</it> that might affect her political campaign.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
