<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="close[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">close</hw> <sound><wav>close_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊz</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clos*es</if></in> <in><if>closed</if></in> <in><if>clos*ing</if></in> <def><snote>The opposite of <it>close</it> is <it>open</it> in every sense except senses 3b and 9.</snote> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move (a door, window, etc.) so that things cannot pass through an opening :<sx>shut</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>close</it> the door.</vi> <vi>We had better <it>close</it> the windows; it looks like it's going to rain.</vi> <vi>I forgot to <it>close</it> the gate.</vi> <vi>She was having trouble <it>closing</it> the drawer.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> the lid on the box tightly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The door opened and <it>closed</it> so quietly that I didn't notice he had come in the room.</vi> <vi>The box's lid <it>closed</it> with a bang.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cover the opening of (something) :<sx>shut</sx> <vi>Remember to <it>close</it> the box of cereal when you're done.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to bring together the parts or edges of (something open) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>close</it> your books and put them under your desks.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> your mouth.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> your eyes and go to sleep.</vi> <vi>I <it>closed</it> my fists and got ready to fight.</vi> <vi><it>close</it> an umbrella</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>This suitcase just won't <it>close</it>!</vi> <vi>Her eyes <it>closed</it>, and she drifted off to sleep.</vi> <vi>My throat <it>closed</it> and I felt like I couldn't breathe.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring together the edges of (a wound) so that it can heal <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>It took 10 stitches to <it>close</it> the wound on his head.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The cut eventually <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed up</it>, <it>healed over</it>] on its own.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to not allow (a road, park, etc.) to be used for a period of time <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The city <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed off</it>] the beach during the storm.</vi> <vi>They <it>closed</it> the bridge to traffic. [=they did not allow cars to use the bridge]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The park <it>closes</it> every evening at dusk.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) for a period of time <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>closed</it> the school today because of the storm.</vi> <vi>We'll be <it>closing</it> the theater while we make the necessary repairs.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The store <it>closes</it> for lunch from 1 to 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The airport <it>closed</it> for two hours yesterday due to icy conditions.</vi> <vi>The bank <it>closes</it> at noon on Saturdays.</vi> <vi>What time does the library <it>close</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) permanently <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed down, shut down</it>] the school/factory/office last year.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The restaurant has <it>closed</it> for lack of business.</vi> <vi>The play <it>closed</it> [=it stopped being performed] after 112 performances.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to end (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The minister <it>closed</it> [=<it>concluded</it>] the services with a short prayer.</vi> <vi>She <it>closed</it> the meeting by thanking everyone for their help.</vi> <vi>Investigators <it>closed</it> the case after concluding that his death was an accident.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The services <it>closed</it> [=<it>concluded</it>] with a short prayer.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>close</it> by thanking you all for your help.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop keeping money in (an account at a bank) <vi>I <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed out</it>] my savings account and opened up a new one at another bank.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to end the use of (a file, document, or program) on a computer <vi>Remember to save the file before <it>closing</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to formally accept (an agreement) <vi>They just <it>closed</it> a deal to take ownership of a new restaurant.</vi> <vi>the custom of <it>closing</it> a deal by shaking hands</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close on <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to reach a specified price or level at the end of the day <vi>The stock opened at $19 a share and <it>closed</it> at $22.</vi> <vi>Stocks opened weak but <it>closed</it> strong.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:to reduce the amount of distance or difference between two things, people, or groups <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The challenger has <it>closed</it> [=<it>narrowed</it>] the champion's lead to within two points.</vi> <vi><it>closing</it> the distance to the lead runner</vi> <vi>These changes will help <phrase>close the gap</phrase> between the richest and the poorest countries.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She has <it>closed</it> to within two points of the champion.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>close down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to permanently stop operating :<sx>close</sx> <vi>The factory <it>closed down</it> in the 1980s.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop broadcasting from a radio or television station for the day <vi>We're <it>closing down</it> for the night: tune in again tomorrow morning!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>close down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close (something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to permanently stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) <vi>They <it>closed down</it> [=<it>closed</it>, <it>shut down</it>] the school due to financial problems.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>closedown</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to come or move nearer or closer <vi>The storm is <it>closing in</it> [=<it>approaching</it>] fast.</vi> <vi>Enemy troops are <it>closing in</it> all around us!</vi> <vi>The lions <it>closed in</it> for the kill.</vi> <vi>I felt that the world was <it>closing in</it> around me.</vi> <vi>The air became colder as night/darkness <it>closed in</it>. [=as darkness fell, as the night became dark]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The fire was <it>closing in on</it> their neighborhood.</vi> <vi>The camera slowly <it>closed in on</it> the actor's face.</vi> <vi>Police were <it>closing in on</it> the two men.</vi> <vi>Researchers are <it>closing in on</it> [=they are close to finding] a cure for the disease.</vi> <vi>She's <it>closing in on</it> 40. [=she is almost 40 years old]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not allow (something) to be used for a period of time :<sx>close</sx> <vi>The city <it>closed off</it> the beach to tourists.</vi> <vi><it>closing off</it> a road with barriers</vi> <vi>Half of the museum was <it>closed off</it> while they made the changes.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He <it>closes</it> himself <it>off</it> to new experiences. [=he does not allow himself to have new experiences]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to formally and legally agree to and complete (an important financial arrangement, such as the purchase of a house) <vi>We're going to <it>close on</it> our house next Friday.</vi> <vi>They <it>closed on</it> the deal.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close <dxn>9 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to quickly sell (all of a particular type of product in a store) at a lower price <vi>We're <it>closing out</it> our entire stock of children's clothing! Come and pick up some bargains!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>closeout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop keeping money in (a bank account) <vi>She withdrew all her money and <it>closed out</it> [=<it>closed</it>] her account.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to end (something) in a specified way <vi>The team <it>closed out</it> the series with a 2–1 win over New York.</vi> <vi>She <it>closed out</it> her remarkable career with a final grand performance.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close ranks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close the door on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>door</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to close and lock all the doors of a building usually for a short period of time <vi>Businesses <it>closed up</it> [=<it>closed</it>] early so employees could attend the parade.</vi> <vi>We've <it>closed up</it> for the day. Please come back tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>close (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to close and lock all the doors of (a house, store, etc.) <vi>They <it>closed up</it> the house and left town.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>close up shop</phrase> is to go out of business forever or stop performing all services or activities for a period of time. <vi>Rather than <it>closing up shop</it> entirely, the company laid off half of its workers.</vi> <vi>The restaurant has already <it>closed up shop</it> for the winter.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to move closer together <vi>The troops <it>closed up</it> and prepared to begin the attack.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a wound</ssl> <dt>:to become completely healed <vi>The cut eventually <it>closed up</it> [=<it>closed</it>] on its own.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become quiet :to stop talking about your thoughts or emotions with other people <vi>She <it>closes up</it> when people ask her about her parents.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>close (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (people or things) closer together <vi><it>Close up</it> the spaces between the lines.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close your doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>door</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close your eyes to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="close[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">close</hw> <sound><wav>close002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>clos*er</if></in> <in><if>clos*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:near in space :not far away or distant <vi>We're not there yet, but we're getting <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>We stood <it>close</it> together to stay warm.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>New York is much <it>closer to</it> Chicago than it is <it>to</it> Los Angeles.</vi> <vi>Don't get too <it>close to</it> the fire.</vi> <vi>Stay <it>close to</it> me, children!</vi> <vi>Let's try to sit <it>close to</it> the front.</vi> <vi>The trees were planted <phrase>in close proximity to</phrase> [=<it>near</it>] the building.</vi> <vi>The gun is made for shooting <phrase>at close range</phrase>. [=from a short distance]</vi> <vi>We were able to observe their behavior <phrase>at close quarters</phrase>. [=from a short distance]</vi> <vi>Over 200 people lived <phrase>in close quarters</phrase> [=very close together] on the ship.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>close encounter</tag> at <dxt>encounter</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:near in time <vi>Christmas is getting <it>closer</it> and will soon be here.</vi> <vi>She had her two children very <it>close</it> together. [=her second child was born soon after her first]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>You shouldn't snack so <it>close to</it> dinnertime.</vi> <vi>It's getting <it>close to</it> midnight.</vi> <vi>My birthday is <it>close to</it> Thanksgiving.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:very similar :almost the same <vi>Their daughters are <it>close</it> in age.</vi> <vi><it>close</it> in size and shape</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a sound <it>close to</it> the sound of breaking glass</vi> <vi>He bears a <phrase>close resemblance to</phrase> his father. [=he looks very much like his father]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <dt>:almost correct <vi>“I'd guess that you're 29 years old.” “You're <it>close</it>. I'm 30.”</vi> <vi>It's not exactly right, but it's <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>You're way off! Not even <it>close</it>! [=you are completely wrong]</vi> <snote>The informal phrase <phrase>close but no cigar</phrase> is used to say that a guess was almost correct or that an effort was almost good enough. <vi>“Was I right?” “<it>Close</it>, <it>but no cigar</it>.”</vi> <vi>We were <it>close but no cigar</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say that someone or something has almost reached a particular condition</un> <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>He was <it>close to</it> death when they brought him to the hospital.</vi> <vi>These rare birds are <it>close to</it> extinction.</vi> <vi>His reply left her <it>close to</it> tears. [=his reply almost made her cry]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:almost <it>doing</it> something <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She was <it>close to</it> crying.</vi> <vi>The bridge came dangerously <it>close to</it> collapsing. [=the bridge almost collapsed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something bad almost happened <vi>That was <it>close</it>! We almost missed our plane.</vi> <vi>That was a <phrase>close one</phrase>. [=<it>close call, close shave</it>]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>too close for comfort</tag> at <dxt>comfort</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the people you are most directly related to (such as your parents, children, sisters, brothers, etc.) <vi>She had no <it>close</it> relatives nearby.</vi> <vi>We're only inviting <it>close</it> family members to our wedding.</vi></un> <dx>compare <dxt>distant</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe people who know each other very well and care about each other very much <vi>They were <it>close</it> friends in high school, but they've since grown apart.</vi> <vi>My sister and I have always been very <it>close</it>.</vi> <vi>We have a very <it>close</it> relationship.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We've always felt very <it>close to</it> each other.</vi> <vi>He's very <it>close to</it> his grandparents.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:connected in a direct way <vi>Sources <it>close</it> to the president say that he is willing to make a deal.</vi> <vi>She stays in <it>close</it> touch/contact with her friends back home.</vi> <vi>Authorities claim he has <it>close</it> ties to terrorist organizations.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>This idea lies <it>close</it> to the heart of Democracy. [=it has an important connection to Democracy]</vi> <vi>Animal rights is a cause that is <phrase>close to my heart</phrase>. [=I care very much about animal rights]</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:very careful, complete, or precise <vi>It's important to pay <it>close</it> attention to the details.</vi> <vi>Take a <it>closer</it> look at the evidence.</vi> <vi>On <it>closer</it> examination, it appeared that something was missing.</vi> <vi>We worked under the <it>close</it> supervision of a trained professional.</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> study of the Greek classics</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> reading of a text</vi> <vi>Keep (a) <phrase>close watch</phrase> on the baby. = Keep a <phrase>close eye</phrase> on the baby. [=watch the baby closely]</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a race, contest, game, etc., in which one person, group, or team defeats the other or is leading the other by only a small amount <vi>That was a <it>close</it> game. We only beat them by one point.</vi> <vi>It was the <it>closest</it> election in recent history.</vi> <vi>a <it>close</it> race</vi> <vi>At this point, the election is <phrase>too close to call</phrase>. [=it is not clear who will win]</vi></un> <snote>When you are <phrase>a close second</phrase>, there is a small difference between you and the winner. <vi>Vanilla is the most popular flavor while chocolate is/finishes/runs <it>a close second</it>.</vi> <vi>She won the race while her teammate came in <it>a close second</it>. [=her teammate finished soon after her]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:very short or near to the skin <vi>a <it>close</it> haircut/shave</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:fitting tightly :having no extra space <vi>I think there's enough room in the car for all of us, but it'll be a <it>close</it> [=<it>tight</it>] fit.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close-fitting</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:warm in an uncomfortable way :not having enough fresh air <vi>It's very <it>close</it> in here: let's open a window.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>close to home</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>close to home</it>, it affects you in a strong and personal way. <vi>I'm a teacher, so their criticisms of our educational system hit <it>close to home</it>.</vi> <vi>People are usually not concerned about crime until it comes <it>close to home</it>. [=until it affects them directly]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to the bone</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>close to the bone</it>, it is very honest and deals with sensitive issues that can shock people or hurt their feelings. <vi>His joke about racism in America cut pretty <it>close to the bone</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to the edge</dre> <dx>see <dxt>edge</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close to the mark</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mark</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close to your chest</dre> <vr><vl>or US</vl> <va>close to the vest</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If you hold, keep, or play something <it>close to your chest</it> or <it>close to the vest</it>, you do not tell other people about it. <vi>It's better to hold such information <it>close to the vest</it>.</vi> <vi>She tends to keep her opinions <it>close to her chest</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>close*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <gram>more close*ly; most close*ly</gram> <utxt><vi>Don't drive too <it>closely</it> behind the car in front of you.</vi> <vi>The houses on our street are crowded very <it>closely</it> together.</vi> <vi>She <it>closely</it> resembles her mother.</vi> <vi>The suspects were watched <it>closely</it> by the police.</vi> <vi>We've been studying their behavior very <it>closely</it>.</vi> <vi><it>closely</it> related family members</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>close*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>closeness</it> of the election results</vi> <vi>the <it>closeness</it> felt by a parent and child</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="close[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">close</hw> <sound><wav>close002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊs</pr> <fl>adverb</fl> <in><if>clos*er</if></in> <in><if>clos*est</if></in> <def><dt>:at or to a short distance or time away <vi>Don't drive so <it>close</it> to the car in front of you.</vi> <vi>He told me to stay/keep <it>close</it> as we walked through the crowd.</vi> <vi>Come <it>close</it>, everyone.</vi> <vi>Look <it>close</it> [=<it>closely</it>] and tell me what you see.</vi> <vi>She drew me <it>close</it> (to her) and held me.</vi> <vi>The time for a decision is drawing <it>closer</it>.</vi> <vi>My teammate came in third, and I finished <phrase>close behind</phrase>.</vi> <vi>They sat <phrase>close together</phrase> at the dinner table.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>close at hand</dre> <def><dt>:near in time or place <vi>I always keep a few tissues <it>close at hand</it> [=near me] just in case.</vi> <vi>The time for us to leave was <it>close at hand</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close by</dre> <def><dt>:at a short distance away <vi>Don't worry: if anything happens I'll be (standing) <it>close by</it> (you).</vi> <vi>They're building a school <it>close by</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close on</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:almost or nearly <vi>We walked for <it>close on</it> [=<it>close to</it>] five miles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close to</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:almost or nearly <vi>They spent <it>close to</it> half a million dollars on the project.</vi> <vi>Our company employs <it>close to</it> a thousand workers.</vi> <vi>I haven't seen her in <it>close to</it> a year.</vi> <vi>I sat there for <it>close to</it> an hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:from a short distance <vi>She's even more beautiful when seen <it>close to</it>. [=<it>close up</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close up</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>up close</va></vr> <def><dt>:from a short distance :at close range <vi>You have to look at the painting <it>close up</it> to really appreciate its detail.</vi> <vi>It looks very different <it>up close</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close-up</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come close</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to almost do something <vi>We didn't win, but we <it>came close</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The band <it>came</it> very <it>close to</it> breaking up.</vi> <vi>We <it>came close to</it> winning the championship this season.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be similar to something or as good as expected <vi>She said they taste just like real hot dogs, but they don't even <it>come close</it> (to the real thing).</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut it close</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cut</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="close[4]"> <hw hindex="4">close</hw> <sound><wav>close001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊz</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:the end of an activity or a period of time <vi>Students vote for their favorite teacher at the <it>close</it> of each year.</vi> <vi>At the <it>close</it> of trading, the stock market was two percent lower than yesterday.</vi> <vi>As the year <phrase>drew to a close</phrase>, the debate over the new project grew more intense.</vi> <vi>The war finally appears to be <phrase>coming to a close</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>brought</phrase> the show <phrase>to a close</phrase> with a performance of her most famous song.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>complimentary close</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>close</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="close[5]"> <hw hindex="5">close</hw> <sound><wav>close002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clos*es</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the area and buildings that are around a cathedral <vi>a cathedral <it>close</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a road that is closed at one end <un>used in street names <vi>Turn into Bloomhill <it>Close</it>.</vi></un></dt></def> <dxnl>compare <dxt>close</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="close call"> <hw>close call</hw> <sound><wav>close_03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊs-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ calls</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an escape that was almost not successful <vi>We nearly didn't get out of the burning building. It was a pretty <it>close call</it>, let me tell you!</vi> <ca>called also <cat>close shave</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="close-cropped"> <hw>close–cropped</hw> <sound><wav>close_05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊsˌkrɑ:pt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:cut very short <vi>his <it>close-cropped</it> hair</vi> <vi>the <it>close-cropped</it> grass of the golf course</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="close-fitting"> <hw>close–fit*ting</hw> <sound><wav>close03ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊsˈfɪtɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more close–fit*ting; most close–fit*ting</gram> <sl>of clothes</sl> <dt>:fitting tightly to the body :not baggy or loose <vi>a <it>close-fitting</it> pair of pants</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="close-knit"> <hw>close–knit</hw> <sound><wav>close_10.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊsˈnɪt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more close–knit; most close–knit</gram> <dt><un>used to describe a group of people who care about each other and who are very friendly with each other <vi>a <it>close-knit</it> family</vi> <vi><it>close-knit</it> communities/towns</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="close-minded"> <hw>close–mind*ed</hw> <sound><wav>close04ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzˈmaɪndəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more close–mind*ed; most close–mind*ed</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>closed-minded</sx> <vi><it>close-minded</it> people</vi> <vi>a very <it>close-minded</it> attitude</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
