<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="closed"> <hw>closed</hw> <sound><wav>closed01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:covering an opening <vi>All the windows in the house are <it>closed</it>. [=<it>shut</it>]</vi> :having an opening that is covered <vi>Keep your eyes <it>closed</it>.</vi> <vi>He looked at me through half-<it>closed</it> eyes.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> container</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> umbrella</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not operating or open to the public <vi>The store is <it>closed</it> for lunch between 1 and 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The beach is <it>closed</it> this time of night.</vi> <vi>These restrooms are <it>closed</it> for cleaning.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> road/bridge</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:having ended :not being worked on anymore <vi>The case is <it>closed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:no longer able to be discussed <vi>The question is <it>closed</it>.</vi> <vi>The chairman declared the discussion <it>closed</it> and allowed no further speeches.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:including only people from a particular group <vi>There was a <it>closed</it> circle of advisers protecting the President.</vi> <vi>clubs with <it>closed</it> memberships</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:happening in private :not allowing the public to participate or know what is being said or done <vi>The meeting was <it>closed</it> to the public.</vi> <vi>The Prime Minister said that today's <it>closed</it> meeting with the President was particularly constructive.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed</it> session of Congress</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:not willing to listen to or accept different ideas or opinions <vi><it>closed</it> societies</vi> <vi>I had a <phrase>closed mind</phrase> at first, but now I understand the need for change.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>behind closed doors</dre> <def><dt>:in a private room or place :in private <vi>All of their meetings are held <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi> <vi>They seemed like the perfect couple, but you never know what goes on <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi> <vi>The decisions are made <it>behind closed doors</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes closed</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="close[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">close</hw> <sound><wav>close_01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊz</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clos*es</if></in> <in><if>closed</if></in> <in><if>clos*ing</if></in> <def><snote>The opposite of <it>close</it> is <it>open</it> in every sense except senses 3b and 9.</snote> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move (a door, window, etc.) so that things cannot pass through an opening :<sx>shut</sx> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>close</it> the door.</vi> <vi>We had better <it>close</it> the windows; it looks like it's going to rain.</vi> <vi>I forgot to <it>close</it> the gate.</vi> <vi>She was having trouble <it>closing</it> the drawer.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> the lid on the box tightly.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The door opened and <it>closed</it> so quietly that I didn't notice he had come in the room.</vi> <vi>The box's lid <it>closed</it> with a bang.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cover the opening of (something) :<sx>shut</sx> <vi>Remember to <it>close</it> the box of cereal when you're done.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to bring together the parts or edges of (something open) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Please <it>close</it> your books and put them under your desks.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> your mouth.</vi> <vi><it>Close</it> your eyes and go to sleep.</vi> <vi>I <it>closed</it> my fists and got ready to fight.</vi> <vi><it>close</it> an umbrella</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>This suitcase just won't <it>close</it>!</vi> <vi>Her eyes <it>closed</it>, and she drifted off to sleep.</vi> <vi>My throat <it>closed</it> and I felt like I couldn't breathe.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to bring together the edges of (a wound) so that it can heal <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>It took 10 stitches to <it>close</it> the wound on his head.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The cut eventually <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed up</it>, <it>healed over</it>] on its own.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to not allow (a road, park, etc.) to be used for a period of time <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The city <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed off</it>] the beach during the storm.</vi> <vi>They <it>closed</it> the bridge to traffic. [=they did not allow cars to use the bridge]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The park <it>closes</it> every evening at dusk.</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) for a period of time <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>closed</it> the school today because of the storm.</vi> <vi>We'll be <it>closing</it> the theater while we make the necessary repairs.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The store <it>closes</it> for lunch from 1 to 2 p.m.</vi> <vi>The airport <it>closed</it> for two hours yesterday due to icy conditions.</vi> <vi>The bank <it>closes</it> at noon on Saturdays.</vi> <vi>What time does the library <it>close</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) permanently <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed down, shut down</it>] the school/factory/office last year.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The restaurant has <it>closed</it> for lack of business.</vi> <vi>The play <it>closed</it> [=it stopped being performed] after 112 performances.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to end (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The minister <it>closed</it> [=<it>concluded</it>] the services with a short prayer.</vi> <vi>She <it>closed</it> the meeting by thanking everyone for their help.</vi> <vi>Investigators <it>closed</it> the case after concluding that his death was an accident.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The services <it>closed</it> [=<it>concluded</it>] with a short prayer.</vi> <vi>I'd like to <it>close</it> by thanking you all for your help.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop keeping money in (an account at a bank) <vi>I <it>closed</it> [=<it>closed out</it>] my savings account and opened up a new one at another bank.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to end the use of (a file, document, or program) on a computer <vi>Remember to save the file before <it>closing</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to formally accept (an agreement) <vi>They just <it>closed</it> a deal to take ownership of a new restaurant.</vi> <vi>the custom of <it>closing</it> a deal by shaking hands</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close on <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to reach a specified price or level at the end of the day <vi>The stock opened at $19 a share and <it>closed</it> at $22.</vi> <vi>Stocks opened weak but <it>closed</it> strong.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:to reduce the amount of distance or difference between two things, people, or groups <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The challenger has <it>closed</it> [=<it>narrowed</it>] the champion's lead to within two points.</vi> <vi><it>closing</it> the distance to the lead runner</vi> <vi>These changes will help <phrase>close the gap</phrase> between the richest and the poorest countries.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She has <it>closed</it> to within two points of the champion.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>close down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to permanently stop operating :<sx>close</sx> <vi>The factory <it>closed down</it> in the 1980s.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop broadcasting from a radio or television station for the day <vi>We're <it>closing down</it> for the night: tune in again tomorrow morning!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>close down (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close (something) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to permanently stop the services or activities of (a business, school, etc.) <vi>They <it>closed down</it> [=<it>closed</it>, <it>shut down</it>] the school due to financial problems.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>closedown</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to come or move nearer or closer <vi>The storm is <it>closing in</it> [=<it>approaching</it>] fast.</vi> <vi>Enemy troops are <it>closing in</it> all around us!</vi> <vi>The lions <it>closed in</it> for the kill.</vi> <vi>I felt that the world was <it>closing in</it> around me.</vi> <vi>The air became colder as night/darkness <it>closed in</it>. [=as darkness fell, as the night became dark]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The fire was <it>closing in on</it> their neighborhood.</vi> <vi>The camera slowly <it>closed in on</it> the actor's face.</vi> <vi>Police were <it>closing in on</it> the two men.</vi> <vi>Researchers are <it>closing in on</it> [=they are close to finding] a cure for the disease.</vi> <vi>She's <it>closing in on</it> 40. [=she is almost 40 years old]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close (something) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not allow (something) to be used for a period of time :<sx>close</sx> <vi>The city <it>closed off</it> the beach to tourists.</vi> <vi><it>closing off</it> a road with barriers</vi> <vi>Half of the museum was <it>closed off</it> while they made the changes.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>He <it>closes</it> himself <it>off</it> to new experiences. [=he does not allow himself to have new experiences]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to formally and legally agree to and complete (an important financial arrangement, such as the purchase of a house) <vi>We're going to <it>close on</it> our house next Friday.</vi> <vi>They <it>closed on</it> the deal.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>close <dxn>9 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>close out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to quickly sell (all of a particular type of product in a store) at a lower price <vi>We're <it>closing out</it> our entire stock of children's clothing! Come and pick up some bargains!</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>closeout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop keeping money in (a bank account) <vi>She withdrew all her money and <it>closed out</it> [=<it>closed</it>] her account.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to end (something) in a specified way <vi>The team <it>closed out</it> the series with a 2–1 win over New York.</vi> <vi>She <it>closed out</it> her remarkable career with a final grand performance.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close ranks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>rank</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close the door on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>door</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to close and lock all the doors of a building usually for a short period of time <vi>Businesses <it>closed up</it> [=<it>closed</it>] early so employees could attend the parade.</vi> <vi>We've <it>closed up</it> for the day. Please come back tomorrow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>close (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to close and lock all the doors of (a house, store, etc.) <vi>They <it>closed up</it> the house and left town.</vi> <snote>To <phrase>close up shop</phrase> is to go out of business forever or stop performing all services or activities for a period of time. <vi>Rather than <it>closing up shop</it> entirely, the company laid off half of its workers.</vi> <vi>The restaurant has already <it>closed up shop</it> for the winter.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to move closer together <vi>The troops <it>closed up</it> and prepared to begin the attack.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a wound</ssl> <dt>:to become completely healed <vi>The cut eventually <it>closed up</it> [=<it>closed</it>] on its own.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become quiet :to stop talking about your thoughts or emotions with other people <vi>She <it>closes up</it> when people ask her about her parents.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>close (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>close up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to bring (people or things) closer together <vi><it>Close up</it> the spaces between the lines.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close your doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>door</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close your eyes to</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="closed-captioned"> <hw>closed–cap*tioned</hw> <sound><wav>closed02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈkæpʃənd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>of a television show or movie</sl> <dt>:having written words that appear on the screen to describe what is being said for people who do not hear well and that can only be seen if you are using a special device</dt></def> <uro><ure>closed–cap*tion*ing</ure> <sound><wav>close01v.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈkæpʃənɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="closed-circuit"> <hw>closed–cir*cuit</hw> <sound><wav>closed03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈsɚkət</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt><un>used to describe a television system that sends its signal through wires to a limited number of televisions <vi>The store uses <it>closed-circuit</it> television to monitor the activities of shoppers.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="closed-door"> <hw>closed–door</hw> <sound><wav>closed04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈdoɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><dt>:held secretly or privately <vi>The council held a <it>closed-door</it> session in Washington.</vi> <vi><it>closed-door</it> meetings</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="closed-minded"> <hw>closed–mind*ed</hw> <sound><wav>close01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈmaɪndəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more closed–mind*ed; most closed–mind*ed</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>disapproving</sl> <dt>:not willing to consider different ideas or opinions :having or showing a closed mind <vi>He's becoming increasingly <it>closed-minded</it> in his old age.</vi> <vi>a <it>closed-minded</it> refusal to listen</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>open-minded</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>closed–mind*ed*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro> <uro><ure>closed–mind*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="closed-mouthed"> <hw>closed–mouthed</hw> <sound><wav>close02ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkloʊzdˈmaʊθt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more closed–mouthed; most closed–mouthed</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>close-mouthed</sx> <vi>He remains <it>closed-mouthed</it> about his plans.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="book[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">book</hw> <sound><wav>book0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbʊk</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>books</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a set of printed sheets of paper that are held together inside a cover :a long written work <vi>The shelves in his office are filled with <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>That's one of the best <it>books</it> I've read in a long time.</vi> <vi>a novelist who has written some wonderful <it>books</it></vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> about plumbing</vi> <vi>The library has many dictionaries and other reference <it>books</it>.</vi> <vi>a hardcover/paperback <it>book</it></vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>You can learn many things by studying the great <it>book</it> of nature. [=by studying nature]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a long written work that can be read on a computer :<sx>e-book</sx> <vi>an electronic <it>book</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of sheets of paper that are inside a cover and that you can write information on <vi>an appointment <it>book</it></vi> <vi>an address <it>book</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>notebook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a major section of a long written work (such as the Bible) <vi>the <it>books</it> of the Bible</vi> <vi>a story that is told in the <it>Book</it> of Job</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good book</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a set of things held together inside a cover like the pages of a book <vi>a <it>book</it> of stamps</vi> <vi>a <it>book</it> of matches [=a matchbook]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>checkbook</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>books</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the financial records of a business <vi>The company's <it>books</it> [=<it>accounts</it>] show a profit.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the official records of a business or organization <vi>I'm sorry, but your name does not appear in/on our <it>books</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:the knowledge or information that relates to a particular subject, person, etc. <vi><it>The book</it> on him is that he can't hit a curveball. [=people have seen and reported that he can't hit a curveball]</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <bnote>the book</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>phone book</sx> <vi>Give me a call if you need to. I'm in <it>the book</it>. [=my telephone number is listed in the telephone book]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a closed book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is difficult to understand <vi>Even to his closest friends, he was always something of <it>a closed book</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>an open book <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an open book</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that is easy to learn about and understand <vi>My life is <it>an open book</it>. I have nothing to hide.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>bring (someone) to book</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to require (someone) to explain and accept punishment or criticism for bad or wrong behavior <vi>The people responsible for these crimes must be <it>brought to book</it>. [=<it>brought to account</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>by the book</dre> <def><dt>:by following the official rules very strictly <vi>My boss insists on doing everything <it>by the book</it>.</vi> <vi>They ran all the investigations <it>by the book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cook the books</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cook</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>every trick in the book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>trick</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hit the books</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to study or begin studying very intensely <vi>I've got to <it>hit the books</it> all weekend if I'm going to pass this test.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in my book</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in my opinion <vi>She deserves credit, <it>in my book</it>, for much of the company's recent success.</vi> <vi>He isn't even a good boss, at least not <it>in my book</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's bad books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are not liked or treated nicely by someone <vi>He remains <it>in her bad books</it>. [=she is still displeased with him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in someone's good books</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:in a state in which you are liked or are treated nicely by someone <vi>He's trying to get back <it>in his boss's good books</it> by offering to work overtime.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>one for the books</dre> <def><dt>:a very unusual, important, or surprising situation, statement, event, etc. <vi>There have been a lot of scandals in local politics over the years, but this is <it>one for the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the books</dre> <def><dt>:part of the set of official laws <vi>It's an outdated law that's still <it>on the books</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>read someone like a book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>read</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>suit someone's book</dre> <dx>see <dxt>suit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>throw the book at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to punish (someone) as severely as possible <vi>The judge threatened to <it>throw the book at</it> him if he committed another offense.</vi> <vi>I thought I would get off with just a warning, but they <it>threw the book at</it> me.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>write the book on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>write</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="door"> <art><artref id="door_rev.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,195.8</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes">door</hw> <sound><wav>door0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdoɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>doors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a movable piece of wood, glass, or metal that swings or slides open and shut so that people can enter or leave a room, building, vehicle, etc. <vi>open/shut/slam/lock/bolt the <it>door</it></vi> <vi>I heard a knock on/at the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>the bedroom/bathroom/cellar <it>door</it></vi> <vi>The car has four <it>doors</it>. = It's a four-<it>door</it> car.</vi> <vi>Leave the package at the front/back/side <it>door</it>. [=the door at the front/back/side of the house, building, etc.]</vi> <vi>Can you <phrase>answer the door</phrase>? [=open the door to see who is knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Is somebody <phrase>at the door</phrase>? [=knocking on the door or ringing the doorbell]</vi> <vi>Let me open the <it>door</it> for you. = (<it>US</it>) Let me <phrase>get the door</phrase> for you.</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) Can you <it>get the door</it>? [=can you open or close the door for me?] My hands are full.</vi> <vi>an <phrase>exterior/outside door</phrase> [=a door that can be used to enter or leave a building]</vi> <vi>an <phrase>interior door</phrase> [=a door inside a building; a door that connects rooms]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>garage door</phrase> [=a large door that covers the opening through which a car enters and leaves a garage]</vi> <vi>turn/pull the <phrase>door handle</phrase></vi> <vi>a large brass <phrase>door knocker</phrase> [=<it>knocker</it>]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>back door</dxt> <dxt>dutch door</dxt> <dxt>french door</dxt> <dxt>revolving door</dxt> <dxt>storm door</dxt> <dxt>trapdoor</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a part of an object (such as piece of furniture or an appliance) that swings or slides open and shut <vi>the cupboard/closet/refrigerator/oven <it>door</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the opening for a door :the entrance to a room or building :<sx>doorway</sx> <vi>Please don't block the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>I peeked through the open <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He stood at/before the <it>door</it>.</vi> <vi>He greeted his guests as they <phrase>came in/through the door</phrase>. = He greeted his guests <phrase>at the door</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>walked out the door</phrase> [=<it>left</it>] without saying goodbye.</vi> <vi>standing (just/right) <phrase>inside/outside the door</phrase> [=inside/outside the room, building, etc., near the door]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a house, building, apartment, office, etc. <un>used with an adverb to indicate where something is in relation to something else <vi>She lives in a house two <phrase>doors down/up</phrase> from me. [=there is one house between our houses]</vi> <vi>The library is a <phrase>few doors down</phrase> from the bank. [=there are several buildings between the library and the bank]</vi> <vi>We grew up <phrase>two doors apart</phrase>. [=with one house/apartment between our houses/apartments]</vi></un> <snote>If you do something <phrase>(from) door to door</phrase>, you do it at each of the houses, apartments, or buildings in an area. <vi>Girl Scouts are selling cookies <it>door to door</it>. = Girl Scouts are <phrase>going door to door</phrase> selling cookies.</vi> <vi>She <it>went (from) door to door</it> looking for her cat.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>door-to-door</dxt> <dxt>next door</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used especially with <it>open</it> or <it>unlock</it> to describe an opportunity or possibility <vi>The grant will <it>open</it> new <it>doors</it> for our town. [=will give our town new opportunities]</vi> <vi>The discovery may <it>unlock</it> the <it>door</it> to a cure for the disease.</vi> <vi>The <it>door</it> is <it>open</it> (to you) if you want a better job.</vi> <vi>A good education can <it>open/unlock</it> the <it>door</it> of success. [=can make success possible]</vi> <vi>The patent on the product has expired, which <phrase>leaves the door open for</phrase> [=makes it possible for] other companies to make it.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>out of doors</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>at death's door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>death</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>behind closed doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>closed</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close the door on</dre> <def><dt>:to no longer think about, consider, or accept (something) <vi>I'd like to <it>close the door on</it> that chapter in my life.</vi> <vi>The former senator says she hasn't <it>closed the door on</it> politics.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>close the door on</it> your options.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>close your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>closed its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to close permanently :to stop operating <vi>The museum may be forced to <it>close its doors</it>.</vi> <vi>The store <it>closed its doors</it> (for the last time) last fall.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>darken someone's door/doors</dre> <dx>see <dxt>darken</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>get your foot in the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep the wolf from the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wolf</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lay the blame for (something) at someone's door</dre> <def><dt>:to blame someone for (something) <vi>They <it>laid the blame for</it> the book's failure <it>at my door</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open doors for</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open the door</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>open your doors</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to allow someone to enter <vi>The country has <it>opened its doors</it> to immigrants.</vi> <vi>local churches that <it>open their doors</it> to the homeless in the winter months [=that let homeless people stay there]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a business or organization</ssl> <dt>:to open for business :to begin operating <vi>The new store will be <it>opening its doors</it> next month.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show (someone) the door</dre> <def><dt>:to tell or force (someone) to leave <vi>We don't tolerate bad behavior. If you cause trouble, we'll <it>show you the door</it>.</vi> <vi>If the coach doesn't win this year, they'll <it>show him the door</it>. [=they'll fire him]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>show/see (someone) to the door</dre> <def><dt>:to go to the door with (someone who is leaving) <vi>My secretary will <it>show you to the door</it>. [=<it>show you out</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>doorless</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>doorless</it> cubicle</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="eye[1]"> <art><artref id="eye.eps"/><capt/><dim>191,72.5</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">eye</hw> <sound><wav>eye00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈaɪ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>eyes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the part of the body that you see with <vi>Her <it>eyes</it> slowly became accustomed to the dark.</vi> <vi>He wears a patch over one <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>I have something in my <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has (a pair of) bright blue <it>eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>bright/sad/sleepy <it>eyes</it></vi> <vi>She has good/strong/bad/weak <it>eyes</it>. [=<it>eyesight</it>]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes lit up</phrase> [=she looked excited and happy] when he showed her the ring.</vi> <vi>His <phrase>eyes were popping out of his head</phrase> with astonishment [=he looked very astonished] when he saw how big it was!</vi> <vi>He punched him <phrase>right between the eyes</phrase>. [=punched him hard in the face]</vi> <vi>She looked me (right) <phrase>in the eye</phrase> [=she looked directly at me] and told me I was fired.</vi> <vi>The garden is <phrase>a feast for the eyes</phrase>. [=the garden is very beautiful]</vi> <vi>The display was very pleasing <phrase>to the eye</phrase>. [=pleasing to look at]</vi> <vi>I measured the distance <phrase>by eye</phrase>. = I measured the distance <phrase>with my eye</phrase>. [=by looking at it to get a rough idea of its size]</vi> <vi>Their daughter came home from school <phrase>with tears in her eyes</phrase>. [=she was crying]</vi> <vi>Seeing her again <phrase>brought tears to my eyes</phrase>. = Seeing her again <phrase>brought a tear to my eye</phrase>. [=made me shed tears]</vi> <vi>He <phrase>had/kept half an eye on</phrase> [=he occasionally looked at] the TV while he read the paper.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an ability to understand and appreciate something seen <vi>Only a trained <it>eye</it> can tell the difference between the original painting and a good copy.</vi> <vi>For decorating, they rely on her discerning/discriminating/expert <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>He has an artist's <it>eye</it> for color.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>have an eye for</phrase> something or <phrase>a good/keen/sharp eye for</phrase> something, you have a special ability to recognize a particular thing or quality. <vi>He <it>has a keen eye for</it> detail.</vi> <vi>He <it>has a good eye</it> for quality.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way something looks to you <vi>It looks a little awkward to my <it>eye</it>. [=it looks awkward to me]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a way of looking at or judging something <vi>He reviewed the proposal with a jaundiced/critical <it>eye</it>.</vi> <vi>The biographer <phrase>cast a cold/critical/skeptical eye</phrase> on the artist's life.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe where someone is looking <vi>Her <it>eye</it> was attracted to the bright colors in the painting.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>dropped her eyes</phrase> [=she looked down] when he looked at her. = Her <phrase>eyes fell</phrase> when he looked at her.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>averted his eyes</phrase> [=he looked away] when she approached him.</vi> <vi>I saw something moving <phrase>out of the corner of my eye</phrase>. [=to the side of where I was looking]</vi> <vi>Her <phrase>eyes fell on</phrase> [=she noticed] a piece of evidence no one had noticed before.</vi> <vi><phrase>All eyes were on her</phrase> [=everyone was looking at her] as she entered the room.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>fixed her eyes on</phrase> me [=she kept looking or staring at me] for a long time before answering.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a way of looking at or thinking about something <vi>We need to look at this problem with a fresh <it>eye</it>. [=to look at the problem in a new way]</vi> <vi><phrase>Beauty is in the eye of the beholder</phrase>. [=different people have different ideas about what is beautiful]</vi> <un>often plural <vi>He was guilty in the <it>eyes</it> of the police. [=the police considered him guilty]</vi> <vi>He was handsome in her <it>eyes</it>. [=she thought he was handsome]</vi> <vi>In the <it>eyes</it> [=<it>opinion</it>] of many, he is the best person for the job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the hole through the top of a needle <vi>the <it>eye</it> of a needle</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a loop that a hook fits into to fasten or attach something</dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an area on a potato from which a new plant can grow :a bud on a potato</dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the center of a storm (such as a hurricane) where there is little wind or rain and sometimes there is clear sky <vi>The <it>eye</it> of the storm should reach the coast by morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all eyes</dre> <def><dt>:watching something or someone closely :very attentive <vi>She was <it>all eyes</it> as I opened the box.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>an eye for an eye</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that a person who has committed a crime should be given punishment that is the same as or as serious as the crime <vi>The ancient code of law called for punishment in the form of <it>an eye for an eye</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as far as the eye could see</dre> <def><dt>:as far as could be seen <vi>The crowd stretched away <it>as far as the eye could see</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>a sight for sore eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a twinkle in your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>twinkle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>bawl your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bawl</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>before your eyes</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>in front of your eyes</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If something happens (<it>right</it>) <it>before your eyes</it> or <it>in front of your (very) eyes</it>, it happens in a very open and visible way so that you can see it very clearly. <vi>Technology is changing <it>right before our eyes</it>.</vi> <vi>We were watching a disaster take place <it>in front of our very eyes</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>can't believe your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>believe</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast/run your eye over</dre> <def><dt>:to read it or look at (something) quickly. <vi>Please <it>run your eye over</it> this and let me know what you think.</vi> <vi>She <it>cast her eye over</it> the apartment, appalled by the mess.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>catch your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>catch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>close/shut your eyes to</dre> <def><dt>:to refuse to notice or accept the truth or existence of (something) :to ignore (something) <vi>Our legislators have <it>closed their eyes to</it> the poverty that surrounds them.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cock an/your eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cock</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cry your eyes out</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy on the eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>eyes in the back of your head</dre> <def><dt><snote>When people are surprised that you have seen or noticed something that is behind you, they may say that you have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>. <vi>How did you know we were here? You must have <it>eyes in the back of your head</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>feast your eyes on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>feast</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for your eyes only</dre> <def><dt>:intended to be seen only by you <vi>This memo is <it>for your eyes only</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>give (someone) the eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Several men were <it>giving her the eye</it> across the bar.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have/keep an/your eye out for</dre> <def><dt>:to be looking for (someone or something) :to hope to see or find (someone or something) <vi>I'm <it>keeping my eye out for</it> a good cheap used car.</vi> <vi>He'll be here soon, so <it>keep your eye out for</it> him.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:to have (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>She <it>has an eye to</it> attending graduate school. [=she hopes to attend graduate school]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(have) stars in your eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>star</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have your eye on</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to watch (someone or something) closely <vi>I'll <it>have my eye on</it> the kids while they're swimming.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be thinking about buying (something) <vi>I <it>have my eye on</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>She's <it>had her eye on</it> that house for a long time.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in a pig's eye</dre> <def><sl>US slang</sl> <dt><un>used to express strong disagreement <vi>You want me to apologize to him? <it>In a pig's eye</it>! [=<it>Never!</it>]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the blink of an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blink</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the public eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a position that receives a lot of public notice and attention <vi>The job requires someone who is comfortable being <it>in the public eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</dre> <def><dt>:in a very short time :very quickly <vi>He was back <it>in the twinkle/twinkling of an eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your mind's eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you see something <it>in your mind's eye</it>, you imagine or remember how it looks. <vi>I can still see the old playground <it>in my mind's eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep an/your eye on</dre> <def><dt>:to watch or take care of (someone or something) <vi>Will you <it>keep an eye on</it> my suitcase (for me) while I get something to eat?</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eye on the ball</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ball</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes glued to</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to watch (something) very closely for a long time <vi>They <it>kept their eyes glued to</it> the television, waiting for more news about the accident.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep your eyes open</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>keep your eyes peeled</va> <vl>or Brit</vl> <va>keep your eyes skinned</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look or watch closely in order to see or find (something) <vi>We <it>kept our eyes peeled</it> for a sign that would tell us where to turn.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lay/set eyes on</dre> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>clap eyes on</va></vr> <def><dt>:to see or look at (someone or something) <vi>I hope never to <it>lay eyes on</it> him again!</vi> <vi>We liked the house from the moment we <it>set eyes on</it> it. [=the moment when we first saw it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make eyes at</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to look at (someone) in a way that shows sexual attraction <vi>Some guy was <it>making eyes at</it> her from across the room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>more than meets the eye</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>more than meets the eye</it> or there is <phrase>more to something than meets the eye</phrase>, there is more to it than there appears to be at first. <vi>There is <it>more to this proposal than meets the eye</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>my eye</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to express surprise or mild disagreement <vi>A diamond, <it>my eye</it>! That's glass!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>not bat an eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>only have eyes for</dre> <def><dt>:to only be attracted to (a particular person) :to only feel love for (someone) <vi>He <it>only has eyes for</it> you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open someone's eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to notice or be aware of something important <vi>The experience really <it>opened his eyes</it> and changed the way he felt about his life.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>It's time they <it>opened their eyes to</it> the truth.</vi> <vi>His film helped <it>open people's eyes to</it> the problem.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:to begin to notice or be aware of something important <vi>You need to <it>open your eyes</it> and face the truth.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>We have to <it>open our eyes to</it> these problems and stop ignoring them.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>pull the wool over someone's eyes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>wool</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>roving eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>roving</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>run your eye down</dre> <def><dt>:to quickly read or look at (something, such as a list) <vi>She <it>ran her eye down</it> the list looking for her name.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>see eye to eye</dre> <def><dt>:to have the same opinion :<sx>agree</sx> <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>They don't <it>see eye to eye</it> (with each other) on this issue.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take your eyes off</dre> <def><dt>:to stop looking at (someone or something) <vi>I <it>took my eyes off</it> the road for one second.</vi> <vi>She was so beautiful, he <phrase>couldn't take his eyes off</phrase> her.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the apple of someone's eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>apple</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>turn a blind eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>under the eye of</dre> <def><dt>:while being watched by (someone) <vi>Students work <phrase>under the watchful/vigilant eye of</phrase> their teacher.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>up to your eyes</dre> <def><dt>:deeply involved in or affected by something <vi>We're <it>up to our eyes</it> in work. [=we are very busy]</vi> <vi>They're <it>up to their eyes</it> in debt.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with an eye to/toward</dre> <def><dt>:with (something) in your thoughts as a goal or purpose <vi>They hired him <it>with an eye toward</it> increased sales.</vi> <vi>They bought the house <it>with an eye toward</it> its restoration.</vi> <vi>He took the job <phrase>with an eye to the future</phrase>. [=he took the job because he felt it would help him in the future]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your/both eyes open</dre> <def><dt>:fully aware of what could happen <vi>I went into the job <it>with my eyes (wide) open</it>.</vi> <vi>If you do this, you need to do it <it>with both eyes open</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>with your eyes shut/closed</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:with little or no effort :very easily <vi>She could run that company <it>with her eyes shut</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</dre> <def><dt><snote>If <it>your eyes are bigger than your stomach</it>, you have taken more food than you can possibly eat. <vi>I can't finish my meal—I guess <it>my eyes were bigger than my stomach</it>!</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>black eye</dxt> <dxt>evil eye</dxt> <dxt>private eye</dxt> <dxt>rib eye</dxt> <dxt>seeing eye</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
