<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cloth"> <hw highlight="yes">cloth</hw> <sound><wav>cloth001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɑ:θ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>cloths</if> <sound><wav>cloth002.wav</wav><wav>cloth003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklɑ:ðz, ˈklɑ:θs</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:material that is made by weaving together threads of cotton, wool, nylon, etc., and that is used to make clothes, sheets, etc. <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a piece of <it>cloth</it> [=<it>fabric</it>]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The dress is made out of a beautiful silk <it>cloth</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>cloth</it> napkins/diapers</vi> <vi>a <it>cloth</it> bag</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a piece of cloth that is used for a particular purpose (such as cleaning things) <vi>Wipe the surface with a clean dry <it>cloth</it>.</vi> <vi>a damp/wet <it>cloth</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>dishcloth</dxt> <dxt>facecloth</dxt> <dxt>loincloth</dxt> <dxt>tablecloth</dxt> <dxt>washcloth</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>the cloth</bnote> <dt>:Christian priests and ministers :<sx>clergy</sx> <vi>He has great respect for <it>the cloth</it>.</vi> <vi><phrase>a man of the cloth</phrase> [=a priest or minister]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut from the same cloth</dre> <def><dt><snote>If people or things are <it>cut from the same cloth</it>, they are very similar to each other. <vi>Our mothers were <it>cut from the same cloth</it>.</vi> <vi>The country's new president is <it>cut from the same cloth</it> as his predecessor.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of whole cloth</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><snote>If something is created <it>out of whole cloth</it>, it is invented in order to trick someone into believing something. <vi>He would make up stories <it>out of whole cloth</it> just to stir up trouble.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="drop cloth"> <hw>drop cloth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cloths</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a sheet of cloth or plastic that is used to cover the floor and furniture while you are painting a room <dx>compare <dxt>dust sheet</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="ground cloth"> <hw>ground cloth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cloths</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a piece of waterproof material that is used under tents, sleeping bags, etc., by people who are sleeping outdoors <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>ground sheet</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="man of the cloth"> <hw>man of the cloth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>men of the cloth</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>formal + old-fashioned</sl> <dt>:a man who is a priest or minister</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="tea cloth"> <hw>tea cloth</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cloths</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>dish towel</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="terry cloth"> <hw>ter*ry cloth</hw> <sound><wav>terry01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈteri-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a type of soft, thick cloth with many tiny loops on its surface that is often used to make towels <vi>a <it>terry cloth</it> robe/towel</vi> <ca>called also <cat>terry</cat> (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>towelling</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cut[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cut</hw> <sound><wav>cut00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cuts</if></in> <in><if>cut</if></in> <in><if>cut*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to use a sharp tool (such as a knife) to open or divide (something, such as paper or wood) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Cut</it> the paper along/on the dotted line (with a pair of scissors).</vi> <vi><it>cutting</it> a piece of string</vi> <vi>He uses the ax to <it>cut</it> wood.</vi> <vi>The meat is so tender you can <it>cut</it> it with a fork.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>The excitement/tension in the room was so thick <phrase>you could cut it with a knife</phrase>. [=there was a lot of excitement/tension in the room]</vi></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Cut</it> along/on the dotted line.</vi> <vi>The saw easily <it>cuts</it> through metal.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> into the melon with a knife.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make a hole or wound in (a person's skin) <vi>I <it>cut</it> myself while shaving.</vi> <vi>I <it>cut</it> my finger on a sharp piece of metal. = A sharp piece of metal <it>cut</it> me (on the finger).</vi> <vi>I had a <it>cut</it> finger.</vi> <vi>We were fighting, and he tried to <it>cut</it> me with his knife.</vi> <vi>Pieces of broken glass <it>cut</it> her face and arms.</vi> <vi>He fell and <it>cut</it> his head open on a sharp rock.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (a hole) in something by using a sharp tool <vi>They <it>cut</it> a hole in the wall for the new window.</vi> <vi>Doctors begin by <it>cutting</it> a small incision in the chest.</vi> <vi><it>Cut</it> several slits in the top of the crust to allow air to escape.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to divide or separate parts of (something) by using a sharp tool <vi>It's time to <it>cut</it> [=<it>slice</it>] the cake!</vi> <vi>I'll <it>cut</it> the apple in half so you both can have some.</vi> <vi>Would you <it>cut</it> me a slice of bread? = Would you <it>cut</it> a slice of bread for me?</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>Add one large onion that has been <it>cut into</it> one-inch pieces.</vi> <vi>The chicken is <it>cut into</it> long strips and served on top of the salad.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>Her walls were covered with pictures <it>cut from</it> magazines.</vi> <vi>a piece of meat that is <it>cut from</it> the hind end of the animal</vi></un> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>She was <it>cutting off</it> pieces of watermelon and giving them to the children.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to cut something <vi>This knife doesn't <it>cut</it> well.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be able to be cut <vi>Aluminum foil <it>cuts</it> easily with scissors.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (hair, grass, etc.) shorter by using a sharp tool (such as scissors) <vi>I <it>cut</it> my hair short for the summer.</vi> <vi>Where'd you get your hair <it>cut</it>?</vi> <vi>I need to <it>cut</it> [=<it>trim</it>] my nails; they're way too long.</vi> <vi>She keeps her nails <it>cut</it> short.</vi> <vi>The grass in our yard needs to be <it>cut</it>. [=<it>mowed</it>]</vi> <vi>the smell of fresh-<it>cut</it> grass</vi> <vi>The wood is already <phrase>cut to size/length</phrase>. [=it has already been cut so that it is the proper size/length]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give (hair or clothing) a certain style by cutting it <un>usually used as <it>(be) cut</it> <vi>Her hair is light brown and <it>cut</it> in a short bob.</vi> <vi>She was wearing a dress that <it>was cut</it> low at the neck. [=she was wearing a low-<it>cut</it> dress]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give (something) a new shape by using a sharp tool <vi>a beautifully <it>cut</it> diamond</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make or form (something) by cutting or removing material <vi>We all <it>cut</it> [=<it>carved</it>] our names on/into the tree.</vi> <vi>The stream <it>cuts</it> a path through the woods.</vi> <vi>builders <it>cutting</it> new roads in the forest</vi> <un>often + <it>out</it> <vi>At the center of the table was a statue <it>cut out</it> of ice.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make the amount of (something) smaller :<sx>reduce</sx> <vi>Our benefits were recently <it>cut</it> at work.</vi> <vi>The drug has been shown to <it>cut</it> the risk of heart attack by half.</vi> <vi>In just three years, the mayor has <it>cut</it> the city's crime in half.</vi> <vi>The President has promised to <it>cut</it> government spending.</vi> <vi><it>Cutting</it> taxes can have positive and negative effects on the economy.</vi> <vi>measures that are designed to <it>cut</it> costs = cost-<it>cutting</it> measures</vi> <vi>The company's expenses had been <phrase>cut to the bone</phrase>. [=reduced to their lowest possible amount]</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>This route can <it>cut</it> as much as five minutes <it>off</it> your driving time.</vi> <vi>The experience <it>cut</it> 20 years <it>off</it> (of) his life. [=shortened his life by 20 years]</vi> <vi>We've <it>cut</it> 20 percent <it>off</it> the regular retail price.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (a book, film, etc.) shorter by removing parts <vi>His article was <it>cut</it> [=<it>shortened</it>] by about 500 words.</vi> <vi>The movie had to be <it>cut</it> because it was too long.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) from a book, film, etc. <vi>The movie's director decided to <it>cut</it> [=<it>cut out</it>, <it>omit</it>] my part.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The director <it>cut</it> the scene <it>from</it> the final version of the film.</vi> <vi>They decided to <it>cut</it> her report <it>from</it> the newscast.</vi> <vi>About 500 words were <it>cut from</it> his article.</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (something) from a computer document in a way that allows you to move it to another part of the document or to another document <vi>After you select the text with your mouse, you can <it>cut</it> it and then paste it at the beginning of the paragraph.</vi> <vi>You can <phrase>cut and paste</phrase> the picture into your file.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut-and-paste</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (a plant or part of a plant) by cutting it <vi>It's illegal to <it>cut</it> [=<it>cut down</it>] trees in this forest.</vi> <vi>We'll start <it>cutting</it> and harvesting the wheat next week.</vi> <snote>A <phrase>cut flower</phrase> is a flower that has been cut off the plant that it grew on. <vi>He brought her a bouquet of <it>cut flowers</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (something) to no longer be connected <vi>The enemy has <it>cut</it> [=<it>severed</it>] our supply lines.</vi> <vi>He wanted to <it>cut</it> all ties with his past and start a new life.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to allow (someone or something) to be free, loose, etc., by cutting something that stops movement <vi>They were trapped inside the crushed car and had to be <phrase>cut free</phrase>. = They had to be <it>cut</it> from the car.</vi> <vi>The boat was <phrase>cut loose</phrase> from the pier and allowed to drift away.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>cut loose</tag> at <dxt>loose</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to remove (someone) from a team, organization, etc. <vi>I was on the team for two weeks before I got <it>cut</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The coach <it>cut</it> two players <it>from</it> the team.</vi> <vi>The band was <it>cut from</it> the show at the last minute.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:to divide (a pack of cards) into two piles <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>cut</it> the deck and I'll deal.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>You <it>cut</it> and I'll deal.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to divide (an area of land) into two parts <vi>The river <it>cuts</it> the city in half.</vi> <vi>The mountain ridges are <it>cut</it> by deep valleys.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or go <it>across</it> or <it>through</it> something <vi>Let's take a shortcut and <it>cut across</it> this field.</vi> <vi>We <it>cut through</it> the park on our way home.</vi> <vi>The boundary line between the two countries <it>cuts</it> directly <it>through</it> the group's traditional homeland.</vi> <un>often used figuratively to describe something that is not limited in the usual way <vi>National security is an issue that <it>cuts across</it> party lines. [=an issue that is important to both political parties]</vi> <vi>Child abuse <it>cuts across</it> all economic and racial lines/boundaries. [=it occurs in all economic and racial groups]</vi> <vi>Her academic interests <it>cut across</it> [=involve or relate to] many disciplines.</vi></un></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move quickly <vi>a fast ship <it>cutting</it> through the waves</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to move suddenly in a different direction <vi>The driver <it>cut</it> across three lanes of traffic to get to his exit and nearly caused an accident.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The runner <it>cut</it> to his left to avoid being tackled.</vi></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move in front of other people in a line <vi>That guy <it>cut</it> to the head of the line.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> in front of us. = She <it>cut</it> ahead of us.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>Our friends let us <it>cut in</it> in front of them.</vi> <vi>Celebrities are allowed to <phrase>cut in line</phrase> at popular restaurants.</vi> <vi>Hey, no <it>cutting</it> (<it>in line</it>)!</vi></un></dt> <sn>18</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to not go to (school or a class) when you should go to it <vi>We used to <it>cut</it> [=<it>skip</it>] school together and hang out at the beach.</vi> <vi>She would take notes for me when I <it>cut</it> class.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to record (a song, album, etc.) <vi>She's in the studio <it>cutting</it> a new track/song for her next album.</vi> <vi>Elvis Presley <it>cut</it> his first record in 1954.</vi></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to suddenly move from one image or scene to another in a movie, television program, etc. <vi>The movie <it>cuts</it> quickly from one scene to the next.</vi> <vi>The camera <it>cut</it> back to the actor's face.</vi> <vi>To explain the present situation, the film <it>cuts</it> back to the hero's childhood.</vi> <un>often + <it>away</it> <vi>They quickly <it>cut away</it> to the announcer when he appeared on stage.</vi></un></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop filming a scene in a movie or television show <un>usually used as a command <vi>“<it>Cut</it>!” yelled the director.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop saying or doing (foolish or annoying things) <un>usually used in phrases like <phrase>cut the nonsense</phrase> and (less politely) <phrase>cut the crap</phrase> <vi>Let's <it>cut the nonsense</it> and get down to business.</vi> <vi><it>Cut the crap</it>, Jen! I know you're lying.</vi></un></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to stop (a motor) by moving a switch <vi>We <it>cut</it> the engine and drifted into shore.</vi> <vi>I parked and <it>cut</it> the ignition.</vi> <un>often + <it>off</it> <vi>The pilot <it>cut off</it> the engine after the plane had come to a stop.</vi></un></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to go to or deal with something in a very direct way <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Her question <it>cut to</it> the heart of the issue.</vi> <vi>This research <it>cuts to</it> the very core of who we are as human beings.</vi> <vi>Let me <it>cut to</it> the real reason why I'm here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to cause painful feelings or emotions <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>His words <it>cut</it> deeply.</vi> <vi>The disappointment <phrase>cut like a knife</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>His harsh words <it>cut</it> me very deeply.</vi> <vi>She was <phrase>cut to the quick</phrase> [=she was very badly hurt] by their insults.</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to make (alcohol) less strong by adding water or another liquid <vi>They <it>cut</it> [=<it>diluted</it>] the wine with water.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make (a drug, such as heroin) less strong by mixing it with another substance <vi>The substance is used to <it>cut</it> cocaine.</vi></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (dirt, grease, etc.) to break apart and be removed <vi>soap that <it>cuts</it> grease and grime</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>cut a check</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to write a check and give it to someone <vi>The company <it>cut</it> him <it>a check</it> and he cashed it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a dash</dre> <dx>see <dxt>dash</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut a deal</dre> <def><dt>:to make an agreement usually about business :to make a deal <vi>The band <it>cut a deal</it> with a recording company.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a figure</dre> <def><dt><snote>If you <phrase>cut a fine/dashing/heroic (etc.) figure</phrase>, you look very good and impressive. <vi>He <it>cut a fine figure</it> in his officer's uniform.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut and run</dre> <def><dt>:to leave quickly in order to avoid danger or trouble <vi>You can't just <it>cut and run</it> when your friends are in trouble.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a rug</dre> <def><sl>old-fashioned slang</sl> <dt>:to dance in an energetic way <vi>He's not young anymore, but he can still <it>cut a rug</it> on the dance floor.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut a tooth</dre> <def><sl>of a baby</sl> <dt>:to have a tooth begin to come through the gums <vi>Their baby daughter <it>cut</it> her first <it>tooth</it> yesterday.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut away (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut (something) away</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to remove (something that is not needed) by cutting <vi>They <it>cut away</it> [=<it>cut off</it>] a few of the tree's lower branches.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>20 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutaway</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use less or do less of something <vi>We've been spending too much money and we need to <it>cut back</it> [=we need to spend less money]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I've been trying to <it>cut back on</it> smoking.</vi> <vi>He's <it>cut back on</it> the time he spends in front of the TV.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut back (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to make (a plant) smaller or shorter by cutting its branches <vi><it>Cut back</it> [=<it>prune</it>] the shrub in the late fall.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reduce the size or amount of (something) <vi>We ran out of time and had to <it>cut back</it> our plans.</vi> <vi>They've <it>cut back</it> my hours at work.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cutback</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut both ways</dre> <def><dt>:to have both good and bad results, effects, etc. <vi>He knows that his extreme competitiveness <it>cuts both ways</it>.</vi> <vi>These changes in the economy <it>cut both ways</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut corners</dre> <dx>see <dxt>corner</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to use less or do less of something <vi>I haven't been able to quit smoking completely, but at least I've <it>cut down</it>. [=<it>cut back</it>]</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>I've had to <it>cut down on</it> [=<it>reduce</it>, <it>cut back on</it>] the amount of money I spend on clothes.</vi> <vi>She suggested he <it>cut down on</it> his drinking.</vi> <vi>a building material that helps <it>cut down on</it> noise</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove (a tree or bush) by cutting through its trunk or base <vi>Most of the tree was dead, so we had to <it>cut</it> it <it>down</it>.</vi> <vi>Much of the forest has been <it>cut down</it> for firewood.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to reduce the size or amount of (something) <vi>We used a shortcut that <it>cut down</it> our traveling time by 15 minutes.</vi> <vi>The machine significantly <it>cuts down</it> the amount of work necessary to harvest crops.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut down (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to kill or wound (someone) <vi>She was <it>cut down</it> by a stray bullet.</vi> <vi>The composer Schubert was <it>cut down</it> in his prime by illness. [=he died because of illness when he was in his prime]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut from the same cloth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut ice</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ice</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to join a conversation suddenly :<sx>interrupt</sx> <vi>We were trying to have a conversation, but she kept <it>cutting in</it>.</vi> <vi>“What are you guys talking about?” he <it>cut in</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>He's always <it>cutting in on</it> our conversations.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop two people who are dancing and take the place of one of them <vi>He went up to the dancing couple and said, “May I <it>cut in</it>?”</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work <vi>Once the heater <it>cuts in</it> [=<it>kicks in</it>], it'll be a lot more comfortable in here.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to include (someone) in a group of people who are receiving money or other benefits <vi>They'll help you start your business provided that you <it>cut</it> them <it>in</it> when you start making a profit.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>They want you to <it>cut</it> them <it>in on</it> [=to give them some of] the profits.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) in</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to add (something, such as butter) to dry ingredients (such as flour) by making cutting motions with a knife or other sharp tool <vi>After sifting the flour into a mixing bowl, use two knives to <it>cut in</it> the butter.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>17 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut into (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to reduce the amount of (something) <vi>Although it would <it>cut into</it> profits, we were forced to lower our prices.</vi> <vi>The extra time I was spending at work was <it>cutting into</it> my time with my family.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be able to do something well enough <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>After two weeks at the new job, he decided that he just couldn't <it>cut it</it>. [=that he couldn't do the job well enough to succeed]</vi> <vi>They didn't think that I would <it>cut it</it> as an actress.</vi> <vi>Everyone's using bold colors to decorate their homes. Plain white walls just don't <it>cut it</it> anymore. [=plain white walls are not acceptable anymore]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>People use the informal phrase <phrase>any way you cut it</phrase> to say that something is true no matter how you look at it or think about it. <vi><it>Any way you cut it</it>, it was a pretty good year for our company.</vi> <vi>She's one of the world's best tennis players <it>any way you cut it</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut it close</dre> <rsl>chiefly US</rsl> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>cut it fine</va></vr> <def><dt>:to almost not be able to do something :to almost fail, lose, etc. <vi>They ended up winning the game, but they really <it>cut it close</it> [=they almost lost the game] at the end</vi> <vi>It's <it>cutting it</it> a bit <it>fine</it> to get to the station at 9:45 when the train leaves at 9:50!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to stop working suddenly :to turn off <vi>The engine suddenly <it>cut off</it>. [=<it>cut out</it>]</vi> <vi>The air-conditioning <it>cut off</it>, and the room was silent.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) by cutting <vi><it>Cut off</it> dead flowers to promote new growth.</vi> <vi>I had very long hair, but I <it>cut</it> most of it <it>off</it> in college.</vi> <vi>He decided to <it>cut off</it> his beard.</vi> <vi>He was running around <phrase>like a chicken with its head cut off</phrase>. [=he was acting in a very excited and confused way]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to stop or end (something) <vi>They had a vote to <it>cut off</it> debate on the budget.</vi> <vi>The organization <it>cut off</it> its ties with the country's government.</vi> <vi>His family <it>cut off</it> all communication/contact with him after the incident.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to stop people from seeing or using (something) :to block (something) <vi>Their fence <it>cuts off</it> our view of the ocean.</vi> <vi>Many of the town's roads were <it>cut off</it> when the river overflowed.</vi> <vi>The army <it>cut off</it> all escape routes.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop the movement or supply of (something) <vi>The power was <it>cut off</it> to our apartment building.</vi> <vi>The earthquake <it>cut off</it> our water supply.</vi> <vi>They've decided to <it>cut off</it> funding/aid to the group.</vi> <vi>His main source of income had been <it>cut off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone or something) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to be separate or alone <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>an island nation geographically <it>cut off from</it> the rest of the world</vi> <vi>They are <it>cut off from</it> (contact with) the outside world.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> herself <it>off from</it> her family.</vi> <vi>He's emotionally <it>cut off from</it> his wife.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) off</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut off (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stop (someone) from talking <vi>I was in the middle of telling a story when she <it>cut</it> me <it>off</it> [=she interrupted me] to ask about dinner.</vi> <vi>He spoke for 12 minutes until his teacher finally <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>get cut off</phrase> when you are using the telephone, the telephone connection suddenly ends and you can no longer hear the other person. <vi>I called him, but we <it>got cut off</it> [=we got disconnected; the telephone connection ended] two minutes into our conversation.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to drive in front of (someone in another vehicle) in a sudden and dangerous way <vi>He shouted at a driver who <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <vi>Hey, that guy/car just <it>cut</it> me <it>off</it>!</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move ahead and force (someone) to stop <vi>“Sheriff, they're getting away!” “Don't worry, we'll take a shortcut and <it>cut</it> them <it>off</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to decide not to give money or property to (someone) after your death <vi>In her will, she <it>cut off</it> her son without a cent/penny.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it> completely.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to refuse to allow (someone) to drink more alcohol <vi>He's had too much to drink. We'd better <it>cut</it> him <it>off</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>1d</dxn> <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutoff</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut off your nose to spite your face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of a machine</ssl> <dt>:to stop working suddenly <vi>The plane's engines suddenly <it>cut out</it>. [=<it>cut off</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to leave quickly and suddenly <vi>We were in a hurry to get home, so we <it>cut out</it> before the performance ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to move out of a line of traffic <vi>The other car/driver <it>cut out</it> from behind and sped ahead of us.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut out (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to form (something) by cutting with a sharp tool <vi>He got a piece of red paper and <it>cut out</it> a big heart. = He <it>cut</it> a big heart <it>out</it> of a piece of red paper.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She <it>cut out</it> [=<it>carved out</it>] a place for herself in history. [=she caused herself to be important in history]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>5 (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>cutout</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) by cutting <vi>I <it>cut out</it> the recipe from a magazine.</vi> <vi><it>cutting out</it> newspaper articles</vi> <vi>Doctors <it>cut out</it> the lump from her chest.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to remove (something) from something <vi>Fortunately, they <it>cut</it> [=<it>took</it>] that scene <it>out</it> of the movie.</vi> <vi>He <it>cut out</it> sugar from his diet and began eating more fruits and vegetables.</vi> <vi>I focused on my work and <it>cut out</it> everything else in my life.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to stop doing (something) <vi>I've cut down on the number of cigarettes I smoke, but I'd like to <it>cut out</it> [=<it>give up</it>] smoking altogether.</vi> <vi>I told you to <phrase>cut that out</phrase>! [=I told you to stop that]</vi> <vi>That's enough, kids. I mean it! <phrase>Cut it out</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt><snote>If your legs, feet, or knees are <phrase>cut out from under you</phrase>, you are knocked down by something that hits your legs very hard. This phrase is often used figuratively. <vi>When I learned that I was seriously ill, I felt like my feet were <it>cut out from under me</it>.</vi> <vi>The financial legs had been <it>cut out from under</it> the program. [=the program lost money and could not do what it needed to do]</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut out (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (someone) to no longer be included in something <vi>She <it>cut</it> all of her children <it>out</it> of her will and left everything to her grandchildren.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>cut</it> me <it>out</it> of your life completely!</vi> <vi>We can save money by <phrase>cutting out the middleman</phrase> and ordering our supplies directly from the manufacturer.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you are <phrase>cut out for (something)</phrase> or <phrase>cut out to do/be (something)</phrase>, you are naturally able or suited to do or be something. <vi>Why do you think that you're <it>cut out for</it> this job? [=why would you be good at this job?]</vi> <vi>I'm really not <it>cut out for</it> this kind of work. [=I'm not naturally good at it]</vi> <vi>He's not <it>cut out to be</it> a teacher. = He's not <it>cut out to</it> teach.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <tag>have your work cut out for you</tag> at <dxt>work</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut short</dre> <dx>see <dxt>short</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut (someone) dead</dre> <def><dt>:to pretend not to see (someone you know) :to deliberately ignore (someone) <vi>When I saw her on the street yesterday, she <it>cut</it> me <it>dead</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut (someone) some slack</dre> <dx>see <dxt>slack</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut the Gordian knot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gordian knot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut the mustard</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mustard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>cut through (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to get through or past (something that blocks you or slows you down) quickly and directly <vi>We were able to start the project once she told us how to <it>cut through</it> the red tape.</vi> <vi>It took some time to <it>cut through</it> the lies and get to the truth.</vi> <vi><it>cutting through</it> all the nonsense</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi><it>cutting through to</it> the heart/essence of the problem</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>cut <dxn>15 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut to the chase</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chase</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to behave in a silly or rude way <vi>I was sent to the principal's office for <it>cutting up</it> [=<it>clowning around</it>] in class.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cutup</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut up (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cut (something) into parts or pieces <vi>He <it>cut up</it> the candy into little pieces and gave it to the child.</vi> <un>often + <it>into</it> <vi>The area was <it>cut up</it> [=<it>divided</it>] <it>into</it> three separate farms.</vi> <vi>They <it>cut up</it> the wood <it>into</it> small pieces.</vi> <vi>We made sandwiches and <it>cut</it> them <it>up into</it> triangles.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>cut (someone or something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>cut up (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to hurt or damage (someone or something) by cutting <vi>He got <it>cut up</it> pretty badly in the fight.</vi> <vi>His face and arms were all <it>cut up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone or something) in a harsh way <vi>The critics really <it>cut up</it> his last play.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><snote>In informal British English, to be <phrase>cut up about</phrase> something is to be very sad or upset about something. <vi>I was pretty <it>cut up about</it> the way the critics treated my last play.</vi> <vi>She's really <it>cut up about</it> losing her job.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut up rough</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to behave in an angry or violent way <vi>He got drunk and started to <it>cut up rough</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>cut your losses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>loss</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut your own throat</dre> <dx>see <dxt>throat</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cut your teeth</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe the things that people do when they are starting their careers <vi>He <it>cut his teeth</it> performing at local bars and nightclubs.</vi> <vi>She <it>cut her</it> political <it>teeth</it> [=she began her political career] as a volunteer during the 1992 presidential elections.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>Many television and movie stars <it>cut their teeth on</it> soap operas.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>fish or cut bait</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fish</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="suede"> <hw>suede</hw> <sound><wav>suede101.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsweɪd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:soft leather that has been rubbed on one side to make a surface that looks and feels like velvet <vi>The gloves are <it>suede</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>suede</it> jacket</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="whole[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">whole</hw> <sound><wav>whole001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhoʊl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:complete or full :not lacking or leaving out any part <vi>The <it>whole</it> [=<it>entire</it>] family went on the trip.</vi> <vi>The doctor assured me that the <it>whole</it> procedure would only take a few minutes.</vi> <vi>The <it>whole</it> place was remodeled. It looks great now.</vi> <vi>He was out sick for the <it>whole</it> [=<it>entire</it>] week.</vi> <vi>It's been a <it>whole</it> week since I've seen him.</vi> <vi>I spent the <it>whole</it> summer traveling through Europe.</vi> <vi>The <it>whole</it> evening was a great success.</vi> <vi>She read the <it>whole</it> book in one day.</vi> <vi>I've been waiting my <it>whole</it> life for this.</vi> <vi>I felt like the luckiest girl <phrase>in the whole wide world</phrase> [=<it>in the world</it>] that day.</vi> <vi>They failed to tell us the <phrase>whole story</phrase>. [=they failed to tell us everything; they only told us certain things]</vi> <vi>It rained <phrase>the whole time</phrase> I was there. [=it rained continuously while I was there]</vi> <vi>We decided to forget the <phrase>whole thing</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having all the parts :not divided or cut into parts or pieces <vi>a <it>whole</it> egg</vi> <vi><it>whole</it> strawberries [=strawberries that are not sliced or cut up]</vi> <vi>We cooked a <it>whole</it> chicken.</vi> <vi><it>whole</it> grains</vi> <vi>The recipe calls for two <it>whole</it> cloves. [=cloves that haven't been ground]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:great or large in size, extent, etc. <vi>The community center offers a <it>whole</it> range of programs.</vi> <vi>The track team took part in a <it>whole</it> series of events. [=in a lot of events]</vi> <vi>There's a <it>whole</it> set of criteria to consider.</vi> <vi>She owns a <it>whole</it> collection of hats. [=she owns many different hats]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used for emphasis before a noun <vi>The <it>whole</it> idea is to make things better, not worse.</vi> <vi>She missed the <it>whole</it> point of the story.</vi> <vi>We weren't quite sure what to make of the <it>whole</it> situation.</vi> <vi>He doesn't seem to have <phrase>a whole lot of</phrase> [=<it>much</it>] respect for other people's feelings.</vi> <vi>Things are looking <phrase>a whole lot</phrase> [=<it>much</it>] brighter now.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>go (the) whole hog</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hog</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>out of whole cloth</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cloth</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the whole enchilada</dre> <dx>see <dxt>enchilada</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the whole (kit and) caboodle</dre> <dx>see <dxt>caboodle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the whole nine yards</dre> <dx>see <dxt>yard</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the whole shebang</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shebang</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the whole shooting match</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shooting match</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>whole nother</dre> <dx>see <dxt>nother</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>whole*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
