<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="club[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">club</hw> <sound><wav>club0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklʌb</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clubs</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a group of people who meet to participate in an activity (such as a sport or hobby) <vi>an exclusive social/men's <it>club</it></vi> <vi>Do you belong to any <it>clubs</it>?</vi> <vi>My friends and I formed/started a chess <it>club</it>. [=a group of people who play chess together]</vi> <vi>She's the <it>club</it> president. = She's the president of the <it>club</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>fan club</dxt> <dxt>glee club</dxt> <dxt>golf club <dxn>2</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the place where the members of a club meet <vi>I'll see you at the <it>club</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>country club</dxt> <dxt>health club</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sports team or organization <vi>the president of a major-league baseball <it>club</it></vi> <vi>He spent five years with the <it>club</it>.</vi> <vi>a ball <it>club</it></vi> <vi>a boxing/football/hockey <it>club</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an organization in which people agree to buy things (such as books or CDs) regularly in order to receive a benefit (such as lower prices) <vi>Join our movie <it>club</it> now and receive four free DVDs.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>book club</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a business that provides entertainment (such as music, dancing, or a show) and that usually serves food and alcohol :<sx>nightclub</sx> <vi>a dance <it>club</it></vi> <vi>jazz <it>clubs</it></vi> <vi>comedy <it>clubs</it> [=clubs in which people perform comedy shows]</vi> <vi>They went <phrase>club-hopping</phrase>. [=they went to several different clubs in one night]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>club</it> owners</vi> <vi><it>club</it> music [=dance music that is played in clubs]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>strip club</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a special metal stick used for hitting a golf ball :<sx>golf club</sx> <vi>I just bought a new set of <it>clubs</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a heavy usually wooden stick that is used as a weapon <vi>In battle, they used swords and wooden <it>clubs</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>billy club</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a playing card that is marked with a black shape that looks like three round leaves <vi>one heart, two diamonds, and two <it>clubs</it></vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>playing card</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>clubs</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the suit in a deck of playing cards that consists of cards marked by a black shape that looks like three round leaves <vi>the nine of <it>clubs</it></vi> <dx>compare <dxt>diamond</dxt> <dxt>heart</dxt> <dxt>spade</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>club sandwich</sx> <vi>She ordered a turkey <it>club</it> with French fries.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in the club</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>pregnant</sx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>join the club</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>welcome to the club</va></vr> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that the problems or feelings someone is having are problems or feelings that you have had yourself <vi>If you don't understand the rules, <it>join the club</it>: no one else does either!</vi></un> <un>often used to suggest that a person's problems or feelings are not unusual and do not deserve much sympathy <vi>So you think you deserve to be paid more money for your work? Well, <it>join the club</it>. [=lots of people think they deserve more money]</vi> <vi>“My son won't do what I tell him to do.” “<it>Join the club</it>. I can't get my daughter to obey me, either.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="club[2]"> <hw hindex="2">club</hw> <altpr>ˈklʌb</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>clubs</if></in> <in><if>clubbed</if></in> <in><if>club*bing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to hit (a person or animal) with a heavy stick or object <vi>They <it>clubbed</it> him with a baseball bat.</vi> <vi>He was <it>clubbed</it> to death. [=killed by being hit him with a heavy object]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>club together</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to combine your money with the money of other people <snote>If a group of people <it>club together</it> to do something, each member of the group gives some money to pay for something. <vi>We <it>clubbed together</it> to buy him a new watch.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="club sandwich"> <hw>club sandwich</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -wiches</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a sandwich that has three slices of bread with two layers of meat (such as turkey) and other cold foods (such as lettuce, tomato, and mayonnaise) between them</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="club soda"> <hw>club soda</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>soda water</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="billy club"> <hw>bil*ly club</hw> <sound><wav>billy01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɪli-</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>nightstick</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="book club"> <hw>book club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an organization that sells books to its members at low prices</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a group of people who meet to talk about the books that they are reading</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="country club"> <hw>country club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a private club where people go for social events and to play golf, tennis, etc.</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="fan club"> <hw>fan club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:an organization for people who admire a famous person, group, etc. <vi>members of the singer's <it>fan club</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="glee club"> <hw>glee club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a group of people who sing together especially as a social activity in a school or college</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="golf club"> <art><artref id="golf_club.tif"/><capt>golf club</capt><dim>41.3,123.9</dim></art> <hw>golf club</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ clubs</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a special long stick with a larger part at the bottom that is used to hit the ball in golf <vi>She bought a new set of <it>golf clubs</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an organization whose members play golf <vi>He joined a <it>golf club</it> last year.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the golf course where the members of such an organization play <vi>I'll meet you at the <it>golf club</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
