<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="coin[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">coin</hw> <sound><wav>coin0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>coins</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a small, flat, and usually round piece of metal issued by a government as money <vi>gold/silver/copper <it>coins</it></vi> <vi>I have a dollar in <it>coins</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>the other/opposite/flip side of the coin</dre> <def><dt>:a different way of looking at or thinking about a situation <vi>The economy is improving, but <it>the other side of the coin</it> is that inflation is becoming a bigger problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>toss/flip a coin</dre> <def><dt>:to decide something by throwing a coin up in the air and seeing which side is shown after it lands <vi>Let's <it>toss a coin</it>. Heads, we don't go; tails, we do.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two sides of the same coin</dre> <def><dt>:two things that are regarded as two parts of the same thing <vi>These problems may seem unrelated but they are really <it>two sides of the same coin</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="coin[2]"> <hw hindex="2">coin</hw> <altpr>ˈkoɪn</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>coins</if></in> <in><if>coined</if></in> <in><if>coin*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to create (a new word or phrase) that other people begin to use <vi>The coach <it>coined</it> the phrase “refuse to lose.”</vi> <vi>William Shakespeare is believed to have <it>coined</it> many words.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>to coin a phrase</phrase> is sometimes used in a joking way to say that you know you are using a very common expression. <vi>The couple lived happily ever after, <it>to coin a phrase</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (money in the form of coins) <vi>The nation plans to <it>coin</it> more money.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>coin it</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>coin money</va></vr> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to earn a lot of money quickly or easily <vi>They are really <it>coining it/money</it> with their new CD.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="flip side"> <hw>flip side</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ sides</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the side of a record that has a song which is not as popular and well known as the one on the other side <vi>That song was on the <it>flip side</it> of their first single.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the bad or unpleasant part or result of something <vi>Loss of privacy is the <it>flip side</it> of fame.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>the flip side of the coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="opposite[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">op*po*site</hw> <sound><wav>opposi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑ:pəzət</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:located at the other end, side, or corner of something :located across from something <vi>The two boys lived on <it>opposite</it> sides of the street.</vi> <vi>the <it>opposite</it> bank of the river</vi> <vi>Fold the bottom right corner of the paper over to the <it>opposite</it> corner.</vi> <vi>She switched her ring to the <it>opposite</it> hand. [=she took her ring off the finger of one hand and put it on a finger of the other hand]</vi> <vi>The text refers to an illustration on the <it>opposite</it> page. [=on the page that faces it]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:completely different <vi>The two scientists had the same information but reached <it>opposite</it> conclusions.</vi> <vi>They represent <it>opposite</it> sides of the issue.</vi> <vi>They ran in <it>opposite</it> directions.</vi> <vi>Some herbs help you sleep while others have the <it>opposite</it> effect. [=other herbs keep you awake]</vi> <vi>Her music is <phrase>at the opposite end of the spectrum/continuum</phrase> from the music her mother made.</vi> <vi>Once serving only small portions at high prices, the restaurant has gone to the <phrase>opposite extreme</phrase> under the new owners. [=the restaurant now serves large amounts of food for low prices]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>the opposite side of the coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="same[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">same</hw> <sound><wav>same0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈseɪm</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:not different <un>used when referring to a particular person or thing that is connected to more than one person, time, place, etc. <vi>He has lived in the <it>same</it> city all his life. [=he has only lived in one city]</vi> <vi>She and her cousin go to the <it>same</it> school. [=she goes to a particular school, and her cousin also goes to that school]</vi> <vi>We graduated the <it>same</it> year.</vi> <vi>She saw the <it>same</it> man at several different times and places yesterday.</vi> <vi>I'd met him earlier that <phrase>exact same</phrase> day. = (<it>US</it>) I'd met him earlier that <phrase>same exact</phrase> day.</vi> <vi>“Puma” and “cougar” are different names for the <phrase>very same</phrase> animal.</vi> <vi>The restaurant's owner and chef are <phrase>one and the same</phrase> person. [=the owner is also the chef]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:exactly like someone or something else <vi>The words “their” and “there” are pronounced in exactly the <it>same</it> way but spelled differently.</vi> <vi>They were wearing the <phrase>exact same</phrase> shirt. = (<it>US</it>) They were wearing the <phrase>same exact</phrase> shirt.</vi> <vi>He should help us—and <phrase>the same thing goes for</phrase> you! [=and you should help us too]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not changed :exactly like an earlier version, event, etc. <vi>She gave the <it>same</it> answer as before.</vi> <vi>He eats the <it>same</it> breakfast every day.</vi> <vi>The <it>same</it> thing happened to me yesterday.</vi> <vi>She is not the <it>same</it> person (that) she used to be—she's changed.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a quality or characteristic that is shared by more than one person or thing <vi>two people of the <it>same</it> sex [=two people who are both male or both female]</vi> <vi>The buildings are the <it>same</it> age/style.</vi> <vi>She has the <it>same</it> dark hair and eyes as her father.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>at the same time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>same difference</dre> <dx>see <dxt>difference</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the same old</dre> <def><sl>informal + usually disapproving</sl> <dt><un>used to refer to something that has not changed <vi>I was hoping for something different, but all I got was more of <it>the same old</it> thing.</vi> <vi>They brought up <it>the same old</it> argument/story yet again!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>the same thing</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that two things are alike or have the same meaning <vi>Lying and cheating amount to much <it>the same thing</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two sides of the same coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="side[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">side</hw> <sound><wav>side0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈsaɪd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>sides</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place, space, or direction that is away from or beyond the center of something <vi>The army was attacked from all <it>sides</it>.</vi> <vi>the right-hand <it>side</it> of the street</vi> <vi>the opposite <it>side</it> of the room</vi> <vi>Move over. This is my <it>side</it> of the bed.</vi> <un>often used with <it>on</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>You have some dirt <it>on</it> the <it>side</it> of your face.</vi> <vi>The car was hit <it>on</it> the driver's <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>They live <it>on</it> the other <it>side</it> of town.</vi> <vi>The cabins are <it>on</it> the east <it>side</it> of the lake.</vi> <vi>Guards stood <it>on</it> either <it>side</it> of the gate.</vi> <vi>The army was surrounded <it>on</it> every <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>He sat <it>on</it> the <it>side</it> [=<it>edge</it>] of the bed.</vi> <vi>The statue is leaning <it>to</it> the <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>The dog tilted its head <it>to</it> one <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Pull over <it>to</it> the <it>side</it> of the road.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:an outer surface or part of something <vi>The box says, “THIS <it>SIDE</it> UP.”</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the dark <it>side of</it> the moon</vi> <vi>You should season both <it>sides of</it> the steak before you grill it.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:one of the surfaces of an object that is not the front, back, top, or bottom <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>Nutritional information can be found on the <it>side of</it> the box.</vi> <vi>Red cloth decorated the front and <it>sides of</it> the platform.</vi> <vi>The <it>side of</it> the car was badly dented.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:one of the two surfaces of a thin object <vi>Flip the record over and play the other <it>side</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>She wrote on both <it>sides of</it> the paper.</vi> <vi>Look on the back <it>side of</it> the note.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a line that forms part of a geometric shape <vi>A square has four <it>sides</it>.</vi> :a surface that forms part of a geometric object <vi>A cube has six <it>sides</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the slopes of a hill or mountain <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>the steep <it>side of</it> the hill</vi> <vi>They built a house on the <it>side of</it> a mountain.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>hillside</dxt> <dxt>mountainside</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the right or left part of your body <vi>She likes to sleep on her right <it>side</it>.</vi> :the right or left part of your body from your shoulder to your hip <vi>I have a pain in my left <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>We laughed so much that our <it>sides</it> hurt.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the place directly to the right or left of someone <un>usually singular <vi>I stood <phrase>at/by her side</phrase> as she spoke to reporters.</vi> <vi>I was standing <phrase>on her left side</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She set/put the book <phrase>to the/one side</phrase> and looked out the window.</vi></un> <un>often used figuratively <vi>His wife <phrase>stood at/by his side</phrase> [=remained loyal to him] throughout the scandal.</vi> <vi>Promise me that you will not <phrase>leave my side</phrase>. [=abandon me]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>blind side</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of two or more opinions, positions, etc., that disagree with each other <vi>He listened to both <it>sides</it> of the argument.</vi> <vi>My <it>side</it> [=<it>version</it>] of the story is different from his.</vi> <vi>She has since changed <it>sides</it> on that issue.</vi> <vi>You are both my friends, so I don't want to <phrase>choose/pick/take sides</phrase>. [=support one person and not the other]</vi> <vi>Are you <phrase>on my side</phrase> or his? [=do you support me or him?]</vi> <vi><phrase>Whose side are you on</phrase>, anyway?</vi> <vi>People <phrase>on both sides</phrase> of the dispute [=people who support one position and people who support the other position] agree that changes are necessary.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>on your side <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the two or more people or groups that are involved in an argument, war, etc. <vi>All <it>sides</it> agreed on the treaty.</vi> <vi>Each <it>side</it> accuses the other of delaying progress.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a sports team <vi>There are 11 players on each <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Our <it>side</it> won the game.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) a football <it>side</it></vi> <vi>We need to <phrase>choose/pick sides</phrase> [=to decide which players will be on each team] before we start playing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:the players on a team who bat in an inning <un>usually singular <vi>The pitcher struck out the <it>side</it> [=struck out three batters] in the first inning.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular part or feature of something that is opposite to or different from another part or feature <vi>There are good/positive and bad/negative <it>sides</it> to owning your own business.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>He's learning about the sales <it>side of</it> the business.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>kept her side of the bargain/deal</phrase>. [=she did what she agreed to do]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>downside</dxt> <dxt>flip side</dxt> <dxt>upside</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>on the large side</phrase>, <phrase>on the heavy side</phrase>, etc., to describe someone or something as somewhat heavy, large, etc. <vi>She has always been a little <it>on the heavy side</it>. [=has always been somewhat heavy]</vi> <vi>These pants are <it>on the tight side</it>. [=are a little tight]</vi> <vi>The sauce is a bit <it>on the spicy side</it>. [=is a bit spicy]</vi> <vi>Your boyfriend is <it>on the young side</it> for you, isn't he?</vi></un></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a part of someone's personality that is opposite or different from another part <vi>I have never seen this <it>side</it> of you before.</vi> <vi>He is in touch with his feminine <it>side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>be/get on someone's good/bad side</phrase> and <phrase>be/get on the right/wrong side of someone</phrase> to talk about doing things that cause someone to like you or dislike you <vi>Trust me. You don't want to <it>get on his bad side</it>. [=you don't want to make him annoyed or angry]</vi> <vi>She tries to <it>keep/stay on her boss's good side</it> by finishing all of her work on time.</vi> <vi>If you <it>get on the wrong side of</it> him [=if you make him annoyed or angry] he can be very mean.</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the ancestors or relatives of your mother or your father <vi>She gets her red hair from her mother's <it>side</it>.</vi> <vi>Both <it>sides</it> of his family are Irish.</vi> <vi>my grandfather on my father's <it>side</it> [=my father's father]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:a small amount of food that is ordered in addition to the main meal <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>I ordered a <it>side of</it> fries with my hamburger.</vi></un></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:one of the two halves of an animal that is eaten as food <un>usually + <it>of</it> <vi>a <it>side of</it> bacon/pork/beef</vi></un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:a page of writing on one side of a piece of paper <vi>I wrote two <it>sides</it> in response to the question.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:a television channel <un>usually singular <vi>What's on the other <it>side</it>?</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>a thorn in the/your side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thorn</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>err on the side of</dre> <dx>see <dxt>err</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>(from) side to side</dre> <def><dt>:moving to the left and then to the right <vi>She shook her head <it>from side to side</it> in disagreement.</vi> <vi>waving the flags <it>from side to side</it></vi> <vi>He moved <it>side to side</it> on the tennis court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>let the side down</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to disappoint your family, friends, etc., by failing to do what is needed or expected <vi>I feel like I really <it>let the side down</it>. [=let everyone down]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on side</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:included among the group of people who support a particular goal, project, etc. <vi>We need to keep everyone <it>on side</it>. [=<it>on board</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the bright side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bright</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the credit side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>credit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the debit side</dre> <dx>see <dxt>debit</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the right/wrong side of 30, 40, 50 (etc.)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:younger/older than 30, 40, 50 (etc.) <vi>She's still <it>on the right side of 40</it>. [=younger than 40]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the side</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:in addition to the main item in a meal <vi>We were served salmon with rice and grilled vegetables <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:served next to something rather than on top of it <vi>For my salad, I'd like Italian dressing <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in addition to your main job <vi>She sells insurance <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:as part of a secret romantic relationship that is outside of your marriage or main romantic relationship <vi>a married man with a girlfriend <it>on the side</it></vi> <vi>She had a fiancé but was seeing another man <it>on the side</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the wrong/right side of the law</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone is or is not living the life of a criminal <vi>He has been <it>on the wrong side of</it> the law since he stole a car at the age of 17.</vi> <vi>Now that she's out of prison she's trying to stay <it>on the right side of the law</it>. [=trying not to get into trouble with the police]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on your side</dre> <def><dt>:as an advantage <vi>He is not a very tall basketball player, but he does have quickness <it>on his side</it>.</vi> :helping you to succeed <vi>Luck seems to be <it>on your side</it> tonight.</vi> <vi>Time is <it>on our side</it>. [=we have a lot of time to do what we need to do]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>side <dxn>6 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>side by side</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:next to each other and facing in the same direction <vi>We walked <it>side by side</it> down the hallway.</vi> <vi>They stood <it>side by side</it> at the altar.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:together or very close to each other <vi>The tribes have lived peacefully <it>side by side</it> for many years.</vi> <vi>People worked <it>side by side</it> to rescue the trapped coal miners.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>split your sides (laughing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>split</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the other side of the coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the wrong side of the tracks</dre> <dx>see <dxt>track</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>this side of</dre> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:very nearly (something) <vi>Their actions were just <it>this side of</it> illegal. [=were almost but not quite illegal]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:that is not (something) :other than (something) <vi>the worst punishment <it>this side of</it> death</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>before</sx> <vi>She's not likely to be back <it>this side of</it> Monday week.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to the/one side</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to a place that is on one side :<sx>aside</sx> <vi>Please move/step <it>to the side</it>. I need to get past you.</vi> <vi>He put his luggage <it>to one side</it>.</vi> <vi>She took the boy <it>to the side</it> [=away from other people] and told him to behave.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a state in which something is not dealt with, done, or used until a later time :<sx>aside</sx> <vi>Let's put/leave that question <it>to the side</it> for a moment.</vi> <vi>He set his household chores <it>to the side</it> to finish writing his essay.</vi> <vi>They managed to put some money <it>to the side</it> every month.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>side <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two sides of the same coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>side</dxt></dxnl></entry>

	<entry id="two"> <hw>two</hw> <sound><wav>two00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈtu:</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>twos</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the number 2</dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the second in a set or series <vi>page <it>two</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:two o'clock <vi>It was <it>two</it> in the morning.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bird</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>a thing or two</dre> <dx>see <dxt>thing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in two</dre> <def><dt>:into two equal parts :in half <vi>He cut the apple <it>in two</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in twos</dre> <def><dt>:in groups of two <vi>You will be working <it>in twos</it>. [=<it>in pairs</it>]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in two shakes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shake</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>it takes two, it takes two to tango</dre> <dx>see <dxt>take</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>of two minds, in two minds</dre> <dx>see <dxt>mind</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put two and two together</dre> <def><dt>:to make a correct guess based on what you have seen or heard :to figure something out <vi>You weren't home so I <it>put two and two together</it> and went back to your office to find you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/stick two fingers up at someone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>finger</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>serve two masters</dre> <dx>see <dxt>serve</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two by two</dre> <def><dt>:in groups of two :in pairs <vi>The children lined up <it>two by two</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two cents</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cent</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two left feet</dre> <dx>see <dxt>foot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two's company, three's a crowd</dre> <dx>see <dxt>company</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two sides of the same coin</dre> <dx>see <dxt>coin</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>two</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>two</it>-hour test</vi> <vi>I had met him just <it>two</it> days earlier.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>two</ure> <fl>pronoun</fl> <utxt><vi>There are only <it>two</it> left.</vi> <vi>Come back in a week or <it>two</it>. [=come back sometime between one and two weeks from now]</vi> <snotebox>Do not confuse <it>two</it> with <it>to</it> or <it>too</it>.</snotebox></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
