<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="cold[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">cold</hw> <sound><wav>cold0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoʊld</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>cold*er</if></in> <in><if>cold*est</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:having a very low temperature <vi>The water was too <it>cold</it> for swimming.</vi> <vi>The weather has been unusually <it>cold</it> this spring.</vi> <vi>a country with a <it>cold</it> climate</vi> <vi>It was a long, <it>cold</it> winter.</vi> <vi>It's <it>cold</it> outside, but the wind makes it feel even <it>colder</it>.</vi> <vi>It's bitterly/freezing <it>cold</it> out there!</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it>, rainy day</vi> <vi>metal that is <it>cold</it> to the touch</vi> <vi>Her hands were icy <it>cold</it>. = They were as <it>cold</it> as ice.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a feeling of low body heat <vi>Are you <it>cold</it>? I could turn up the temperature if you'd like.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:not heated <vi>a bowl of <it>cold</it> cereal</vi> <vi>He ate <it>cold</it> pizza for breakfast.</vi> <vi>We were happy to eat a hot meal rather than <it>cold</it> sandwiches.</vi> <vi><it>cold</it> meats</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of drinks</ssl> <dt>:served at a very low temperature or with ice <vi>They're serving coffee, tea, and <it>cold</it> drinks.</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it> glass of milk</vi> <vi>a <it>cold</it> beer</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:not appealing or pleasant :causing a cold or unhappy feeling <vi>the <it>cold</it> gray sky</vi> <vi>the harsh <it>cold</it> lights of the hospital</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:not friendly or emotional :lacking emotional warmth <vi>Why is he so <it>cold</it> and distant toward me?</vi> <vi>She gave me a <it>cold</it> stare and turned away.</vi> <vi>I got a <it>cold</it> reception when I came home.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:not changed or affected by personal feelings or emotions <vi>Like them or not, these are the <it>cold</it> facts!</vi> <vi>It's time they took a <it>cold</it>, hard look at the situation.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:learned or memorized exactly <un>used with <it>have</it> <vi>Keep repeating the lines until you <it>have</it> them (down) <it>cold</it>. [=until you have memorized them perfectly]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:unconscious or sleeping very deeply <vi>He passed out <it>cold</it>.</vi> <un>usually used in the phrase <phrase>out cold</phrase> <vi>She was <it>out cold</it> by eight o'clock.</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>knock cold</tag> at <dxt>knock</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:not fresh or strong :no longer easy to follow <vi>The dogs picked up a <it>cold</it> scent.</vi> <vi>The police had been hot on the trail of the escaped prisoners, but then the trail went <it>cold</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:not close to finding something or solving a puzzle <un>used especially in children's games <vi>You're getting warmer! You're getting hot! Oh, now you're getting <it>colder</it>!</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:not having success or good luck <vi>The team was hot in the first half, but their shooting turned <it>cold</it> in the second half. [=they missed a lot of shots in the second half]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blow hot and cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cast a cold eye on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in cold blood</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in the cold light of day</dre> <def><dt>:in the day when things can be seen clearly rather than at night <vi>The house that had looked so sinister at night seemed much less frightening <it>in the cold light of day</it>.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She forced me to look at myself <it>in the cold light of day</it>, and I didn't like what I saw.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave you cold</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <it>leaves you cold</it> does not interest or excite you. <vi>His movies <it>leave me cold</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make someone's blood run cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blood</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>pour/throw cold water on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>water</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>cold*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>“Your application has been denied,” he said <it>coldly</it>.</vi> <vi>She looked at me <it>coldly</it> and turned away.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>cold*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the icy <it>coldness</it> of winter</vi> <vi>Why does he treat me with such <it>coldness</it> and reserve?</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="cold[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">cold</hw> <altpr>ˈkoʊld</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>colds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a cold condition <vi>I mind <it>cold</it> more than heat.</vi> <vi>They died of exposure to <it>cold</it>.</vi> <vi>She was shivering with <it>cold</it>. [=because she was cold]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the cold</bnote> <dt>:cold weather <vi><it>The cold</it> really sets in around late November and doesn't let up until April.</vi> <vi>I stood there shivering in <it>the cold</it>.</vi> <vi>He waited outside for her in <it>the</it> bitter <it>cold</it>.</vi> <vi>Come in out of <it>the cold</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a common illness that affects the nose, throat, and eyes and that usually causes coughing, sneezing, etc. <vi>It's not the flu, it's just a <it>cold</it>.</vi> <vi>He got/caught a <it>cold</it>. = He came down with a <it>cold</it>. = (<it>Brit</it>) He went down with a <it>cold</it>.</vi> <vi>the <phrase>common cold</phrase></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>the <it>cold</it> virus</vi> <vi><it>cold</it> symptoms/remedies</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>head cold</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>blue with cold, blue from the cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blue</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>come in from the cold</dre> <def><dt>:to become part of a group or of normal society again after you have been outside it <vi>a former spy who has <it>come in from the cold</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>leave (someone) out in the cold</dre> <def><dt>:to leave (someone) in a bad position :to not give (someone) the rights or advantages that are given to others <vi>The changes benefit management but <it>leave the workers out in the cold</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="cold[3]"> <hw hindex="3">cold</hw> <altpr>ˈkoʊld</altpr> <fl>adverb</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:in a very clear, complete, and definite way <vi>She turned their offer down <it>cold</it>. [=<it>flat</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:in a sudden way <vi>He was telling me a story but stopped <it>cold</it> [=<it>abruptly</it>] when the door opened.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:without practicing or preparing before doing something <vi>She was asked to perform the song <it>cold</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold-blooded"> <hw>cold–blood*ed</hw> <sound><wav>cold_b01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoʊldˈblʌdəd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>more cold–blood*ed; most cold–blood*ed</sgram> <dt>:showing no sympathy or mercy <vi><it>cold-blooded</it> [=<it>ruthless</it>] murderers</vi> :done in a planned way without emotion <vi>a <it>cold-blooded</it> killing</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>more cold–blood*ed; most cold–blood*ed</sgram> <dt>:based on facts :not affected by emotions <vi>A <it>cold-blooded</it> [=<it>cold-eyed</it>, <it>dispassionate</it>] assessment of the situation showed that we had to take harsh measures.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>biology</ssl> <dt>:having cold blood :having a body temperature that is similar to the temperature of the environment <vi>Reptiles are <it>cold-blooded</it>.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>warm-blooded</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>cold–blood*ed*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro> <uro><ure>cold–blood*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram></uro></entry>

	<entry id="cold call"> <hw>cold call</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ calls</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a telephone call made by a business to try to sell something <snote><it>Cold calls</it> are made to people who have not been contacted before and have not asked to be called.</snote></dt></def> <uro><ure>cold–call</ure> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>cold–calls</if></in> <in><if>cold–called</if></in> <in><if>cold–call*ing</if></in> <gram>+ obj</gram> <utxt><vi>I <it>cold-called</it> the people on the list.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="cold cash"> <hw>cold cash</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:money that a person has and can use immediately <vi>He paid $500 for it in <it>cold cash</it>. [=in cash and not with a check or credit card]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold comfort"> <hw>cold comfort</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:something that is good for a situation but does not make someone happy because the whole situation is still bad <vi>The good news about the economy is <it>cold comfort</it> to people who have lost their jobs.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold cream"> <hw>cold cream</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a cream that people use to clean the face or soften the skin <vi>She uses <it>cold cream</it> to remove her eye makeup.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold cuts"> <hw>cold cuts</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>plural</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:cold cooked meats (such as turkey, roast beef, or ham) that have been cut into thin slices</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold-eyed"> <hw>cold–eyed</hw> <sound><wav>cold_e01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkoʊldˈaɪd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more cold–eyed; most cold–eyed</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:not affected by emotions <vi>Unlike her sentimental sister, she has a <it>cold-eyed</it> [=<it>cold-blooded</it>, <it>dispassionate</it>] view of reality.</vi> <vi>a <it>cold-eyed</it> analysis of the data</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having a cold or unfriendly appearance <vi>a <it>cold-eyed</it> businessman</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
