<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="collapse[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">col*lapse</hw> <sound><wav>collap01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈlæps</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>col*laps*es</if></in> <in><if>col*lapsed</if></in> <in><if>col*laps*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break apart and fall down suddenly <vi>The bridge/building <it>collapsed</it>.</vi> <vi>The roof <it>collapsed</it> under a heavy load of snow.</vi> <vi>The chair he was sitting in <it>collapsed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to fall down or become unconscious because you are sick or exhausted <vi>He <it>collapsed</it> on stage during the performance and had to be rushed to the hospital.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to completely relax the muscles of your body because you are very tired, upset, etc. <vi>She came home from work and <it>collapsed</it> on the sofa.</vi> <vi>The crying child ran to his mother and <it>collapsed</it> in her arms.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to fail or stop working suddenly :to break down completely <vi>The civilization <it>collapsed</it> for reasons that are still unknown.</vi> <vi>He warned that such measures could cause the economy to <it>collapse</it>.</vi> <vi>Negotiations have completely <it>collapsed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to lose almost all worth :to become much less valuable <vi>The country's currency <it>collapsed</it>.</vi> <vi>Oil prices had <it>collapsed</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>medical</ssl> <dt>:to become flat and empty <vi>a blood vessel that <it>collapsed</it></vi> <vi>a <it>collapsed</it> lung</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to fold together <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The stroller <it>collapses</it> easily.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You can <it>collapse</it> the stroller easily and store it in the trunk of your car.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>col*laps*ible</ure> <sound><wav>collap03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈlæpsəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>collapsible</it> chair/table/stroller</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="collapse[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">collapse</hw> <altpr>ˈkəˈlæps</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>collapses</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a situation or occurrence in which something (such as a bridge, building, etc.) suddenly breaks apart and falls down <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>a fatal bridge <it>collapse</it></vi> <vi>The earthquake caused the <it>collapse</it> of several homes.</vi> <vi>the <it>collapse</it> of the roof</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The structure is in danger of <it>collapse</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a situation or occurrence in which someone suddenly falls down or becomes unconscious because of being sick or exhausted <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>After her <it>collapse</it> she was rushed to the hospital.</vi> <vi>He suffered a <it>collapse</it> at work.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She was on the verge of <it>collapse</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a situation or occurrence in which something (such as a system or organization) suddenly fails :a complete failure or breakdown <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>the <it>collapse</it> of the Soviet Union</vi> <vi>the <it>collapse</it> of negotiations</vi> <vi>She moved to the city after the <it>collapse</it> of her marriage.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The country has endured civil war and economic <it>collapse</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a situation or occurrence in which something loses almost all of its worth or value <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The country's currency is in danger of <it>collapse</it>.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>a <it>collapse</it> in the value of their currency</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="heap[1]"> <hw hindex="1">heap</hw> <sound><wav>heap0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhi:p</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>heaps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a large, disordered pile of things <vi>He dumped the grass clippings into the compost <it>heap</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>heap</it> of old newspapers</vi> <vi>She left her dirty clothes <phrase>in a heap</phrase> on the floor.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>scrap heap</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a great number or large amount of something <vi>He's in a <it>heap</it> of trouble!</vi> <un>often plural <vi>They've got <it>heaps</it> of money.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:an old car that is in poor condition <vi>I can't believe he's still driving that old <it>heap</it>.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>at the bottom/top of the heap</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe a person's level of success, position in society, etc. <vi>Quite a few people applied for the job, but his past work experience put him <it>at the top of the heap</it>. [=made him the strongest candidate of the group]</vi> <vi>People <it>at the bottom of the heap</it> [=poor people] will not be helped much by the new tax cuts.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>collapse/fall (etc.) in a heap</dre> <def><dt>:to fall very suddenly to the ground and lie there <vi>Overcome by heat exhaustion, he <it>collapsed/fell in a heap</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
