<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="collection"> <hw highlight="yes">col*lec*tion</hw> <sound><wav>collec07.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈlɛkʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>col*lec*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act or process of getting things from different places and bringing them together <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a system of tax <it>collection</it></vi> <vi>The technology makes data <it>collection</it> easier.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>There will be a trash <it>collection</it> this week.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of interesting or beautiful objects brought together in order to show or study them or as a hobby <vi>The museum's <it>collection</it> is one of the best in the country.</vi> <vi>his baseball card <it>collection</it></vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>He has a huge <it>collection of</it> CDs.</vi> <vi>She has an impressive <it>collection of</it> modern art.</vi> <vi>He has quite a <it>collection of</it> exercise equipment.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She has acquired quite a <it>collection of</it> friends/contacts/experiences/stories.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a request for money in order to help people or to pay for something important <vi>We <phrase>took up a collection</phrase> for the school renovations.</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the money collected in this way <vi>Ten percent of the <it>collection</it> goes to the city's shelters for homeless people.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>a <it>collection</it> plate/box</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of clothes that a fashion designer has created <vi>a fashion show featuring his spring <it>collection</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of different writings that are brought together in one book <vi>You should consider publishing these stories as a <it>collection</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>of</it> <vi>I have a <it>collection of</it> her short stories.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
