<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="collar[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">col*lar</hw> <sound><wav>collar01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:lɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>col*lars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a part of a piece of clothing that fits around a person's neck and is usually folded down <vi>He wore a shirt with a tight-fitting <it>collar</it>.</vi> <vi>She grabbed me by the <it>collar</it>.</vi> <vi>He <phrase>loosened his collar</phrase>. [=unbuttoned the top button of his shirt]</vi> <dx>see color picture on page C14</dx> <dx>see also <dxt>blue-collar</dxt> <dxt>pink-collar</dxt> <dxt>white-collar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a band of leather, plastic, etc., worn around an animal's neck <vi>I bought a new <it>collar</it> for the dog.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>flea collar</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a ring or band used to hold something (such as a pipe or a part of a machine) in place</dt></def> <dro><dre>hot under the collar</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hot</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="collar[2]"> <hw hindex="2">collar</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:lɚ</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>collars</if></in> <in><if>collared</if></in> <in><if>collar*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to catch or arrest (someone) <vi>The police <it>collared</it> the guy a few blocks from the scene.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop (someone) in order to talk :to force (someone) to have a conversation <vi>He <it>collared</it> me on my way out the door.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="blue-collar"> <hw>blue–col*lar</hw> <sound><wav>bluec02w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈblu:ˈkɑ:lɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:requiring physical work <vi><it>blue-collar</it> jobs [=jobs making things in a factory, fixing machines, building things, etc.]</vi> :relating to or having jobs that require physical work <vi><it>blue-collar</it> [=<it>working-class</it>] workers/families</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>pink-collar</dxt> <dxt>white-collar</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="flea collar"> <hw>flea collar</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -lars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a collar for dogs and cats that contains a substance which kills fleas</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="pink-collar"> <hw>pink–collar</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:traditionally held by women <vi><it>pink-collar</it> jobs</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>blue-collar</dxt> <dxt>white-collar</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="white-collar"> <hw>white–col*lar</hw> <sound><wav>white02w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwaɪtˈkɑ:lɚ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><dt>:of, relating to, or having the kind of jobs that are done in an office instead of a factory, warehouse, etc. <vi><it>white-collar</it> jobs/workers</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>blue-collar</dxt> <dxt>pink-collar</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>white-collar crime</dre> <def><dt>:crime that typically involves stealing money from a company and that is done by people who have important positions in the company :crime committed by white-collar workers <vi>Embezzlement is a <it>white-collar crime</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="wing collar"> <hw>wing collar</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -lar</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <dt>:a type of high, stiff shirt collar that has the top corners turned down and that is worn by a man on formal occasions</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="hot[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">hot</hw> <sound><wav>hot00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhɑ:t</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>hot*ter</if></in> <in><if>hot*test</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:having a high temperature <vi><it>hot</it> August nights</vi> <vi><it>hot</it> and humid weather</vi> <vi>taking a <it>hot</it> bath/shower</vi> <vi>a <it>hot</it> climate/country</vi> <vi>It is/gets <it>hot</it> in the summer and cold in the winter.</vi> <vi>The baked potatoes were too <it>hot</it> to handle with our bare hands.</vi> <vi>We worked all afternoon in/under the <it>hot</it> sun.</vi> <vi>The chicken was fried in <it>hot</it> oil.</vi> <vi>Your forehead feels <it>hot</it>. I think you might have a fever.</vi> <vi>a blazing/sizzling/steaming <it>hot</it> afternoon</vi> <vi>boiling/burning/fiery <it>hot</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>red-hot</dxt> <dxt>white-hot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a feeling of high body heat <vi>I was feeling <it>hot</it> and tired.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of food or drink</ssl> <dt>:heated to a hot or warm temperature :served at a hot or warm temperature <vi><it>hot</it> cereal</vi> <vi>a <it>hot</it> meal</vi> <vi>a selection of <it>hot</it> beverages</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>piping hot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:currently liked or wanted by many people <vi>The new toys are so <it>hot</it> that stores can't keep them in stock.</vi> <vi>a <it>hot</it> new restaurant</vi> <vi>He's considered a <it>hot</it> [=<it>appealing, desirable</it>] prospect.</vi> :currently very active or strong <vi>Her new book is a <it>hot</it> seller.</vi> <vi>She spoke about the latest <it>hot</it> trends in the computer industry.</vi> :currently causing a lot of interest or discussion <vi>reporters pursuing a <it>hot</it> story</vi> <vi>a <it>hot</it> concept/idea</vi> <vi>His decision has been a <it>hot</it> topic of conversation.</vi> <snote>Something or someone that is a <phrase>hot commodity/item/property</phrase> is currently very valuable or popular. <vi>Exotic mushrooms are a <it>hot commodity</it>.</vi> <vi>The success of her latest movie has made her a <it>hot property</it> in Hollywood.</vi> <vi>Computer games are a <it>hot item</it> in stores this year.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:very good <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>I don't think that's such a <it>hot</it> idea. [=I don't think it's a good idea]</vi> <vi>He came home early because he wasn't feeling too <it>hot</it>. [=he wasn't feeling well]</vi> <vi>Things aren't looking so <it>hot</it> at this point.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a period of unusual success or good luck <vi>The team has been <it>hot</it> recently. = The team has recently been on a <phrase>hot streak</phrase>. [=the team has been winning a lot recently]</vi> <vi><phrase>When you're hot, you're hot</phrase>. [=when you are having good luck, you keep winning or succeeding repeatedly]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:marked by anger or strong feelings <vi>a <it>hot</it> [=<it>heated</it>] argument</vi> <vi>His decision has been a topic of <it>hot</it> debate.</vi> <vi>This is an area of <it>hot</it> dispute.</vi> <snote>An issue or topic that is <phrase>too hot to handle</phrase> causes so much anger or controversy that people avoid discussing or dealing with it.</snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:easily excited or angered <vi>He's known for his <it>hot</it> [=<it>bad</it>] temper.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>angry</sx> <vi>He was starting to get pretty <it>hot</it> about the delays.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't allow these little delays to get you all <phrase>hot and bothered</phrase>. [=to make you angry and upset]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>hot under the collar <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:having a spicy or peppery flavor <vi><it>hot</it> chilis</vi> <vi><it>hot</it> sauce/mustard</vi> <vi>Do you prefer your curry <it>hot</it> or mild?</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:sexually excited by or interested in someone <un>+ <it>for</it> <vi>Everyone knows she's <it>hot for</it> the new guy in her office.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:sexually attractive <vi>The girl he's dating is really <it>hot</it>.</vi> <vi>He was voted the <it>hottest</it> [=<it>sexiest</it>] actor in Hollywood.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:exciting in a sexual or romantic way <vi>He's nervous because he has a <phrase>hot date</phrase> tonight.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <ssl>of sex</ssl> <dt>:very intense or exciting <vi><it>hot</it> sex</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:<sx>eager</sx> <un>usually followed by <it>to + verb</it> <vi>She's <it>hot to party</it>.</vi></un> <un>sometimes + <it>for</it> <vi>The students are <it>hot for</it> reform.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>music</ssl> <dt>:having an exciting rhythm <vi><it>hot</it> jazz</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:very strong or determined <vi>We're going to face some <it>hot</it> competition.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:newly made :fresh and warm <vi>bread <it>hot</it> from the oven</vi> <snote>Something, such as a story or book, that is <phrase>hot off the press</phrase> has just recently been completed, published, or printed. <vi>His new book is <it>hot off the press</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:following closely <vi>The police are <phrase>in hot pursuit</phrase> of the escaped convicts. [=the police are chasing the convicts and are close to catching them]</vi> <snote>To be <phrase>hot on the heels of</phrase> or <phrase>hot on the trail of</phrase> someone is to be chasing someone very closely. <vi>The escaped convicts are heading south, but the police are <it>hot on their heels</it>.</vi> <vi>The police are <it>hot on the trail of</it> the escaped convicts.</vi> To be/follow/come <it>hot on the heels of</it> something is to come or happen immediately or very soon after something. <vi>Their second album is coming <it>hot on the heels of</it> the first.</vi> To be <it>hot on the trail of</it> something is to be very close to doing, finding, or getting something. <vi>The company says it is <it>hot on the trail</it> of a new cancer treatment.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:very bright <vi><it>hot</it> colors</vi> <vi><it>hot</it> pink</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:carrying electric current <vi>The black wire is <it>hot</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:recently stolen <vi><it>hot</it> jewels</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:dangerous and difficult :difficult to deal with because of danger <vi>criminals who leave town when things get <it>hot</it> [=when there is too much danger that they will be caught by the police]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>blow hot and cold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>blow</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hot and heavy</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:sexually intense, active, or exciting <vi>They have a very <it>hot and heavy</it> relationship.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hot on</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:strongly favoring or liking (something) <vi>The company president is very <it>hot on</it> [=<it>big on</it>] the idea of developing new products.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hot tip</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a valuable piece of information about something (such as the stock market or a horse race) that can help someone get money or an advantage</dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hot to trot</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:very eager to have sex <vi>a movie about a couple of college students who are <it>hot to trot</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hot under the collar</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:angry or upset <vi>He tends to get a little <it>hot under the collar</it> when his wife keeps him waiting.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>like a hot knife through butter</dre> <dx>see <dxt>knife</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>strike while the iron is hot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>strike</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>hot*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>hotly</it> contested election</vi> <vi>a <it>hotly</it> debated issue</vi> <vi>He <it>hotly</it> denied any involvement in the controversy.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>hot*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>hotness</it> [=<it>spiciness</it>] of the pepper</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
