<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="combine[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*bine</hw> <sound><wav>combin09.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəmˈbaɪn</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>com*bines</if></in> <in><if>com*bined</if></in> <in><if>com*bin*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (two or more things) to be together or to work together <vi>We decided to <it>combine</it> both methods/techniques.</vi> <vi>The groups have <it>combined</it> forces to lobby for reform.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The drug may be <it>combined with</it> other treatments.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to mix (two or more things) together to form a single thing <vi><it>Combine</it> the ingredients (together) in a large bowl.</vi> <vi><it>combining</it> oxygen and/with hydrogen</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to come together and form a single thing or group <vi>Atoms <it>combine</it> [=<it>unite</it>] to form molecules.</vi> <vi>The two companies <it>combined</it> [=<it>merged</it>] under his leadership.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (two or more different things) at the same time <vi>a writer whose novels <it>combine</it> imagination and scholarship</vi> <vi>She found it difficult to <it>combine</it> a career and family.</vi> <vi>This method of payment <it>combines</it> the advantages of cash with the convenience of a check.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to act together <vi>Many factors <it>combined</it> to cause the recession.</vi> <vi>All of these elements <it>combine</it> to make a wonderfully entertaining movie.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="combine[2]"> <hw hindex="2">com*bine</hw> <sound><wav>combin11.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:mˌbaɪn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*bines</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a group of people or organizations that work together <vi>The teams belong to a <it>combine</it> that scouts new players.</vi> <vi>a political <it>combine</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a machine that cuts crops (such as corn or wheat) and separates the seeds of the plant from the rest of the plant</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="force[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">force</hw> <sound><wav>force001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfoɚs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>forc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:physical strength, power, or effect <vi>The front of the car took the full <it>force</it> of the collision.</vi> <vi>instruments used to measure the <it>force</it> of the wind</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:power or violence used on a person or thing <vi>The police were accused of using excessive <it>force</it> when they made the arrest.</vi> <vi>We discourage the use of <it>force</it>.</vi> <vi>a show of <it>force</it></vi> <vi>He used brute <it>force</it> to open the door.</vi> <vi>He took the purse from her <phrase>by force</phrase>. [=he used physical power to take her purse]</vi> <vi>He feels that this conflict can only be resolved <phrase>by force of arms</phrase>. [=by using weapons; by military action]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:strength or power that is not physical <vi>I was impressed by the <it>force</it> of her personality.</vi> <vi>lending <it>force</it> to his arguments [=making his arguments more effective/persuasive]</vi> <vi>These regulations do not have the <it>force</it> of law. [=they do not have the power that laws have]</vi> <vi>She succeeded by/through sheer <phrase>force of will</phrase>. [=because she was so determined to succeed]</vi> <vi>Through/By <phrase>force of circumstance(s)</phrase> [=because of conditions that cannot be controlled], the company has had to lay off several hundred workers.</vi> <vi>Even after he retired, he still woke up early every day <phrase>by/from force of habit</phrase>. [=he woke up early every day because he was in the habit of doing so]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:a natural power or effect that is able to change the speed or direction of something <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>the <it>force</it> of gravity</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>gravitational/electromagnetic <it>forces</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>centrifugal force</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something (such as rain or wind) that occurs in nature and that can be very powerful <un>usually plural <vi>The cliff was gradually eroded by the <it>forces</it> of nature.</vi> <vi>natural <it>forces</it></vi></un> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>She gets people to do whatever she wants: she's <phrase>a force of nature</phrase>. [=she's a very powerful person who cannot be easily controlled]</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a group of soldiers trained to fight in a war <vi>a <it>force</it> of 20,000 soldiers</vi> <vi>He belonged to an elite fighting <it>force</it>.</vi> <vi>The enemy <it>forces</it> had us surrounded.</vi> <vi>ground <it>forces</it></vi> <vi>allied/rebel <it>forces</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>air force</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who do a particular job or are available for a particular purpose <vi>our country's labor/work <it>force</it></vi> <vi>The company has a very large sales <it>force</it>.</vi> <vi>security <it>forces</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>task force</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <bnote>the Force</bnote> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:<sx>police force</sx> <vi>After graduating from high school, he joined <it>the Force</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <bnote>the forces</bnote> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>armed forces</sx> <vi>Will the new defense policy weaken <it>the forces</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person or group that has the power to do something or make something happen <vi>The organization has been a strong <it>force</it> for good. [=has done a lot of good things]</vi> <vi>He has been the driving/motivating <it>force</it> behind these changes. [=he has been the person who has caused these changes to occur]</vi> <vi>He has become a <phrase>force to be reckoned with</phrase> [=a person who has power and influence] in politics.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the strength of a wind <vi>damage caused by a <it>force</it> 9 gale</vi> <vi>The house was flattened by hurricane-<it>force</it> winds.</vi> <vi>Storm-<it>force</it> winds [=very strong winds] are expected tonight.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>baseball</ssl> <dt>:<sx>force-out</sx> <vi>a <it>force</it> at second base</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in force</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:in large numbers <vi>Picnickers were out <it>in force</it> today. [=there were many picnickers out today]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of a law, rule, etc.</ssl> <dt>:actually working or operating <vi>The ban remains <it>in force</it>. [=<it>in effect</it>]</vi> <vi>The resolution remains <phrase>in full force</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>into force</dre> <def><dt>:into the condition of actually working or operating <vi>The law came/went <it>into force</it> [=<it>into effect</it>] last year.</vi> <vi>The regulations have not yet been put/brought <it>into force</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>join forces</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>combine forces</va></vr> <def><dt>:to begin working together in order to achieve something <vi>We must all <it>join forces</it> to prevent violence.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The company has <it>joined forces with</it> local environmental groups.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>moving force</dre> <dx>see <dxt>moving</dxt></dx></dro> <dxnl>see also <dxt>tour de force</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
