<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="combination"> <hw highlight="yes">com*bi*na*tion</hw> <sound><wav>combin01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkɑ:mbəˈneɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*bi*na*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a result or product of combining two or more things or people <vi>Water is a <it>combination</it> of hydrogen and oxygen.</vi> <vi>The car's interior is available in various/different color <it>combinations</it>.</vi> <vi>It's an unusual <it>combination</it>.</vi> <vi>A <it>combination</it> of factors led to her decision.</vi> <vi>The milkshakes come in chocolate, strawberry, and vanilla, or any <it>combination</it> of these.</vi> <vi>He has the right <it>combination</it> of talent and experience.</vi> <vi>Together on one team they are a <phrase>winning combination</phrase>. [=they work, perform, etc., very well together]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an act of combining two or more things <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The <it>combination</it> of these two chemicals can cause an explosion.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The drugs should not be taken <phrase>in combination</phrase>. [=should not be taken together]</vi> <vi>It can be used by itself or <phrase>in combination with</phrase> [=<it>together with</it>] our other products.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a particular series of numbers or letters that is used to open a lock <vi>What is the <it>combination</it> to the safe?</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to describe something that can be used in more than one way <vi>The tool is a <it>combination</it> jackknife and bottle opener.</vi> <vi>The book is a <it>combination</it> dictionary and thesaurus.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="combination lock"> <art><artref id="combination_lock.tif"/><capt>combination lock</capt><dim>61.1,65.3</dim></art> <hw>combination lock</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ locks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a lock that can only be opened by using a particular series of numbers of letters</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="combination therapy"> <hw>combination therapy</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ pies</if></in> <def><gram>count, noncount</gram> <sl>medical</sl> <dt>:the use of more than one method and especially more than one drug to treat a disease</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
