<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="comfort[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*fort</hw> <sound><wav>comfor01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌmfɚt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*forts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a state or situation in which you are relaxed and do not have any physically unpleasant feelings caused by pain, heat, cold, etc. <vi>These boots provide warmth and <it>comfort</it> in the coldest temperatures.</vi> <vi>The car's seats are designed for <it>comfort</it>.</vi> <vi>The suites combine <it>comfort</it> with convenience.</vi> <vi>The drug gave some <it>comfort</it> to the patient.</vi> <vi>I found a cozy chair where I could read <phrase>in comfort</phrase>.</vi> <vi>We like to watch movies <phrase>in the comfort of our own home</phrase>. [=in our own home where we can relax and be comfortable]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a state or feeling of being less worried, upset, frightened, etc., during a time of trouble or emotional pain <vi>He turned to her for <it>comfort</it> and support when he lost his job.</vi> <vi>We found little/no <it>comfort</it> in their words. [=their words did not make us feel better]</vi> <vi>If it is any <it>comfort</it> to you, I've made the same mistake myself. = It might give you <it>comfort</it> to know that I've made the same mistake myself.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>take comfort</phrase> in the knowledge that I'm not alone. [=I feel less worried/upset because I know that I am not alone]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>cold comfort</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person or thing that makes someone feel less worried, upset, frightened, etc. <vi>They were great <it>comforts</it> to each other during that difficult time.</vi> <un>usually singular <vi>Her grandchildren were always a great <it>comfort</it> to her.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>comfort</it> to know that you are nearby.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <bnote>comforts</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:the things that make you more comfortable and that make your life easier and more pleasant <vi>domestic <it>comforts</it></vi> <vi>a country inn with all <phrase>the comforts of home</phrase></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>creature comfort</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a state or situation in which you have all the money and possessions that you need <vi>They lived a life of <it>comfort</it> and ease.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>too close for comfort</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>too near for comfort</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>Something or someone that is <it>too close/near for comfort</it> is close enough to make you feel nervous, worried, or upset. <vi>That bus came a little <it>too close for comfort</it>!</vi> <vi>When we went out for drinks together, I realized we were getting <it>too close for comfort</it>. [=we were getting closer than I wanted to be]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="comfort[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">comfort</hw> <altpr>ˈkʌmfɚt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>comforts</if></in> <in><if>comfort*ed</if></in> <in><if>comfort*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to feel less worried, upset, frightened, etc. :to give comfort to (someone) <vi>She did her best to <it>comfort</it> [=<it>console</it>] the crying child.</vi> <vi>Our family was <it>comforted</it> by the outpouring of support from the community.</vi> <vi>We can <it>comfort</it> ourselves with the thought that the worst is over.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>comforting</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more comforting; most comforting</gram> <utxt><vi>Knowing that I can rely on your help is a <it>comforting</it> thought. = It is <it>comforting</it> to know that I can rely on your help.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>com*fort*ing*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>comfortingly</it> familiar face</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="comfort food"> <hw>comfort food</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ foods</if></in> <def><dt>:food that is satisfying because it is prepared in a simple or traditional way and reminds you of home, family, or friends <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>Pot roast and fried chicken are my favorite <it>comfort foods</it>.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a restaurant that serves <it>comfort food</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="comfort zone"> <hw>comfort zone</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ zones</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a place, situation, or level where someone feels confident and comfortable <vi>He pushes the players to perform beyond their <it>comfort zone</it>.</vi> <vi>I need to expand my <it>comfort zone</it> and try new things.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="cold comfort"> <hw>cold comfort</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:something that is good for a situation but does not make someone happy because the whole situation is still bad <vi>The good news about the economy is <it>cold comfort</it> to people who have lost their jobs.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="creature comfort"> <hw>creature comfort</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -forts</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:something that makes life easier or more pleasant <un>usually plural <vi>a hotel with all the <it>creature comforts</it> [=<it>amenities</it>] of home</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="near[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">near</hw> <altpr>ˈniɚ</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>nearer</if></in> <in><if>nearest</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:located a short distance away :<sx>close</sx> <vi>The <it>nearest</it> grocery store is three blocks away.</vi> <vi>The airport is quite <it>near</it>. [=<it>nearby</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not far away in time <vi>Summer is getting <it>nearer</it>.</vi> <vi>I hope to visit in the <it>near</it> future. [=I hope to visit soon]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to refer to the side, end, etc., that is closer <vi>There is a fishing camp on the far side of the lake, but nothing on the <it>near</it> side.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>of a car</ssl> <dt>:<sx>left-hand</sx> <vi>The <it>near</it> side headlight is out.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>off</dxt></dx> <dx>see also <dxt>nearside</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:almost happening <vi>The ceremony was a <it>near</it> disaster. [=was nearly a disaster]</vi> <vi>After a <it>near</it> win [=after nearly winning] in the first competition, he is ready to try again.</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Our team won the match, but it was a very <phrase>near thing</phrase>. [=we almost lost the match]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>near miss</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:close to being something <vi>Her victory is a <it>near</it> certainty. [=it is nearly certain that she will win]</vi> <vi>a <it>near</it> miracle</vi> <vi>celebrities and <it>near</it> celebrities [=people who are almost celebrities]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>nearest</bnote> <dt>:most similar <vi>The lake was the <it>nearest</it> thing to an ocean [=the thing most like an ocean] that she had ever seen.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:coming after someone or something :in the position or rank after someone or something <vi>He finished the race ahead of his <it>nearest</it> rival by only a few feet.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:closely related <vi>These two kinds of plants are <it>near</it> relatives.</vi> <vi>Only <phrase>near relations</phrase> [=sisters, brothers, parents, etc.] were invited to the wedding.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>near and dear</dre> <def><dt>:very close in relationship <vi>friends who are <it>near and dear</it></vi> <vi>my <phrase>nearest and dearest</phrase> friend</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>too near for comfort</dre> <dx>see <dxt>comfort</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>to the nearest</dre> <def><dt><un>used to indicate the number of pounds, dollars, etc., that is closest to a slightly higher or lower number or amount <vi>What is the weight of your baggage <it>to the nearest</it> pound?</vi> <vi>$13.75 rounded up <it>to the nearest</it> dollar is $14.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>near*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>He missed her <it>nearness</it>. [=<it>closeness</it>]</vi> <vi>the <it>nearness</it> of the storm</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
