<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="community"> <hw highlight="yes">com*mu*ni*ty</hw> <sound><wav>commun30.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈmju:nəti</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*mu*ni*ties</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who live in the same area (such as a city, town, or neighborhood) <vi>a respectable member of the <it>community</it></vi> <vi>The festival was a great way for the local <it>community</it> to get together.</vi> <vi>Many <it>communities</it> are facing budget problems.</vi> <vi>People in the <it>community</it> wanted better police protection.</vi> <vi>a rural <it>community</it></vi> <vi><it>community</it> leaders</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who have the same interests, religion, race, etc. <vi>an artistic/business/medical <it>community</it></vi> <vi>the town's Jewish <it>community</it></vi> <vi>ethnic/religious <it>communities</it></vi> <vi>the scientific <it>community</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of nations <un>usually singular <vi>the international <it>community</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a feeling of wanting to be with other people or of caring about the other people in a group <vi>The school encourages a sense/feeling of <it>community</it> in its students.</vi> <vi><it>community</it> spirit</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>biology</ssl> <dt>:a group of animals or plants that live in the same place <vi>a <it>community</it> of bacteria</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="community center"> <hw>community center</hw> <hsl>US</hsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>community centre</va></vr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a building or group of buildings where there are classes and activities for the people who live in a community</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="community college"> <hw>community college</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -leges</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a school that you go to after high school :a school that offers courses leading to an associate's degree <snote>A community college offers two years of studies similar to those in the first two years of a four-year college.</snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="community service"> <hw>community service</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:work that is done without pay to help people in a community <snote>People do community service because they want to or because a court of law has ordered them to do it as a form of punishment for a crime. <vi>She was sentenced to 100 hours of <it>community service</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="community theater"> <hw>community theater</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ters</if></in> <def><sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the activity of acting in or producing a play in the theater for enjoyment and not as a job <vi>She spends her free time acting in <it>community theater</it>.</vi> <vi>He's done school plays and <it>community theater</it>.</vi> <vi>a <it>community theater</it> group/production</vi> <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>amateur dramatics</cat></ca></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a small theater where community theater is performed <vi>performing at the/a local <it>community theater</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
