<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="commit"> <hw highlight="yes">com*mit</hw> <sound><wav>commit01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈmɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>com*mits</if></in> <in><if>com*mit*ted</if></in> <in><if>com*mit*ting</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to do (something that is illegal or harmful) <vi><it>commit</it> [=<it>perpetrate</it>] a crime</vi> <vi><it>commit</it> suicide/murder/rape/adultery</vi> <vi>The massacre was <it>committed</it> by the rebel army.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to decide to use (a person, money, etc.) for some particular purpose or use <un>often + <it>to</it> or <it>for</it> <vi>The army <it>committed</it> two divisions <it>to</it> the battle.</vi> <vi>The city <it>committed</it> millions of dollars <it>for</it> the housing project.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to say that (someone or something) will definitely do something :to make (someone or something) obligated to do something <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>I've <it>committed</it> myself to a meeting on Thursday. = I'm <it>committed</it> to a meeting on Thursday. [=I have said that I will definitely go to a meeting on Thursday]</vi> <vi>The contract <it>commits</it> the company to finishing the bridge by next fall.</vi> <vi>He keeps delaying his decision because he doesn't want to <phrase>commit himself</phrase>.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Many companies are reluctant to <it>commit</it> to the new technology. [=to say that they will definitely use it]</vi> <vi>They have not yet <it>committed</it> to a particular course of action.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to decide to give your love, support, or effort to someone or something in a serious or permanent way <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>My girlfriend just can't seem to <it>commit</it>!</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He won't <it>commit</it> himself to a long-term relationship.</vi> <vi>Many local officials have not yet <it>committed</it> themselves to a presidential candidate.</vi> <vi>They are <it>committing</it> themselves to the pursuit of truth.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be put in a prison or a mental hospital <un>usually used as <it>(be) committed</it> <vi>She <it>was committed</it> to a state mental hospital.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>law</ssl> <dt>:to order (someone) to be tried in a court of law <vi>The magistrate <it>committed</it> him to stand trial at the Bristol Crown Court.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>commit (something) to memory</dre> <def><dt>:to learn (something) so that you remember it perfectly :to memorize (something) <vi>I <it>committed</it> the poem <it>to memory</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>commit (something) to paper/writing</dre> <def><dt>:to write (something) down <vi>She <it>committed</it> her thoughts <it>to writing</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
