<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="commission[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*mis*sion</hw> <sound><wav>commis09.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈmɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*mis*sions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who have been given the official job of finding information about something or controlling something :<sx>committee</sx> <vi>She served on the city's water <it>commission</it>.</vi> <vi>the Federal Elections <it>Commission</it></vi> <vi>Both states set up <it>commissions</it> to examine their public schools.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an amount of money paid to an employee for selling something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>She gets a <it>commission</it> for each car she sells.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She sells cars <phrase>on commission</phrase>. [=she receives an amount of money for each car that she sells]</vi> <vi>The salespeople in that store all work <it>on commission</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:the act of committing a crime <vi>a weapon used in the <it>commission</it> of a crime</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a request or order for someone to do something for money <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He received a <it>commission</it> from the king to paint the queen's portrait.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>an artist working <phrase>on commission</phrase> [=an artist doing work that has been specifically requested or ordered]</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a position of high rank in the military <vi>He received his <it>commission</it> in the Army as a colonel.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in commission</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>into commission</va></vr> <def><dt>:able to function properly :ready for use <vi>The Internet connection is back <it>in commission</it>. [=is working again]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>out of commission</dre> <def><dt>:not able to function properly <vi>The elevator/doorbell was <it>out of commission</it>. [=<it>broken, out of order</it>]</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>He was <it>out of commission</it> [=unable to work, travel, etc.] for three days with the flu.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="commission[2]"> <hw hindex="2">commission</hw> <altpr>kəˈmɪʃən</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>commissions</if></in> <in><if>commissioned</if></in> <in><if>commission*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to order or request (something) to be made or done <vi>A portrait of the queen was <it>commissioned</it>.</vi> <vi>The magazine <it>commissioned</it> a story about the world's best beaches.</vi> <vi>The report on poverty was <it>commissioned</it> by the governor.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to order or request (someone) to make or do something <vi>The king <it>commissioned</it> the artist to paint his portrait.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) an officer in the military <vi>She was <it>commissioned</it> in the Navy as a captain.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (a ship) officially active and ready for use <vi>The ship was <it>commissioned</it> in 2004.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>decommission</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>commissioned</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>The ship remained a <it>commissioned</it> ship for more than 30 years. [=the ship was officially in use for more than 30 years]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>commissioned officer</phrase> [=a military officer of high rank; an officer whose rank is higher than sergeant]</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="Royal Commission"> <hw>Royal Commission</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -sions</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a group of people chosen by the British government to examine a particular topic or issue and recommend changes in the law <vi>a <it>Royal Commission</it> on the death penalty</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
