<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="commitment"> <hw>com*mit*ment</hw> <sound><wav>commit03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈmɪtmənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*mit*ments</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a promise to do or give something <vi>We've got <it>commitments</it> from several charities to donate food and clothing.</vi> <vi>the government's <it>commitment</it> of troops to the region</vi> <vi>I can't coach my daughter's basketball team. I have too many <it>commitments</it> already. [=I have too many things that I have promised to do]</vi> <vi>It's been a struggle to balance my professional and family <it>commitments</it>. [=to do both what I have promised to do for my job and what I have promised to do for my family]</vi> <vi>The church has a <it>commitment</it> to helping the poor.</vi> <vi>Getting a dog is a <phrase>big commitment</phrase>. [=something that requires you to do a lot]</vi> <vi>Opening your own business requires a significant <phrase>financial commitment</phrase>. [=it requires you to spend a lot of money over a long time]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a promise to be loyal to someone or something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>She isn't ready to make a lifelong <it>commitment to</it> another person.</vi> <vi>Are you willing to make a <it>commitment to</it> our cause?</vi> <vi>He questions the company's <it>commitment to</it> safety.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He's afraid of <it>commitment</it>. [=he's afraid of committing himself to a serious relationship with one person]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the attitude of someone who works very hard to do or support something <vi>Some of his teammates said he showed a lack of <it>commitment</it> (to the team).</vi> <vi>The boss noticed her strong <it>commitment</it> to her work.</vi> <vi>No one doubts your <it>commitment</it> to the cause.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
