<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="command[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*mand</hw> <sound><wav>comman01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈmænd</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>com*mands</if></in> <in><if>com*mand*ed</if></in> <in><if>com*mand*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to give (someone) an order :to tell (someone) to do something in a forceful and often official way <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>commanded</it> us to leave.</vi> <vi>Military leaders <it>commanded</it> the troops to open fire.</vi> <vi>She <it>commanded</it> that work on the bridge cease immediately.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>We had no choice but to do as they <it>commanded</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have authority and control over (a group of people, such as soldiers) <vi>He <it>commands</it> a platoon of 60.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to deserve or be able to get or receive (something) <vi>She has a reputation that <it>commands</it> attention/respect. [=people give her respect/attention because of her reputation]</vi> <vi>With his skills and experience, he can <it>command</it> a high salary.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have and be able to use or control (something) <vi>The company <it>commands</it> much power and influence in the business world.</vi> <vi>They <it>command</it> many resources.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to be in a place in which you can clearly see (something) <vi>Their house is on a hill that <it>commands</it> an excellent view of the valley.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="command[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">command</hw> <altpr>kəˈmænd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>commands</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:an order given to a person or animal to do something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>We are expected to obey his <it>commands</it>.</vi> <vi>She shouted out <it>commands</it> to the crew.</vi> <vi>Begin on/at my <it>command</it>.</vi> <vi>We started to teach the dog simple <it>commands</it> like “sit” and “lie down.”</vi> <vi>The dog will only attack <phrase>on my command</phrase>. [=will only attack when I tell it to]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The soldiers marched <phrase>on command</phrase>. [=they marched when they were ordered to march]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>your wish is my command</tag> at <dxt>wish</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an instruction in the form of a code or signal that tells a computer to do something <vi>You can perform several actions with keyboard <it>commands</it>.</vi> <vi>The system recognizes voice <it>commands</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the power that someone (such as a military officer) has to give orders and to control a group of people <vi>He was relieved of his <it>command</it> after being charged with misconduct.</vi> <vi>He has <it>command</it> of 100 troops. = He has 100 troops <phrase>under his command</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Who is the officer <phrase>in command of</phrase> the unit?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>chain of command</dxt></dx> <synref>power</synref></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:control of something (such as a situation, activity, or feeling) <vi>I assumed <it>command</it> of the business after my father's death.</vi> <vi>He immediately took <it>command</it> of the situation.</vi> <vi>She seems to be <phrase>in (full) command of</phrase> the situation. [=she seems to have complete control of the situation]</vi> <vi>He finally felt <it>in command of</it> his life.</vi> <vi>She stayed <it>in command of</it> herself [=she did not lose control of her emotions] during the trial.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:knowledge and skill that allows you to do or use something well <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi>She has a good <it>command of</it> French. [=she speaks French well]</vi> <vi>His <it>command of</it> the piano is impressive.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of people or an area that is under the control of a military officer <vi>He is an officer in the Middle East <it>command</it>.</vi> <vi>He quickly earned the respect of his <it>command</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of military officers of high rank who give orders <vi>The order came down from Naval <it>Command</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>high command</dxt> <dxt>second-in-command</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>at your command</dre> <def><dt>:available for your use <vi>They used every resource <it>at their command</it>. [=<it>at their disposal</it>]</vi> <vi>If you need anything, please ask me. I am <it>at your command</it>. [=I am available to help you at any time]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="command performance"> <hw>command performance</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -mances</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a special performance of a concert, play, etc., that is done at the request of an important person (such as a king)</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="chain of command"> <hw>chain of command</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>chains of command</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a series of positions of authority or rank within an organization that are ordered from lowest to highest <vi>In the United States, the President as the commander in chief is at the head of the military <it>chain of command</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="high command"> <hw>high command</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>singular</gram> <dt>:the most powerful and important leaders of an organization or military force <vi>the Republican <it>high command</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="second-in-command"> <hw>second–in–command</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>seconds–in–command</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:someone who is ranked second in a group or organization <vi>He served as <it>second-in-command</it> to the sheriff.</vi> <vi>the police chief's <it>second-in-command</it></vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="wish[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">wish</hw> <altpr>ˈwɪʃ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>wishes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a desire for something to happen or be done :a feeling of wanting to do or have something <vi>Please respect my <it>wishes</it> [=please do what I want you to do] and leave me alone.</vi> <vi>It is my <it>wish</it> that my estate go to my granddaughter. [=I want my estate to go to my granddaughter]</vi> <vi>He has a <it>wish</it> to be reunited with his son.</vi> <vi>She has expressed a <it>wish</it> to retire [=has said she wants to retire] within the next two years.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>have no wish</phrase> [=I do not want] to interfere in your plans.</vi> <vi>It was her <phrase>dying wish</phrase> to see them married. [=it was the last thing she wanted before she died]</vi> <vi>They did it <phrase>against my wishes</phrase>. [=they did it even though they knew that I did not want them to do it]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>went against their parents' wishes</phrase> and got married. [=they got married even though they knew that their parents did not want them to]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>death wish</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an act of thinking about something that you want and hoping that you will get it or that it will happen in some magical way <vi>The genie will grant you three <it>wishes</it>.</vi> <vi>Close your eyes and <phrase>make a wish</phrase>. [=wish for something]</vi> <vi>I <phrase>got my wish</phrase>. = My <phrase>wish came true</phrase>. [=I got what I wished for]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <bnote>wishes</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:good thoughts or feelings directed toward a person <vi>Send her my good/best <it>wishes</it>.</vi> <vi>Best <it>wishes</it>!</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>pious wish</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pious</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>your wish is my command</dre> <def><sl>humorous</sl> <dt><un>used to say that you will do what someone else wants you to do <vi>“Could you put these dishes away for me?” “<it>Your wish is my command</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="self-"> <hw>self-</hw> <pr>ˌsɛlf</pr> <fl>combining form</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-pitying</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-destructive</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-sacrifice</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:by, to, with, for, or toward yourself or itself <vi><it>self</it>-made</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-evident</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-propelled</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-addressed</vi> <vi><it>self</it>-respect</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
