<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="comment[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*ment</hw> <sound><wav>commen16.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:ˌmɛnt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*ments</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a spoken or written statement that expresses an opinion about someone or something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The most frequent <it>comment</it> was that the service was slow.</vi> <vi>I find your <it>comments</it> offensive.</vi> <vi>I'd like to begin with a few general <it>comments</it>.</vi> <vi>We have no further <it>comments</it>. [=we have nothing more to say]</vi> <vi><it>Comments</it> or suggestions can be sent to our main Web address.</vi> <vi>She heard him making rude <it>comments</it> [=<it>remarks</it>] about the neighbors.</vi> <vi>We haven't gotten any <it>comments</it> on/about the new design.</vi> <vi>I'd appreciate your <it>comments on</it> this issue.</vi> <vi>We've received positive <it>comments</it> from many of our readers.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>She couldn't be reached for <it>comment</it>.</vi> <vi>We let the remark pass without <it>comment</it>. [=we did not respond to the remark]</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>no comment</phrase> is used to tell someone (such as a reporter) that you do not wish to answer a question. <vi>“Did you know the defendant well?” “<it>No comment</it>.”</vi></snote> <synref>remark</synref></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a written note that explains or discusses the meaning of something (such as a piece of writing) <vi>The new edition includes the translator's <it>comments</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:spoken or written discussion about something (such as an event in the news) <vi>The radio program offers news and <it>comment</it>.</vi> <vi>The trial drew widespread <it>comment</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that shows or makes a statement about the true state or condition of something <un>usually singular</un> <un>+ <it>on</it> <vi>Their case is a sad <it>comment</it> [=<it>commentary</it>] <it>on</it> the current state of the justice system.</vi> <vi>She sees the film as a <it>comment on</it> modern values.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="comment[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">comment</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:ˌmɛnt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>comments</if></in> <in><if>comment*ed</if></in> <in><if>comment*ing</if></in> <def><dt>:to make a statement about someone or something :to make a comment <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>When asked about his involvement in the scandal, he refused/declined to <it>comment</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>Several people have <it>commented on</it> my new dress.</vi> <vi>He declined to <it>comment on</it> the matter.</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>commented</it> that the service seemed slow.</vi> <vi>“The service seems slow today,” she <it>commented</it>. [=<it>remarked</it>]</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
