<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="compare[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">com*pare</hw> <sound><wav>compar10.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəmˈpeɚ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>com*pares</if></in> <in><if>com*pared</if></in> <in><if>com*par*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to say that (something) is similar <it>to</it> something else <vi>The poet <it>compared</it> [=<it>likened</it>] his sweetheart <it>to</it> a beautiful rose.</vi> <vi>The singer's voice has been <it>compared to</it> that of Elvis.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to look at (two or more things) closely in order to see what is similar or different about them or in order to decide which one is better <vi>We each did the homework assignment, then <it>compared</it> answers.</vi> <vi>I <it>compared</it> several bicycles before buying one.</vi> <vi>For our assignment we must <phrase>compare and contrast</phrase> the two poets. [=say what is similar and different about them]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be as good or as bad as something else :to be on the same level or in the same category as something else <un>usually + <it>with</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>He says skiing is fun enough but it can't <it>compare with</it> snowboarding. [=he says skiing is fun but snowboarding is better]</vi> <vi>Spraining an ankle hurts but doesn't <it>compare to</it> breaking a leg. [=breaking a leg is worse than spraining an ankle]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to seem better or worse in comparison to something else :to be good or bad when measured against something else <vi>How do the restaurants <it>compare</it>?</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>How does your new job <it>compare to</it> the last one? [=is your new job better or worse than the last one?]</vi> <vi>Her scores <it>compare</it> well <it>with</it> those of the rest of the class.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>compare apples and/to/with apples</dre> <def><dt>:to compare things that are very similar <vi>The article <it>compares apples to apples</it>, grouping wines of the same variety and price together.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>compare apples and/to/with oranges</dre> <def><dt>:to compare things that are very different <vi>To compare large trucks with compact cars is to <it>compare apples with oranges</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>compared to</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>compared with</va></vr> <def><dt>:in relation to (something else) :measured or judged against (something else) <vi>I'm a slob <it>compared to</it> my roommate.</vi> <vi>This rain is nothing <it>compared to</it> what we got yesterday. [=yesterday's rain was worse than today's rain]</vi> <vi>Today's quiz was easy <it>compared with</it> the last one.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>compare notes</dre> <def><dt>:to talk to someone about something that you and that person have each done, experienced, etc. <vi>The parents <it>compared notes</it> on raising children.</vi> <vi>I phoned a coworker after the meeting to <it>compare notes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="compare[2]"> <hw hindex="2">compare</hw> <altpr>kəmˈpeɚ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>beyond compare</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>without compare</va></vr> <def><dt>:better or greater than any other :having no equal <vi>The singer's voice is <it>beyond compare</it>.</vi> <vi>beauty <it>beyond compare</it></vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="apple"> <hw highlight="yes">ap*ple</hw> <sound><wav>apple001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæpəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ap*ples</if></in> <def><dt>:a round fruit with red, yellow, or green skin and firm white flesh <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>crisp juicy <it>apples</it></vi> <vi>a bad/rotten <it>apple</it> [=an apple that has rotted and cannot be eaten]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a piece of <it>apple</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>apple</it> pie</vi> <vi><it>apple</it> juice</vi> <vi><it>apple</it> trees</vi></un> <dx>see color picture on page C5</dx> <snote>In figurative use, a <phrase>bad apple</phrase> or <phrase>rotten apple</phrase> is a bad member of a group who causes problems for the rest of the group. <vi>A few <it>bad apples</it> cheated on the test, and now everyone has to take the test again.</vi> <vi>One <it>rotten apple</it> ruined the day for the rest of us.</vi></snote> <dx>see also <dxt>adam's apple</dxt> <dxt>crab apple</dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>compare apples to apples/oranges</dre> <dx>see <dxt>compare</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>the apple of someone's eye</dre> <def><dt>:a person or thing that someone loves very much <vi>His daughter is <it>the apple of his eye</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>upset the apple cart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>upset</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="note[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">note</hw> <sound><wav>note0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈnoʊt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>notes</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a short piece of writing that is used to help someone remember something <vi>She wrote a <it>note</it> to remind herself about the appointment.</vi> <vi>I left you a <it>note</it> on the kitchen table.</vi> <vi>making/writing <it>notes</it> in the margins of a book</vi> <vi>She jotted down a few <it>notes</it> during the interview.</vi> <vi>I'll make a <phrase>mental note</phrase> [=I'll try to remember] to reschedule the meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <bnote>notes</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <dt>:an informal written record of things that are said and done <vi>After class, I usually study my <it>notes</it> and read the next chapter.</vi> <vi>I can't come to class today. Would you mind <phrase>taking notes</phrase> for me?</vi> <vi>His secretary <it>took notes</it> during our meeting.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a short piece of writing that gives you information :a brief comment or explanation <vi>Please include a brief <it>note</it> about where the picture was taken.</vi> <vi>He writes in the program <it>notes</it> that the play was inspired by his own childhood.</vi> <vi>The dictionary includes many <phrase>usage notes</phrase>. [=short explanations about how a word or phrase is used]</vi> <vi>One <phrase>final note</phrase>: tickets will be available at the door the night of the concert.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>liner notes</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a comment or added piece of information that is separate from the main writing of a book <vi>For further details, see the <it>notes</it> to Chapter 3.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>footnote</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a short and usually informal letter <vi>Remember to send a thank-you <it>note</it> to the host of the party.</vi> <vi>This is just a brief <it>note</it> to say how much I enjoyed your party.</vi> <vi>Drop me a <it>note</it> while you're away.</vi> <vi>I have a handwritten <it>note</it> here from the governor.</vi> <vi>If you are out sick for more than one week, you will need a <it>note</it> from your doctor.</vi> <vi>The girl's kidnappers left a <phrase>ransom note</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mash note</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>music</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a specific musical tone <vi>musical <it>notes</it></vi> <vi>That <it>note</it>'s a B not a C.</vi> <vi>Despite a few wrong <it>notes</it>, the pianist gave a generally good performance.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a written symbol that is used to show what note should be played and how long it should last <dx>see also <dxt>eighth note</dxt> <dxt>half note</dxt> <dxt>quarter note</dxt> <dxt>sixteenth note</dxt> <dxt>whole note</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a characteristic or quality that expresses a mood or feeling <vi>I detected a <it>note</it> of sadness in his voice.</vi> <un>often used after <it>on</it> <vi>Let's try to end our conversation <it>on</it> a lighter/happier <it>note</it>.</vi> <vi>If I may end <it>on</it> a personal <it>note</it>, I'd like to wish my father a happy 85th birthday!</vi> <vi>The party ended <phrase>on a high note</phrase>. [=the party ended pleasantly or well]</vi> <vi>Their relationship ended <phrase>on a sour note</phrase>. [=ended unpleasantly]</vi></un> <un>often used with <it>hit, strike</it> or <it>sound</it> <vi>The movie <it>hits</it> just the right <it>note</it> with young audiences.</vi> <vi>Her judgment rarely <it>strikes</it> a wrong <it>note</it>.</vi> <vi>In her chapter about rising oil prices, she <it>sounds</it> a cautionary <it>note</it>.</vi> <vi>Most reviewers loved the show, but one critic <it>struck</it> a discordant <it>note</it>, finding it “clichéd” and “predictable.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>bill</sx> <vi>a ten-pound <it>note</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>compare notes</dre> <dx>see <dxt>compare</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>of note</dre> <def><dt>:important and deserving to be noticed or remembered <vi>American writers <it>of note</it> include Herman Melville, Mark Twain, and Emily Dickinson.</vi> <vi>historical events <it>of note</it></vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take note</dre> <def><dt>:to notice or give special attention to someone or something <vi>She has been extremely successful in her own country, and now the rest of the world is beginning to <it>take note</it>.</vi> <vi>She <it>took note</it> of the exact time.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="orange"> <hw highlight="yes">or*ange</hw> <sound><wav>orange01.wav</wav><wav>orange01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑrɪnʤ, ˈorɪnʤ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>or*ang*es</if></in> <def><gram>count, noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a citrus fruit that is round and that has an orange skin <vi>He peeled the <it>orange</it>.</vi> <vi>a slice of <it>orange</it></vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>an <it>orange</it> tree/grove/peel</vi> <vi>I drink a glass of <phrase>orange juice</phrase> [=juice from an orange] every morning.</vi></un> <dx>see color picture on page C5</dx> <dx>see also <dxt>blood orange</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a color between red and yellow that is like the color of fire and carrots <dx>see color picture on page C1</dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>compare apples and/to/with oranges</dre> <dx>see <dxt>compare</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>orange</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>orange</it> flame</vi> <vi>He was wearing an <it>orange</it> shirt.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>or*ang*ish</ure> <sound><wav>orangi01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈɑrɪnʤɪʃ, ˈorɪnʤɪʃ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>the cat's <it>orangish</it> fur</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
