<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="company"> <hw highlight="yes">com*pa*ny</hw> <sound><wav>compan08.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkʌmpəni</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*pa*nies</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a business organization that makes, buys, or sells goods or provides services in exchange for money <vi>He runs his own trucking <it>company</it>.</vi> <vi>She joined the <it>company</it> last year.</vi> <vi>record/insurance/computer <it>companies</it></vi> <vi>The <it>company</it> is based in Paris.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>company</it> policy/profits</vi> <vi>the <it>company</it> director</vi> <vi><it>company</it> executives/officials</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition of being with another person <vi>I enjoy her <it>company</it>. [=I enjoy being with her]</vi> <vi>I would love for you to come over. I could really use the <it>company</it>. [=I really want to spend time with someone; I do not want to be alone]</vi> <vi>I turned the radio on <phrase>for company</phrase>. [=so that I wouldn't be lonely]</vi> <vi>I felt nervous being <phrase>in the company of</phrase> [=<it>around, with</it>] such important people.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) She arrived <phrase>in company with</phrase> the mayor. [=she was with the mayor when she arrived]</vi> <vi>I'll <phrase>keep you company</phrase> [=I'll stay with you] while you wait for your mom.</vi> <vi>He has been <phrase>keeping company with</phrase> [=associating with] a gang of known criminals.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) The children have no idea how to behave <phrase>in company</phrase>. [=with a group of people]</vi> <vi>It's not something you should talk about <phrase>in polite company</phrase>. [=in formal settings; with people you do not know well]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>in mixed company</tag> at <dxt>mixed</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:someone or something you spend time with or enjoy being with <vi>He's good <it>company</it>. [=he's enjoyable to be around]</vi> <vi>I'm lousy <it>company</it> tonight. [=I'm not enjoyable to be around tonight; I'm in a bad mood]</vi> <vi>Her dogs/sisters/books/thoughts are her only <it>company</it> these days.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the people you spend time with <vi>You can tell a lot about people by the <phrase>company they keep</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She's been <phrase>keeping bad company</phrase>. [=spending time with people who are not morally good]</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>in good company</phrase> or have <phrase>plenty of company</phrase>, you are in the same situation or have the same problem or opinion as many other people. <vi>If you're confused about the new system, you're <it>in good company</it>. [=other people are also confused]</vi> <vi>Do you know now what you will do when you retire? If not, you have <it>plenty of company</it>.</vi> <vi>If you think health-care costs are out of control, you've got <it>plenty of company</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:guests or visitors especially at your home <vi>We are having <it>company</it> for dinner. [=guests or visitors will be eating dinner with us at our home]</vi> <vi>Are you expecting <it>company</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a group of soldiers <vi>the soldiers of <it>Company</it> C</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the officers and crew of a ship <vi>the ship's <it>company</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a group of actors, dancers, singers, etc., who perform together <vi>a theater/ballet <it>company</it></vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:people who are not named but are part of a group <vi>the law firm of Smith and <it>Company</it></vi> <vi>(<it>informal</it>) John and <it>company</it> got to the party pretty late.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>part company</dre> <dx>see <dxt>part</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>two's company, three's a crowd</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a third person is not welcome when two people (such as two lovers) want to be alone with each other <vi>Well, I'll leave you two lovebirds alone. <it>Two's company, three's a crowd</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="company car"> <hw>company car</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ cars</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a car that an employer gives an employee to use for driving that relates to the employee's work</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="finance company"> <hw>finance company</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -nies</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a company that makes small loans to people <ca>called also (<it>Brit</it>) <cat>finance house</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="holding company"> <hw>holding company</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ies</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>business</sl> <dt>:a company whose main business is owning more than half of another company's stock</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="stock company"> <hw>stock company</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -nies</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a company whose ownership is divided into shares that can be bought and sold</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a theater group made up of actors who perform together</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="crowd[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">crowd</hw> <altpr>ˈkraʊd</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>crowds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large group of people who are together in one place <vi>The President will address the <it>crowd</it> later.</vi> <vi>The <it>crowd</it> is restless. = (<it>Brit</it>) The <it>crowd</it> are restless.</vi> <vi>a <it>crowd</it> of kids/reporters/shoppers</vi> <vi>The formerly unknown singer now regularly performs to <it>crowds</it> of 10,000 (people).</vi> <vi><it>Crowds</it> lined the street to watch the parade.</vi> <vi>His speeches always <phrase>draw a big/large crowd</phrase>. [=a lot of people come to hear him speak]</vi> <vi>You can <phrase>avoid the crowds</phrase> by visiting a popular resort area in the off-season.</vi> <vi>police trained in <phrase>crowd control</phrase></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the crowd</bnote> <dt>:ordinary people :people who are not special or unusual <vi>kids trying to distinguish themselves from <it>the crowd</it></vi> <vi>She prefers to be <phrase>one of the crowd</phrase>. [=she prefers to not to be noticed or treated in any special way]</vi> <snote>Someone who is <phrase>just another face in the crowd</phrase> is not famous or well-known. <vi>Until her book became a best seller, she was <it>just another face in the crowd</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>Someone or something that <phrase>stands out from the crowd</phrase> is unusual in a good way. <vi>As a teacher, he always <it>stood out from the crowd</it>.</vi> <vi>The high quality of these tools makes them <it>stand out from the crowd</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>Someone who <phrase>follows the crowd</phrase> or <phrase>goes with the crowd</phrase> does whatever most other people are doing. <vi>He was never one to <it>follow the crowd</it>, so we weren't surprised when he dropped out of college to start his own business.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:a group of people who spend time together or have something in common <vi>Her parents are concerned that she's been hanging out with <phrase>a bad crowd</phrase>. [=with people who do illegal or immoral things]</vi> <un>usually used with <it>the</it> <vi>Her parents are concerned that she's been hanging out with <it>the</it> wrong <it>crowd</it>.</vi> <vi>The new dance club caters to <it>the</it> under-18 <it>crowd</it>. [=to people who are less than 18 years old]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>join the crowd</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become part of a larger group :to do what most other people are doing <vi>You can find a private hideaway or <it>join the crowd</it> at the beach.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that the problems or feelings someone is having are problems or feelings that you have had yourself <vi>If you don't understand the rules, <it>join the crowd</it> [=(more commonly) <it>join the club</it>]: no one else does either!</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>two's company, three's a crowd</dre> <dx>see <dxt>company</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="good[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">good</hw> <sound><wav>good0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgʊd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <in><if>bet*ter</if> <sound><wav>bettor01.wav</wav><wav>good0002.wav</wav><wav>better01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛtɚ</pr></in> <in><if>best</if> <sound><wav>good0003.wav</wav><wav>best0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈbɛst</pr></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:of high quality <vi>The food was <it>good</it>. = It was <it>good</it> food.</vi> <vi>You'll need <it>better</it> tools for this job.</vi> <vi>The car is in <it>good</it> condition/shape.</vi> <vi>There are some <it>good</it> restaurants in this neighborhood.</vi> <vi>That was a <it>good</it> game. [=the game was exciting, people played well, etc.]</vi> <vi>I'm afraid your work is just not <it>good</it> enough.</vi> <vi>Keep up the <it>good</it> work.</vi> <vi>“Would you hire her again?” “Yes, I would. She <phrase>does good work</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>His most recent movie is <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=it is boring, poorly made, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of somewhat high but not excellent quality <vi>The food was <it>good</it> but not great.</vi> <vi>He has done <it>good</it> but not outstanding work.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:correct or proper <vi><it>good</it> manners</vi> <vi><it>good</it> grammar</vi> <vi>She speaks very <it>good</it> English. [=she uses correct pronunciation, grammar, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:pleasant, pleasing, or enjoyable <vi>Did you have a <it>good</it> time at the party?</vi> <vi>We're expecting <it>good</it> weather for the weekend.</vi> <vi>The soup tastes/smells <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>food that is <it>good</it> to eat</vi> <vi>It feels <it>good</it> to sit down after so much walking.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> feeling to know that we were able to help.</vi> <vi><it>good</it> [=<it>happy</it>] memories</vi> <vi>I want to make a <it>good</it> [=<it>favorable</it>] impression on my future in-laws.</vi> <vi>his rugged <it>good</it> looks [=attractive appearance]</vi> <vi>You look <it>good</it> in that dress. = That dress looks <it>good</it> on you.</vi> <vi>You don't look so <it>good</it>. [=you look like you feel sick] Do you feel okay?</vi> <vi><phrase>Have a good day</phrase>! = (<it>US, informal</it>) <phrase>Have a good one</phrase>! [=I hope you have an enjoyable day]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good life</dxt> <dxt>good-looking</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not having, marked by, or relating to problems, troubles, etc. <vi><it>good</it> and bad news</vi> <vi>They've been together in <it>good</it> times and bad.</vi> <vi>I had a <it>good</it> feeling about the meeting.</vi> <vi>Things are looking pretty <it>good</it> for the company right now.</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> omen</vi> <vi>I had the <it>good</it> luck/fortune to meet her when I was in New York.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>good luck</tag> at <dxt>luck</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:adequate or suitable <vi>It's a <it>good</it> day for a sail.</vi> <vi>We need to have a meeting. Is tomorrow <it>good</it> [=<it>convenient</it>] for you?</vi> <vi>He's a <it>good</it> person to contact if you're ever in trouble.</vi> <vi>I need tires that are <it>good</it> (for driving) in snow.</vi> <vi>These tires aren't <phrase>any good</phrase>. = These tires are <phrase>no good</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:sensible or reasonable <vi>She has a very <it>good</it> reason for being angry.</vi> <vi>He showed <it>good</it> judgment in buying a small car.</vi> <vi>She gave us some <it>good</it> advice.</vi> <vi>That's a very <it>good</it> question/point.</vi> <vi>She had the <it>good</it> sense to ask for help. [=she showed that she is able to think in a reasonable way by asking for help]</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> idea to arrive early.</vi> <vi>“We'd better arrive early.” “<it>Good</it> idea/thinking.”</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:producing or likely to produce a pleasant or favorable result <vi>a <it>good</it> deal/plan</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> risk/investment</vi> <vi>a lot of <it>good</it> marketing ideas</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> time to be investing in the stock market.</vi> <vi>Please accept our <it>best</it> wishes for your success.</vi> <vi>“The plane arrived on time.” “That's <it>good</it>.”</vi> <vi>Nothing <it>good</it> came of our efforts.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> thing (that) you answered so quickly. = It was <it>good</it> that you answered so quickly.</vi></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:having a desired quality <vi>We paid a <it>good</it> price [=a low price] for the tickets.</vi> <vi>The painting should fetch/bring a <it>good</it> price [=a high price] when it's sold.</vi> <vi>Did you get <it>good</it> [=<it>high</it>] grades in school?</vi> <vi>We found a <it>good</it> parking space near the restaurant.</vi> <vi>She has <it>good</it> taste in clothes. [=she likes clothes that are fashionable, of high quality, etc.]</vi></dt> <sn>g</sn> <dt>:expressing approval or praise <vi>a movie that has been getting <it>good</it> reviews</vi> <vi>I've heard a lot of <it>good</it> things about you.</vi></dt> <sn>h</sn> <dt><un>used in speech as a response <vi>“I'm ready to go when you are.” “<it>Good</it>. Let's get going.”</vi> <vi>“I passed the exam!” “(Very) <it>Good</it>!”</vi> <vi>“I passed the exam!” “<phrase>Good for you</phrase>!” = (<it>chiefly Australia</it>) “<phrase>Good on you</phrase>!” [=well done]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not marked or affected by injury or disease :<sx>healthy</sx> <vi>I went home early because I wasn't feeling too/very <it>good</it>. [=I wasn't feeling well; I was feeling sick]</vi> <vi>Her health is pretty <it>good</it>. = She's in pretty <it>good</it> health.</vi> <vi>The patient was reported to be in <it>good</it> condition following surgery.</vi> <vi>His hearing is still <it>good</it> but his eyesight is pretty poor/bad.</vi> <vi>my <it>good</it> arm/leg [=the arm/leg that is not injured or weak]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not causing harm or trouble :causing something desired <vi>a <it>good</it> [=<it>healthy, healthful</it>] diet</vi> <vi><it>good</it> nutrition</vi> <vi>You've been a <it>good</it> influence on the kids.</vi> <vi><it>good</it> habits</vi> <vi><phrase>good cholesterol</phrase> [=a type of cholesterol that helps prevent a disease that stops your blood from flowing easily]</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>Regular exercise is <it>good for</it> you. [=regular exercise makes you healthier]</vi> <vi>Hot soup is <it>good for</it> a cold. [=hot soup makes you feel better when you have a cold]</vi> <vi>Being with friends is especially <it>good for</it> him right now.</vi></un></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:not morally bad or wrong :morally proper or correct <vi>a <it>good</it> person</vi> <vi><it>good</it> conduct/behavior</vi> <vi>a woman/man of <it>good</it> character</vi> <vi>Like most people, she has a <it>good</it> side and a bad side.</vi> <vi>My intentions were <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>You did a <it>good</it> thing/deed when you helped that stranger.</vi> <vi>He lived a <it>good</it> life.</vi> <vi>It's hard to tell the <phrase>good guys</phrase> [=morally correct people/characters] from the bad guys in this movie.</vi> <vi>She is admired for her many <phrase>good works</phrase>. [=for the many things she does to help poor people, sick people, etc.]</vi> <vi>You should stay away from that guy. He's <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=he's a bad person]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good life</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:kind or helpful <vi>You've always been so <it>good</it> to me.</vi> <vi>It was <it>good</it> of you to answer my request so quickly.</vi> <un>sometimes used to formally make a request <vi><phrase>Would you be good enough</phrase> to show me the way? = <phrase>Would you be so good</phrase> as to show me the way? [=would you please show me the way?]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:behaving properly :not causing trouble <vi>a <it>good</it> dog</vi> <vi>The children were very <it>good</it> today.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:having or showing talent or skill :doing or able to do something well <vi>She's a very <it>good</it> golfer.</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> musician/doctor/cook</vi> <vi>He was really <it>good</it> in his last movie. [=he acted very well]</vi> <vi>I don't know if I'm <it>good</it> enough to make the team.</vi> <vi>I have a <it>good</it> memory. [=I am good at remembering things]</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> sense of direction [=an ability to find your way easily in a new place]</vi> <vi>an agent with a <phrase>good eye</phrase> for new talent [=an agent who is good at finding talented people who are not yet known or famous]</vi> <vi>It's a great school where you know your kids are <phrase>in good hands</phrase>. [=with people who are able to teach and take care of them well]</vi> <vi>I'm confident the café will be <it>in good hands</it> with you in charge.</vi> <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>She's very <it>good at</it> (playing) golf.</vi> <vi>He's not very/any <it>good at</it> expressing his feelings. = He's <phrase>no good at</phrase> expressing his feelings.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used in a joking way <vi>I'm very/really <it>good at</it> saying the wrong thing. [=I often say things that make people uncomfortable, unhappy, etc.]</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>no good</tag>, <tag>not any good</tag> at <dxt>good</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:able to use something or to deal with something or someone well <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>He's very <it>good with</it> his hands. [=he can easily make/do things with his hands]</vi> <vi>She's <it>good with</it> children. [=she manages and interacts with children well; children like her and behave well when they are with her]</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a tendency to do something <un>+ <it>about</it> <vi>He's <it>good about</it> writing everything down. [=he usually writes everything down]</vi> <vi>I'm trying to be <it>better about</it> exercising. [=I'm trying to exercise more often]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:happy or pleased <vi>I <phrase>feel good</phrase> about what happened. [=I'm pleased by what happened]</vi> <vi>She <it>felt good</it> that she had remembered his birthday. = She <it>felt good</it> about remembering his birthday.</vi> <vi>Helping other people makes me <it>feel good</it>.</vi> <vi>She didn't <it>feel good</it> about having to fire her secretary.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:cheerful or calm <vi>She's in a <it>good</it> mood. [=a happy mood]</vi> <vi>He has a <it>good</it> temper. [=he is good-tempered; he doesn't become angry easily]</vi> <vi>Everyone was in <it>good</it> spirits.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how long something will continue or be valid <vi>This offer is <it>good</it> only until the end of the month.</vi> <vi>This offer is <phrase>good for</phrase> the remainder of the month.</vi> <vi>Our old car should be <it>good for</it> a few more years. [=it should last a few more years; it should continue to operate for a few more years]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:still suitable to eat or drink :not spoiled <vi>Is the milk still <it>good</it> or has it gone bad?</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases like <phrase>good heavens</phrase> and <phrase>good God</phrase> to express surprise or anger or to make a statement or question more forceful <vi><it>Good heavens</it>! You startled me!</vi> <vi>“Do you agree with him?” “<it>Good God</it>, no!”</vi> <vi>(<it>somewhat old-fashioned</it>) <it>Good gracious</it>, I completely forgot!</vi></un> <dx>see also <tag>good grief</tag> at <dxt>grief</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:causing laughter :<sx>funny</sx> <vi>I heard a <it>good</it> joke the other day.</vi> <vi>“He says he's never met her.” “That's a <it>good</it> one. [=that's amusing because it isn't true] I saw them together last week.”</vi> <vi>She's always <phrase>good for a laugh</phrase>. [=she is always funny]</vi></dt> <sn>11 a</sn> <dt>:large in size, amount, or quantity <vi>The store has a <it>good</it> selection of products.</vi> <vi>She won the election by a <it>good</it> [=<it>considerable</it>] margin.</vi> <vi>He makes <it>good</it> money as a lawyer. = He makes a <it>good</it> living as a lawyer. [=he earns a lot of money]</vi> <vi>They couldn't have succeeded without <phrase>a good deal of</phrase> luck. [=a lot of luck]</vi> <vi>Things could be <phrase>a good deal</phrase> worse. [=things could be much worse]</vi> <vi>Tourists have been coming to the area <phrase>in good numbers</phrase>. [=many tourists have been coming to the area]</vi> <vi>an actress who has appeared in <phrase>a good number of</phrase> films [=in many films]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not less or fewer than a particular amount :at least <un>used in the phrase <phrase>a good</phrase> <vi>He weighs <it>a good</it> 200 pounds.</vi> <vi>We waited <it>a good</it> hour. [=we waited at least an hour]</vi> <vi>There are <it>a good</it> 80 people here.</vi></un></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:forceful or thorough <vi>If you give the machine a <it>good</it> kick, it might start working again.</vi> <vi>Give the bottle a <it>good</it> shake before you open it.</vi> <vi>Take a <it>good</it> look at this.</vi> <vi>You just need (to get) a <it>good</it> night's sleep.</vi> <vi>We were scared when it happened, but we had a <it>good</it> laugh about it later.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:having a high social position or status <vi>He comes from a <it>good</it> family.</vi> <vi>She thinks her son is too <it>good</it> for me.</vi> <vi>It's a <it>good</it> neighborhood.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <sn>a</sn> <dt><un>used to describe people who know each other well and care about each other very much <vi>She's a <it>good</it> [=<it>close</it>] friend of mine. = She and I are <it>good</it> friends.</vi> <vi>my <it>good</it> friend/pal/buddy Joe</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:showing true and constant support for someone <vi>He's been a <it>good</it> friend to me.</vi> <vi>I'm trying to be a <it>better</it> sister.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:belonging to and having loyalty to a group or organization <vi>a <it>good</it> party member</vi> <vi>a <it>good</it> Catholic</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>sports</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of a serve or shot</ssl> <dt>:landing in the proper area of the court in tennis and similar games <vi>I thought the ball/serve was <it>good</it> but my opponent said it was out.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a shot or kick</ssl> <dt>:successfully done <vi>(<it>basketball</it>) The first foul shot was <it>good</it>, but he missed the second one.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The field goal was <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>(<it>American football</it>) The field goal was <phrase>no good</phrase>. [=the field goal was missed]</vi></dt> <sn>16</sn> <slb>not used before a noun</slb> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:not wanting or needing anything more <vi>“Would you like more coffee?” “No, thanks. I'm <it>good</it>.”</vi> <vi>“Here's the money I owed you. So we're <it>good</it> now, right?” “Yeah, we're <it>good</it>.” [=we have settled our business; there is no longer any problem between us]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all in good time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>all well and good</dre> <dx>see <dxt>well</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as good as</dre> <def><dt>:almost or nearly <vi>The plan is <it>as good as</it> dead.</vi> <vi>Those people <it>as good as</it> ruined the school with their foolish ideas!</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>(as) good as gold</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gold</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>as good as it gets</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to say that nothing better is possible or available <vi>It's not a great restaurant, but in this part of the city, it's <it>as good as it gets</it>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to say that something is very good and cannot be improved <vi>There's nothing I enjoy more than spending time at home with my family. That's <it>as good as it gets</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as good as new</dre> <dx>see <dxt>new</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>fight the good fight</dre> <dx>see <dxt>fight</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>for good measure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>measure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give as good as you get</dre> <dx>see <dxt>give</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good and</dre> <sound><wav>good0005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌgʊdn̩</pr> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <vi>I hit him <it>good and</it> hard.</vi> <vi>He was <it>good and</it> angry.</vi> <vi>I like my coffee <it>good and</it> hot.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:completely or entirely <vi>We'll leave when I'm <it>good and</it> ready.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good egg</dre> <dx>see <dxt>egg</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good for</dre> <def><sl>somewhat informal</sl> <dt>:able to provide or produce (something) <vi>I'm <it>good for</it> a hundred dollars if you need a loan.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>good <dxn>4b, 8a (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good for it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:able to pay back a loan <vi>Why won't you lend me the money? You know I'm <it>good for it</it>. [=you can trust me to pay it back]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good graces</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good old</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used before a noun to describe a familiar person or thing with affection or approval <vi><it>Good old</it> John: you can always count on him to help.</vi> <vi>I don't need fancy shoes. I prefer <it>good old</it> sneakers.</vi> <vi>They were talking about <phrase>the good old days</phrase>. [=happy times in the past]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>good old boy</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good riddance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>riddance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>good to go</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:ready to leave or to start doing something <vi>We have all the tools and supplies we need, so we're <it>good to go</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>good word</dre> <dx>see <dxt>word</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have it good</dre> <def><dt>:to be in a favorable position or situation <vi>There's no reason for her to be so unhappy. She really <it>has it</it> (pretty) <it>good</it>.</vi> <vi>He's <phrase>never had it so good</phrase>. [=he has never been in such a favorable situation]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have the good grace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>hold good</dre> <def><dt>:to be true <vi>The advice she gave us 10 years ago still <it>holds good</it> [=(more commonly) <it>holds true</it>] today.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>if you know what's good for you</dre> <def><dt>:if you want to avoid trouble, problems, etc. <vi>You'll take my advice <it>if you know what's good for you</it>.</vi> <vi>She'll forget about the whole thing <it>if she knows what's good for her</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in good company</dre> <dx>see <dxt>company</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>in good part</dre> <dx>see <dxt>part</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make good</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become successful <vi>It's a story about a kid from a small town trying to <it>make good</it> in the big city.</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>make good your escape</phrase>, you escape successfully. <vi>The prisoners dug a tunnel under the fence and <it>made good their escape</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do something that you have promised or threatened to do <vi>He <it>made good</it> his promise.</vi> <un>usually + <it>on</it> in U.S. English <vi>He <it>made good on</it> his promise.</vi> <vi>They <it>made good on</it> their threat and forced the company to go out of business.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to pay for (something) <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>The insurance company was required to <it>make good on</it> the loss.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to repair (something) <vi>The contract obliges you to <it>make good</it> any damaged windows.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>so far, so good</dre> <dx>see <dxt>far</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>too good to be true</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something cannot be as good as it seems to be <vi>The price of the car is <it>too good to be true</it>. There must be something wrong with it.</vi> <vi>If it looks/seems <it>too good to be true</it>, it probably is. [=there is probably some cost or bad part you do not know about]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>very good</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt><un>used as a response to say you will do something that you have been told or asked to do <vi>“Show the ambassador in.” “<it>Very good</it>, sir.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what's good for the goose is good for the gander</dre> <dx>see <dxt>goose</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>with (a) good grace</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grace</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="keep[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">keep</hw> <sound><wav>keep0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈki:p</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>keeps</if></in> <in><if>kept</if> <sound><wav>kept0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɛpt</pr></in> <in><if>keep*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to continue having or holding (something) :to not return, lose, sell, give away, or throw away (something) <vi>She's going to <it>keep</it> the money she found.</vi> <vi>I can't decide whether to sell my old car or <it>keep</it> it for another year.</vi> <vi>While the company laid off some employees, others had hopes of <it>keeping</it> their jobs.</vi> <vi>The shirt will <it>keep</it> [=<it>retain</it>] its shape after many washings.</vi> <vi>an actress who has <it>kept</it> her looks/beauty [=continued to be attractive/beautiful] as she has grown older</vi> <vi>“The fare is $4.” “Here's $5. <phrase>Keep the change</phrase>.”</vi> <vi>He struggled to <phrase>keep his cool/composure</phrase>. [=to remain calm; to not become upset or angry]</vi> <vi>He vowed to <phrase>keep his silence</phrase> about what he had seen. [=to not tell anyone about what he had seen]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to continue in a specified state, condition, or position <vi>I asked them to <it>keep</it> quiet.</vi> <vi><it>keep</it> still/warm</vi> <vi>He vowed to <it>keep</it> silent about what he had seen. [=to not tell anyone about what he had seen]</vi> <vi>She likes to <it>keep</it> [=<it>stay</it>] busy.</vi> <vi>The program teaches kids how to <it>keep</it> safe near water.</vi> <vi>Have you <phrase>kept in touch</phrase> with your college roommate? [=have you continued to talk to or write to your college roommate?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to continue in a specified state, condition, or position <vi>I tried to <it>keep</it> the children quiet during the ceremony.</vi> <vi>The local newspaper <it>keeps</it> people informed about what's happening in town.</vi> <vi>The article offers tips on how to <it>keep</it> kids safe near water.</vi> <vi>The movie will <it>keep</it> you on the edge of your seat.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>keep</it> costs under control.</vi> <vi>This scarf will help <it>keep</it> you warm.</vi> <vi>She <it>keeps</it> herself fit by jogging.</vi> <vi>He <it>kept</it> his hands behind his back while we were talking.</vi> <vi><it>Keep</it> both hands on the steering wheel.</vi> <vi>It was so cold inside that I <it>kept</it> my coat on.</vi> <vi>I promise I'll <it>keep</it> your decision a secret. [=I will not tell anyone your decision]</vi> <vi><it>Keep</it> the mixture chilled until you are ready to serve it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to cause or force (someone) to stay in a place <vi>I won't <it>keep</it> you (here) much longer.</vi> <vi>The doctors want to <it>keep</it> me in (the hospital) for further tests.</vi> <vi>If you're in a hurry, don't let me <it>keep</it> you.</vi> <vi><it>keep</it> a prisoner in jail</vi> <vi>She <it>kept</it> the children in the house during the storm.</vi> <vi>There was nothing to <it>keep</it> me in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be late <vi>You're late. <phrase>What kept you</phrase>? [=what delayed you?; why are you late?]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do (something) continuously or again and again <un>+ <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>The teacher asked them to be quiet, but they just <it>kept talking</it>.</vi> <vi>The rain <it>kept falling</it> all afternoon.</vi> <vi>The dog <it>keeps running</it> away.</vi> <vi><it>Keep walking/driving</it> until you come to a traffic light.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>The band's music just <it>keeps on getting</it> better (and better).</vi> <vi>I'll never get this work done if you <it>keep on interrupting</it> me.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to cause (someone or something) to do something continuously or again and again <un>+ <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>She has a desire for success that <it>keeps</it> her <it>striving</it> to do better.</vi> <vi>His boss <it>kept</it> him <it>waiting</it> [=forced him to wait] for over an hour.</vi> <vi>They want to <it>keep</it> the company <it>growing</it>.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>keep going <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>She always <it>keeps</it> her promises/word. [=she always does what she promises to do; she always does what she says she will do]</vi> <vi>He failed to <it>keep</it> his appointment. [=he did not go to his appointment; he missed his appointment]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to not tell (a secret) <vi>I can <it>keep</it> a secret.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>poorly kept</phrase> secret [=a secret that has been told to many people]</vi> <vi>a <phrase>well-kept</phrase> secret [=a secret that has not been told to people]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to act properly in relation to (something) <vi>He <it>keeps</it> [=<it>observes</it>] the Sabbath.</vi> <vi>They <it>keep</it> kosher.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to store (something) in a specified place <vi>They <it>keep</it> the ketchup in the refrigerator.</vi> <vi>I <it>keep</it> my socks in a drawer.</vi> <vi>The sheets are <it>kept</it> in the closet.</vi> <vi>He <it>keeps</it> his wallet in his back pocket.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have or hold (something) for later use instead of using it now <vi>We'll eat some of the cookies now and <it>keep</it> [=<it>save</it>] some for later.</vi> <vi>I'll <it>keep</it> my news until later. [=I'll tell you my news later]</vi> <vi>(<it>Brit</it>) Would you <it>keep</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>save</it>] a seat for me?</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:to continue to be in a good condition <vi>Carrots and potatoes <it>keep</it> well.</vi> <vi>The meat will <it>keep</it> in the freezer for several months.</vi> <un>sometimes used figuratively <vi>I have something to tell you, but it will <it>keep</it>. [=I can tell you later]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to protect (someone) <vi>May the Lord bless you and <it>keep</it> you.</vi> <un>usually + <it>from</it> <vi>May the Lord <it>keep</it> you <it>from</it> harm.</vi></un></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to produce (something, such as a journal or record) by putting information in a book, document, etc., over a period of time <vi>She <it>kept</it> a diary/journal.</vi> <vi>He <it>keeps</it> a detailed record of all his purchases.</vi> <vi>She <it>keeps</it> a list of books for future reading.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take care of (something) <vi><it>keep</it> [=<it>tend</it>] a garden</vi> <vi>We <it>kept</it> chickens and goats when I was a child.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to operate (something, such as a business) :<sx>manage</sx> <vi>They <it>keep</it> [=(more commonly) <it>run</it>] a bed-and-breakfast.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) <it>keep</it> a shop</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to have (something) available for use <vi>He <it>keeps</it> a car even though he lives in the city.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a continuing sexual relationship with (someone who is not your husband or wife) <vi>a married man who <it>keeps</it> a mistress</vi> <vi>She never married but she <it>kept</it> a lover for years.</vi> <vi>a <phrase>kept man/woman</phrase> [=a man/woman who is kept as a lover by someone]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>How are you keeping?</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt><un>used to ask if someone feels good, bad, happy, well, etc. <vi>“<it>How are you keeping</it> [=<it>how are you doing</it>], Jill?” “Oh, pretty well, thanks.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to tell (someone) again and again to do something <vi>My kids <it>kept after</it> me to quit smoking, so I finally did.</vi> <vi>I wasn't going to audition, but my friends <it>kept after</it> me.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) after</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to require (a student) to stay at school after classes have ended <vi>The teacher <it>kept</it> him <it>after</it> (school) for misbehaving in class.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue doing or trying to do something <vi>If you <it>keep at it</it> long enough you'll succeed.</vi> <vi>The project was difficult, but we <it>kept at it</it> and eventually it was done.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to force or cause (someone) to continue doing something <vi>The coach <it>kept</it> us (hard) <it>at it</it> until late afternoon.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not go near something <vi>The police asked the spectators to <it>keep back</it>. [=<it>stay back</it>]</vi> <vi>The guide told us to <it>keep back</it> from the edge of the cliff.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep back (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not allow (someone) to go near something <vi>The police <it>kept</it> the spectators <it>back</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to not allow (a student) to advance to the next grade level <un>usually used as <it>(be) kept back</it> <vi>Students who fail the exam may <it>be kept back</it> a year.</vi></un></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to require (a student) to stay at school after classes have ended <vi>She was <it>kept back</it> [=(<it>US</it>) <it>kept after</it>, <it>kept after school</it>] for talking in class.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) back</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep back (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not allow (something) to appear or be known <vi>He struggled to <it>keep back</it> his tears. [=he tried hard not to cry]</vi> <vi>The government <it>kept back</it> [=<it>withheld</it>] some crucial information from the media.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep company</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep company with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to spend time with (someone) <un>usually used figuratively <vi>In her garden, roses <it>keep company with</it> lilies.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) company</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to spend time with (someone who would be alone if you were not there) <vi>I'll <it>keep you company</it> while you wait for the train.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to stay close to the ground or floor <vi>The soldiers were ordered to <it>keep down</it>. [=<it>stay down</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) down</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prevent (someone) from succeeding, winning, etc. <vi>You can't <it>keep</it> a good man <it>down</it>. [=you can't prevent a good or talented person from succeeding]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) down</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep down (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to prevent (something) from increasing or rising <vi>The company is trying to <it>keep down</it> costs/expenses/prices.</vi> <vi>She watered the path to <it>keep</it> the dust <it>down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prevent (something) from coming up from your stomach and into your mouth again <vi>He was so ill that he could only <it>keep down</it> a small amount of food.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep it down</pva></phrasev> <dt><un>used to ask someone to be quiet <vi>Please <it>keep it down</it> in there. I'm trying to study.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep from</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep from (doing something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep (someone or something) from (doing something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not do or experience (something) :to prevent or stop (someone or something) from doing or experiencing (something) <vi>She found it hard to <it>keep from</it> laughing. [=she found it hard not to laugh]</vi> <vi>She's been trying to <it>keep</it> herself <it>from</it> eating too much candy.</vi> <vi>An umbrella will <it>keep</it> you <it>from</it> getting wet.</vi> <vi>It's difficult to <it>keep from</it> feeling worried about this situation.</vi> <vi>He was anxious to <it>keep</it> his son <it>from</it> getting into trouble.</vi> <vi>Her happy nature <it>kept</it> her <it>from</it> worrying.</vi> <vi>I don't want to <it>keep</it> you <it>from</it> (doing) your work. = I don't want to <it>keep</it> you <it>from</it> working.</vi> <vi>She tied the knot tightly to <it>keep</it> it <it>from</it> loosening.</vi> <vi>The company has taken steps to <it>keep</it> the building <it>from</it> being broken into again.</vi> <vi>It was hard to <it>keep from</it> [=<it>avoid</it>] confusing the twins.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) from (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not tell (something) to (someone) <vi>What information are you <it>keeping from</it> me? [=what information are you not telling me?]</vi> <vi>They think the government is <it>keeping</it> [=<it>withholding</it>] the truth <it>from</it> us.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep going</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue moving forward <vi>He walked right past me and just <it>kept going</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to continue doing something <vi>I was ready to give up on the search, but they convinced me to <it>keep going</it>. [=to continue searching]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) going</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make (someone) able to continue doing something at a difficult time <vi>I don't know what <it>keeps her going</it> after all these years.</vi> <vi>Their grandson is the only thing <it>keeping them going</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) going</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to cause (something) to continue to exist or function <vi>They tried everything they could think of to <it>keep</it> the business <it>going</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>kept</it> the conversation <it>going</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep house</dre> <dx>see <dxt>house</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) in</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not show or express (something, such as an emotion) <vi>You shouldn't <it>keep</it> your anger <it>in</it> all the time.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) in (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to provide (someone) with (something needed or wanted) <vi>It's very expensive <it>keeping</it> my children <it>in</it> clothes that fit.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to remain friendly with (someone) <vi>She's always <it>kept in with</it> the people with power.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep off (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep (someone or something) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop or prevent (someone or something) from being on (something) <vi><it>Keep</it> [=<it>stay</it>] <it>off</it> the grass. [=do not walk on the grass]</vi> <vi>Please <it>keep</it> the dog <it>off</it> the sofa.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (weight) off</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to weigh a lower amount than you formerly weighed :to not regain weight that you have lost <vi>She has managed to <it>keep</it> (most of) the weight <it>off</it> for two years.</vi> <vi>Losing weight is not as hard as <it>keeping</it> it <it>off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not talk about (something) <vi>I think we'd better <it>keep off</it> [=<it>avoid</it>] the subject of the war.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) off (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prevent (someone) from talking about (something) <vi>We tried to <it>keep</it> them <it>off</it> (the subject of) the war.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to continue happening, doing something, working, etc. <vi>The rain <it>kept on</it> [=<it>kept up</it>] throughout the day.</vi> <vi>He talked and talked. At one point I thought he would <it>keep on</it> all night.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) on</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to continue to have (someone) as an employee <vi>The chef was <it>kept on</it> even after the restaurant was sold.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say the same thing to (someone) again and again in a way that is annoying <vi>My parents <it>kept on at me</it> to go back to college.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to not enter a place <vi>The sign on the door said “<it>Keep out</it>!”</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep out of (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to not enter (a place) <vi>We were told to <it>keep out of</it> his office.</vi> <vi>Please <it>keep</it> [=<it>stay</it>] <it>out of</it> the way.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to not become involved in (something) <vi>This argument doesn't involve you, so you should just <it>keep</it> [=<it>stay</it>] <it>out of</it> it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep out (someone or something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep (someone or something) out (of a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stop or prevent (someone or something) from entering (a place) <vi>The curtains help <it>keep out</it> the drafts.</vi> <vi><it>Keep</it> the cat <it>out</it> of the bedroom.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep pace with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>pace</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep score</dre> <dx>see <dxt>score</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep tabs on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>tab</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep the faith</dre> <dx>see <dxt>faith</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep time</dre> <dx>see <dxt>time</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep to (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to stay in or on (something) :to not leave (something) <vi>He <it>kept to</it> the house most of the time.</vi> <vi>She <it>keeps to</it> the main roads when she travels.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to not go beyond (something) <vi>He tried to <it>keep</it> [=<it>stick</it>] <it>to</it> his budget.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to act or behave in the way required by (something) <vi><it>keep to</it> [=<it>abide by, obey</it>] the rules of the game</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to not move away from or change (something) <vi>I wish you'd just <it>keep to</it> [=<it>stick to</it>] the point.</vi> <vi>They <it>kept to</it> their story.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep to yourself</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <svr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>keep yourself to yourself</va></svr> <dt>:to stay apart from other people :to avoid other people <vi>She was a shy girl who <it>kept</it> pretty much <it>to herself</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) to yourself</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to keep (something) secret <vi>He knew what the facts were but <it>kept them to himself</it>. [=he did not tell anyone what the facts were]</vi> <vi>She likes to <it>keep things to herself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep track</dre> <dx>see <dxt>track</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to go or make progress at the same rate as others :to stay even with others in a race, competition, etc. <vi>The leader began to run faster, and the other runners found it hard to <it>keep up</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>The other runners struggled to <it>keep up with</it> the leader.</vi> <vi>He found it difficult to <it>keep up with</it> the rest of the class.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to continue to know the newest information about something <vi>There is so much happening in the world now that I find it hard to <it>keep up</it>. [=stay informed]</vi> <vi>I find it hard to <it>keep up</it> on/with the news.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to continue happening <vi>The rain <it>kept up</it> all night.</vi> <vi>The gunfire <it>kept up</it> for a long time.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep up with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to continue to talk to or write to (someone) <vi>She still <it>keeps up with</it> [=<it>keeps in touch with</it>] her old friends from college.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (someone) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to prevent (someone) from sleeping <vi>I hope our party didn't <it>keep</it> you <it>up</it> all night!</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>keep (something) up</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>keep up (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to continue doing (something) <vi><it>Keep up</it> the good work.</vi> <vi><it>Keep</it> that <it>up</it> and you'll get into trouble!</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to prevent (something) from getting worse, weaker, etc. <vi>We need to <it>keep</it> standards <it>up</it>.</vi> <vi><it>Keep</it> your spirits <it>up</it>!</vi> <vi>The house had been <it>kept up</it> [=<it>maintained</it>] nicely.</vi> <vi>You need to exercise more to <it>keep</it> your strength <it>up</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>keep up your end</phrase> of something (such as a bargain or agreement) you do what you have promised or agreed to do. <vi>I'm never sure if she will <it>keep up her end</it> of the deal.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>keep up appearances</dre> <dx>see <dxt>appearance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep up with the Joneses</dre> <dx>see <dxt>joneses</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your chin up</dre> <dx>see <dxt>chin</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your distance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>distance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>keep your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

	<entry id="part[2]"> <hw hindex="2">part</hw> <altpr>ˈpɑɚt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>parts</if></in> <in><if>part*ed</if></in> <in><if>part*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to separate into two or more parts that move away from each other <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The crowd <it>parted</it> to let the president through.</vi> <vi>The rain stopped and the clouds <it>parted</it>.</vi> <vi>The big red curtains <it>parted</it> to reveal a new car!</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The Bible tells the story of how God <it>parted</it> the Red Sea.</vi> <vi>She closed her eyes and <it>parted</it> her lips.</vi> <vi>Her lips were <it>parted</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to separate (the hair on a person's head) into two parts on each side of a line by using a comb <vi>She <it>parts</it> her hair on the side.</vi> <vi>His dark hair was <it>parted</it> down/in the middle.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to leave each other <vi>The two lovers <it>parted</it> at dawn.</vi> <vi>Tomorrow we shall <it>part</it> and, I fear, never see each other again.</vi> :to go or move away <it>from</it> someone <vi>She couldn't bear the thought of <it>parting from</it> her family.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to be separated <it>from</it> someone <un>usually used as <it>(be) parted</it> <vi>She couldn't bear to <it>be parted from</it> her family.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>somewhat formal</ssl> <dt>:to end a relationship <vi>The band <it>parted</it> after 10 successful years of performing together.</vi> <vi>We <it>parted</it> on friendly terms.</vi> <vi>The couple <it>parted</it> [=<it>separated</it>] in the summer of 2005.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>By that time, he had already <it>parted from</it> his first wife.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>part company</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to end a relationship <vi>There are rumors that the football team and its coach have <it>parted company</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I <it>parted company with</it> my business partners after a dispute about finances.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to leave each other <vi>Much has happened since we <it>parted company</it>.</vi> <vi>The two friends <it>parted company</it> in the parking lot and drove home separately.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to disagree with someone about something <vi>The president and I <it>part company</it> on some important issues.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I don't believe in the death penalty, so I'm afraid I must <it>part company with</it> you there. [=I do not agree with you about that]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>part ways</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to end a relationship <vi>The band <it>parted ways</it> after releasing their third album.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>She has since <it>parted ways with</it> the organization.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to leave each other <vi>We said our goodbyes and <it>parted ways</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to disagree with someone about something <vi>We <it>part ways</it> on that issue.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>part with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>part with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to give up possession or control of (something) <vi>He hated to <it>part with</it> that old car.</vi> <vi><it>parting with</it> a large amount of money</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="present[3]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="3">pres*ent</hw> <sound><wav>presen04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈprɛzn̩t</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:not past or future :existing or happening now <vi>the <it>present</it> [=<it>current</it>] situation</vi> <vi>No further changes are planned <phrase>at the present time</phrase>. [=<it>now</it>]</vi> <vi>The game has existed in its <phrase>present form</phrase> for more than 300 years.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say what someone or something is now <vi>the company's <it>present</it> [=(more commonly) <it>current</it>] employees</vi> <vi>the <it>present</it> leadership of the Senate [=the people who have positions of power in the Senate now]</vi> <vi>The ceremony honors our soldiers, <phrase>past and present</phrase>. [=people who were soldiers in the past and people who are soldiers now]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:at the particular place or event that is being referred to <un>often + <it>at</it> <vi>She was <it>present at</it> the meeting.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>There was a large crowd <it>present in</it> the auditorium.</vi></un> <un>sometimes used as an interjection <vi>“John Smith?” “<it>Present</it>!” [=<it>here</it>]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:existing in something <un>usually + <it>in</it> <vi>There were high levels of lead <it>present in</it> the water. [=the water contained high levels of lead]</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>all present and accounted for</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>all present and correct</va></vr> <def><dt><un>used to say that all the people who are supposed to be at a place or event are there <vi>The students are <phrase>all present and accounted for</phrase>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>present company excepted/excluded</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that a critical comment you have made about a group of people does not include the person or people you are with <vi>Men are such jerks—<it>present company excepted/excluded</it>, of course.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>present writer</dre> <def><sl>somewhat formal</sl> <dt><un>used to refer to yourself as the person who is writing something <vi>No one—<it>present writer</it> included—thought the plan would work. [=no one, including me, thought the plan would work]</vi> <vi>She is promoting her latest movie, which <phrase>the present writer</phrase> has not yet seen. [=which I have not yet seen]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
