<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="comparison"> <hw highlight="yes">com*par*i*son</hw> <sound><wav>compar11.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəmˈperəsən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*par*i*sons</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act of looking at things to see how they are similar or different <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a <it>comparison</it> of the data from the two studies</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a wine that <phrase>stands/bears comparison</phrase> with [=it is as good as] wines that are much more expensive</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of suggesting that two or more things are similar or in the same category <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>the <it>comparison</it> of monkeys to humans</vi> <vi>I don't think <it>comparisons</it> of her situation and/with mine are appropriate.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>His poetry <phrase>evokes/invites comparison with</phrase> [=it is similar to] the work of Robert Frost.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by/in comparison</dre> <def><dt>:when compared with another :when looked at or thought about in relation to someone or something else <vi>Yesterday's weather was very cold. Today's weather is mild <it>by comparison</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>He's a well-behaved child <it>in comparison with</it> his brother.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>draw a comparison</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>draw comparisons</va></vr> <def><dt>:to say that two or more things or people are similar <vi>The brochure <it>draws a comparison</it> between the hotel and a medieval palace.</vi> <vi>The writer <it>draws</it> unflattering <it>comparisons</it> between the mayor and a dictator.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a comparison</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>make comparisons</va></vr> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to say that two or more things or people are similar <vi>His work has been widely praised. <it>Comparisons have been made</it> to the great painters of past centuries.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to look at similarities and differences between two or more things or people <vi>The Web site allows consumers to <it>make</it> direct <it>comparisons</it> between competing products.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no comparison</dre> <def><dt><un>used to suggest that two or more things are very different <vi>There's really <it>no comparison</it> between the two models. [=one is much better than the other]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="comparison shop"> <hw>comparison shop</hw> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>⁓ shops</if></in> <in><if>⁓ shopped</if></in> <in><if>⁓ shopping</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <dt>:to compare items while shopping in order to see which one is the best or has the lowest price <vi>The Internet allows consumers to <it>comparison shop</it> with ease.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>comparison shopper</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <gram>count</gram></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
