<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="competition"> <hw highlight="yes">com*pe*ti*tion</hw> <sound><wav>compet05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkɑ:mpəˈtɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>com*pe*ti*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act or process of trying to get or win something (such as a prize or a higher level of success) that someone else is also trying to get or win :the act or process of competing <vi>The school fosters an atmosphere of <it>competition</it> rather than cooperation. [=it encourages students to compete against each other instead of work together]</vi> <vi>There will be intense/fierce <it>competition</it> for the top spots. [=many people will be trying to get the top spots]</vi> <vi>These products are <phrase>in competition</phrase> with each other. [=these products are competing with each other]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:actions that are done by people, companies, etc., that are competing against each other <vi>Prices are lower when there is <it>competition</it> among/between the stores.</vi> <un>often + <it>from</it> <vi>The industry has been affected by <it>competition from</it> new technologies.</vi> <vi>We're up against some stiff/tough <it>competition from</it> our rivals.</vi> <vi>Downtown stores are looking for new ways to attract customers in the face of <it>competition from</it> the stores at the mall.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <bnote>the competition</bnote> <dt>:a person or group that you are trying to succeed against :a person or group that you are competing with <vi>He sized up <it>the competition</it>. [=looked at who he was competing against]</vi> <vi>Don't let <it>the competition</it> know our trade secrets.</vi> <snote>Someone or something that <phrase>has no competition</phrase> is much better than others. <vi>In my opinion, this restaurant <it>has no competition</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a contest in which people try to win by being better, faster, etc., than others :an event in which people compete <vi>They had/held/staged a <it>competition</it> to see who could sell the most lemonade.</vi> <vi>a gymnastics/dance/talent <it>competition</it></vi> <vi>She won/lost the <it>competition</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
