<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="concentration"> <hw highlight="yes">con*cen*tra*tion</hw> <sound><wav>concen06.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌkɑ:nsənˈtreɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the ability to give your attention or thought to a single object or activity :the ability to concentrate <vi>the power of <it>concentration</it></vi> <vi>All that noise is disturbing my <it>concentration</it>.</vi> <vi>The job required her full <it>concentration</it>.</vi> <vi>When you're tired it's easy to lose your <it>concentration</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the act of giving your attention to a single object or activity <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>There was a <it>concentration</it> on ethics within the agency.</vi> <vi>His <it>concentration</it> [=<it>focus</it>] was on gathering evidence for the trial.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>a student who chose law as his field/area of <it>concentration</it> [=his main area of study]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a large amount of something in one place <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>There is a <it>concentration</it> of wealth in the cities.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He objects to the <it>concentration</it> of power in the hands of a few rich men.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a large number of people in one place <vi>Officials are expecting a heavy/high <it>concentration</it> of tourists [=are expecting many tourists] for the festival.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the amount of an ingredient in a mixture <vi>Contaminants were found in low <it>concentrations</it>. [=<it>amounts</it>]</vi> <vi>measuring the <it>concentration</it> of salt in a solution</vi> <vi>They detected high <it>concentrations</it> of pollutants in the water.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="concentration camp"> <hw>concentration camp</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ camps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a type of prison where large numbers of people who are not soldiers are kept during a war and are usually forced to live in very bad conditions</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
