<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="concern[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*cern</hw> <sound><wav>concer01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈsɚn</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*cerns</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a feeling of worry usually shared by many people <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They have expressed/voiced <it>concern</it> about the cost of the project.</vi> <vi>There is much/great <it>concern</it> among voters about/over the economy. = The economy is a matter of much/great <it>concern</it> to/for many voters.</vi> <vi>There is some <it>concern</it> that the economy might worsen.</vi> <vi>I share your <it>concern</it> about these problems.</vi> <vi>Their friend's health is a constant source/cause of <it>concern</it>.</vi> <vi>There is no <phrase>cause for concern</phrase>. [=there is no reason to worry]</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The governor needs to address voters' <it>concerns</it> about/over the economy.</vi> <vi>They have raised <it>concerns</it> about the cost of the project.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that causes people to worry <vi>The economy is one of our main <it>concerns</it>. [=the economy is one of the things that we are most worried/concerned about]</vi> <vi>Their friend's health is a constant <it>concern</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a feeling of being interested in and caring about a person or thing <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>His <it>concern</it> with/for the well-being of his family is obvious.</vi> <vi>She has always shown genuine/deep <it>concern</it> for the poor.</vi> <vi>I appreciate your <it>concern</it>, but there's really nothing you can do to help.</vi> <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>She has always shown a genuine/deep <it>concern</it> for the poor.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that is regarded as important <vi>She articulated the major <it>concerns</it> of the administration.</vi> <vi>Our main/primary/principal <it>concern</it> is to assure that these problems do not occur again.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that a person is responsible for or involved in <un>usually singular <vi>Paying for the tickets is your <it>concern</it> [=<it>responsibility</it>], not mine.</vi> <vi>It's <phrase>not our concern</phrase>. = It's <phrase>none of our concern</phrase>. = It's <phrase>no concern of ours</phrase>. [=it's not our business; it doesn't involve/concern us]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:a business or company <vi>a banking <it>concern</it></vi> <vi>a <phrase>going concern</phrase> [=a successful business]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="concern[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">concern</hw> <altpr>kənˈsɚn</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>concerns</if></in> <in><if>concerned</if></in> <in><if>concern*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to relate to (something or someone) :to be about (something or someone) <vi>The novel <it>concerns</it> three soldiers.</vi> <vi>This study <it>concerns</it> the noise levels in cities.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to affect or involve (someone) :to be the business or interest of (someone) <vi>The problem <it>concerns</it> [=<it>affects</it>] us all.</vi> <vi>This conversation doesn't <it>concern</it> you.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>To whom it may concern</phrase> is used at the beginning of a formal letter (such as a letter written to a company) when the name of the person who will read the letter is not known.</snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) worried :to cause concern for (someone) <vi>Our mother's illness <it>concerns</it> us.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>concern yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to become involved or interested in something :to give your attention to something <vi>She can handle the problem alone. There's no need for you to <it>concern yourself</it>.</vi> <vi>There's no need for you to <it>concern yourself</it> with/in her problem.</vi> <vi>They shouldn't <it>concern themselves</it> with/about small details.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="going concern"> <hw>going concern</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -cerns</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a business that is making a profit <vi>They had a difficult start, but they've turned the restaurant into a <it>going concern</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="whom"> <hw highlight="yes">whom</hw> <sound><wav>whom0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈhu:m</pr> <fl>pronoun</fl> <cx><cl>objective case of</cl> <ct>who</ct></cx> <def><dt><un>used in formal writing or speech <vi>To <it>whom</it> am I speaking?</vi> <vi>His brother, with <it>whom</it> he is very close, works for the same company.</vi> <vi>I was introduced to the artist, <it>whom</it> I was anxious to meet.</vi> <vi>an author <it>whom</it> I had never heard of</vi></un></dt> <usage><it>Whom</it> is a more formal word than <it>who</it> and is not commonly used in ordinary speech and writing, where it can seem awkward and unnatural. <vi>(<it>formal</it>) To <it>whom</it> did you speak? = (<it>formal</it>) <it>Whom</it> did you speak to? = (more commonly) <it>Who</it> did you speak to?</vi> <vi>(<it>formal</it>) We weren't sure <it>whom</it> to hire. = (more commonly) We weren't sure <it>who</it> to hire.</vi> <vi>(<it>formal</it>) The person to <it>whom</it> we spoke to was very helpful. = (<it>formal</it>) The person <it>whom</it> we spoke to was very helpful. = (more commonly) The person <it>who/that</it> we spoke to was very helpful.</vi> <vi>(<it>formal</it>) Her brother, <it>whom</it> I met last year, is an attorney. = (more commonly) Her brother, <it>who</it> I met last year, is an attorney.</vi></usage></def> <dro><dre>to whom it may concern</dre> <dx>see <dxt>concern</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
