<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="concentrate[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*cen*trate</hw> <sound><wav>concen03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:nsənˌtreɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*cen*trates</if></in> <in><if>con*cen*trat*ed</if></in> <in><if>con*cen*trat*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to think about something :to give your attention to the thing you are doing, reading, etc. <vi>All that noise makes it hard to <it>concentrate</it>.</vi> <vi>The student has difficulty <it>concentrating</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>All that noise makes it hard to <it>concentrate on</it> the book I'm trying to read.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>concentrate</it> [=<it>focus</it>] <it>on</it> this problem.</vi> <vi>We need to <it>concentrate on</it> finding ways to work more efficiently.</vi> <vi>He thought about becoming a lawyer, but he has decided to <it>concentrate on</it> a medical career instead. [=he has decided to direct his efforts toward a medical career instead]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (attention, efforts, strength, etc.) to be used or directed for a single purpose <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>She is <it>concentrating</it> her attention <it>on</it> her studies. [=she is giving her attention to her studies]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>concentrate</it> our efforts <it>on</it> finding ways to work more efficiently.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (something, such as a liquid) stronger by removing water <vi><it>concentrate</it> syrup</vi> <vi>The sauce should be simmered for a few minutes to <it>concentrate</it> its flavors.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>concentrate the/your mind</dre> <def><dt><snote>Something that <it>concentrates the/your mind</it> makes you think very clearly. <vi>Working under a tight deadline can <it>concentrate the mind</it> wonderfully.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="concentrate[2]"> <hw hindex="2">concentrate</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:nsənˌtreɪt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>concentrates</if></in> <def><dt>:a substance that is made stronger or more pure by removing water <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>a frozen orange juice <it>concentrate</it></vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Is this orange juice fresh or is it made from <it>concentrate</it>?</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="mind[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">mind</hw> <sound><wav>mind0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈmaɪnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>minds</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:the part of a person that thinks, reasons, feels, and remembers <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>He read great literature to develop/cultivate his <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>It's important to keep your <it>mind</it> active as you grow older.</vi> <vi>He went for a walk to help clear his <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>the mysteries of the human <it>mind</it></vi> <vi>My <it>mind</it> is always open to new ideas.</vi> <vi>You can't argue with him. His <it>mind</it> is closed.</vi> <vi>I can't concentrate: my <it>mind</it> is always wandering and I can't keep it focused on anything.</vi> <vi>Let me get this clear/straight in my <it>mind</it> [=let me understand this clearly]: are you saying that she was lying to me all along?</vi> <vi>I can't get that image out of my <it>mind</it>. = I can't stop seeing that image in my <it>mind</it>. = That image is stuck in my <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>The smell of pine sends my <it>mind</it> back to childhood.</vi> <vi>The sound of her voice jerked my <it>mind</it> back to the present.</vi> <vi>My <it>mind</it> tells me it can't work, but my heart tells me I want to try it.</vi> <vi>We must appeal to and win (over) the <phrase>hearts and minds</phrase> of the people. [=the emotions and the reasoning of the people]</vi> <vi>His <phrase>conscious mind</phrase> had forgotten the incident, but the memory of it was still buried somewhere in his <phrase>subconscious/unconscious mind</phrase>.</vi> <vi>There's absolutely <phrase>no doubt in my mind</phrase> about his guilt. [=I am sure that he is guilty]</vi> <vi>I know you're disappointed by their decision, but you should just <phrase>put that out of your mind</phrase> [=stop thinking about that] and go back to work.</vi> <vi>I'll handle the schedule. Just <it>put it out of your mind</it>. [=don't think or worry about it]</vi> <vi>Is there something <phrase>on your mind</phrase>? [=is there something troubling you?; are you worried or bothered about something?]</vi> <vi>Why don't you just say what's <it>on your mind</it>? [=why don't you just say what you are thinking?]</vi> <vi>I wish there were some way I could <phrase>ease your (troubled) mind</phrase>. = I wish there were some way I could <phrase>set/put your mind at ease/rest</phrase>. [=could make you stop worrying]</vi> <vi>These problems have been <phrase>preying/weighing on his mind</phrase>. [=he has been worrying about these problems]</vi> <vi>The safety of the children should be <phrase>foremost/uppermost in all our minds</phrase> now. [=we should all be thinking most about the safety of the children now]</vi> <vi>The idea that we might lose was <phrase>the furthest thing from my mind</phrase>. [=I never thought that we might lose]</vi> <vi>I have no intention of quitting my job. <phrase>Nothing could be further from my mind</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She says that getting married again is <phrase>the last thing on her mind</phrase> right now. [=she is not thinking at all about getting married again]</vi> <vi>What was <phrase>going/running through your mind</phrase> [=what were you thinking] when you agreed to do this?</vi> <vi>His name <phrase>slips/escapes my mind</phrase> at the moment. [=I can't remember his name]</vi> <snote>If something (such as an illness) is <phrase>all in your/the mind</phrase>, you are imagining it. <vi>He thinks he's very ill, but it's <it>all in his mind</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If <phrase>your mind is set on</phrase> something or you <phrase>have your mind set on</phrase> something, you are very determined to do or to get something. <vi><it>Her mind is set on</it> becoming a doctor. = She <it>has her mind set on</it> becoming a doctor.</vi></snote> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>It's important to be healthy in both body and <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>He's in a bad/good <phrase>state of mind</phrase>. [=he's in a bad/good mood]</vi> <vi>Installing a security system in your home will give you greater <phrase>peace of mind</phrase>. [=a feeling of being safe or protected]</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>frame of mind</dxt> <dxt>presence of mind</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the way a person thinks or the intelligence of a person <vi>She has a brilliant <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>He has an inquisitive/inquiring <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>He's an evil man with a warped/twisted <it>mind</it>.</vi> <vi>He's recognized as having one of the sharpest <it>minds</it> [=<it>intellects</it>] in this field.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in phrases that describe someone as mentally ill or crazy <vi>There's something wrong with him. He's <phrase>not in his right mind</phrase>. [=he is mentally ill]</vi> <vi>No one <it>in their right mind</it> would try such a stunt. = Who <it>in their right mind</it> would try such a stunt?</vi> <vi>(<it>law</it>) She claims that her father was not <phrase>of sound mind</phrase> when he changed his will. = She claims her father was <phrase>of unsound mind</phrase>. [=was not sane or rational]</vi></un> <un>usually used informally in an exaggerated way <vi>What a ridiculous idea! You must be <phrase>out of your mind</phrase> [=<it>crazy</it>] to believe that.</vi> <vi>I was (going) <phrase>out of my mind with worry</phrase>. [=I was extremely worried]</vi> <vi>I feel like I'm <phrase>losing my mind</phrase>. = I feel like I'm <phrase>going out of my mind</phrase>. [=I feel like I'm going crazy]</vi> <vi>That noise is <phrase>driving me out of my mind</phrase>! [=driving me crazy]</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>out of your mind</phrase> is also used informally to make a statement stronger. <vi>I was bored <it>out of my mind</it>. [=I was very bored]</vi> <vi>She was frightened <it>out of her mind</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a very intelligent person <vi>Many of the world's greatest <it>minds</it> in physics will be attending the convention.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a particular way of thinking about a situation <vi>Everyone at the meeting was <phrase>of like mind</phrase> [=everyone agreed] about how to proceed.</vi> <vi>She is <phrase>of the same mind</phrase> as me. [=she agrees with me]</vi> <vi>We're all <phrase>of one mind</phrase> about him [=we all agree about him]: he's the one we want.</vi> <vi><phrase>To/In my mind</phrase>, that's wrong.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:attention that is given to a person or thing <vi>Try to relax and <phrase>take/get/keep your mind off</phrase> your problems. [=stop thinking about your problems]</vi> <vi>I'm finding it hard to <phrase>keep my mind on</phrase> my work. [=to concentrate on my work]</vi> <vi>After finishing work on the remodeling project, she was able to <phrase>turn her mind to</phrase> [=direct her attention to; work on] other matters.</vi> <vi><phrase>Don't pay him any mind</phrase>. [=don't pay attention to him; ignore him]</vi> <vi>He kept talking but she <phrase>paid him no mind</phrase>.</vi> <vi>You shouldn't <phrase>pay any/much mind to</phrase> what he says.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>a meeting of (the) minds</dre> <dx>see <dxt>meeting</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>at/in the back of your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>back</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>blow someone's mind</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to strongly affect someone's mind with shock, confusion, etc. :to amaze or overwhelm someone's mind <vi>The music really <it>blew my mind</it>.</vi> <vi>The thought of all she's accomplished at such a young age just <it>blows my mind</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mind-blowing</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>call/bring (something) to mind</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (something) to be remembered or thought of <vi>Seeing her again <it>brought to mind</it> the happy times we spent together in college.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change someone's mind</dre> <def><dt>:to cause someone to change an opinion or decision <vi>I tried to convince her, but I couldn't <it>change her mind</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>change your mind</dre> <def><dt>:to change your decision or opinion about something <vi>He wasn't going to come, but at the last minute he <it>changed his mind</it>.</vi> <vi>I tried to convince her, but she wouldn't <it>change her mind</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come/spring/leap to mind</dre> <def><dt>:to be remembered or thought of <vi>What <it>comes to mind</it> when you hear his name?</vi> <vi>I didn't mean to offend you. I just said the first thing that <phrase>came to/into my mind</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>concentrate the/your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>concentrate</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>cross someone's mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>cross</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>enter your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>enter</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>give someone a piece of your mind</dre> <def><dt>:to speak to someone in an angry way <vi>He stopped making so much noise after I went over there and <it>gave him a piece of my mind</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a good mind</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>have half a mind</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>have a good mind</it> or <it>have half a mind</it> to do something, you have a feeling that you want to do it, especially because you are angry or annoyed, but you will probably not do it. <vi>I <it>have a good mind</it> to go over there and tell him to be quiet.</vi> <vi>I <it>have half a mind</it> to tell her what I really think of her.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a mind like a sieve</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sieve</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>have a mind of your own</dre> <def><dt>:to have your own ideas and make your own choices about what should be done <vi>Her parents want her to go to college, but she <it>has a mind of her own</it> and she insists on trying to become an actress.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>I can't get the camera to work right. It seems to <it>have a mind of its own</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have (someone or something) in mind</dre> <def><dt>:to be thinking of (someone or something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be thinking of choosing (someone) for a job, position, etc. <vi>They <it>have you in mind</it> for the job. [=they are thinking of giving the job to you]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be thinking of doing (something) <vi>“I'd like to do something special for our anniversary.” “What sort of thing did you <it>have in mind</it>?”</vi> <vi>He <phrase>had it in mind</phrase> [=<it>intended</it>] to leave the business to his daughter.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in mind</dre> <def><dt>:in your thoughts <vi>We designed this product with people like you <it>in mind</it>. [=we designed it for people like you]</vi> <vi>He went into the bar with trouble <it>in mind</it>. [=intending to cause trouble]</vi> <vi>Before you disregard his advice, <phrase>keep/bear in mind</phrase> [=<it>remember</it>] that he is regarded as one of the leading experts in this field.</vi> <vi>We have a limited amount of money to spend, and we need to <it>keep that in mind</it> [=think of that; consider that] while we're planning our vacation.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in your mind's eye</dre> <dx>see <dxt>eye</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>know your own mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>know</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>make up your mind</dre> <def><dt>:to make a decision about something <vi>I can't <it>make up my mind</it> [=<it>decide</it>] where to take my vacation.</vi> <vi>He had <it>made up his mind</it> not to go.</vi> <vi>He's thinking about going, but he still hasn't <it>made up his mind</it> (about it).</vi> <vi>He's not going. <phrase>His mind is made up</phrase>. [=he has made a decision and will not change it]</vi> <vi>I can't decide for you. You'll have to <phrase>make up your own mind</phrase>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>mind over matter</dre> <def><dt><un>used to describe a situation in which someone is able to control a physical condition, problem, etc., by using the mind <vi>His ability to keep going even when he is tired is a simple question of <it>mind over matter</it>.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>of two minds</dre> <rsl>US</rsl> <vr><vl>or Brit</vl> <va>in two minds</va></vr> <def><dt>:not decided or certain about something :having two opinions or ideas about something <vi>I can't make up my mind where to take my vacation: I'm <it>of two minds</it> about where to go.</vi> <vi>I'm <it>of two minds</it> about (hiring) him: he seems well-qualified, but he doesn't have much experience.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>open your mind</dre> <dx>see <dxt>open</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>put (someone) in mind of (something)</dre> <def><dt>:to cause (someone) to remember or think of (something) <vi>What happened to you yesterday <it>puts me in mind of</it> [=reminds me of] what happened to me a year ago.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>put/set your mind to (something)</dre> <def><dt>:to give your attention to (something) and try very hard to do it <vi>You'd be surprised at what you can accomplish when you <it>put your mind to</it> it.</vi> <vi>We can solve this problem if we <it>put our minds to</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>read someone's mind</dre> <def><dt>:to know exactly what someone is thinking <vi>“I think we should go out to a movie tonight.” “You <it>read my mind</it>. I was thinking the same thing.”</vi> <vi>It's as if you could <it>read my mind</it>.</vi> <vi>He claims that he has the ability to <phrase>read minds</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>mind reader</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>speak your mind</dre> <def><dt>:to say what you think :to state your opinion <vi>If you don't agree with him, don't be afraid to <it>speak your mind</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>take a load/weight off your mind</dre> <def><dt>:to make you stop worrying about something <vi>Hearing that she's safe has really <it>taken a load off my mind</it>!</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
