<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="concerned"> <hw>concerned</hw> <altpr>kənˈsɚnd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more concerned; most concerned</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:feeling worry or concern <vi>The school's decision is being questioned by a group of <it>concerned</it> parents.</vi> <vi>Her family was very <it>concerned</it> for/about her safety.</vi> <vi>Voters are deeply <it>concerned</it> about the economy.</vi> <vi>I was <it>concerned</it> (to hear) that they stayed out too late.</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:having an interest or involvement in something <vi>a discussion that will be of interest to everyone <it>concerned</it></vi> <vi>The lawyers called a meeting of all the <phrase>concerned parties</phrase>.</vi> <vi>She was more <phrase>concerned with</phrase> [=<it>interested in</it>] flirting than with getting the job done.</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) She was <phrase>concerned to</phrase> show that she could do the job. [=she thought it was important to show that she could do it]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having a relation to something <vi>The memo is chiefly <phrase>concerned with</phrase> hiring policies. [=the memo chiefly concerns hiring policies; the memo is chiefly about hiring policies]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>as far as (someone) is concerned</dre> <def><dt>:in the opinion of (someone) <vi><it>As far as I'm concerned</it> [=in my opinion], everything he says is a lie.</vi> <vi><it>As far as she's concerned</it>, he is perfect.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as far as (something) is concerned</dre> <def><dt>:about (something) :with regard to (something) <vi>He has no worries <it>as far as money is concerned</it>. [=he has no worries about money]</vi> <vi><it>As far as the weather is concerned</it> [=<it>as for the weather</it>], we've been having nothing but rain for the past week.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="concern[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">concern</hw> <altpr>kənˈsɚn</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>concerns</if></in> <in><if>concerned</if></in> <in><if>concern*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to relate to (something or someone) :to be about (something or someone) <vi>The novel <it>concerns</it> three soldiers.</vi> <vi>This study <it>concerns</it> the noise levels in cities.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to affect or involve (someone) :to be the business or interest of (someone) <vi>The problem <it>concerns</it> [=<it>affects</it>] us all.</vi> <vi>This conversation doesn't <it>concern</it> you.</vi> <snote>The phrase <phrase>To whom it may concern</phrase> is used at the beginning of a formal letter (such as a letter written to a company) when the name of the person who will read the letter is not known.</snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to make (someone) worried :to cause concern for (someone) <vi>Our mother's illness <it>concerns</it> us.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>concern yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to become involved or interested in something :to give your attention to something <vi>She can handle the problem alone. There's no need for you to <it>concern yourself</it>.</vi> <vi>There's no need for you to <it>concern yourself</it> with/in her problem.</vi> <vi>They shouldn't <it>concern themselves</it> with/about small details.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
