<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="conclusion"> <hw highlight="yes">con*clu*sion</hw> <sound><wav>conclu02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈklu:ʒən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*clu*sions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a final decision or judgment :an opinion or decision that is formed after a period of thought or research <vi>What is your <it>conclusion</it>? [=what do you conclude?]</vi> <vi>The evidence does not support the report's <it>conclusions</it>.</vi> <vi>The evidence points/leads to the inescapable <it>conclusion</it> that she was negligent.</vi> <vi>The logical/obvious <it>conclusion</it> is that she was negligent.</vi> <vi>What led/brought you to that <it>conclusion</it>?</vi> <vi>After thinking about it, we <phrase>came to the conclusion</phrase> [=we decided] that we shouldn't go.</vi> <vi>Scientists haven't yet <phrase>reached a conclusion</phrase> [=made a judgment/decision] on/about the causes of this illness.</vi> <vi>They haven't yet <phrase>arrived at a conclusion</phrase>.</vi> <vi>Is it possible to <phrase>draw conclusions</phrase> [=make judgments] from this evidence?</vi> <snote>To <phrase>jump/leap to conclusions</phrase> is to make judgments too quickly before knowing all the facts. <vi>The evidence suggests that he's to blame, but let's be careful not to <it>jump to conclusions</it>. He may have a good explanation for what happened.</vi> <vi>We should hear his explanation before we <phrase>jump to the conclusion</phrase> that he's to blame.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the last part of something :<sx>end</sx> <un>usually singular <vi>Many people were upset at the <it>conclusion</it> of the meeting. [=when the meeting concluded/ended]</vi> <vi>a satisfactory <it>conclusion</it> to the negotiations</vi> <vi>The <it>conclusion</it> of her speech contained some surprising news.</vi> <vi>The strike has finally <phrase>reached its conclusion</phrase>. [=has finally ended]</vi> <vi>At this point, his victory seems to be a <phrase>foregone conclusion</phrase>. [=his victory seems certain; there seems to be no doubt that he will win]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the act of concluding or finishing something or the state of being finished <wsgram>singular</wsgram> <vi>We had hoped for a quick <it>conclusion</it> of/to the war. [=had hoped that the war would end quickly]</vi> <vi>The case was finally <phrase>brought to a conclusion</phrase> [=was finally concluded] last week.</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>the <it>conclusion</it> of a business deal</vi> <vi>The case was finally <phrase>brought to conclusion</phrase> last week.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in conclusion</dre> <def><dt><un>used to introduce the final comments at the end of a speech or a piece of writing <vi><it>In conclusion</it>, I would like to thank you for inviting me to speak tonight.</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="foregone"> <hw>fore*gone</hw> <sound><wav>forego05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈfoɚˌgɑ:n</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <dro><dre>a foregone conclusion</dre> <def><dt>:something in the future that is certain to happen or be true <vi>It was a <it>foregone conclusion</it> that he would take over the business after his father retired.</vi> <vi>Most people felt that the outcome of the trial was a <it>foregone conclusion</it>. [=they felt sure that the trial would end in a certain way]</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
