<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="conduct[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*duct</hw> <sound><wav>conduc04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈdʌkt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*ducts</if></in> <in><if>con*duct*ed</if></in> <in><if>con*duct*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to plan and do (something, such as an activity) <vi>The police are <it>conducting</it> an investigation into last week's robbery.</vi> <vi>scientists <it>conducting</it> research/experiments</vi> <vi>I like the way the company <it>conducts</it> business.</vi> <vi>The magazine <it>conducted</it> a survey.</vi> <vi>Who will be <it>conducting</it> the meeting?</vi> <vi>The committee is expected to <it>conduct</it> hearings in May.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to direct the performance of (musicians or singers) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>He <it>conducts</it> the choir with great skill and emotion.</vi> <vi><it>conducting</it> the music of Mozart</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>She <it>conducts</it> extremely well.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <slb>always followed by a preposition or adverb</slb> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to guide or lead (someone) through or around a place <vi>Our guide slowly <it>conducted</it> us through the museum.</vi> <vi>Our guide <it>conducted</it> us along the path.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>technical</ssl> <dt>:to allow (heat or electricity) to move from one place to another <vi>Metals <it>conduct</it> electricity well.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>conduct yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to behave especially in a public or formal situation <vi>The way you <it>conduct yourself</it> in an interview often determines whether or not you get the job.</vi> <vi>She <it>conducted herself</it> as a professional and earned the respect of her coworkers.</vi> <vi>I don't approve of the way he <it>conducts himself</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="conduct[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">con*duct</hw> <sound><wav>conduc03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:nˌdʌkt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>somewhat formal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the way that a person behaves in a particular place or situation <vi>A panel investigated her <it>conduct</it> and she was subsequently fired.</vi> <vi>His personal <it>conduct</it> reflected poorly on the company. [=he behaved in a way that made the company look bad]</vi> <vi>professional/sexual <it>conduct</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the way that something is managed or directed <un>+ <it>of</it> <vi>Laws and regulations control the <it>conduct</it> [=<it>management</it>] <it>of</it> business and trade.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="safe-conduct"> <hw>safe–con*duct</hw> <sound><wav>safeco01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈseɪfˈkɑ:ndəkt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>safe–con*ducts</if></in> <def><dt>:protection from the government, police, etc., that is given to a person who is passing through an area that might be dangerous <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>They were given <it>safe-conduct</it> through the city.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The rebels' leader was granted a <it>safe-conduct</it> to talk with the president.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
