<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="condition[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*di*tion</hw> <sound><wav>condit01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈdɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*di*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a way of living or existing <vi>Happiness is the state or <it>condition</it> of being happy.</vi> <vi>The need to be loved is simply part of <phrase>the human condition</phrase>. [=being human]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the state in which something exists :the physical state of something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>The museum restores paintings to their original <it>conditions</it>. [=the museum makes the paintings look the way they were originally]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The car is in excellent/perfect (physical) <it>condition</it>.</vi> <vi>Both clocks are still in good working <it>condition</it>. [=both clocks still work well]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <dt>:the physical or mental state of a person or animal <vi>The driver was taken to the hospital where he was reported to be in (a) good/stable/critical <it>condition</it>.</vi> <vi>Their weakened <it>condition</it> makes them more likely to get sick.</vi> <vi>He can't drive in that <it>condition</it>. [=he is too drunk, ill, upset, etc., to drive]</vi> <vi>The players are all in excellent physical <it>condition</it>. [=<it>shape</it>]</vi> <snote>If you are <phrase>in no condition to do something</phrase>, you are not physically or mentally able to do it. <vi>I was <it>in no condition to go</it> to work yesterday. [=I was too sick to go to work]</vi> <vi>He is <it>in no condition to drive</it>. [=he is too drunk, ill, etc., to drive]</vi></snote> <snote>If you are <phrase>in condition</phrase> or <phrase>in good/excellent (etc.) condition</phrase>, you are strong and healthy. <vi>She was running every evening to stay/keep <it>in condition</it>.</vi> <vi>The players are all <it>in good condition</it>.</vi></snote> <snote>If you are <phrase>out of condition</phrase> or <phrase>in poor/bad (etc.) condition</phrase>, you are not strong and not ready to work or play a sport. <vi>He's overweight and <it>out of condition</it>.</vi> <vi>She hasn't been taking care of herself and is <it>in poor condition</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a sickness or disease that a person has for a long time <vi>He was born with a serious heart <it>condition</it>.</vi> <vi>hereditary/genetic <it>conditions</it></vi> <vi>The <it>condition</it> is often fatal.</vi> <vi>Her medical <it>condition</it> made it impossible for her to walk.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <bnote>conditions</bnote> <sgram>plural</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the situation in which someone or something lives, works, etc. <vi>The organization is working to improve <it>conditions</it> for the poor by providing them with jobs, health care, and better housing.</vi> <vi>They need better living <it>conditions</it>.</vi> <vi>Companies must provide safe working <it>conditions</it> for their employees.</vi> <vi>This type of plant can live in very dry <it>conditions</it>.</vi> <vi>Both teams had trouble with the difficult playing <it>conditions</it>.</vi> <vi>dangerous driving <it>conditions</it></vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the things that affect the way something is or happens :the characteristics of a situation <vi>The President discussed the social and economic <it>conditions</it> of the country.</vi> <vi>New policies have made <it>conditions</it> more favorable for small businesses.</vi> <vi>Scientists controlled the <it>conditions</it> of the experiment.</vi> <vi>Under certain <it>conditions</it> [=in certain circumstances], it is possible to take the test at a later date.</vi> <vi>I will only take the job under the right set of <it>conditions</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the type of weather that occurs at a particular time <vi>weather/atmospheric <it>conditions</it></vi> <vi>The area is experiencing cold/dry <it>conditions</it>.</vi> <vi>severe drought <it>conditions</it></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that you must do or accept in order for something to happen <vi>The buyer must meet the terms and <it>conditions</it> of the contract.</vi> <vi>It was a <it>condition</it> of employment that I join the union. [=I had to join the union in order to get the job]</vi> <vi>You can go <phrase>on one condition</phrase>: you have to finish your homework. [=you can go only if you finish your homework]</vi> <snote>If you agree to do something <phrase>on (the) condition that</phrase> something happens, you will do it only if that thing happens. <vi>She spoke <it>on the condition that</it> she not be identified. = She spoke <phrase>on condition of anonymity</phrase>.</vi> <vi>He taught me the trick <it>on condition that</it> I never tell anyone else how to do it.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that must happen or exist in order for something else to happen <un>usually + <it>for</it> or <it>of</it> <vi>Hard work is a necessary <it>condition for/of</it> success.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>under no condition</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that something is definitely not allowed <vi><it>Under no condition</it> are you to answer the phone. [=you are not to answer the phone at all]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="condition[2]"> <hw hindex="2">condition</hw> <altpr>kənˈdɪʃən</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>conditions</if></in> <in><if>conditioned</if></in> <in><if>condition*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to train or influence (a person or an animal) to do something or to think or behave in a certain way because of a repeated experience <un>often used as <it>(be) conditioned</it> <vi>an experiment in which mice are <it>conditioned</it> to press a button in order to receive food</vi> <vi>People have <it>been conditioned</it> to expect immediate results.</vi> <vi><it>conditioned</it> behavior/responses/reflexes</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make (something, such as hair or leather) softer and less dry by applying a liquid <vi>She shampoos and <it>conditions</it> [=uses conditioner on] her hair daily.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>be conditioned on/upon</dre> <def><sl>formal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something will happen only if something else also happens <vi>Payment <it>is conditioned on/upon</it> completion of the project. [=if you complete the project, you will be paid]</vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="air-conditioning"> <hw>air–con*di*tion*ing</hw> <sound><wav>airco03w.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌeɚkənˈdɪʃənɪŋ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a system used for cooling and drying the air in a building, room, etc. <vi>She wanted her house to have <it>air-conditioning</it>.</vi> <vi>We bought a car with <it>air-conditioning</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi>an <it>air-conditioning</it> system</vi> <vi><it>air-conditioning</it> ducts/equipment</vi></un> <un>abbr. <it>AC</it></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>air–con*di*tioned</ure> <sound><wav>airco01ld.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌeɚkənˈdɪʃənd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>an <it>air-conditioned</it> building/room/car</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="mint[2]"> <hw hindex="2">mint</hw> <altpr>ˈmɪnt</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>mints</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a place where coins are made <un>usually used with <it>the</it> <vi>coins shipped directly from <it>the mint</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a large amount of money <vi>He made a <it>mint</it> [=he earned a large sum of money] in real estate.</vi> <vi>Her family is worth a <it>mint</it>. [=is very wealthy]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in mint condition</dre> <def><dt><snote>If something is <it>in mint condition</it>, it is in perfect condition, just as if it were new. <vi>He kept the car <it>in mint condition</it>.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dxnl>compare <dxt>mint</dxt></dxnl></entry>

</entry_list>
