<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="conflict[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*flict</hw> <sound><wav>confli01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:nˌflɪkt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*flicts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:a struggle for power, property, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>an armed <it>conflict</it></vi> <vi>violent border <it>conflicts</it></vi> <vi>a <it>conflict</it> between two gangs</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>years of armed <it>conflict</it> [=<it>battle</it>]</vi> <vi>recent violent <it>conflict</it> in the region</vi> <vi><it>conflict</it> between (forces of) good and evil</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:strong disagreement between people, groups, etc., that results in often angry argument <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>Everyone in my family always tries to avoid <it>conflict</it>.</vi> <vi>There was inevitable <it>conflict</it> over what to name the group.</vi> <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>They're having serious <it>conflicts</it> over the budget.</vi> <vi>A few students are being trained to resolve <it>conflicts</it> [=<it>arguments, disputes</it>] between other students.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a difference that prevents agreement :disagreement between ideas, feelings, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>I don't see any <it>conflicts</it> between the theories.</vi> <vi>exploring the character's <phrase>inner conflicts</phrase> [=ideas, feelings, etc., that disagree with one another]</vi> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>You'll need to resolve the <it>conflict</it> between your parents' plans for you and your own ambitions.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>conflict of interest</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:a situation in which you are unable to do something because there is something else you have already agreed to do at that same time <vi>He has a <it>conflict</it> and can't attend tomorrow's meeting.</vi> <vi>a scheduling <it>conflict</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>come into conflict</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be different in a way that prevents agreement <vi>Unfortunately, their goals for the project <it>came into conflict</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>There are cases in which these rules <it>come into conflict with</it> [=<it>contradict</it>] one another.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to enter a situation in which there is a struggle for power, property, etc. <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>groups <it>coming into conflict with</it> neighboring tribes</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>in conflict</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:different in a way that prevents agreement <vi>They're <it>in conflict</it> over which car to buy. [=they disagree about which car to buy]</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>The law is <it>in conflict with</it> [=does not agree with] the state's constitution.</vi> <vi>Her ideas were <it>in</it> direct <it>conflict with</it> those of her professor.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in a struggle for power, property, etc. <vi>The two clans were <it>in</it> constant <it>conflict</it> (with one another).</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="conflict[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">con*flict</hw> <sound><wav>confli04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈflɪkt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*flicts</if></in> <in><if>con*flict*ed</if></in> <in><if>con*flict*ing</if></in> <def><gram>no obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be different in a way that prevents agreement :to say or express opposite things <vi>Their versions of what happened <it>conflict</it>. [=do not agree]</vi> <vi>Their goals for the project <it>conflict</it>. [=<it>clash, disagree</it>]</vi> <vi>Reports <it>conflicted</it> on how many people were involved.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>His statement <it>conflicts with</it> the facts.</vi> <vi>Their research <it>conflicts with</it> [=<it>contradicts</it>] what other scientists have found.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to happen at the same time as something else <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>The appointment <it>conflicts with</it> an important meeting I have to go to.</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>conflicting</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>We heard <it>conflicting</it> reports about how many people were involved.</vi> <vi>the candidates' <it>conflicting</it> views</vi> <vi>our <it>conflicting</it> schedules</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="conflict of interest"> <hw>conflict of interest</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>conflicts of interest</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:a problem caused by having official responsibilities that involve things that might be helpful or harmful to you <vi>Critics say the senator created a <it>conflict of interest</it> when she recommended a change to the law that could benefit her husband's company.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
