<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="confidence"> <hw highlight="yes">con*fi*dence</hw> <sound><wav>confid04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:nfədəns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*fi*denc*es</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a feeling or belief that you can do something well or succeed at something <vi>The class gave me more <it>confidence</it>.</vi> <vi>He lacked the <it>confidence</it> to succeed.</vi> <vi>The experience gave her the <it>confidence</it> to start her own business.</vi> <vi>Good grades boosted/bolstered her <it>confidence</it>.</vi> <vi>It takes time to build/gain <it>confidence</it> when you are learning a new skill.</vi> <vi>He's brimming with <it>confidence</it>. = He's full of <it>confidence</it>.</vi> <vi>They have an air of <it>confidence</it> about them.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>He has a lot of <it>confidence in</it> himself.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>self-confidence</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a feeling or belief that someone or something is good or has the ability to succeed at something <vi>The candidate has won/lost the <it>confidence</it> [=<it>trust</it>] of voters.</vi> <vi>She has done little to gain/earn their <it>confidence</it>.</vi> <vi>There is a recent increase in <phrase>consumer confidence</phrase>. [=the good feelings that people have about the economy]</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>They have complete/full <it>confidence in</it> their coach.</vi> <vi>His parents had <it>confidence in</it> their son's ability to succeed.</vi> <vi>The case inspired/restored <it>confidence in</it> our system of justice.</vi> <vi>Recent scandals have undermined <it>confidence in</it> the city's public officials.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>vote of confidence</dxt> <dxt>vote of no confidence</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the feeling of being certain that something will happen or that something is true <vi>School officials express <it>confidence</it> that the problem will soon be resolved.</vi> <vi>We still can't talk about the future with any degree of <it>confidence</it>. [=we don't know what will happen in the future]</vi> <vi>We have <phrase>every confidence</phrase> [=we are sure] that you'll make the right decision.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a relationship in which you tell personal and private information to someone <vi>Doctors cannot betray the <it>confidence</it> of their patients. [=cannot reveal their patients' personal information to other people]</vi> <vi>She accused him of a betrayal/breach of <it>confidence</it>.</vi> <vi>He told me <phrase>in confidence</phrase> that he didn't know how to read.</vi> <vi>Your personal information will be kept <phrase>in strict/strictest confidence</phrase>. [=no one will be told your personal information]</vi> <snote>If you <phrase>take someone into your confidence</phrase>, you tell someone secrets or private information about your life. <vi>She <it>took me into her confidence</it> and told me all about her health problems.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a secret that you tell someone you trust <vi>close friends sharing <it>confidences</it></vi> <vi>She accused him of betraying a <it>confidence</it>. [=she said that he told her secret to other people]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="confidence game"> <hw>confidence game</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ games</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>con</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="confidence man"> <hw>confidence man</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ men</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:<sx>con artist</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="confidence trick"> <hw>confidence trick</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ tricks</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>con</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="confidence trickster"> <hw>confidence trickster</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ -ers</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:<sx>con artist</sx></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="vote of confidence"> <hw>vote of confidence</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>votes of confidence</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a formal process in which people (such as the members of a legislature) vote in order to indicate whether or not they support a leader, government, etc.</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a statement or action that shows continuing support and approval for someone <vi>Many people say the coach should be fired, but he was given a <it>vote of confidence</it> by the team president this week. [=the team president said that he supports and has confidence in the coach]</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="vote of no confidence"> <hw>vote of no confidence</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>votes of no confidence</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a formal vote by which people (such as the members of a legislature) indicate that they do not support a leader, government, etc. <vi>He was forced to resign after a <it>vote of no confidence</it> by the board of directors.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="self-confident"> <hw>self–con*fi*dent</hw> <sound><wav>selfco19.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌsɛlfˈkɑ:nfədənt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more self–con*fi*dent; most self–con*fi*dent</gram> <dt>:having or showing confidence in yourself and your abilities <vi>a quietly <it>self-confident</it> man</vi> <vi>She has a <it>self-confident</it> look about her.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>self–con*fi*dence</ure> <sound><wav>selfco18.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˌsɛlfˈkɑ:nfədəns</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>He lacks the <it>self-confidence</it> to speak his mind.</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>self–con*fi*dent*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
