<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="confirm"> <hw highlight="yes">con*firm</hw> <sound><wav>confir01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈfɚm</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*firms</if></in> <in><if>con*firmed</if></in> <in><if>con*firm*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to state or show that (something) is true or correct <vi>The tests <it>confirmed</it> the doctors' suspicions of cancer.</vi> <vi>The attack <it>confirmed</it> her worst fears about the neighborhood.</vi> <vi>Police would not <it>confirm</it> [=<it>verify</it>] reports of a shooting.</vi> <vi>The award <it>confirmed</it> her status as one of the great movie actresses.</vi> <vi>Medical tests <it>confirmed</it> (that) he did not have a heart attack.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to tell someone that something has definitely happened or is going to happen :to make (something) definite or official <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The dentist's office called to <it>confirm</it> your appointment for tomorrow.</vi> <vi>Please <it>confirm</it> [=<it>acknowledge</it>] receipt of the shipment.</vi> <vi><it>confirm</it> a hotel reservation</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>We have a reservation for you for tomorrow night. Please call to <it>confirm</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:to make (something) stronger or more certain :to cause (someone) to believe (something) more strongly <vi>Her parents' attitude only <it>confirmed</it> [=<it>strengthened, reinforced</it>] her resolve to get her own apartment.</vi> <un>often + <it>in</it> <vi>She was <it>confirmed in</it> her determination to get a higher-paying job.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to give official approval to (something or someone) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They voted to <it>confirm</it> [=<it>ratify</it>] the treaty.</vi> <vi>The Senate has <it>confirmed</it> him as a Supreme Court justice.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The Senate is expected to vote to <it>confirm</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to make (someone) a full member of a church or synagogue :to administer confirmation to (someone) <un>usually used as <it>(be) confirmed</it> <vi>Our son will <it>be confirmed</it> in the spring.</vi> <vi>What year <it>were</it> you <it>confirmed</it>?</vi></un></dt></def> <uro><ure>con*firm*able</ure> <sound><wav>confir03.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈfɚməbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more con*firm*able; most con*firm*able</gram> <utxt><vi>Reports of a battle in the city were not <it>confirmable</it> today.</vi> <vi>The judicial nominee should be easily <it>confirmable</it>.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
