<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="confine"> <hw highlight="yes">con*fine</hw> <sound><wav>confin02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈfaɪn</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*fines</if></in> <in><if>con*fined</if></in> <in><if>con*fin*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to keep (someone or something) within limits :to prevent (someone or something) from going beyond a particular limit, area, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>Please <it>confine</it> [=<it>restrict, limit</it>] your comments <it>to</it> 200 words.</vi> <vi>The cancer was <it>confined to</it> the lung. [=the cancer was only in the lung; the cancer had not spread to any other parts of the body]</vi> <vi>We must <it>confine</it> ourselves <it>to</it> the agenda we've agreed on for this meeting. [=we must only talk about what is on the agenda]</vi> <vi>The town would like to <it>confine</it> commercial development <it>to</it> an area by the highway.</vi> <vi>Students need not <it>confine</it> themselves <it>to</it> a single area of study.</vi> <vi>The city's poverty is not <it>confined to</it> just one neighborhood.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to keep (a person or animal) in a place (such as a prison) <un>usually used as <it>(be) confined</it> <vi>Violent criminals <it>are</it> sometimes <it>confined</it> for life.</vi> <vi>a camp where prisoners <it>were confined</it> during the war</vi></un> <un>often + <it>to</it> or <it>in</it> <vi>She <it>was confined to</it> a psychiatric hospital for a year.</vi> <vi>The bull <it>was confined in</it> a pen behind the barn.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to force or cause (someone) to stay in something (such as a bed or wheelchair) <un>usually used as <it>(be) confined</it> <vi>I regularly visit a sick neighbor who <it>is confined</it> at home. [=who cannot leave home because of being sick]</vi></un> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>was confined to</it> a wheelchair.</vi> <vi>She <it>was confined to</it> bed for a week with the flu.</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
