<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="connection"> <hw highlight="yes">con*nec*tion</hw> <sound><wav>connec04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈnɛkʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*nec*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that joins or connects two or more things <vi>The state plans to improve roads that serve as <it>connections</it> between major highways.</vi> <vi>pipe/hose <it>connections</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the act of connecting two or more things or the state of being connected <vi>There is a fee for <it>connection</it> to the town's water supply.</vi> <vi>All classrooms will be wired for <it>connection</it> to the Internet.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a situation in which two or more things have the same cause, origin, goal, etc. <vi><it>connections</it> between thought and language</vi> <vi>Investigators found no <it>connection</it> between the two fires.</vi> <vi>The school has no <it>connection</it> with the museum.</vi> <vi>Evidence suggests there's a <it>connection</it> between the languages.</vi> <vi>I'm not sure I see the <it>connection</it>.</vi> <vi>Our family feels a deep <it>connection</it> to the land.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a situation in which one thing causes another <vi>the <it>connection</it> between smoking and lung cancer</vi> <vi>The study suggests a <it>connection</it> between small class sizes and higher reading scores.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:something that allows you to become connected to a system, network, etc., through a telephone, computer, or other device <vi>a high-speed Internet <it>connection</it></vi> <vi>The company provides telephone <it>connections</it> for most of the city's residents.</vi> <vi>I can't hear you very well. We must have a <phrase>bad connection</phrase>. [=a problem with the way our phones are connected]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a place where two parts or wires meet and touch <vi>an electrical <it>connection</it></vi> <vi>I fixed the loose <it>connection</it> and now the speaker works fine.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a train, bus, or airplane that you get onto after getting off another train, bus, or airplane as part of the same journey <vi>We fly out of Oslo and then have a <it>connection</it> [=connecting flight] in London.</vi> <vi>We don't have a direct flight to Boston. We have to make a <it>connection</it> in Chicago.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a relationship between people who are part of the same family, who do business together, etc. <vi>He has no <it>connection</it> with his former law firm.</vi> <vi>They are proud of their <it>connection</it> to the royal family.</vi> <vi>Family <it>connections</it> can make getting a job much easier.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a shared feeling of affection and understanding <vi>We didn't know each other for very long, but we had a real <it>connection</it>.</vi> <vi>They're working hard to make an emotional <it>connection</it> with their adopted children.</vi> <vi>a performer's <it>connection</it> with the audience</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:a powerful person who you know and who can help you <un>usually plural <vi>She has some <it>connections</it> in the banking industry.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:a person who sells something illegal <vi>a drug <it>connection</it></vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>in connection with</dre> <def><dt>:in relation to (something) :for reasons that relate to (something) <un>used especially in journalism <vi>Police arrested four men <it>in connection with</it> the robbery.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a/the connection</dre> <def><dt>:to understand that there is a relationship between two or more things <vi>It didn't take long for us to <it>make the connection</it> between the missing money and our partner's new car.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="clamp[1]"> <hw hindex="1">clamp</hw> <sound><wav>clamp001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈklæmp</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>clamps</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a device that holds or presses parts tightly together <vi>a hose <it>clamp</it></vi> <dx>see picture at <dxt>carpentry</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:<sx>denver boot</sx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
