<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="connect"> <hw highlight="yes">con*nect</hw> <sound><wav>connec01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kəˈnɛkt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>con*nects</if></in> <in><if>con*nect*ed</if></in> <in><if>con*nect*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to join (two or more things) together <vi>Can you <it>connect</it> the hose to the sprinkler?</vi> <vi><it>Connect</it> the cable to the battery.</vi> <vi>A hallway <it>connects</it> the two rooms.</vi> <vi>It's the major highway <it>connecting</it> the two towns.</vi> <vi>A common theme <it>connects</it> the stories.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) connected</it> <vi>The two rooms <it>are connected</it> by a hallway.</vi> <vi>The stories <it>are connected</it> by a common theme.</vi> <vi>They <it>are</it> somehow <it>connected</it> to the royal family. [=they are related in some way to the royal family]</vi> <vi>people <it>connected</it> by a common language</vi> <vi>The schools <it>are</it> closely <it>connected</it>. [=they are closely involved with one another]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to join with or become joined to something else <vi>The two bones <it>connect</it> at the elbow.</vi> <vi>The hose <it>connects</it> easily to the sprinkler.</vi> <vi>The bedroom <it>connects</it> to the kitchen.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disconnect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to think of (something or someone) as being related to or involved with another person, thing, event, or idea <vi>People usually <it>connect</it> [=<it>associate</it>] clowns with the circus.</vi> <vi>I never <it>connected</it> you with that group of people.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) connected</it> <vi>In my mind, the two places <it>are connected</it>. [=I think of the two places as being related to each other]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to show or prove that a person or thing is related to or involved with something <vi>Police were unable to <it>connect</it> [=<it>link</it>] her to the crime.</vi> <vi>There's no evidence <it>connecting</it> the company directly to the scandal.</vi> <un>often used as <it>(be) connected</it> <vi>Many people still believe she <it>is</it> somehow <it>connected</it> to the crime.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to join or become joined to something (such as a system or network) through a telephone, computer, or other device <un>usually + <it>to</it></un> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Guests can <it>connect to</it> the Internet from their hotel rooms.</vi> <vi>The computer <it>connects to</it> the fax machine.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>“Operator, can you <it>connect</it> me to the front desk?” [=can you link my telephone with the telephone at the front desk so that I can talk to the person there?]</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>disconnect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to say that an airplane, train, etc., stops at a particular place where passengers get onto another airplane, train, etc., in order to continue their journey <vi>Our flight to New York <it>connects</it> in Chicago.</vi> <vi>We leave from Boston and then <it>connect</it> in New York with a flight bound for China.</vi> <vi>I took an early flight to <it>connect</it> with a train to the coast.</vi> <vi>passengers <it>connecting</it> to/with international flights</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to have or share a feeling of affection and understanding <vi>We really <it>connected</it> on our first date.</vi> <vi>She truly <it>connects</it> with her audience in concert.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:to make a successful shot, hit, or throw <vi>He <it>connected</it> for a home run.</vi> <vi>She failed to <it>connect</it> on the shot. = The shot failed to <it>connect</it>. [=the shot missed]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>connect the dots</dre> <def><sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to learn or understand how different things are related <vi>The information about these events is not new but no one had ever <it>connected the dots</it> until today.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>connect up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>connect up (something)</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>connect (something) up</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to join or link (a device, piece of equipment, etc.) to something <vi>I'm having trouble <it>connecting</it> the speakers <it>up</it> to the TV.</vi> <vi>An electrician will be <it>connecting up</it> the new lights tomorrow. [=joining the lights to a source of electricity]</vi></dt></def></dro> <uro><ure>con*nect*able</ure> <pr>kəˈnɛktəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <gram>more con*nect*able; most con*nect*able</gram> <utxt><vi>The devices are <it>connectable</it>. [=they can be connected]</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>con*nect*ing</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>I missed my <it>connecting</it> flight in Detroit.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="connector"> <hw>con*nec*tor</hw> <pr>kəˈnɛktɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*nec*tors</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a device or a part of a device that connects two computers, pieces of equipment, etc. <vi>an electrical <it>connector</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a road that connects two places, roads, etc. <vi>The road is a major <it>connector</it> from the highway to the town's commercial district.</vi> <vi>Take the airport <it>connector</it> from the main highway.</vi> <vi>a <it>connector</it> road/highway/bridge</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="dot[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">dot</hw> <sound><wav>dot00001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈdɑ:t</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>dots</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a small round mark <vi>Put a <it>dot</it> over the <it>i</it>.</vi> <vi>The <it>dots</it> on the map represent cities.</vi> <vi>She said, “Go to Learners Dictionary dot com [=the Web site www.learnersdictionary.com] for more information.”</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>polka dot</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a small spot :a small area that is different in color from the main part <vi>You have a <it>dot</it> of ketchup on your shirt.</vi> <vi>As we drove away, the house became just a <it>dot</it> on the horizon.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a short signal (such as a sound or a flash of light) that represents a letter or a part of a letter in Morse code <vi>The Morse code for the letter <it>v</it> is three <it>dots</it> and a dash.</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>dash <dxn>7</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def> <dro><dre>connect the dots</dre> <dx>see <dxt>connect</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>on the dot</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:exactly at a particular time <vi>She arrived at 3 o'clock <it>on the dot</it>. = She arrived <it>on the dot of</it> 3. [=she arrived exactly at 3 o'clock]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>since the year dot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>year</dxt></dx></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
