<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="construction"> <art><artref id="construction.eps"/><capt/><dim>394,150.9</dim></art> <hw highlight="yes">con*struc*tion</hw> <sound><wav>constr14.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈstrʌkʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*struc*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the act or process of building something (such as a house or road) <vi><it>Construction</it> of the new bridge will begin in the spring.</vi> <vi><it>Construction</it> on the bridge will occur daily from 8:00 p.m. to 4:00 a.m.</vi> <vi>The new school is now <phrase>under construction</phrase>. [=is now being built]</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>construction</it> costs/equipment/materials</vi> <vi>They haven't chosen a <it>construction</it> site for the building yet. [=they haven't decided where the building will be built yet]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the business of building things (such as houses or roads) <vi>“What do you do for a living?” “I'm <phrase>in construction.”</phrase> [=I do work that involves building things]</vi> <vi>the <it>construction</it> industry</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the way something is built or made <vi>Note the similar <it>construction</it> of the buildings.</vi> <vi>I like these binoculars because of their sturdy <it>construction</it>. [=because they are strongly built]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:the way words in a sentence or phrase are arranged <vi>Some people think it is wrong to end a sentence with a preposition, but the <it>construction</it> is quite common in English.</vi> <vi>That verb is commonly used in passive <it>constructions</it>.</vi> <vi>This word is used in positive/negative <it>constructions</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the process of organizing ideas or thoughts into a new theory, statement, etc. <vi>His ideas were pivotal in the <it>construction</it> of a new way to understand time and space.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:a way of understanding something <vi>Don't put a negative <it>construction</it> on what I said: [=don't understand what I said in a negative way]</vi> <vi>a broad/strict <it>construction</it> [=<it>interpretation</it>] of the Constitution</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="construction paper"> <hw>construction paper</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>US</sl> <dt>:a kind of thick paper that comes in many colors and is used especially by children in school to create art</dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
