<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="consideration"> <hw highlight="yes">con*sid*er*a*tion</hw> <pr>kənˌsɪdəˈreɪʃən</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*sid*er*a*tions</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:careful thought :the act of thinking carefully about something you will make a decision about <vi>You should give some serious <it>consideration</it> to your retirement plans.</vi> <vi>After careful <it>consideration</it>, he agreed to their requests.</vi> <vi>Her suggestion is still <phrase>under consideration</phrase> by the committee. [=the people on the committee are still thinking about and discussing her suggestion]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:a desire to avoid doing something that will make another person sad, upset, angry, etc. <vi>Show/have some <it>consideration</it> and turn down that radio.</vi> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>He has no <it>consideration for</it> her feelings.</vi> <vi>Out of <it>consideration for</it> the victim's family, no photos will be shown.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:something that you think about when you make a choice or decision <vi>Finding a house close to work was an important <it>consideration</it> for them.</vi> <vi>Economic/practical <it>considerations</it> forced her to delay her education.</vi> <vi>The tent weighs 10 pounds, which is no small <it>consideration</it> [=which is something that is important to think about] when you're going to be hiking.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <ssl>formal</ssl> <dt>:payment for something <wsgram>count</wsgram> <un>usually singular <vi>She offered to do the job for a small <it>consideration</it>.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>He charged a small fee <phrase>in consideration of</phrase> [=as payment for] his many services.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>take (something) into consideration</dre> <def><dt>:to think about (something) before you make a decision or form an opinion <vi>We will <it>take</it> your experience <it>into consideration</it> [=we will think about how much experience you have] when we decide who will get the job.</vi> <vi>Results of the study should be <it>taken into consideration</it> before the medication is prescribed to patients.</vi> <vi>When you <phrase>take everything into consideration</phrase> [=when you think about both the good and bad things], it really wasn't a bad deal.</vi> <vi><it>Taking everything into consideration</it> [=<it>all things considered</it>], we're probably better off now.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
