<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="consistent"> <hw highlight="yes">con*sis*tent</hw> <sound><wav>consis05.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈsɪstənt</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more con*sis*tent; most con*sis*tent</gram> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:always acting or behaving in the same way <vi>He is a <it>consistent</it> supporter of the museum.</vi> <vi>We need to be more <it>consistent</it> in handling this problem.</vi> <vi>Data from recent experiments show <it>consistent</it> results. [=results that do not change]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of the same quality</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:good each time <vi>His pitching has always been very <it>consistent</it>. [=<it>reliable</it>]</vi> <vi>Customers expect that the quality of service they receive will be <it>consistent</it>.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>inconsistent</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:continuing to happen or develop in the same way <vi>The pain has been <it>consistent</it>.</vi> <vi>Your grades have shown <it>consistent</it> improvement this school year.</vi> <vi>You need to exercise on a more <it>consistent</it> [=<it>regular</it>] basis.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>inconsistent</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:having parts that agree with each other <vi>Their descriptions of the accident were <it>consistent</it>.</vi> <vi>She is not being <it>consistent</it> in her argument. [=her argument includes parts that do not agree with one another]</vi> :in agreement <it>with</it> something <vi>His statements were not <it>consistent with</it> the truth. [=were not true]</vi> <vi>His symptoms are <it>consistent with</it> heart disease. [=the symptoms he has are symptoms of heart disease]</vi> <vi>The decision was <it>consistent with</it> the company's policy.</vi> <dx>opposite <dxt>inconsistent</dxt></dx></dt></def> <uro><ure>con*sis*tent*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl> <utxt><vi>The technique is now being used <it>consistently</it>.</vi> <vi>He <it>consistently</it> earned high grades all through high school.</vi> <vi>She has played <it>consistently</it> all season.</vi> <vi>The store has <it>consistently</it> low prices.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="consistency"> <hw>con*sis*ten*cy</hw> <sound><wav>consis04.wav</wav></sound> <pr>kənˈsɪstənsi</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*sis*ten*cies</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the quality or fact of being consistent: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the quality or fact of staying the same at different times <vi>His statements on this subject have lacked <it>consistency</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:the quality or fact of being good each time <vi>He's a good pitcher, but he lacks <it>consistency</it>. [=his pitching is good in some games and bad in other games]</vi> <vi>Customers expect <it>consistency</it> in the quality of service they receive.</vi> <vi>Practice will ensure greater <it>consistency</it> of performance.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the quality or fact of having parts that agree with each other <vi>Her argument lacks <it>consistency</it>. [=her argument is not logical because its ideas do not agree with each other]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the quality of being thick, firm, smooth, etc. <wsgram>count</wsgram> <vi>paints of varying <it>consistencies</it></vi> <un>usually singular <vi>She mixed the dough to the right <it>consistency</it>.</vi> <vi>The batter should have/be the <it>consistency of</it> pudding.</vi> <vi>Boil the juice to the <it>consistency of</it> a thick syrup.</vi></un> <wsgram>noncount</wsgram> <vi>The paints vary in <it>consistency</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
