<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="contact[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">con*tact</hw> <sound><wav>contac01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈkɑ:nˌtækt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>con*tacts</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition that exists when two people or things physically touch each other :a state of touching <vi>Physical <it>contact</it> between a mother and child is very important.</vi> <vi>the point of <it>contact</it> between the bat and the ball [=the point where the bat and ball touch each other]</vi> <vi>a disease that is spread by sexual <it>contact</it></vi> <vi>The players <phrase>made contact</phrase> [=touched or hit each other] and a foul was called.</vi> <vi>The train's wheels should <phrase>make contact with</phrase> [=<it>touch</it>] the track continuously.</vi> <vi>Do not let your skin <phrase>come in/into contact with</phrase> [=<it>touch</it>] the acid.</vi> <vi>The chemical kills germs <phrase>on contact</phrase> [=as soon as the chemical touches the germs]</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <dt>:the state or condition that exists when people see and communicate with each other <vi>The actor has had little <it>contact</it> with the public [=has not interacted much with the public] in recent years.</vi> <vi>It was during that time that native people first <phrase>came into/in contact with</phrase> [=first saw and began communicating with] the settlers.</vi> <vi>She joined a book club to get a little <phrase>human contact</phrase> [=interaction with other people] while the kids were in school.</vi> <snote>Your <phrase>contact information</phrase> is the information (such as your telephone number, address, or e-mail address) that tells someone how to communicate with you. <vi>Don't forget to put your <it>contact information</it> on the application.</vi></snote> <snote>If you are <phrase>in contact</phrase> with someone, you communicate with them sometimes. <vi>“Are you <it>in contact</it> [=<it>in touch</it>] with them?” “No, I haven't been <it>in contact</it> with them for years. I don't even know where they live anymore.”</vi> <vi>We kept/stayed <it>in</it> close <it>contact</it> [=we communicated often] after college.</vi> <vi>He's been <it>in</it> direct <it>contact</it> with the president. [=he has communicated directly with the president]</vi> <vi>We'd lost touch, but a mutual friend put us <it>in contact</it> (with each other) again.</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>lose contact</phrase> with someone or something, you are no longer able to communicate with that person or thing. <vi>I <it>lost contact</it> [=<it>lost touch</it>] with her years ago, but recently got her e-mail address through a mutual friend.</vi> <vi>We <it>lost</it> radio <it>contact</it> with the ship for a short time. [=we could not communicate with the ship using their radio]</vi></snote> <snote>If you <phrase>make/establish contact</phrase>, you have succeeded in communicating with someone. <vi>She's been trying to <it>make contact</it> with distant relatives.</vi> <vi>The phone system wasn't working so we weren't able to <it>make contact</it>.</vi> <vi>We were finally able to <it>establish contact</it> with them.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an occurrence in which people communicate with each other <vi><it>Contacts</it> between the two leaders have been frequent in recent weeks.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>eye contact</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:a person who you know and who can be helpful to you especially in business <vi>I applied for a job at that law firm because I have a <it>contact</it> there.</vi> <vi>business <it>contacts</it></vi> <snote>Someone who is listed as a <phrase>contact</phrase> in information from a company or organization is the person you can write to or call with questions about that company or organization.</snote></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:<sx>contact lens</sx> <vi>He lost one of his <it>contacts</it> in the swimming pool.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the connection of two objects (such as pieces of metal) that allows an electrical current to pass through them <vi>The <it>contact</it> must be maintained for the current to flow.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a part through which electricity passes from one object to another <vi>The camera's flash isn't working because the electrical <it>contacts</it> need to be cleaned.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="contact[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">contact</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:nˌtækt</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>contacts</if></in> <in><if>contact*ed</if></in> <in><if>contact*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to call or write to (someone or something) :to communicate with (someone or something) <vi>For more information, <it>contact</it> the city's tourism office.</vi> <vi>We were able to <it>contact</it> them by radio.</vi> <vi>She <it>contacted</it> everyone on the list.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="contact[3]"> <hw hindex="3">contact</hw> <altpr>ˈkɑ:nˌtækt</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:allowing players to touch or hit each other <vi>Ice hockey is a <it>contact</it> sport.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:acting when physical contact occurs <vi><it>contact</it> insecticides/poisons</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="contact lens"> <art><artref id="contact_lens.tif"/><capt>contact lens</capt><dim>76.8,87</dim></art> <hw>contact lens</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>⁓ lenses</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a thin piece of round plastic that is worn on the eye to improve vision <vi>She wears <it>contact lenses</it> more often than glasses.</vi> <ca>called also <cat>contact</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="eye contact"> <hw>eye contact</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:a situation in which two people are looking directly into each other's eyes <vi>He maintained <it>eye contact</it> with me throughout the conversation.</vi> <vi>The speaker <it>made eye contact</it> with audience members.</vi> <vi>The jury <it>avoided eye contact</it> with the defendant as the verdict was read.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="lose"> <hw highlight="yes">lose</hw> <sound><wav>lose0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlu:z</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>los*es</if></in> <in><if>lost</if> <sound><wav>lose0002.wav</wav><wav>lost0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlɑ:st</pr></in> <in><if>los*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to be unable to find (something or someone) <vi>She's always <it>losing</it> her gloves.</vi> <vi>Don't <it>lose</it> your keys.</vi> <vi>Hold my hand: I don't want to <it>lose</it> you.</vi> <vi>The police <it>lost</it> him in the crowd. [=the police were no longer able to find/see him after he went into the crowd]</vi> <vi>The airline <it>lost</it> my luggage. [=my luggage did not arrive at the airport I flew into]</vi> <vi>He <it>lost</it> the fly ball in the sun. [=he was unable to see the fly ball because he was looking toward the sun]</vi> <vi>The letter was <phrase>lost in the mail</phrase>. [=it was sent but never delivered to the person it was addressed to]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail to win (a game, contest, etc.) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi><it>lose</it> a battle/game</vi> <vi>She <it>lost</it> her bid for reelection. [=she failed to win the election; she was not reelected]</vi> <vi>We <it>lost</it> the game by a score of 4–2.</vi> <vi>He <it>lost</it> his title in the rematch.</vi> <vi>She <it>lost</it> the lawsuit.</vi> <vi>The team <it>lost</it> three games but won the next four.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The team <it>lost</it> in the finals.</vi> <vi>an athlete known for <it>losing</it> with grace</vi> <vi>That horse always <it>loses</it>.</vi> <vi>He hates to <it>lose</it> when money is involved.</vi> <vi>How could she play that well and still <it>lose</it>?</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The Yankees <it>lost to</it> the Red Sox.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail to keep or hold (something wanted or valued) <vi><it>lose</it> an advantage</vi> <vi>The country <it>lost</it> its independence 50 years ago.</vi> <vi>The mayor is <it>losing</it> power/influence/support.</vi> <vi>He is in danger of <it>losing</it> control of the company.</vi> <vi>She <it>lost</it> control of the car and skidded off the road.</vi> <vi>I was so angry that I <it>lost</it> control (of myself, of my temper) and yelled at them.</vi> <vi>She didn't <it>lose</it> her job but she <it>lost</it> access to all confidential company materials.</vi> <vi>The senator <it>lost</it> votes when he angered some of his supporters.</vi> <vi>The religious community was <it>losing</it> its younger members.</vi> <vi>He hasn't <it>lost</it> his sense of humor.</vi> <vi>They had <it>lost</it> all hope of winning the title.</vi> <vi>I don't want anything to eat. I've <it>lost</it> my appetite. [=I no longer feel hungry]</vi> <vi>She began to <it>lose</it> confidence in herself. [=to feel less confident]</vi> <vi>Try not to <it>lose</it> patience with the children.</vi> <vi>The accident victim was rapidly <it>losing</it> blood.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry I'm late. I <phrase>lost track of</phrase> the time. [=I failed to stay aware of the time; I did not realize that so much time had passed]</vi> <vi>She <phrase>lost her balance</phrase> [=failed to keep her weight spread equally] and fell.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>have nothing (else/left) to lose</phrase>, you cannot make a situation worse by taking a risk. If you <phrase>have a lot to lose</phrase> or <phrase>have too much to lose</phrase>, you could make your situation much worse by taking a risk or doing something. <vi>You might as well apply for the job. You have <it>nothing to lose</it> and everything to gain.</vi> <vi>Some of them are married and have young children—they <it>have a lot to lose</it>.</vi> <vi>I can't quit now. I <it>have too much to lose</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to fail to earn or keep (money) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>They <it>lost</it> all their money/savings in a poor investment.</vi> <vi>The company has been <phrase>losing money</phrase> for the past several years. [=it has been spending more money than it has been earning]</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>Investors <it>lost</it> heavily when the company's stock failed to meet expectations.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to have (something) taken from you or destroyed <vi>We <it>lost</it> (electrical) power during the storm.</vi> <vi>He <it>lost</it> an arm in the war. [=one of his arms was destroyed or so badly injured that it had to be removed]</vi> <vi>They <phrase>lost everything</phrase> in the fire. [=all their possessions were destroyed in the fire]</vi> <vi>He yelled so much during the game that he <phrase>lost his voice</phrase> [=he was unable to speak] for two days.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to gradually have less of (something) as time passes <vi>Many people who <it>lose</it> weight by dieting eventually gain the weight back.</vi> <vi>She has been <it>losing</it> strength in her legs.</vi> <vi>He was gradually <it>losing</it> his eyesight.</vi> <vi>He's <it>losing</it> his hair. [=becoming bald]</vi> <vi>The public seems to have <it>lost</it> interest in the case.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to cause (someone) to fail to win or keep (something) :to cause the loss of (something) for (someone) <vi>One careless statement <it>lost</it> the election for her. = One careless statement <it>lost</it> her the election. [=she lost the election because of one careless statement]</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to decrease in (something) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The TV program has <it>lost</it> popularity [=become less popular] in recent years.</vi> <vi>The plane was <it>losing</it> altitude.</vi> <vi>What will you do if the company's stock <it>loses</it> value when you expect it to gain value?</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>What will you do if the stock <it>loses</it> when you expect it to gain?</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to decrease in value by (a specified amount) <vi>His retirement account <it>lost</it> three percent last quarter.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to decrease in value when compared to something else <vi>The dollar <it>lost</it> against the pound last week.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to experience or suffer the death of (a relative, friend, etc.) <vi>She <it>lost</it> her husband in the war. [=her husband was killed in the war]</vi> <vi>He <it>lost</it> his best friend to cancer. [=his best friend died of cancer]</vi> <vi>The country <it>lost</it> thousands of young men in/during the war. = Thousands of young men were <it>lost</it> [=<it>killed</it>] in/during the war. = Thousands of young men <phrase>lost their lives</phrase> in/during the war.</vi> <vi>She's very sick, and the doctors say they're afraid they're going to <it>lose</it> her. [=they're afraid that she is going to die]</vi> <vi>I was sad to hear that she <phrase>lost the baby</phrase>. [=that her baby died before being born or soon after being born]</vi> <vi>a sailor who was <phrase>lost at sea</phrase> [=who died at sea]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to no longer have or be with (someone who leaves) <vi>We'll be sorry to <it>lose</it> you when you leave for your new job.</vi> <vi>He begged his wife to forgive him and told her that he didn't want to <it>lose</it> her.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail to keep control of (something) <vi>He <phrase>lost his temper/cool/composure</phrase>. [=he became angry]</vi> <vi>She wondered if she was <phrase>losing her mind/sanity</phrase>. [=becoming insane]</vi> <vi>He seems to be <phrase>losing his nerve</phrase>. [=becoming afraid]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>lose your head</tag> at <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to fail to use (something, such as time) :<sx>waste</sx> <vi>I don't want to <it>lose</it> this chance/opportunity.</vi> <vi>We <it>lost</it> (a good bit of) <it>time</it> in that traffic jam.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>lost no time</phrase> in getting the project started. [=she got the project started immediately]</vi> <vi>We need to get started immediately. There's <phrase>no time to lose</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a watch or clock</ssl> <dt>:to show a time that is earlier than the correct time :to run slow by (an amount of time) <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>My old watch <it>loses</it> a minute every day.</vi> <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>a clock that <it>loses</it> less than any other clock yet invented</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to explain something in a way that is not clear to (someone) :to confuse (someone) <vi>I'm sorry. You've <phrase>lost me</phrase>. [=I don't understand what you're telling me]</vi> <vi>I understood the first part of the lecture, but when he started to talk about quantum physics he <it>lost me</it> completely. [=I was completely unable to understand what he was saying]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <dt>:to succeed in getting away from (someone who is following or chasing you) <vi>She tried to <it>lose</it> them by turning down a side street.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to get rid of (something unwanted) <vi>I just can't seem to <it>lose</it> this cold.</vi> <vi><it>Lose</it> the attitude, okay? [=stop having a bad attitude; stop being annoyed, uncooperative, etc.]</vi> <vi>You can <it>lose</it> [=<it>remove</it>] that sentence and the paragraph will sound better.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>lose contact</dre> <dx>see <dxt>contact</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose count</dre> <dx>see <dxt>count</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose face</dre> <dx>see <dxt>face</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose ground</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ground</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose it</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to become insane <vi>He was always a little strange, but now he's completely <it>lost it</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start behaving in an uncontrolled way because you are angry or upset <vi>I was so angry that I almost <it>lost it</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><dt>:to fail to keep or get something valued or desired <vi>Whoever benefits from the new government programs, the American taxpayer is bound to <it>lose out</it> in the end.</vi> <un>often + <it>on</it> or <it>to</it> <vi>If you don't invest with us, you'll be <it>losing out on</it> a great opportunity! [=you'll be missing/wasting a great opportunity]</vi> <vi>She <it>lost out to</it> a better-known actress for the lead role. [=she did not get the lead role because a better-known actress got it]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose sleep over</dre> <dx>see <dxt>sleep</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose the plot</dre> <dx>see <dxt>plot</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose touch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>touch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your bearings</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bearing</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your grip</dre> <dx>see <dxt>grip</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your head</dre> <dx>see <dxt>head</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your heart</dre> <dx>see <dxt>heart</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your life</dre> <dx>see <dxt>life</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your lunch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>lunch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your marbles</dre> <dx>see <dxt>marble</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose yourself</dre> <def><dt>:to give all of your attention or thought to something <vi>He <it>lost himself</it> in his work.</vi> <vi>a musician who completely <it>loses herself</it> in the music</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>lose your shirt</dre> <dx>see <dxt>shirt</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your touch</dre> <dx>see <dxt>touch</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>lose your way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <uro><ure>los*able</ure> <sound><wav>lose0004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈlu:zəbəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>a <it>losable</it> game</vi></utxt></uro> <uro><ure>los*ing</ure> <fl>adjective</fl> <utxt><vi>the <it>losing</it> candidate in the race [=the candidate who did not win; the candidate who lost]</vi> <vi>The team is on a <it>losing</it> streak.</vi> <vi>The team had a <it>losing</it> record/season.</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

</entry_list>
