<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="absolute"> <hw highlight="yes">ab*so*lute</hw> <sound><wav>absolu02.wav</wav><wav>absolu01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæbsəˌlu:t</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>always used before a noun</slb> <dt>:complete and total <vi>You can't predict the future with <it>absolute</it> certainty.</vi> <vi>I have <it>absolute</it> faith/confidence in her ability to get the job done.</vi> <vi>He swore an oath of <it>absolute</it> secrecy.</vi> <vi>When it comes to using computers, I'm an <it>absolute</it> beginner.</vi> <un>often used informally to make a statement more forceful <vi>I swear that what I'm telling you is the <it>absolute</it> truth.</vi> <vi>He was an <it>absolute</it> disgrace to his family.</vi> <vi>That's <it>absolute</it> nonsense/rubbish!</vi> <vi>(<it>US</it>) That restaurant serves the <it>absolute</it> best Mexican food I've ever eaten. [=that restaurant serves absolutely the best Mexican food I've ever eaten]</vi></un> <un>sometimes used with <it>the most</it> <vi>That's <it>the most absolute</it> nonsense/rubbish I ever heard!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:not limited in any way <vi>a ruler with <it>absolute</it> power = a ruler whose power is <it>absolute</it></vi> <vi><it>absolute</it> authority</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having unlimited power <vi>The country is ruled by an <it>absolute</it> dictator/monarch.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:ruled by someone with unlimited power <vi>The country is an <it>absolute</it> monarchy.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not allowing any doubt <vi>He says that he has <it>absolute</it> [=<it>certain</it>] proof that his client is innocent.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:never changing :always true or real <vi>You have the <it>absolute</it> right to remain silent.</vi> <vi>an <it>absolute</it> requirement = a requirement that is <it>absolute</it></vi> <vi><it>absolute</it> [=<it>unqualified</it>] freedom</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not depending on or compared with anything else <vi>The company has grown <phrase>in absolute terms</phrase>, but its share of the market is actually less than it was a few years ago.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>ab*so*lute*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl> <gram>noncount</gram> <utxt><vi>the <it>absoluteness</it> of the king's power</vi> <vi>the <it>absoluteness</it> of his certainty</vi></utxt></uro></entry>

	<entry id="absolute zero"> <hw>absolute zero</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>technical</sl> <dt>:the temperature that is believed to be the lowest possible temperature <snote>Absolute zero is equal to approximately -273.15°C or -459.67°F.</snote></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
