<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="access[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">ac*cess</hw> <sound><wav>access01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈækˌsɛs</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a way of getting near, at, or to something or someone <vi>All public buildings should provide wheelchair <it>access</it>. [=a way for people in wheelchairs to enter]</vi> <vi>The cup holders are placed for easy <it>access</it>. [=so that they can be easily reached]</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>The town wants to increase public <it>access to</it> beaches.</vi> <vi>A dirt road provides <it>access to</it> the home.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a way of being able to use or get something <vi>We have Internet <it>access</it> at the library.</vi> <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>We have <it>access to</it> the Internet at the library.</vi> <vi>I don't have <it>access to</it> a car right now. [=I don't have a car that I can use right now]</vi> <vi>Patients need better <it>access to</it> medical care.</vi> <vi>increasing children's <it>access to</it> education</vi> <vi>They tried to gain illegal <it>access to</it> the company's network.</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>access time</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:permission or the right to enter, get near, or make use of something or to have contact with someone <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>They refused to give the police <it>access to</it> their home.</vi> <vi>divorced parents who want increased/improved <it>access to</it> their children</vi> <vi>Investigators are trying to <phrase>gain/get access to</phrase> his financial records. [=trying to get the right to see his financial records]</vi> <vi>He was <phrase>granted/denied access to</phrase> the report. [=he was given/refused permission to see the report]</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="access[2]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="2">access</hw> <altpr>ˈækˌsɛs</altpr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>access*es</if></in> <in><if>accessed</if></in> <in><if>access*ing</if></in> <def><gram>+ obj</gram> <dt>:to gain access to (something): such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to use, enter, or get near (something) <vi>The new system makes it easier to <it>access</it> the money in your bank account.</vi> <vi>Your favorite radio stations can be <it>accessed</it> at the touch of a button.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to open or load (a computer file, an Internet site, etc.) <vi>The file loads every time you <it>access</it> the Web site.</vi> <vi>The file can be <it>accessed</it> by many users at the same time.</vi> <vi>She could work at home by remotely <it>accessing</it> the company's network.</vi> <vi>You'll need a password to <it>access</it> the database.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="access time"> <hw>access time</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>technical</sl> <dt>:the time required to get stored information from a computer memory</dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="public access"> <hw>public access</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <dt>:a television channel on which any person can broadcast a program <vi>The city council meeting will be broadcast on <it>public access</it>.</vi> <un>often used before another noun <vi><it>public access</it> television</vi> <vi>a <it>public access</it> channel</vi></un></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="random-access memory"> <hw>random–access memory</hw> <fl>noun</fl> <def><gram>noncount</gram> <dt>:<sx>ram</sx></dt></def></entry>

</entry_list>
