<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<entry_list version="1.0">

	<entry id="accident"> <hw highlight="yes">ac*ci*dent</hw> <sound><wav>accide02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈæksədənt</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>ac*ci*dents</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a sudden event (such as a crash) that is not planned or intended and that causes damage or injury <vi>We got in a car <it>accident</it>. = We had a car <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>a traffic <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>a fatal <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>a motorcycle <it>accident</it></vi> <vi>He was injured in an <it>accident</it> at work.</vi> <vi>The <it>accident</it> happened when her car slid on a patch of ice.</vi> <vi>Investigators are still trying to determine the cause of the <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>“I'm sorry that I broke the bowl.” “That's OK. It was just an <it>accident</it>.” = “That's OK. <phrase>Accidents will happen</phrase>.”</vi> <snote>An <phrase>accident waiting to happen</phrase> is a person or thing that is dangerous or unsafe. <vi>My brother is the clumsiest person I know. He's just an <it>accident waiting to happen</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an event that is not planned or intended :an event that occurs by chance <vi>Their meeting was an <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>It is just an <it>accident</it> that they arrived when they did.</vi> <vi>She says that her pregnancy was an <it>accident</it>.</vi> <vi>His wealth is a mere <phrase>accident of birth</phrase>. [=he is wealthy only because he was born into a wealthy family]</vi> <vi>He says that no one is to blame for his illness. It was just an <phrase>accident of nature</phrase>. [=something that happened naturally]</vi> <vi>It is <phrase>no accident</phrase> that the assistant he hired is so good-looking. [=he deliberately chose a good-looking person to be his assistant]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>by accident</dre> <def><dt>:in a way that is not planned or intended <vi>They met <it>by accident</it>. [=<it>by chance</it>]</vi> <vi>She says that she became pregnant <it>by accident</it>. [=<it>unintentionally</it>]</vi> <vi>Scientists discovered the vaccine almost/quite/entirely <it>by accident</it>.</vi> <vi>Did it happen <it>by accident</it> [=<it>accidentally</it>] or by design?</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>

	<entry id="accident-prone"> <hw>accident–prone</hw> <fl>adjective</fl> <def><gram>more accident–prone; most accident–prone</gram> <dt>:tending to have many accidents <vi>He is clumsy and <it>accident-prone</it>.</vi></dt></def></entry>

	<entry id="wait[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">wait</hw> <sound><wav>wait0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈweɪt</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>waits</if></in> <in><if>wait*ed</if></in> <in><if>wait*ing</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to stay in a place until an expected event happens, until someone arrives, until it is your turn to do something, etc. <vi>I hate <it>waiting</it> in long lines.</vi> <vi>They <it>waited</it> at the train station together.</vi> <vi>You should have <it>waited</it> a little longer. He showed up right after you left.</vi> <vi>I don't have time to <phrase>wait around</phrase>. If he's not here in five minutes, I'm leaving.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>waited behind</phrase> after class to talk to the professor.</vi> <vi>I'm sorry to have <phrase>kept you waiting</phrase>. How may I help you?</vi> <vi>I <phrase>waited and waited</phrase> but he never showed up.</vi> <un>often followed by <it>to</it> + <it>verb</it> <vi>I'm <it>waiting to use</it> the bathroom.</vi> <vi>The taxi is <it>waiting to bring</it> us to the airport.</vi> <vi>Doctors are <phrase>ready and waiting</phrase> <it>to give</it> aid.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>She read the newspaper while <it>waiting for</it> the bus.</vi> <vi><it>Wait for</it> me! I'll go with you.</vi> <vi>Take a seat and <it>wait for</it> your name to be called.</vi> <vi>It can take over an hour to be served at the restaurant, but the food is <phrase>worth waiting for</phrase>.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to not do something until something else happens <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi><it>Wait</it>! Don't start the engine yet.</vi> <vi>We <it>waited</it> for the sun to set before starting the fire.</vi> <un>often + <it>until</it> <vi>We'll <it>wait until</it> you come back to start the movie. [=we will not start the movie until you come back]</vi></un> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>You will have to <phrase>wait your turn</phrase>. [=you cannot do something until it is your turn]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to remain in a state in which you expect or hope that something will happen soon <vi>I know she was happy when I lost my job. She was <it>waiting</it> to see me fail.</vi> <vi>I have <it>waited</it> for this opportunity for a long time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to remain in a state in which you expect to learn or find out something soon <vi>You will have to <it>wait</it> two weeks for the test results.</vi> <vi>She <it>waited</it> for his answer.</vi> <vi>We are <it>waiting</it> to hear back from the doctor.</vi> <vi>He'll be a star some day—<phrase>just (you) wait</phrase>. [=I feel sure that he will be a star some day]</vi> <vi>I have to <phrase>wait and see</phrase> whether or not I got the job.</vi> <vi>“What are you making?” “<it>Wait and see</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be done or dealt with at a later time <vi>The other issues will just have to <it>wait</it> until our next meeting.</vi> <vi>“Can this <it>wait</it> until tomorrow?” “No, it can't <it>wait</it>.”</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be in a place ready to be dealt with, taken, etc. <un>always used as <it>(be) waiting</it> <vi>It's time to come inside. Dinner <it>is waiting</it>.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>for</it> <vi>There <it>is</it> a package <it>waiting for</it> you at home.</vi> <vi>She had several messages <it>waiting for</it> her at the office.</vi></un></dt></def> <dro><dre>accident waiting to happen</dre> <dx>see <dxt>accident</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>can't wait</dre> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>can hardly wait</va></vr> <def><dt><snote>If you <it>can't wait</it> or <it>can hardly wait</it>, you are very excited about doing something or eager for something to happen or begin. <vi>The concert is tomorrow, and we <it>can hardly wait</it>!</vi> <vi>The children <it>can hardly wait</it> for summer.</vi> <vi>I <it>can't wait</it> to try your apple pie.</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>hurry up and wait</dre> <dx>see <dxt>hurry</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>wait a minute/moment/second</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to tell someone to stop and wait briefly <vi><it>Wait a minute</it>. I need to tie my shoe.</vi> <vi>Please <it>wait one moment</it> while I take this call.</vi> <vi>If you would just <it>wait a second</it>, I could explain what happened.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used to interrupt someone or something because you have noticed, thought of, or remembered something <vi><it>Wait a second</it>—that's not what she said.</vi> <vi><it>Wait a minute</it>. I just remembered where I put the keys.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait at table</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>formal</sl> <dt>:to serve food or drinks as a waiter or waitress <vi>He <it>waited at table</it> for two years.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait for it</dre> <def><sl>chiefly Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to emphasize that the following statement is foolish, surprising, funny, etc. <vi>He says he was fired because—<it>wait for it</it>—he refused to compromise his principles.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait in</dre> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to stay at home and wait for someone or something to arrive <vi>I can't go out. I've got to <it>wait in</it> for a delivery.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait on</dre> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>wait upon</va></vr> <def><gram>phrasal verb</gram> <sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>wait on/upon (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to serve food or drinks as a waiter or waitress to (someone) <vi>The hostess <it>waits on</it> tables/people when the restaurant is crowded.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to provide service to (a customer) :to help (a customer) make purchases <vi>He is busy <it>waiting on</it> customers at the moment.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to act as a servant to (someone) <vi>He seems to expect his wife to <it>wait on</it> him.</vi> <vi>She <phrase>waited on</phrase> her children <phrase>hand and foot</phrase>. [=she acted like a servant to her children; she provided her children with everything they needed or wanted]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>wait on/upon (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to wait for (someone or something) to arrive or happen <vi>We <it>waited on</it> him, but he never came.</vi> <vi>The government's decision must <it>wait on</it> the committee's report. [=the government's decision will not be made until the committee has issued its report]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>wait (something) out</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>wait out (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to stay in one place until the end of (something) <vi>We <it>waited out</it> the storm in our hotel room.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait tables</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <dt>:to serve food or drinks as a waiter or waitress <vi>She has a job <it>waiting tables</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait until/till</dre> <def><dt><un>used to emphasize that a future event is going to be very surprising, important, etc. <vi><it>Wait till</it> you see their new house. It's just beautiful!</vi> <vi>You think you're in trouble now? <phrase>Just wait until</phrase> your father finds out what you did, young lady! [=your father will be very angry and will punish you when he finds out what you did]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>wait up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to delay going to bed while you wait for someone to arrive <vi>I'll be late; don't <it>wait up</it> (for me).</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to stop moving forward so that someone who is behind you can join you <vi>Hey, <it>wait up</it> (for me)! I'm going with you.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>what are you waiting for?</dre> <def><dt><un>used to say that someone should do something immediately <vi><it>What are we waiting for?</it> Let's go inside and get something to eat.</vi> <vi>If you have so much work to do, then <it>what are you waiting for?</it></vi></un></dt></def></dro></entry>

</entry_list>
